<movie id="257" title="Hannah and Her Sisters">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="32">
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Lee glances over her shoulder, then turns from the doorway and walks away. The camera follows her, moving across a book-and-photograph-filled bookshelf that obscures her from view as she walks into a crowded, comfortable vestibule. People, some holding drinks, some just entering the apartment, surround her. Everyone is talking at once, carrying on easy, familiar conversation.</context>
      <utterance>God, she's beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Lee smiles at the various people, exchanging greetings.</context>
      <utterance>She's got the prettiest eyes, and she looks so sexy in that sweater.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two more guests enter the apartment; the vestibule is full now. Still walking, Lee lightly hugs one of the children as she continues on her way towards the living room. Elliot's voice, as well as the jazzy music, is heard.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, how are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Lee walks into the living room, turning her head back for a moment to talk to the child she has just hugged.</context>
      <utterance>I just want to be alone with her and hold her and kiss her...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The camera is still moving with Lee as she smiles and stops to chat with her mother. Elliot's voice, as well as the music, continues over the low din of warm conversation.</context>
      <utterance>...and tell her how much I love her and take care of her. Stop it, you idiot. She's your wife's sister. But I can't help it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Lee starts to walk off again, finishing her conversation with her mother. She passes several other guests, then turns to greet April, giving her a warm, brief hug.</context>
      <utterance>I'm consumed by her. It's been months now. I dream about her. I- I, I think about her at the office. Oh, Lee.  What am I gonna do?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Elliot's voice-over continues as he is actually seen, standing in a doorway having a conversation with a gesturing, rotund man. Both are holding drinks as Lee, carrying a tray of hors d'oeuvres and two drinks, walks between them. The space is very tight; the men hold up their drinks to make room for her.</context>
      <utterance>I hear myself mooning over you, and it's disgusting. Before, when she...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Elliot watches Lee walk off; the other man, oblivious, continues to talk. Elliot reluctantly returns to the conversation, but he can't help turning his head to gaze at the offscreen Lee as the other man chatters on.</context>
      <utterance>...squeezed past me in the doorway, and I smelled that perfume on the back of her neck...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The camera resumes following a smiling Lee. She has just put down the tray and drinks near April, and briskly and obliviously, she walks past a doorway where Elliot, still ruminating, watches her, entranced.</context>
      <utterance>...Jesus, I, I thought I was gonna swoon! Easy...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The camera stays with Elliot, who is still watching the offscreen Lee. In the background, guests continue to chatter warmly with each other. Hannah, carrying a tray of hors d'oeuvres, walks up behind the distracted Elliot.</context>
      <utterance>You're a dignified financial advisor. It doesn't look good for you to swoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elliot returns from his reveries with a start.</context>
      <utterance>Elliot? Elliot?  Sweetheart?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mm-hm?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elliot, taking one of the hors d'oeuvres, starts nibbling as well as he and Hannah walk past the bookshelf into the living room.</context>
      <utterance>Have you tried these? These are wonderful.  Holly and her friend made them.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're fantastic.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't they great?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your sister is an unbelievable cook.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elliot and Hannah, eating and talking, walk past a hallway and offscreen as Holly appears, walking down the hallway. She holds a drink and a plate of hors d'oeuvres; she stands at the entrance to the hallway, eating and looking at the offscreen guests.</context>
      <utterance>I know! I know!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She has all the cooking talent.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, she doesn't, either. You've got tons as well.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holly, why don't you open your own restaurant?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmm, we practically are. Well...  not a restaurant, but...  April and I are going to do some catering!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? You're kidding!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holly takes a sip of her drink as Hannah and Elliot walk over to her.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, we decided!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perfect!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmm...I mean, we love to cook for our friends, so  we thought until an acting job comes through, we could just make some extra money, you know, doing a few private parties.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's where your talent lies.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holly and Hannah begin to laugh.</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get outta here.  Could I speak to you privately?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holly and Hannah walk off; Elliot watches them leave.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm her husband! She tells me anything!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hannah, I have to borrow some more money.  Don't get upset.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mmm?</context>
      <utterance>Mmm, I never get upset over that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Holly talks, sipping her drink, Hannah busily works in the kitchen, which contains a large center table stacked with bowls and plates of food, hanging pots and pans, and general party clutter. She walks on-and-offscreen as she talks and listens to her sister.</context>
      <utterance>This is the last time, I promise. And I'm keeping strict accounts.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holly, please. Don't insult me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someday, I'll pay it all back.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. H-how much do you need?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hannah, who'd been mashing some food in a bowl on a nearby counter, hesitates momentarily. She turns to Holly.</context>
      <utterance>Two thousand dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hannah, licking her fingers, walks past Holly.</context>
      <utterance>Hannah, I know it's a lot, but my friend April and I, we have this catering idea I think's going to be great.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You admit that we're great cooks, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, in order to get started, there's just a few things I have to buy...  and some old debts I have outstanding.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you just tell me one thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we talking about cocaine again?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A timer goes off. Hannah walks past Holly to attend to some food on a different stove. Holly turns to face her. Only Holly is seen as she talks to the offscreen Hannah, the camera moving in closer on her face. As Holly speaks, she distractedly nibbles an hors d'oeuvre. In the background, her parents can be heard singing in the living room.</context>
      <utterance>I swear. I swear. We've already got some requests to do a few dinner parties.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holly pops another hors d'oeuvre into her mouth as the background singing gets louder and the film cuts to:</context>
      <utterance>I mean, obviously, I'm not going to be a caterer forever, you know. We both still go to auditions. Something could turn up at any moment. But the parties are at night, days are free, I can still take my acting class. I haven't done drugs on a year.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="30">
   <speaker>EVAN &amp; NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they continue to sing, the film cuts back to the kitchen, where Lee, carrying some glasses, enters through the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>"A whimpering, simpering Child again Bewitched, bothered, and bewildered Am I..."</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee walks over to her sisters, putting the glasses down on a counter. Hannah is scooping seeds out of a cantaloupe. Holly, leaning on the table, sips her drink. The music from the living room is softly heard as the three sisters chat comfortably and easily with each other.</context>
      <utterance>Mom and Dad are floating down memory lane again!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aah... Hey, have you tried Holly and her friend's shrimp puffs?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think they're fantastic.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've outdone yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, my God. Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need an antihistamine. Mom thinks she's feeling her asthma, and so...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ohh?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(laughing)</context>
      <utterance>...before she starts turning into Camille...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Mom's Camille when she gets up in the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least she isn't drinking. Did you notice?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mm-hm.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't she look great in that new dress?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sisters all talk at once; Hannah is still working at the sink.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you think she does?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She really does, though.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, she knows it, too, 'cause she's flirting with all the men here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe when she's eighty, she'll stop straightening her garter belt when there's a guy around.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should get a garter belt.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get a garter belt...  Get a garter belt and flirt.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are the antihistamines?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uh, he's got them somewhere.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I don-- Ask Elliot for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee leaves the kitchen. Holly, puffing on her cigarette, watches her go.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frederick didn't come with her.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When does Frederick ever come with her?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN &amp; NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"A pill he is But still he is All mine and I'll Keep him until he is Bewitched, a'both--"</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="68">
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watch out, you guys. Beep-beep!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, your kids are so adorable.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHILDREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bye! Bye!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, it gets so lonely on the holidays.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the sisters talk, the piano music stops. There's the sound of light applause as Evan begins a new song, faintly heard in the dining room.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, gosh. Well, you know, that's why I invited Phil Gammage tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Hannah!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's, uh, you never know--</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's such a loser!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not a loser at all!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, he's such a loser!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's the headmaster of Daisy's school.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, perfect! He reminds me of Ichabod Crane.  His Adam's apple keeps jumping up and down whenever he gets excited.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen. He's a lot better than your ex-husband. He's got a good job.  Would you light those, please? He's-he's-he's not a dope addict or anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me a break.</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The film cuts to April, standing in the doorway of the dining room and holding a drink.</context>
      <utterance>Am I interrupting...</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...any sister talk?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mm-mm!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera moves with April as she walks over to the table, where Hannah and Holly are lighting candles.</context>
      <utterance>Come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, good...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come in, come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...because there are no interesting single men at this party!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, listen...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. It's terrible!</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, I've looked everywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holly groans, looking at her sister, while April sips her drink and nods.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe April would like Phil. Phil Gammage, the tall guy in there by the piano.</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hm-mm. Oh, yeah. I met Phil.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmm?</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hannah screams with laughter as she walks toward the end of the table, past a gleeful Holly, who points her finger at Hannah as she passes. Hannah, still laughing, playfully pushes the accusing finger away.</context>
      <utterance>He's the--He looks like Ichabod Crane?</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love that. That's my type.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks over to a nearby china cabinet.</context>
      <utterance>I can't believe it!</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, really, I really like him a lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Holly continues to tease her sister, Hannah opens a drawer in the cabinet. She takes out two apples decorated with paper turkey heads and tails and hands them to April.</context>
      <utterance>No, really, we mustn't get discouraged.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hannah will invite some men over who don't look like Ichabod Crane.</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>April starts to put the turkey apples on the table. A bemused Hannah takes two more out of the cabinet and places one of them on the table as well.</context>
      <utterance>Mmm.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not this Thanksgiving, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here. Be careful with those.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>While Holly is talking, Hannah hands her the last turkey apple, accidentally sticking her with one of the toothpicks that keeps the decorations in place.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe at Christmas, New Year's. If not this New Year's, maybe next New Year's.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ouch!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The film cuts to a short hallway leading to a bathroom in Hannah's apartment. In the foreground is a standing lamp. In the background, Elliot is seen walking inside the bathroom, looking around the room. Light piano music is dimly heard.</context>
      <utterance>Oh!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks out of the bathroom, moving down the hallway towards the camera.</context>
      <utterance>Must be here someplace.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you know, I, I love that book you lent me. The Easter Parade? You were right. It had very special meaning for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elliot walks into the bedroom as Lee continues to talk offscreen. The camera, leaving Elliot, moves across the room, past a wall of framed paintings, a headboard and bed, a night table and lamp, revealing Lee. She is flipping through a book by a curtained window.</context>
      <utterance>How's Frederick? He didn't come.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, well, you know Frederick. One of his moods. Although it wasn't a bad week. He  uh, sold a picture.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera stays with Lee as she walks around the room, past another curtained window, a television set, and a rolltop desk. She absently flips through the book as she talks to the offscreen Elliot.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, great.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee puts the book she's been holding down on the desk, only to pick up another one. She looks at the offscreen Elliot.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it was, it was one of his better drawings, a very beautiful nude study. Actually, it was of me.  It's funny, you know, it's a funny feeling to know you're being hung naked in some stranger's living room.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reacts. The camera moves to a blushing Elliot, following him now as he walks across the room.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you can't tell it's me, although--  You're turning all red, Elliot.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? So, so, what else? Wh- what are you up to?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I don't know. My unemployment checks are running out. Um, I was thinking of taking some courses at Columbia with the last of my savings. As Lee speaks, Elliot parts a hanging curtain against the wall to reveal a stereo and some records. He looks at the offscreen Lee.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like, uh...?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Elliot reaches inside the stereo shelf, grabbing a bottle of antihistamines, the camera moves back to Lee, who sits down on the bed. She is still holding a book.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elliot walks over to Lee; he sits down on a footstool in front of her.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, sociology, psychology maybe. I always thought I might like to work with children.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(chuckling self-consciously)</context>
      <utterance>Incidentally, I-I always have clients who are furnishing places. Some of them might-might be interested in buying art. Shall I, shall I call you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She chuckles; Elliot smiles and chuckles with her.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, sure.  You know, uh, Frederick would really by grateful for a sale.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elliot turns in the direction of his wife's voice.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, you guys?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hannah, eating a carrot stick, enters the bedroom. The camera stays with her momentarily as she walks towards Elliot and Lee.</context>
      <utterance>Dinner's ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, great.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look so beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't she look pretty?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bumped into your...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...ex-husband on the street the other day.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was, he's just as crazy as ever. He was on his way to get a blood test.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, Mickey's such a hypochondriac. I wonder how he'd handle it if there was ever anything really wrong with him?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go have dinner, shall we?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmm.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good idea.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, ladies and gentlemen...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan continues to clank his glass to get everyone's attention.</context>
      <utterance>Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, now...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Resigned, Holly puts down her silverware. Lee smothers a laugh. Norma, reacting, glances at Holly and Lee. Everyone knows what's coming.</context>
      <utterance>I'm starving!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...this is a toast! This is a toast.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get his wine away.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holly laughs. Lee glances over to her, reacting. Hannah, embarrassed, reacts and sits with her hands on her face. Lee and the rest of the guests put down their silverware. They look at Evan, listening.</context>
      <utterance>This is a toast. You know this beautiful Thanksgiving dinner was all...</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hannah, embarrassed, makes a victory sign.</context>
      <utterance>...prepared...by Hannah.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee and Holly try to suppress their laughter. Norma glares at them.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, and a little help...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elliot wraps his arm around Hannah; he pulls her towards him affectionately and kisses her on the cheek. She hugs him back.</context>
      <utterance>...from Mavis, also.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mavis the maid exits, carrying some trays, as the group starts to cheer and applaud. Holly waves her napkin at April, then holds up her wine glass.</context>
      <utterance>Holly and April, thanks for helping.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you did it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>April, April!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am... I did slave all day.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The group continues to cheer as they all toast Hannah. She reacts, smiling but embarrassed.</context>
      <utterance>And we drink to her, and we all congratulate her on her wonderful accomplishment during this last year...her great success in A Doll's House!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guests, sipping their wine, quiet down as Norma continues to speak. Lee and Holly unsuccessfully try to contain their laughter. Mavis reenters the dining room to serve more food to the children.</context>
      <utterance>Ya-a-a-a-y!  I played Nora. I hate to tell you what year...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And it's very difficult to behave like Torvald's little chipmunk without making a perfect ass out of yourself!  Now I think that Ibsen would have been damn proud of our Hannah! Norma toasts her daughter; everyone follows her. The applause and cheers begin anew. Hannah, reacting, chuckles.</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Speech! Speech! Speech!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A few guests sip their wine. They all quiet down as Hannah starts her speech, glancing around the table and gesturing.</context>
      <utterance>Yea-a-a-a-ah!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know about that. Oh, no, I just, see, I-I've been very, very lucky. W-when I had the kids, I decided to stop working and just, you know, devote myself to having the family, and I've been very, very happy  but...I've always secretly hoped that maybe some little gem would come along and tempt me back on the stage...</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hannah, still embarrassed, looks down at a plate. The group applauds once more, toasting and drinking, and warmly sounding their approval.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, bravo! Bravo!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="32">
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want some coffee or tea?</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee continues to walk, past a modern chaise, a bookcase, some sofas, two columns. Lamps hang down from the ceiling. The classical music still plays in the background. Lee stops at a plastic-enclosed work area. Frederick can be seen working at a drawing board on the other side of the clear plastic screen.</context>
      <utterance>No, thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about something to eat?</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The background music stops.</context>
      <utterance>No, nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Lee walks over to the drawing board where Frederick is sitting, he is seen intently cleaning some paintbrushes with a rag. Lee stands by him, leaning over the board, and looks directly at him. The table is filled with cans of brushes and artist's equipment.</context>
      <utterance>Mmm, what am I gonna do with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God!  And why didn't you come tonight? We all had a terrific time. I really think you would have enjoyed yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going through a period of my life where I just can't be around people.  I didn't want to wind up abusing anyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're all so sweet.</context>
      <utterance>You're not going to abuse them.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lee...  you are the only person I can be with...who I really look forward to being with.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frederick and Lee embrace; Lee sighs.</context>
      <utterance>You're too harsh with everyone. You know that, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't it enough that I can love you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmm...</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmm?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(sighing)</context>
      <utterance>...you're such a puzzle.  So sweet with me and so...contemptuous of everyone else.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, there was a time  when you were very happy to be only with me. You wanted to learn everything about poetry, about music.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mm-hm.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee kisses Frederick twice, then releases him and walks out of the work area.</context>
      <utterance>Have I really taught you everything I have to give?  I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee walks over to the loft's stereo area, pulling up the sleeves of her sweater as Frederick talks.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Elliot said he might have a couple of clients for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure all those morons he handles have a deep feeling for art. Lee picks up a book from the stereo shelf. She leans back against the unit, glancing through its pages.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmm  you never know. They might. He's just trying to do the nice thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because he likes you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me?</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frederick, leaving his work area, walks past Lee; his hands are in his pockets.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elliot lusts after you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera stays with Frederick as he walks into the loft's bedroom area.</context>
      <utterance>Based on what? You never even see him.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sits down at the foot of the bed and starts taking off his shoes.</context>
      <utterance>Based on...whenever you see him, you always come home full of books he's recommended...</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(shrugging)</context>
      <utterance>...or films you must see or...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee sits down next to Frederick; he takes her hand.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no, no, no. He's my sister's husband. And I think if you gave him half a chance, you'd like him. He's very intelligent.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee kisses Frederick back on the cheek. They embrace. Frederick laughs; their embrace gets tighter.</context>
      <utterance>He's a glorified accountant, and he's after you.  And I prefer to sell my work to people who appreciate it, not to rock stars.  You understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ohhh!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="49">
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, they won't let us do the sketch?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The trio pass Mary, another assistant, in conversation with two other co-workers. She holds a clipboard.</context>
      <utterance>Talk to Standards and Practices. They think it's too dirty.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without missing a beat, he takes Mary's wrist and continues walking.</context>
      <utterance>But we showed it to them in rehearsal!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the group walks through a large doorway, Larry catches up to Mickey.</context>
      <utterance>Mickey, we got a half hour to air!</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The group turns right into a new corridor, briefly off the screen. As they scurry off, their voices are heard.</context>
      <utterance>We're short! The show is five minutes short!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How could it be short? We timed everything  long.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are all now seen walking down the new corridor towards the camera. The corridor is crowded with busy TV personnel. The group continues to talk frantically as people hurry past them. One man pushes rudely past Mary as he walks; she looks back at him briefly.</context>
      <utterance>If we have to...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...pull out the sketch, then we'll be ten minutes short!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary checks her wristwatch as they rush down the corridor.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know how they can do that to us. That's-- We go on in thirty minutes, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're doing it because our ratings are low.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the group briskly walks past an open door, Gail, another assistant, runs out, brandishing her glasses.</context>
      <utterance>I got such a migraine.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gail runs in front of the group. Without missing a step, she faces Mickey and walks backwards, gesturing and talking frantically.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Mickey!</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The fast-tracking group turns the corner. Gail pats Mickey's back; she gestures in exasperation.</context>
      <utterance>Mickey! Listen, we better go right to Ronny's dressing room. This kid must have taken sixteen hundred Quaaludes. I don't think he's going to be able to do the show!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is interrupted by Ed Smythe, an official from the Standards and Practices Department, who's been standing in the corridor waiting for Mickey. Mickey stops and shakes Ed's hand as if he'd known the official would be there. Gail stops by his side while the others walk into a background studio doorway that is busy with scurrying personnel.</context>
      <utterance>Why me, Lord? What did I--</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You--  Standards and Practices?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ed Smythe, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Why, all of a sudden, is the sketch dirty?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Child molestation is a touchy subject...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could you--</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...with the affiliates.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Read the papers! Half the country's doing it!</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, but you name names.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We nev-- We don't name names!  We say the Pope.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We always say the Pope!</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That sketch...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We--</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A writer, holding a script, walks out of the background studio, looking around.</context>
      <utterance>...cannot go on the air.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Je--</utterance>
   <speaker>WRITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Mickey, Gail, and Ed turn towards the writer.</utterance>
   <speaker>WRITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mickey and Gail walk over to the angry writer, Ed forgotten with this new crisis.</context>
      <utterance>Who changed my sketch about the PLO?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had to make some cuts. It's four lousy lines!</utterance>
   <speaker>WRITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mickey, Gail, and the writer start walking down a corridor adjacent to the studio.</context>
      <utterance>The whole premise is ruined!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The writer reacts angrily. Gail tries to get Mickey's attention as they walk.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, you're crazy! It's not so delicate. Everybody's married to every line.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mickey, I can--</utterance>
   <speaker>WRITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care! I don't want anyone tampering with my goddamn work without telling me!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(muttering)</context>
      <utterance>All right, all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mickey, Mickey, listen, listen.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know...</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In-in-in-instead of the child molestation sketch, why don't we repeat the Cardinal Spellman Ronald Reagan homosexual dance number?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No--</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ron coughs.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, wh-- Yeah, what did you do? Swallow a drugstore?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at this guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gail walks around the chair. The camera shows she and Mickey talking to Ron through the reflection in the cluttered makeup mirror.</context>
      <utterance>I lost my voice.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jesus!</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ron sighs.</context>
      <utterance>Ron...Ronny, you know you do have to go on in twenty-five minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>My, my ulcer's starting to kill me!</context>
      <utterance>Hey, does anybody got a Tagamet?</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mickey, as reflected in the mirror, starts to pace as the movie cuts to:</context>
      <utterance>You want a Quaalude?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="48">
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi! Hi!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know...I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Glad you could put in an appearance.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got two minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hannah nods as Mickey comes inside. She closes the door behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Very good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta see new comedians later, I've gotta--</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her voice trails off as Mickey walks over to the twins.</context>
      <utterance>Two minutes on your sons' birthday. You know, it's not going to kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hannah's twins greet Mickey with cries of "Hi, Daddy!" and indistinct chatter.</context>
      <utterance>Happy Birthday, fellas! Happy Birthday!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mickey hands a gift to each twin. They grow quiet, suddenly shy.</context>
      <utterance>Guys, look what Daddy brought. Presents!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, aren't you like, you know...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The twins put down their gifts, one on the sofa, one on the coffee table, and hug their father.</context>
      <utterance>...a little, uh, hey! A little hug! What is this? Now how 'bout a little action from the kids?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is everything?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything's good. Everything's fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Yeah?  Okay, kids, you can open the presents now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me get a little reaction here.  How's Elliot?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you know what? I'm trying to convince him to produce a play.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think he'll find that satisfying.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? That'll be terrific for him, I think.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like him. I think he's a sweet guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The few times that I've met him...  Isn't that a great mitt?</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Daddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Cause he's a loser.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ohh!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>H-he's so awkward and he's clumsy like me...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...so I, so I like that. I always like an underconfident person...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's really nice!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...you know? I, uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She helps Twin 2 open his present. It's a football.</context>
      <utterance>You know, he's been wanting a mitt.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've always had good taste in husbands, so...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mh-hm.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a beauty!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't that great?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go right over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Twin 2, panting, runs offscreen to catch the football.</context>
      <utterance>Football!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on! Hurry up! Let's go!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mickey throws the football.</context>
      <utterance>Go out, go out by the Sung vase and, and catch this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(whistling)</context>
      <utterance>See?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a sound of breaking glass. Hannah and Mickey react.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, d-- Watch, watch the picture.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Mickey pushes open the outside door of Dr. Abel's office, as the movie cuts to the doctor's consultation room. The doctor is framed in the doorway, looking through a file cabinet.</context>
      <utterance>Gee, Hannah's sweet. Although, sometimes I still do get angry when I think of things. Oh, what the hell. At least, I'm not paying child support.  Oh, God, I hope there's nothing physically wrong with me, either.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. ABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's the, uh, problem this time?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, so, but it was when I was younger, so--</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. ABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I saw your father this week about his sinus...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mm-hm.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. ABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and, uh, he complained of chest pains.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, this guy's the real hypochondriac of the family. I mean, he's, you know, he's--</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. ABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mentioned on the phone that you'd had some dizziness.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Abel chuckles.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, a little dizziness, and I think, I think I'm developing a hearing loss in my right ear  ...or my left ear, my, my left...oh, n-n-n-no. No, I'm sorry. It was my right, my right, my right or my left ear.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now I ca-can't remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. ABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An uptempo big-band sound is heard as the movie cuts to Mickey's examination, beginning with a close-up of Dr. Abel using an otoscope to examine the ear of a nervous Mickey. Next is a hearing test. The film shows the doctors's hands turning the dials on a sonometer. Mickey sits on a nearby high stool, large earphones on his head. He listens with such concentration that he squints his eyes. He holds up a finger in response to the sounds he hears in his headset. Finally, the film shows Dr. Abel hitting a large turning fork with his finger. He puts the vibrating fork to Mickey's ear. Mickey, looking up at the offscreen doctor's face, nods. The music stops as the film cuts back to Dr. Abel's consultation room. Dr. Abel walks from the examining room, through the consultation room, to a second examining room across the way. He talks to the offscreen Mickey as he walks.</context>
      <utterance>Let's take a look.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. ABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm sorry to say you have had a significant drop in the high- decibel range of your right ear.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Abel moves offscreen in the second examining room. The camera stays focused on the doorway to this room as the doctor and Mickey talk offscreen.</context>
      <utterance>Really?!</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. ABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you been exposed to a loud noise recently, or did you have a virus?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Abel briefly passes by the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>No, I-I've been perfectly healthy. You know me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I always, I-I always imagine that I have things.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. ABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When did you first notice this?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. ABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Have you, uh, noticed any of that?</context>
      <utterance>You've had some dizzy spells.  What about ringing and buzzing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Um, am I going deaf, or something?</context>
      <utterance>Yes, now-now that you mention it, uh, I-I-I have, uh, buzzing and also ringing. Ringing and buzzing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. ABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And it's just in one ear?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Abel chuckles as he closes Mickey's file and straightens up. The camera looks past his back and shoulders to the anxious Mickey.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, is it, is it, uh, healthier to have problems in both ears?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. ABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'd like to have them run some tests.</context>
      <utterance>What I'd like to do, is to make an appointment for you at the hospital.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Abel lays his pen across Mickey's closed file. He walks around his desk and sits on its edge close to Mickey.</context>
      <utterance>The hospital? What kind of tests?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. ABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, don't get alarmed. These are just more sophisticated audiometry tests than I can run here.  I mean, it's, it's nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if it's nothing, then why do I have to go into the hospital at all? I mean, uh, I hear perfectly fine, so I'm, so I'm a little weak on the, on the high decibels. So I, you know, I won't go to the opera.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. ABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, there's no reason for panic. I just want to rule out some things.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. ABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's nothing. Will you trust me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The film cuts to Dr. Wilkes, on the telephone at his end. He is in his office; he leans back in his chair, dangling his stethoscope as he speaks. Behind him, a chest X-ray is mounted on a light panel.</context>
      <utterance>Huh, uh, hello, Dr. Wilkes? Dr. Wilkes, this is Mickey Sachs. You have a minute? I want to ask you a question.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. WILKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The movie cuts back and forth between Mickey in his phone booth asking questions and Dr. Wilkes in his office answering them.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, Mickey. What's up?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I-if you have, i-if you have a hearing loss in one ear, and-and it's not from a, uh, virus or a loud noise or anything, wh-what are the possibilities?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. WILKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything. Uh, often it's hereditary. Flu, uh, even a small noise will do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, right, but-but nothing worse?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. WILKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, yes, I guess the, uh, dark side of the spectrum is a brain tumor.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="37">
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, so here's the new pages.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, did cards get these?</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not yet. No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, let's hope it's good.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The assistants walk off. As they leave, Gail calls out after them.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, really. Really.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The telephone starts to ring, Gail pauses, looking offscreen. She takes off her glasses and squints.</context>
      <utterance>Eh, we'll be down in a minute, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The film cuts to Mickey, who is pacing and wringing his hands. He walks over to Gail. The phone continues to ring.</context>
      <utterance>Mickey, what's the matter with you? You're all white!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to pant, looking worriedly around the room. He continues to wring his hands as Gail stares at him, concerned.</context>
      <utterance>I feel dizzy. Sshh, you know, I don't feel well.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(sighing)</context>
      <utterance>Do you hear a ringing? Is there, is there a, is there a ringing sound?</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sits down and picks up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Yeah, yeah. I hear, I hear it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>N-n-no, not that.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like--</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gail hangs up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, yeah, yeah. We're going to be working late tonight. N-no, we'll order out. It's all right. Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(sighing)</context>
      <utterance>Sssss, if I have a brain tumor, I don't know what I'm gonna do.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have a brain tumor. He didn't say you had a brain tumor.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, naturally  they're not gonna tell you, because, well, you know, th--, sometimes the weaker ones will panic if you tell 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But not you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pants and begins to pace around the room. The camera follows him as he walks away from Gail.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, God!  Do you hear a buzzing? Is there a buzzing?</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mickey, come on, we got a show to do!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't keep my mind on the show.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But there's nothing wrong with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If there's nothing wrong with me  then why does he want me to come back for tests?!</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(sighing)</context>
      <utterance>Well, he has to rule out certain things.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like what?! What?</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Cancer, I--</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't say that! I don't want to hear that word!  Don't mention that while I'm in the building.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you don't have any symptoms!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mickey sighs.</context>
      <utterance>You--I got the classic symptoms of a brain tumor!</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two months ago, you thought you had a malignant melanoma.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naturally, I, I--Do you know I--The sudden appearance of a black spot on my back!</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was on your shirt!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sighs again as Gail, frustrated, gestures impatiently to the papers on the desk.</context>
      <utterance>I--How was I to know?!  Everyone was pointing back here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mickey begins pacing around the room again. He wrings his hands and blows on them.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, we've got to make some booking decisions.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(sighing)</context>
      <utterance>I can't. I can't think of it. This morning, I was so happy, you know. Now I, I don't know what went wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eh, you were miserable this morning! We got bad reviews, terrible ratings, the sponsors are furious...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I was happy, but I just didn't realize I was happy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="48">
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, um, those are quail eggs.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE BRUNCH GUEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holly walks past the painting towards the female brunch guest. A man walks in front of her. Chatter, light laughter, and music are still heard; a party is in progress.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, they're very good.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, my friend April makes those.  Here, try the shrimp puffs. These are delicious.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE BRUNCH GUEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, thank you. That looks great.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I make those.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE BRUNCH GUEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holly laughs lightly as she walks away from the woman. Holding her tray, she passes a large oval loft window and several clusters of brunch guests. They are eating and drinking. No one pays any attention to her.</context>
      <utterance>Mmm. Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of the men, murmuring his thanks, takes a last shrimp puff as Holly passes.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holly finally makes her way into the cluttered loft kitchen. Her tray is empty.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holly, excited, runs over to April, who is busy taking the Stroganoff out of the oven. She wears the same uniform as Holly: black skirt, white shirt, and black bowtie.</context>
      <utterance>The Stroganoff is ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're a big hit.</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>April, holding the Stroganoff, dashes out of the kitchen to serve the party guests. Holly calls after her, offscreen, as David walks past the hurrying April into the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, in this we're a big hit. Yesterday I auditioned for Come Back Little Sheba. That, I wasn't such a big hit.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, are there any more claims?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only a few. A few.  Do you like 'em?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't resist.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? How flattering! Did you try the shrimp puffs?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, you guys are too attractive to be caterers. Something's wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're actresses.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this your first job?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? Is the food that bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Holly carries the quiche outside to the party, April comes back into the kitchen from another doorway. Music, as well as the chatter of mingling guests, is heard in the background.</context>
      <utterance>Oh no. Not at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need more bread and some baked lasa--  uh, lasagne.  Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. You're an actress with a great flair for shrimp puffs.</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks past David to a counter where she begins to fold napkins. David leans back against the sink.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, no, the shrimp puffs are Holly's. I do the, uh, crpes caviar.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the quail is responsible for the quail eggs.</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holly enters the kitchen holding out a plate of clams. She walks over to David.</context>
      <utterance>Well, let's hope so.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here, I stole you a couple of extra clams.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Incidentally, I'm David Tolchin.</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They shake hands.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, uh, April Knox. Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>April walks offscreen to another area of the kitchen. Holly picks up a napkin from the crowded table.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're Holly.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, we're the Stanislavski Catering Company.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now I'm going to tell you the truth. I really came in here because I was bored stiff by the party.</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No...no. No--</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>David checks his wristwatch as Holly walks over to him.</context>
      <utterance>Not at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We saw, um, Pavarotti, eh, uh, in Ernani at the Met, and I cried...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I cry at the opera.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>April chuckles as Holly walks back onscreen; she is busy preparing another tray of hors d'oeuvres.</context>
      <utterance>Me, too. I have a private box at the Met.  I bring my little bottle of wine, I open it, I sit there and I watch and  I cry. It's disgusting.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, what, what do you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm an architect.</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wha--  What kind of things do you build?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you really interested?</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three exchange glances. Holly shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>What time do you get off?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="73">
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow, it's the red one?</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, it's magnificent!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The film moves down from the buildings to reveal the trio sitting in David's Jaguar across the street. David and April sit in the front seat; Holly sits scrunched up in back, her head slightly forward.</context>
      <utterance>It's terrific!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The design's deliberately noncontextural. But I wanted to... keep the atmosphere of the street, you know, and the proportions.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And in the material. That's...that's unpolished red granite.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh!</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, is that what it is?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh--</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I-i-it has an o-organic quality, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's almost...almost, uhhh, entirely wholly interdependent, if you know what I mean. I-I... I can't put it into words. The important thing is-is-is it-it breathes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, April, people pass by vital structures in this city all the time, and they never take the time to appreciate them. I get the feeling you tune in to your environment.</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh--</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>David turns and briefly glances at Holly; he then turns back to April.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, it's really important.</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are your favorite buildings, David?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to see some?</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, let's do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>David starts the car and the movie cuts to an unfolding visual excursion through New York City's landmark buildings, as seen from the trio's point of view in the moving Jaguar. Inspiring classical music plays in the background. The series of shots includes the Dakota, complete with surrounding winter trees, the Graybar building on Lexington Avenue, an incredibly ornate building on Seventh Avenue and Fifty-eighth Street, a red-stone church, an old building with embellished, bulging windows on West Forty-fourth Street, the Art Deco Chrysler Building, a red-brick building, Abigail Adams's old stone house, and the Pomander Walk nestled off Broadway on the Upper West Side. The group can be seen walking down the path between the old-fashioned row houses and shrubbery. A lamppost sits in the foreground. It is now dark. The music continues to play as the film cuts to the faade of a rococo-style building, complete with French doors and ornate windows. The admiring group is heard offscreen.</context>
      <utterance>Great.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, it's just so romantic. I just want to put on a long gown...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and open the French doors and go on the balcony --</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's French, though. It really is.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It feels like you're in France.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The music stops. The screen, which has been exploring the rococo building's faade, now shows the equally elegant building alongside it.</context>
      <utterance>It-it is. It's romantic.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And it's got a handsome partner sitting right beside it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The film moves from the two elegant faade to show an ugly, ultra-modern structure covered with tiny, diamond-shaped motifs.</context>
      <utterance>They fit right in together. And your eye goes along, lulled into complacency, and then...</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's just --</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at this.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's disgusting!</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...a monstrosity! Who would do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's really terrible.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's really sad.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And it ruins everything else.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The film moves from the ugly faade to the building's equally ugly entrance. A large car is parked right in front of the building.</context>
      <utterance>It does.</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well...we have seen a lot of stuff today, though.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The group is now seen walking down the canopied entrance stairs of an apartment house on the other side of the street, where they'd been gazing at both the lovely and ugly faades across the way. David is in the lead; the women follow, Holly slightly behind April.</context>
      <utterance>A lot of works.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe we should start thinking about going home, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, geez, yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk towards the car.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, who gets dropped first?</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh --</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, gee, I don't know. Um...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well...</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I live downtown.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>David leans over the roof of the car, looking at the women, waiting for their decision.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I, we both live downtown.</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It depends on what way you want to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, wait. You know what? I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If...well, if we took the, if we took Fifth, then-then-then we'd get to your house first, yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We could...we could do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at David.</context>
      <utterance>Right. Yeah, but Fifth is so jammed, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, sometimes, some, uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both she and April mumble awkwardly.</context>
      <utterance>I mean, it's jammed. If we went... um...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y-you live in Chelsea, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I-I guess if you live in Chelsea, that's probably first.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then, uh, April...huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They get into the car. Once again Holly's in the backseat. The classical music begins anew. The movie cuts briefly to cut to the traffic and lights of a Manhattan avenue as seen from the moving Jaguar. It then moves to a close-up of Holly, sitting in the backseat, her head near the window. She is staring straight ahead.</context>
      <utterance>Great.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>where David and April sit, the Jaguar's windshield, and the passing lights and traffic of the street. Holly continues her ruminations as April leans over to say something to David.</context>
      <utterance>Naturally I get taken home first. Well, obviously he prefers April. Of course I was so tongue-tied all night. I can't believe I said that about the Guggenheim. My stupid little roller-skating joke. I should never tell jokes. Mom can tell 'em and Hannah, but I kill 'em.  Where did April come up with that stuff about Adolph Loos and terms like "organic form"?  Well, naturally. She went to Brandeis. The movie cuts to Holly's point of view: the front seat</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The film moves back to Holly in the backseat, still lost in thought.</context>
      <utterance>But I don't think she knows what she's talking about. Could you believe the way she was calling him David? "Yes, David. I feel that way, too, David. What a marvelous space, David."  I hate April. She's pushy.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The classical music stops and some uptempo jazz begins. The screen cuts to black and a title appears. "...nobody, not even the rain, has such small hands."</context>
      <utterance>Now they'll dump me and she'll invite him up. I blew it.  And I really like him a lot. Oh, screw it. I'm not gonna get all upset. I've got reading to do tonight. You know, maybe I'll get into bed early. I'll turn to a movie and take an extra Seconal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="68">
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, my goodness!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Elliot!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm-I'm looking for a bookstore.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, what, in this section of town?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Yeah, I-I'm kill--</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're out looking here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, yes, I'm killing time. I have a client near here and I...I'm quite early.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ohhhh!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Well, I live--</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes! You live near here, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you headed?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I was just going to my AA meeting.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They begin to walk down the street.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, my goodness. Well, why do you still go to those? You never tough alcohol.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, listen, you didn't know me before Frederick. I'd...I'd start with a beer at about ten in the morning, and...go on.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. You must have been, uh, very unhappy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, unhappy and fat.  And I still find the meetings very comforting, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll never understand it. You're so bright and charming and beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, God.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think to myself  what problems could she possibly have?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't let me get started on my childhood.  Oh, you know what? There is a bookstore.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You'd really love it.</context>
      <utterance>A couple of blocks from here. If you don't know about it, you should.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you would.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, i-if-if you have some free time...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(chuckling)</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They begin to walk again as the movie cuts to the interior of the Pageant Book &amp; Print Shop, an old, serious bookstore. A nude print hangs at the end of one of the library shelf- like bookcases, which are packed, row after row, with books. An unseen Elliot and Lee carry on a conversation as the camera moves down an aisle, past the rows of books. A piano playing "Bewitched" is heard. Pictures hang on the aisle ends of the shelves.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't this great?  They have everything here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, it's-it's wonderful.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What book did you want to buy?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Book?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, book? Oh, no, I...  I'm killing time. I...I-I just, uh, w-want to browse, uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks down a center aisle, the camera still in its parallel aisle, following her.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you sure picked the right place. I mean, you can stay here all afternoon, not buy anything and just read.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unless, of course, if-if you had some time, I mean, we could get some coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee stops at the row where Elliot has been browsing. She is hidden by a shelf; only Elliot is seen as he talks to the offscreen Lee.</context>
      <utterance>No, I don't have time.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No problem. Y-you're busy. I-I-I...</context>
      <utterance>No, no. I-I-I understand completely.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You seem tense. Is everything all right? You feel okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! No...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elliot starts walking down the center aisle, in the same direction Lee had walked up. He continues to talk to her as she remains offscreen in a nearby row.</context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(chuckling)</context>
      <utterance>Everything's okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. How are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm...all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elliot stops walking to browse through some books. "Bewitched" still plays.</context>
      <utterance>How-how's Frederick?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine. Oh, we went to the Caravaggio exhibition at the Met. It's such a treat to go through a museum with Frederick. I mean...you learn so much. Do you like Caravaggio?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elliot turns and walks back down the center aisle to a row of books he'd already passed.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes. Who doesn't?  Look!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>e.e. cummings. I'd like to get you this.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's too much.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no, I can't let you get me that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, oh, yes. I-I-I-'d like to, uh, uh, very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee walks over to Elliot in the center aisle. She looks at the book.</context>
      <utterance>I-I read a poem of you and thought of his last week.  A poem of  his and thought of you last--  You'll be fine, though.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, uh, this is great. I mean, I love e.e. cummings, but I can't let you get this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I'd...I-I-I'd love, I'd love to get you this.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, thanks a lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for showing me the bookstore. Perhaps you could, uh, take me to an AA meeting sometime. Uh...uh, I'd love to see what goes on.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, yeah, yeah. You'd love it. It's really entertaining. You'd have a good time.  I know you would.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A taxi pulls over to the curb; they walk over to it.</context>
      <utterance>And, uh, d-don't forget the poem on page a hundred and twelve. It reminded me of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elliot opens the rear door for Lee. She laughs as she gets in.</context>
      <utterance>Really? Well...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Page a hundred and twelve.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He watches the taxi pull away.</context>
      <utterance>Bye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"your slightest look easily will unclose me though I have closed myself as fingers, you open always petal by petal myself... As Lee continues to read aloud, the movie cuts to Elliot's darkened den, lit by a light in the hallway. Elliot enters, wearing a robe, crossing the room in the dark.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Elliot turns on a light. The camera stays on his face as he looks off into the distance, mouthing indistinctly the line of poetry Lee next reads.</context>
      <utterance>"...as Spring opens [touching skillfully, mysteriously] her first rose [i do not know what it is about you that closes and opens; only something in me understands the voice of your eyes is deeper than all roses]...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The film leaves Elliot's face and cuts back to the loft, where Lee, having finished the poem, sits up in the bed, staring pensively, lost in her thoughts.</context>
      <utterance>"nobody, not even the rain, has such small hands."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DR. GREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The doctor turns his chair around to face a tense Mickey sitting on the other side of his desk.</context>
      <utterance>I wasn't too happy with the results of your ENG or your BSER either.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. GREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mickey stares at the X-ray, horrified.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, which is why I sent you to Tomography, which was all that stuff you saw rolling around.  You see this little gray area here?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. GREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That gray area's what I had hoped that we wouldn't run into. I'd like you to come in Monday morning for, uh, a CAT scan.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A brain scan?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. GREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Sachs, let's take one step at a time. We won't make any decisions until we have all the information in front of us, all right?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Mickey brushes against a heavyset man who gives him a nasty look. Mickey is so dazed, he doesn't even notice.</context>
      <utterance>Okay...take it easy. He didn't say you had anything. He just doesn't like the spot on your X-ray, that's all. It doesn't mean you have anything. Don't jump to conclusions.  Nothing's gonna happen to you. You're in the middle of New York City. This is your town. You're surrounded by people and traffic and restaurants.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, God, how can you, how can you just one day...vanish? Keep calm. You're gonna be okay. Don't panic.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Mickey, still ruminating, stands up. Fixing his pants, he walks out of his bedroom loft into a dark upper hallway.</context>
      <utterance>I'm dying! I'm dying! I know it! There's a spot on my lungs!  All right now, take it easy, will you? It's not on your lungs. It's on your ear. No, it's the same thing, isn't it?  Oh, jeez, I can't sleep! Oh, God, there's a tumor in my head the size of a basketball!  N-now I keep thinking I can feel it every time I blink! Oh, Jesus! He-he-he wants me to do a brain scan to confirm what he already suspects.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>He walks down a spiral staircase into the dark living room.</context>
      <utterance>Look...I'll make a deal with God. Let it just be my ear, okay? I'll go deaf. I'll go deaf and blind in one eye maybe. But I don't want a brain operation! Once they go into my skull, I'll-I'll wind up like the guy with the, with the wool cap who delivers for the florist!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The film cuts to a flashback of Mickey's past. Dr. Smith, sitting behind his desk, faces the camera. Rows of periodicals line the wall behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, relax, will ya? Your whole life you run to doctors. The news is always fine.  That's not true. What about years ago?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera moves to Dr. Smith's point of view: Hannah and Mickey, sitting on the opposite side of the desk. They look stunned.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry to say, Mr. Sachs, that you cannot have children.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gee.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there no chance?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera moves back to the stunned Mickey and Hannah, following Dr. Smith with their eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Well, naturally, this doesn't mean that you can't have a normal sex life.  But Mr. Sachs's tests indicate that he is infertile. Small sperm volume and infertile.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Push-ups or hormones?</context>
      <utterance>Isn't there anything I can do?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid not.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I gotta get a second opinion.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the second opinion.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I realize this is a blow. My experience is that many very fine marriages become unstable and are destroyed by an inability to deal with this sort of problem. I hope you won't make too much of it. One can adopt children, and there are various artificial methods of fertilization.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="52">
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so humiliated. I don't know what to say. I mean--</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could you have ruined yourself somehow?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How could I ruin myself? What do you mean, ruin myself?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Excessive masturbation?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hannah sobs, clutching her tissue to her face.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, you gonna start knocking my hobbies? Jesus!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He said you could adopt one--</context>
      <utterance>Maybe, maybe we can adopt a child.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what about artificial insemination?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, where I-I-I would get implanted from a-a donor.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deep in conversation, they cross a tree-lined street. They pass a yellow wood-frame house bordered by a wrought-iron fence.</context>
      <utterance>What, by a st-stranger?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, they have these banks, you know, where they keep them frozen.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Is that your idea?</context>
      <utterance>Fro--? You want a-a defrosted kid?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to experience childbirth.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With a, with a stranger? With a--</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk offscreen and the film cuts to Hannah and Mickey's living room. The room is brightly lit; it's cluttered with pillows and plants. Norman and Carol, his wife, sit on the couch drinking coffee.</context>
      <utterance>Just think about it. That's all I ask.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, that was a wonderful show. I think that's the best show you two ever wrote.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mickey walks from the kitchen into the living room, holding a half-eaten chocolate cake on a serving plate. The sun pours through the windows he passes. Hannah is briefly seen in the background, preparing more coffee in the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>No, the funniest show that Mickey and I ever did was the one we won the Emmy for.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mickey puts the cake down on the coffee table, which is already crowded with assorted plants, plates, and a bamboo tray holding utensils and napkins.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah...I-I think as, I think as far as laughs, I mean just plain laughs, you know, that was probably the best thing that we ever did.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mm-hm.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mickey sighs and flops down on an adjoining couch. He rubs his forehead.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it was funny, it was very funny. But the show was about the two Frenchmen, now that was funny and it was warm.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got that idea on that trip to Paris.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmm?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norman chuckles.</context>
      <utterance>Do you remember that summer in France? Hannah, you had jet lag for six straight weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but it was, you know, I guess we had fun when we were there and, you know, it's just, I--</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hannah walks over to the group, holding a pot of coffee. She awkwardly steps past Mickey to pour coffee for Norman and Carol.</context>
      <utterance>Mm-hm.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry.  Coffee? Listen, you guys, we were-- You want some more?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmm.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We-we...we had something we-we really wanted to discuss with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hannah refills Carol's cup. She puts the pot down on the coffee table and sits down next to Mickey.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to pace. Hannah, her hands clasped near her face, glances briefly at Carol.</context>
      <utterance>Jeez, this is, this is, this is very delicate and-and I only bring this up amongst friends, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean...  this is, uh... this should not go any further than this room.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hannah sighs. Mickey pauses for a moment, collecting his thoughts.</context>
      <utterance>I'm all ears.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hannah and I...can't have any children. Now I-I-I don't want to get into whose fault it--  It's my fault that we can't and- and-and the details are too embarrassing to--</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mickey stops his pacing and looks at the group.</context>
      <utterance>W-w-we-we've decided after a lot of discussion that we-we'd try with artificial insemination.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'm not so sure that I, that I like that idea myself, anyway-- He starts to pace behind the couch anew.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um, I-I didn't really want to, you know, go to a sperm bank or something, have some anonymous donor.  I-I just, you know, I-I-I wouldn't want that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norman and Carol remain silent.</context>
      <utterance>Right. We felt that if we were gonna do it, that we would like somebody who we knew and who we liked and who was warm and bright and...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mickey stops pacing and leans on the couch behind Norman.</context>
      <utterance>And you can say no... you know. Feel free to say no. W-we realize it has all kinds of implications.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mickey, rubbing his hands on his knees, leans back against the wall. Norman and Carol turn to each other, reacting.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but the-the point that, uh, that we're making here is that we need some sperm.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gee.  Well... My first reaction after the initial shock is, uh, flattered that you would ask me.  Carol glances at Norman.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, I would be the father.  You would just have to masturbate into a little cup.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can handle that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She chuckles nervously.</context>
      <utterance>Obviously we wou-wouldn't have intercourse.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm a little uneasy about this.</context>
      <utterance>Gosh, listen.  I've gotta tell you the truth here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carol, I know it's a lot to ask.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well...I feel for you. I do. I...I'm gonna cry. You want my husband to have a child with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ye-- D-d-d-don't answer now. Just, you know, take it home and think about it for a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>clothing to the poor.</context>
      <utterance>I gave blood before and, uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Norman, listen, I really want to talk about this at home.  I think it's a matter for your analyst...and mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a sip of coffee.</context>
      <utterance>And maybe my lawyer.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you had my ex-partner's baby. Twins. Maybe that did cause some trouble, but  I think we were drifting apart anyhow. Now instead of man and wife we're just good friends. Boy, love is really unpredictable.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="108">
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee closes the door behind the men and walks over to Dusty.</context>
      <utterance>Lee, Frederick...say hello to Dusty Frye.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Dusty.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee chuckles as she looks at him; he is wearing sunglasses, a red-imprinted T-shirt, and a baggy coat. She turns and walks with Frederick, Elliot, and Dusty farther into the loft, her hands clasped behind her back.</context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dusty's just bought a huge house in Southampton and he's in the process of decorating it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(chuckling)</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. It's kind of a weird place, actually. A lotta wall space.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk into the living room area of the loft, where Frederick, his hands in his pockets, neatly attired in vest sweater and white shirt, stands, waiting.</context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How ya doin', man?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told him about your work, and he's very excited.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frederick covers his face to hide his disgust.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I got an Andy Warhol. And I got a Frank Stella, too. Oh, it's very beautiful.  Big, weird...you know.  If you stare at that Stella too long, the colors just seem to float. It's kinda weird.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you excited about becoming a collector?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got a lot more to learn, though. I really wasn't into art when I was a kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you appreciate drawings?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Dusty talks, the camera follows Elliot, who walks past the others to examine the drawings more closely. Two framed nude drawings of Lee are propped up on an easel. Elliot glances admiringly at the drawings, then surreptitiously at Lee, admiring her body as she converses with an offscreen Dusty and Frederick.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.  Oh! Hey! Wow!  She's beautiful. But, uh, really, I-I-I-I need something... I'm looking for something big.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big. Frederick, show him the oils.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera leaves Elliot to follow the enthusiastic Lee as she takes Dusty by the arm and starts leading him to the door. Frederick follows at a distance.</context>
      <utterance>They're in the basement.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frederick's done this whole new series that I'm sure you would really love.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, are...are they big?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Some of them...yeah, some of them are very big.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(chuckling)</context>
      <utterance>'Cause I got a lot of wall space there.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't sell my work by the yard!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera now moves back to Elliot, still staring at the nude drawings, as the sounds of Frederick's and Dusty's footsteps are heard leaving the loft. He turns and hesitantly smiles to an offscreen Lee.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Frederick!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's everything?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you know...I talked to Hannah this morning on the phone, and she said that you two might be going to the country for the weekend.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, she loves to go out in the woods.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs. Lee, uneasy, looks down.</context>
      <utterance>But I go nuts. It's a conflict.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to get my teeth cleaned this week.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's an awkward moment of silence.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, that's nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I figured I'd get, uh, Frederick and Dusty together.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah, that's really nice of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. This kid, he's earned a trillion dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got like six gold records.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera follows Lee as she walks quickly to the stereo unit, pulling a record off the shelf.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, speaking of records...I bought that Mozart Trio you recommended...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and the man in the record shop showed me another one that I think you'd love. It's a... another Bach, second movement. She pulls the record out of its jacket and puts it on the turntable.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you-you have that one?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bach's Concerto for Harpsichord fills the room.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I would love to hear it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, and Holly met a wonderful man who loves opera. An architect.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't that beautiful?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee, smiling, continues to listen to the music, her head down; Elliot stares at her.</context>
      <utterance>I know this. Bach. F Minor Concerto. It's one of my favorites.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>cummings?</context>
      <utterance>Uh...did you ever get around to e.e.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elliot nods.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, he's just adorable.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They have a very large gay clientele, you know, where I get my teeth cleaned, and...all the hygienists now wear gloves because they're afraid of AIDS.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is another moment of silence. Elliot stares at Lee, who continues to look down, her arms around her chest. The harpsichord plays on.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, right.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you ever get around to the poem on page a hundred and twelve?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee looks down again; the music plays softly and Elliot continues to stare at her, thinking.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, it made me cry  it was so beautiful...so romantic.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>As Elliot's thoughts are heard over the scene, Lee glances around the loft, then begins to walk away. The camera follows her as she goes past the nude drawings, which become the focus of attention as Lee walks offscreen.</context>
      <utterance>I want so badly to kiss her. Not here, you idiot. You've got to get her alone someplace.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Lee walks back onscreen, to the bookshelf behind the drawings. She takes the e.e. cummings book from the shelf and flips through it as she walks back to Elliot, who is still leaning by the stereo, still ruminating.</context>
      <utterance>But I've got to proceed cautiously. This is a very delicate situation. Okay, uh...ask her if you can see her for lunch or a drink tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And be ready to make light of the offer if she's unresponsive. This has to be done very skillfully, very diplomatically.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elliot leaps up, grabs Lee, and kisses her passionately. Lee, surprised, pushes him away.</context>
      <utterance>Did you ever read this one--?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elliot! Don't!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses Lee again. He clumsily turns around; she humps against the stereo unit. As Lee pulls away, she smashes into the turntable. The needle scratches loudly. Lee, shocked, is gasping. The record, pushed to a different part of the concerto, now plays a more complicated, faster fugue.</context>
      <utterance>Lee! Lee! Lee, I'm in love with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee stares at Elliot in shock.</context>
      <utterance>I...I'm-I'm-I'm-I'm sorry. I have to talk to you for... There's so much that I want to tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elliot!</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please forget it! I don't have any interest in selling anything!</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ask you if you have something with a little puce in it, you gotta fly off the handle!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not interested in what your interior decorator would think, okay?!</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's what I have her for, okay?</context>
      <utterance>Well, I can't commit to anything without consulting her first.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is degrading! You don't buy paintings to blend in with the sofa!</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not a sofa, it's an ottoman!  God, forget it! Let's just get outta here, Elliot.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The film moves outside the loft building. Dusty and Elliot emerge and walk to Dusty's waiting limousine. Elliot is rubbing his forehead, anguished.</context>
      <utterance>We'll go.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a weirdo that guy is! Paranoid.  What's the matter with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look I-I-I'll be okay. I'll be okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not that big a deal. We just didn't hit it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, look, you-you-you go on ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you okay? You look-- You're sweatin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dusty settles down in the backseat and closes the door. Elliot leans down to the chauffeur's window, signaling for him to start driving.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Yeah, I just-just need so- some-some fresh air. It's probably something I ate. I'll-I'll walk. You go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The limousine drives off. Elliot runs to a phone booth across the street. He picks up the phone and dials. The film cuts to Frederick in his loft, standing near the phone. It rings. Frederick picks it up.</context>
      <utterance>You go. Go on. Go.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When no one answers, Frederick, reacting, hangs up, and the film moves back outside to the phone booth, where Elliot, the phone receiver to his ear, listens for a moment, then hangs up. He walks out of the booth, reacting, then walks down the sidewalk, where he bumps into a frantic Lee, just turning the corner.</context>
      <utterance>Hello? Hello? Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elliot mumbles, relieved and confused.</context>
      <utterance>Oh! There you are!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was looking for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I, I must apologize. I-I'm, I-I'm sorry. I'm so mixed up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wh--, uh, I know, I know but, I am in love with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, don't say those words!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I-I, I'm sorry. I know it's terrible.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sighs.</context>
      <utterance>Why, you know the situation.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know! I-I-I-I, I realize.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you expect me to say?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hannah and I are in the last stages.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wh-- She's never said anything, and we're very close. She'd tell me such a thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wh--, it-it-it-it, it's so sad. She's crazy about me, but somewhere on the, along the line, I've fallen out of love with her.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not because of me, I hope.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, no, no.  Well, yes! I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I can't be the cause of anything between you and Hannah. I jus--</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, no, no, no. It, uh, it-it-it- it was i-inevitable that Hannah and I part, anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tch, w-well, for a million reasons.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But not over me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tch, no! We were, we were both going in different directions.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Poor Hannah.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But-but, but how about you? Do you, do you share any of my feelings? Or is this just an unpleasant embarrassment to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't say anything!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>W-well, please be candid. I, I-I don't want you to feel bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Yes! But I...I have certain feelings for you, but don't make me say anything more, all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>O-o-o-okay, Lee. Okay, okay. You, you, y-you've said enough. It's my responsibility now. I will work things out.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, don't do anything on my behalf.  I live with Frederick, and Hannah and I are close.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, but you, you do care about me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sighs.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Elliot, please! I can't be a party to this! I'm suddenly wracked with guilt just standing her talking to you on the street!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your guilt is because you feel the same.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks off. Elliot stares after her, grinning.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, please, I have to go. I have to get my teeth cleaned.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs.</context>
      <utterance>I have my answer. I have my answer! I'm walking on air!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="34">
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. How's she doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hannah takes off her shoulder bag and her coat as her aggravated father walks past her towards the kitchen. He passes a wall with an ornate mirror and some framed photographs.</context>
      <utterance>I am glad to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Through a doorway, Norma can be seen sitting on a chair in the kitchen. She wears a robe over a slip and stockings; she's drinking. Evan stands in the doorway looking at her; he doesn't go in.</context>
      <utterance>She's in the kitchen there. It's the same thing. Same thing. She promises, promises.  But it's all lies.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't make it worse, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hannah hurriedly passes her father and enters the kitchen; her mother takes a sip of her drink.</context>
      <utterance>Always.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Mom. How you doing? Here, let me get you some coffee. That's enough of that.  What triggered it?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norma reacts, turning to her daughter. Hannah, however, has her back turned. She is busy taking charge in the kitchen as Evan speaks. She takes some pills out of a cupboard and hands them to her mother with a glass of water.</context>
      <utterance>We were making a commercial down at the mayor's office, and there was this young, good-looking salesman...</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and your mother was throwing herself at him in a disgusting way, and when she found she was too old to seduce him, that he was just embarrassed by her--</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera moves to Evan, who continues to tell his story, ignoring his wife's outburst, as he walks away from the kitchen doorway into the den.</context>
      <utterance>Liar! Liar!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan walks over to the piano, where several framed family photographs sit in a line on its top. He picks one up as Norma speaks offscreen in the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Then at lunch she got drunker and drunker  and finally she became Joan Collins!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan is back in the doorway, listening to Norma, getting more and more angry. As he makes a retort, he starts to walk back to the den and his piano.</context>
      <utterance>...from this non-person, this, th- th-this haircut that passes for a man.  He could never support us. It's a good thing we had a talented daughter!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can only hope that she was mine. With you as her mother  her father could be anybody in Actors' Equity!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(taking a sip of water)</context>
      <utterance>She's talented...so it's not likely she's yours!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hannah goes back to Norma; she takes the glass of water away.</context>
      <utterance>Dad, could you just please stay in the other room and let me take care of her?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hannah, choosing to ignore Evan's remark, hands her mother a cup of coffee; she puts her mother's hands on the cup.</context>
      <utterance>You never know when she's going to fall off the wagon and humiliate everybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here, Mom. Drink this.  You know, you're awful. You probably were flirting.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! I like to joke around and have fun, and he gets angry because I get the attention. He's gotten sourer as he's gotten older, and I've tried to stay young...at heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You promised to stay on the wagon.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The sacrifices I've made because of that man.  He's ruined me with his ego, his philandering, his--  his-his-his-his mediocrity!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, stop being so dramatic.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's the one that's made every ingenue in stock!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Th-th-they, they wanted me for a screen test.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I know, Mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I, I knew that he'd get up there and he'd flounder around with his expensive haircuts and hairdos and clothes. He's all show!  Now how can you act when there's nothing inside to come out?! Norma sips her coffee, softly sobbing. Hannah, reacting, walks away from the counter and, capping the bottle of pills, puts them back in the cupboard. Evan plays the piano offscreen. The camera moves in on Hannah's face as she reflects, her voice heard over the screen.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The camera leaves Hannah's face as she continues to reflect; it moves to the den, to the row of family photos on the piano: one of a present-day Evan and Norma, others where both Norma and Evan are young, beautiful, hopeful. The music plays on.</context>
      <utterance>She was so beautiful at one time, and he was so dashing. Both of them just full of promise and hopes that never materialized.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The film cuts back to the kitchen. Norma stands up; Hannah takes her coffee cup and sets it on the counter.</context>
      <utterance>And the fights and the constant infidelities to prove themselves...and blaming each other. It's s-sad. They loved the idea of having us kids, but raising us didn't interest them much. But it's impossible to hold it against them. They didn't know anything else.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts her arm around Hannah's shoulder. Mother and daughter walk out of the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>You know, of all of us in the family, you were the one blessed with the true gift.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norma chuckles.</context>
      <utterance>Ohhh, my true gift is luck, Mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just had a lot of luck...from my first show, you know? I've always thought Lee was the one destined for great things.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, she's lovely, but she doesn't have your spark.  She knows it. She worships you. She wouldn't dare get up there on the stage.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stop at the entrance to the den. Evan can be seen playing the piano as they continue their conversation.</context>
      <utterance>Now, Holly's not shy.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holly takes after me.</context>
      <utterance>No, Holly's game for anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>True.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Brooks turns to an offscreen Mickey.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Sachs,  I'm afraid the news is not good.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The film quickly cuts to a close-up of Mickey's face, reacting in total despair. He closes his eyes; he covers his face with his hand.</context>
      <utterance>If I can show you exactly where the tumor is, and why we feel that surgery would be of no use.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's over. I'm face-to-face with eternity.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...grown quite large without being detected...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>As Mickey finishes his speech, the "real" Dr. Brooks is seen walking into the office. The previous scene had been a figment of Mickey's imagination, a nightmare fantasy only. Holding Mickey's X-rays, the "real" Dr. Brooks walks past the same row of books to the light panel.</context>
      <utterance>Not later, but now. I'm so frightened I can't move, speak, or breathe.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you're just fine. There's absolutely nothing here at all. And your tests are all fine.  I must admit, I was concerned, given your symptoms.  What caused this hearing loss in one ear, I guess we'll never really know for sure. But whatever it was, it's certainly not anything serious at all.  I'm very relieved.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mickey, standing behind his desk, his back to the camera, his coat still on, looks out at the Manhattan skyline.</context>
      <utterance>What do you mean you're quitting? Why? The news is good! You don't have canc--the thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you realize what a thread we're all hanging by?</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mickey, you're off the hook. You should be celebrating.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you understand how meaningless everything is? Everything! I'm talking about nnnn--our lives, the show...the whole world, it's meaningless.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...but you're not dying!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gail gets up from her chair. She walks past Mickey to a nearby cabinet. She opens a drawer, rummaging around for something. The camera follows her, leaving Mickey briefly.</context>
      <utterance>No, I'm not dying now, but, but  you know, when I ran out of the hospital, I, I was so thrilled because they told me I was going to be all right. And I'm running down the street, and suddenly I stop, 'cause it hit me, all right, so, you know, I'm not going to go today. I'm okay. I'm not going to go tomorrow.  But eventually, I'm going to be in that position.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're just realizing this now?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't realize it now, I know it all the time, but, but I managed to stick it in the back of my mind... As Mickey continues to talk offscreen, Gail closes the cabinet drawer and walks to a file cabinet behind Mickey's desk.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gail opens the file cabinet and takes out a pack of gum. She slams it closed, distracted.</context>
      <utterance>...because it-it's a very horrible thing to... think about!</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I tell you something? Can I tell you a secret?</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A week ago, I bought a rifle.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I went into a store, I bought a rifle. I was gonna... You know, if they told me that I had a tumor, I was going to kill myself. The only thing that mighta stopped me, might've, is my parents would be devastated. I would, I woulda had to shoot them, also, first. And then, I have an aunt and uncle, I would have... You know, it would have been a bloodbath.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tch, well, you know, eventually it, it is going to happen to all of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gail sighs. She pops a piece of gum into her mouth as Mickey continues to speak.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, but doesn't that ruin everything for you? That makes everything...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everything!</context>
      <utterance>...you know it, it just takes the pleasure out of everything.  I mean, you're gonna die, I'm gonna die, the audience is gonna die, the network's gonna-- The sponsor.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, I know, and your hamster.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mickey sighs.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, kid, I think you snapped your cap.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you need a few weeks in Bermuda, or something. Or go to a whorehouse! No?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't stay on this show. I gotta get some answers. Otherwise  I'm telling you, I'm going to do something drastic.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you weren't coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I almost didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lee... uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't sleep all night.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk towards the camera, further into the room. Elliot puts his arm around Lee.</context>
      <utterance>No, no-no-no, I'm sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The music stops. The camera follows Lee as she walks towards the curtained windows, past a fireplace, a mirror, some innocuous pictures, a delicate table holding a lamp, the foot of the bed.</context>
      <utterance>What are we doing, meeting in a hotel room? It's terrible, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I-I couldn't think where to invite you without taking risks.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She parts a corner of the curtains, looking out the window, turning when Elliot speaks.</context>
      <utterance>I promised myself I wouldn't let this happen till you were living alone. I was so torn when you called.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks over to Lee by the curtained windows.</context>
      <utterance>I've wanted to call you everyday since I first told you how I felt.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes Lee into his arms.</context>
      <utterance>I resisted so many times.  Don't think badly of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is not an easy situation.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They kiss, their figures almost silhouetted in the warm glow of the room. Elliot takes Lee's coat off without breaking the kiss. They embrace. They kiss each other lightly, then stronger, more passionately, their embrace much tighter. And it's later that night. The harpsichord music begins to play again as the camera moves over the bed covers to reveal Lee, lying contentedly under the sheets, her hair fanned out on the pillows, one arm near her head.</context>
      <utterance>I know it isn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was just perfect. You've ruined me for anyone else.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want anyone else ever to have you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was so worried I wouldn't compare with Hannah.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He enters the screen, sitting down on the edge of the bed next to Lee. He holds a cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, my God.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really do have those thoughts, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elliot chuckles; they hold hands.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, all the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know she must be a really passionate person.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, she's, she's very warm, but, but it-it's me that wants to be giving to you. I-I-I want to do things for you. Hannah doesn't need me as much.  I'm being presumptuous. Not that you need me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elliot leans down to Lee; they begin to kiss passionately.</context>
      <utterance>I want you to take care of me... And I love when you do things to me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="51">
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee walks through the loft's living room area, unbelting her coat, towards the bathroom. She passes Frederick, who sits at a table in the kitchen area, drinking a cup of coffee and reading the paper. A plate with a half-eaten sandwich sits in front of him. The music stops.</context>
      <utterance>You're late.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lucy and I kept talking, and I didn't realize how late it had gotten.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he talks, Lee is seen turning on the bathroom light. She takes off her coat, hanging it on a hook, then begins to dry her hair with a towel.</context>
      <utterance>You missed a very dull TV show about Auschwitz. More gruesome film clips...and more puzzled intellectuals declaring their mystification over the systematic murder of millions.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frederick takes a bite of his sandwich and another sip of coffee as Lee walks out of the bathroom, tossing the towel down on the counter.</context>
      <utterance>The reason why they could never answer the question "How could it possibly happen?" is that it's the wrong question. Given what people are, the question is  "Why doesn't it happen more often?" Of course it does, in subtler forms.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes a kettle and fills it with water.</context>
      <utterance>I have a little headache from this weather.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a bite of his sandwich and a sip of coffee. Lee sets her glass on the kitchen counter and walks towards the bedroom area.</context>
      <utterance>You see the whole culture...Nazis, deodorant salesman, wrestlers...beauty contests, the talk show... Can you imagine the level of a mind that watches wrestling?  Hmm? But the worst are the fundamentalist preachers...third- rate con men, telling the poor suckers that watch them that they speak for Jesus...and to please send in money.  Money, money, money! If Jesus came back, and saw what's going on in his name, he'd never stop throwing up.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts to take off her wet clothes by the bed. Frederick takes off his glasses. He turns and looks at Lee in surprise.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, God, Frederick, could you please lighten up?! I'm really not in the mood to hear a review of contemporary society again.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, you've been very nervous lately.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't take this anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just trying to complete an education I started on you five years ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not your pupil.  I was, but I'm not.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls Lee down next to him on the bed.</context>
      <utterance>When you leave the nest, I just want you to be ready to face the real world.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sighs.</context>
      <utterance>Frederick, we're going to have to make some changes.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you know what. I'm suffocating!</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh! Are we going to have this conversation again?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, we're going to have this conversation again. I...I have to leave. I have to move out.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I have to!</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you going to use for money?!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I thought, maybe I'd move in with my parents for a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tch, oh. I always told you you would leave me.  But...does it have to be now?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, maybe it'll only be temporary, but I ha--I have to try.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh...Lee, you are my whole world.  Good God! Have you been kissed tonight?!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes, you have!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've been with someone!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee runs into the kitchen, her hands tight around her chest.</context>
      <utterance>Stop accusing me!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frederick enters the kitchen area and leans against the counter.</context>
      <utterance>Leave me alone!</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Christ! What's wrong with you?!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, couldn't you say something? You have to slither around behind my back!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm saying it now!</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you met somebody else?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frederick cringes, reacting. He puts his hand to his forehead; he sighs.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you, God, you knew that was going to happen sooner or later. I can't live like this!</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the difference?! It's just somebody I met!</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But who? Where did you meet him?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't make a difference! I have to move out!</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee turns and faces Frederick in the bathroom doorway.</context>
      <utterance>You are, you are my only connection to the world!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, God, that's too much responsibility for me. It's not fair! I want a less complicated life, Frederick. I want a husband, maybe even a child before it's too late.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus...Jesus!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, God, I don't even know what I want.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frederick furiously shakes Lee away. He pounds his fist against a cupboard. Lee, gasping, moves away.</context>
      <utterance>Tch, oh, what do you get out of me, anyway? I mean...  it's not sexual anymore. It's certainly not intellectual. I mean, you're so superior to me in every way that--</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts his hand on his forehead, then turns to the offscreen Lee.</context>
      <utterance>Please, don't patronize me!</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks over to Lee in another area of the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>God! I should have married you years ago when you wanted to! I should have agreed.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, God, don't you know it never would have worked? Frederick turns away from Lee. He begins to pace near the counter.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDERICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He loudly pounds his fist on the counter in despair and frustration, then covers his eyes with his hands in sorrow.</context>
      <utterance>I told you, one day you would leave me...  for a younger man. I--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Elliot frantically stands up and leaves the room.</context>
      <utterance>What passion today with Lee. She's a volcano. It was a totally fulfilling experience... Just as I dreamed it would be.  That's what it was. It was like living out a dream...a great dream.  Now I feel very good and cozy being here next to Hannah. There's something very lovely and real about Hannah.  She gives me a very deep feeling of being part of something. She's a wonderful woman...and I betrayed her. She came into my empty life and changed it...and I paid her back by banging her sister in a hotel room. God, I'm despicable. What a cruel and shallow thing to do.  I have to call her now and tell her what we did was crazy.  It can't ever happen again. I'm not that kind of man...and I value Hannah too much. I love my wife. Now I've betrayed her. Oh, God!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where're you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've, uh...gotta find, gotta get a phone number in my desk. I forgot to phone Mel Kaufman.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's so late.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elliot walks quickly into the darkened hallway.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I know. I-I can't believe I forgot.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elliot switches on the light. He paces back and forth in front of the piano and an accompanying music stand. The top of the piano is filled with family photos; the lamp he turned on illuminates some framed pictures on the wall and the piece of sheet music open on the piano.</context>
      <utterance>What if he answers?  I'll hang up.  I'll tell her we can't communicate until I terminate my marriage.  It's immoral.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elliot stops pacing and checks his wristwatch.</context>
      <utterance>Then, time will pass. I won't call, and she'll get the idea. I gotta stop this before I get in too deep. I'd rather hurt Lee a little, than destroy Hannah.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The phone rings. Elliot jumps.</context>
      <utterance>It's one-thirty. She...she can't have a conversation with me...with him around. I'm getting hysterical.  I'll call her first thing in the morning. I'll call her at six.  Frederick goes jogging at six, yeah, she'll be alone. And I'll, I'll call her and nip it in the bud.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The movie cuts to Lee, standing in the dark in Frederick's loft. She talks softly into the telephone.</context>
      <utterance>I've got it! I've got it! I've got it!  Hello?  Mel!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee hangs up the phone and the movie cuts back to Elliot, standing in his living room. Stunned, he slowly lowers the phone receiver.</context>
      <utterance>I would have hung up if you hadn't answered and I promise I won't ever do this again, but I just had to tell you, I feel very close to you tonight. Very, very close.  Good night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="30">
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The movie next cuts to a sunny day in Central Park. A male jogger, seen through some tree branches, runs by. The camera moves past him, revealing a pondering Mickey walking by the reservoir. He continues to talk over the screen.</context>
      <utterance>Millions of books written on every conceivable subject by all these great minds, and, and in the end, none of 'em knows anything more about the big questions of life than I do. Ss--I read Socrates. You know, n-n-n--, this guy used to kn-knock off little Greek boys. What the hell's he got to teach me? And, and Nietzsche with his, with his Theory of Eternal Recurrence. He said that the life we live, we're gonna live over and over again the exact same way for eternity. Great. That means I, uh, I'll have to sit through the Ice Capades again. Tch. It's not worth it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Several joggers pass Mickey; he continues to ruminate.</context>
      <utterance>And, and Freud, another great pessimist. Jeez, I was in analysis for years. Nothing happened. My poor analyst got so frustrated. The guy finally put in a salad bar.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Mickey goes over to the chain-link fence encircling the reservoir. He stops walking and looks out over the water.</context>
      <utterance>Oh! Look at all these people jogging...trying to stave off the inevitable decay of the body. Boy  it's so sad what people go through with their-their stationary bike and their exercise and their...  ...Oh! Look at this one! Poor thing. My God, she has to tote all that fat around. Maybe the poets are right. Maybe love is the only answer.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Mickey continues to look through the fence at the water and the distant skyline. A jogger crosses in front of him. It's very quiet; the soft jazz continues.</context>
      <utterance>Shh--Of course, I was in love with Hannah. That didn't work out too well.  I even took her sister out. Remember that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The film cuts abruptly to Mickey's flashback of his date with Holly, beginning with a rock club performance. The soft jazz becomes loud, pulsating rock. Three punkers--a girl with pink hair, a girl with a spiked mohawk, and a guy with Stevie Wonder braids and sunglasses--watch and bop their heads to the sounds of the offscreen rock band, The 39 Steps. The camera moves to the stage, revealing a sleazy-looking rock band in the midst of their number.</context>
      <utterance>Remember years ago when Hannah and I got divorced and she fixed me up with her sister Holly?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE 39 STEPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"I'm gonna dance at clubs Gonna do just what I'm told Because I'm bleedin' now And I'm bleedin' now I wanna slip, slip, slip, slip, slip Into the crowd I wanna slip, slip, slip, slip, slip Into the crowd..." The camera moves back to Holly and the even more stricken- looking Mickey. They are crowded in with people. In the background, a waitress holds up a tray. A man drinks from a glass mug; people chatter indistinctly over the loud band. The club is noisy, smoky, and thick with people. Holly glances at Mickey once again, this time unable to contain her annoyance.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, why are you making those faces?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't hear you. I can't hear anything. I'm, I'm, I'm, I'm gonna lose hearing in my ear! I'm--</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, you are witnessing genius!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I, I, my ears are experiencing a meltdown! I can't hear anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens a vial of cocaine.</context>
      <utterance>Look, can't you feel the energy? It's tangible energy! The room's alive with positive vibrations!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holly holds a short metal straw of cocaine to her nose and sniffs it.</context>
      <utterance>Holly, I'm frightened! I'm--After they sing... they're gonna take hostages! Now let's--</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't, no, please. Will you-- No, don't...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want some?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE 39 STEPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"I want to dress like you Say, I'll buy all the clothes I want to fuck like you Yeah, I'm sure it shows Because I'm..."</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't. No. No.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Mickey. Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>While Mickey pleads with her, Holly puts her cocaine vial into her purse. She holds a finger against one nostril and sniffs. She then picks up her lit cigarette and continues to smoke.</context>
      <utterance>But, no, you've been doing that all night! You're gonna...you're gonna burn a hole in your... You're gonna develop a third nostril! Really,  don't, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we, can we go?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera leaves the crowded tables and moves back to the band. The lead singers continues to sing with his band, swaying his body to the music...</context>
      <utterance>My--uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love songs about extraterrestrial life, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not when they're sung by extraterrestrials.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, well, I cannot communicate with you! I, you know, I never realized you were such a tightass.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't understand you. Your sisters, both sisters have such good taste in music. I don't know where you went, went wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you mind? I'm-I'm my own person.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I take you someplace to hear something nice?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eh, Mickey, it's getting late.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stop briefly at a street corner and look for oncoming cars before crossing. Mickey takes Holly's arm as they walk across the street towards the camera.</context>
      <utterance>Now come on, you're be--, 'cause you're being angry at me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not angry! You know, you, well, you don't believe in ESP, you don't like rock music, you won't get high... It's like I'm dating Cardinal Cooke!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BOBBY SHORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just as reckless as a child? Why am I Like a racehorse running wild? Why am I In a state of ecstasy? The reason is 'cause something's Happened to me I'm in love again And the spring is comin'..." ...as the camera leaves the musicians and moves to the conversatively dressed audience. A far cry from the rock club atmosphere, the Carlyle is quiet except for Bobby Short's singing. The audience at their tables watch him, some with smiles of pleasure. A man has his arm around a woman. Jewels sparkle in another woman's hair. The men wear suits. Mickey and Holly sit at one of the tables; a candle burns in its holder on the tabletop. Holly takes a cigarette from her purse as she holds her hand to her nose, sniffing. Mickey keeps shooting glances at Holly; she can't sit still. Bobby Short continues to sing...</context>
      <utterance>"Why am I</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY SHORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The film cuts back briefly to Bobby Short playing the piano...</context>
      <utterance>"I'm in love again Hear my heart strings strummin' I'm in love again And the hymn they're hummin' Is those cuddle-up huddle-up blues I'm in love again And I can't rise above it..." ...as Holly lights her cigarette, dropping her matchbook on the floor. She bends down to pick it up, then starts to fidget in her chair. She gulps her wine; she sniffs. Mickey tries to watch the offscreen Bobby Short; he crosses his arms across his chest.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY SHORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"I'm in love again And I love, love, love it." ...then abruptly cuts to:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for a swell time.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if you didn't like it, you didn't like it, but you didn't have to talk while the guy was singing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was so bored!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that's tough! You don't deserve Cole Porter. You should stay with those groups that look like they're gonna stab their mother!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least I'm open to new concepts!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you don't have to snort cocaine at the table all the time! What do you, what do you do? Carry a kilo around in your purse?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This crowd wouldn't know the difference! They're embalmed!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A taxi pulls up to the curb. Mickey and Holly walk up to its rear door.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus...  I'm glad Hannah got us together. You know, she's got a great instinct for people. Really.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, look, I'm sorry it didn't work out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Me, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I've been a little depressed lately.</context>
      <utterance>You know, it's probably my fault.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Yeah. I had a...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds the door open for Holly. She gets in.</context>
      <utterance>...I had a great time tonight, really. It was like the Nuremberg Trials.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Both a bus and a taxi drive down the street, blocking Mickey from view. The music stops and the film cuts to: Afternoons. A big-band rendition of "You Made Me Love You" begins as the film cuts to a hotel room. Elliot and Lee can be seen dancing cheek to cheek in the reflection of a mirror over a dresser. A TV sits in the corner. A lamp is on one side of the dresser; on the other side is a bucket with champagne. Two half-full glasses sit nearby. Elliot and Lee dance into view. Without missing a beat, Elliot picks up one of the glasses of champagne and hands it to Lee. She sips. Elliot sips, then puts it back down on the dresser. They embrace tightly, continuing to dance.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it was quite an evening. Holly with her cocaine...  She should have been wearing a gold shovel around her neck. Tch, she was polymorphously insensitive, I think.  Too bad, too... 'cause, you know, I always had a little crush on her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="41">
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you just have to read the instructions. I mean, you just set one of these things and you can take, you can take pictures underwater.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHILD 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I try it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The child takes the camera from Hannah, as well as picking up a second identical one from the table.</context>
      <utterance>Sure! Yeah. When we get to the country, we'll try it in the lake.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHILD 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHILD 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I go?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHILD 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The adopted children leave, the twins going off with them. When they're gone, Hannah takes a sip of her coffee and looks at Elliot. She puts down her cup, still watching him.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah! Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you in a bad mood?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera moves in on their faces as they continue to speak. Family photos line the mantel behind Hannah's head.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Um...I'm just antsy.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I know. The last few weeks, you haven't been yourself. And tonight at, tonight at dinner, you, you were kind of curt with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was I?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, you were. A-and when I, when I brought up the idea of having a baby, you just, you jumped down my throat.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I-I don't think it's a very good idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because it's the last thing in the world we need right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you say that? Is there something wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, tell me. Should I be worried?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, you got four children!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want one with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well...I-I think we should wait till things settle.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>How settled can things get?</context>
      <utterance>But what do, what do you--  what's that mean? W-w-we've been, we've been married for four years.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, y-you have some very set plans on how your life should be structured. A-a house, uh, kids, certain schools, a h--, a home in Connecticut. I-it's all very...preconceived.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but I...uh--I thought you needed that. When-when-when we met, you said your life was chaos.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hannah sighs. Elliot angrily throws his napkin on the table. He stands up and begins to pace behind Hannah.</context>
      <utterance>I-I-I know, but there's got to be some give and take.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, let's not--I, I don't know what the hell I'm talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you angry with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you feel, um...are you disenchanted with our marriage?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't say that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you in love with someone else?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God! Wha-what is this? The Gestapo? No. He sits down again, in a chair next to Hannah; the ketchup bottle sits in front of him.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what? What, wh-what are you not telling me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of interrogation... Su- supposing I said yes? I-I-I am disenchanted. I am in love with someone else.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!  But you keep asking these, these awful questions. My God, it's-it's like you want me to say yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, you, of c-- What are you talking about? Of course not. I'd be destroyed! The camera moves in on Elliot's anguished face. He talks over the screen.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>He looks down. Hannah leans over and tenderly puts her hand on his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>For Chrissakes, stop torturing her. Tell her you want out and get it over with. You're in love with her sister. You didn't do it on purpose. Be honest. It's always the best way.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She touches his hand; Elliot embraces her.</context>
      <utterance>Look, can I help you? If you're suffering over something, will you share it with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elliot kisses Hannah again; they embrace tightly. She touches his hair.</context>
      <utterance>Hannah, you know how much I love you.  I ought to have my head examined. I don't deserve you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I just want to look so good, but I don't want to seem, you know, like I'm overdressed.  You know what I'm saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, no, not at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, how about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I, I really like that. I think that's a pretty color on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hannah and Holly reach the top of the stairs. They walk onto a cavernous, high-tech floor. Empty bleachers line one wall; the rest of the floor is filled with racks of clothes and empty space.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(chuckling)</context>
      <utterance>Did you ever think you'd be helping me buy something to wear to the opera?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holly follows Hannah to a rack of blouses.</context>
      <utterance>Nuh-uh...but I think it's great. I can't wait to meet him.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's married...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh-oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes she's terrific...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oooo.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and then she just breaks down.  And he has this sweet daughter...and when she goes to college next year, he's going to split permanently. I mean...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hannah takes a jacket on a hanger off the rack and looks at it. She holds it to her.</context>
      <utterance>...he's really paid his dues, but...then she helped put him through architecture school, you know, so...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You found all this, all this out on one date?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hannah turns to Holly with surprise. She puts the jacket back on the rack and stares at her; she inhales.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I think he was dying to open up. It's so sad.  Now...what should I wear to my audition?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got a singing audition for a Broadway musical.  Of course, I'll never get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Singing?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, can you believe it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I mean, why not? You know, wh-what have I got to lose? Uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hannah begins to look at the rack of clothes on Holly's side, while her sister stares at her, frowning.</context>
      <utterance>Well, no...I-I know, I just, uh... No, I-I, eh, you know, I, I didn't, I didn't know you sung.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you think everybody in m- musicals sings so well?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holly is silent for a moment. Hannah takes a blouse off the rack and looks at it.</context>
      <utterance>No! No, I, eh, it's just that they sing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(chuckling self-consciously)</context>
      <utterance>Well...you know, uh...I sing a little, I mean...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ohh!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, no--  I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, y-you know, don't say it that way, you know, because my confidence is not my strong point,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, you know, I think I can fake my way through a song.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holly pauses, looking at her sister. They continue to walk.</context>
      <utterance>Easily.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>W-why? You don't think it's realistic?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I didn't, I, that's no. No, I- I-I, no, I-I just...  hate to see you put yourself in a position where, where you get hurt, you know. You know, you know how you take...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk over to a table laid out with colorful scarves and decorated with hurricane lamps bordering its edges.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...every, eh, single rejection as- as-as a...a confirmation that you have no talent, or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(chuckling and gesturing)</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Well, maybe I'll get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holly looks at her sister for a beat.</context>
      <utterance>I hope.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, you really know how to cut me down.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? You don't, don't be so sensitive. Can't I say anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A female customer, who'd come over to the table, browsing through the rack of clothes near Hannah, looks up, reacting. She walks away.</context>
      <utterance>Tch, well, I sing!  For Chrissake, Hannah, you heard me sing!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks past Holly and briefly looks at a different rack of clothes beneath the table.</context>
      <utterance>Okay!  Okay. I-- What happened? You know, we were having a really nice time, a-and suddenly, everything went to bad feeling.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I don't know why.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody but you can do that to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holly chuckles and begins to look through the scarves on the table.</context>
      <utterance>You're right.  I'm happy.  Why must I let my insecurities spoil everything?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The film moves from the audience to the stage where Holly, her hands clasped in front of her, continues to sing her song. A large group of other hopefuls are seen in the background behind her.</context>
      <utterance>"This year's fancies Are passing fancies..."</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera moves from Holly back to the executives in the audience. As it passes the empty audience seats, they are heard offscreen.</context>
      <utterance>"But sighing sighs Holding hands This my heart Understands I'm old-fashioned And I don't mind it It's how I want to be As long as you agree To stay old-fashioned with me."</utterance>
   <speaker>PRODUCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRODUCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was very nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera has reached the executives in the audience. They are now chattering among themselves, Holly forgotten.</context>
      <utterance>Terrific.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAGE MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The film cuts back to the stage, where April, handling the audition pianist some sheet music, prepares herself to sing "The Way You Look Tonight." The stage is very black, stark, except for April and the pianist.</context>
      <utterance>April Knox?</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Someday When I'm awfully low When the world is cold I will get a glow Just thinking of you And the way you look Tonight..."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="48">
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You, uh, you may be surprised.</context>
      <utterance>I'm telling you, you sounded great.</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm just glad we have a catering job this week. I'm real low on money.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, we have Mr. Morris Levine's eightieth birthday party on Riverside Drive...or Riverside Memorial Chapel, depending on his health.</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, uh, listen, David called me up.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, David called me last night, and he wants to take me to the opera.  I didn't know what to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're joking.</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, he called late last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I, uh, I'm very surprised.</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wants to take me to see Rigoletto.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you, you-you're going?</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I-I-I didn't know what to say. First I said no, but then, he pressed it. He said, uh, he'd taken you once and he really wanted to invite me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I'm seeing him.</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. I said that, but...  he said it was something he really felt like doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gee, um...  I...I don't know what to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holly looks away sadly; she shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>Look, it's just an evening at the opera. Did I, I-I do wrong in accepting?</utterance>
   <speaker>APRIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, uh, because, y-you know, I gotta have something to believe in, otherwise life is just meaningless.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The movie cuts to Mickey's face. He's very neat in a tie, sweater, and sports jacket.</context>
      <utterance>I understand. But why did you make the decision to choose the Catholic faith?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tch. Well, y-you know...first of all, because it's a very beautiful religion. It's very well structured. Now I'm talking now, incidentally, about the-the, uh, against-school- prayer, pro-abortion, anti-nuclear wing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. A-a-and I-I want to. You know, I'm-I'm willing to do anything. I'll, you know, I'll dye Easter eggs if it works.  I-I need some evidence. I gotta have some proof. Uh, you know, i- i-if I can't believe in God  then I don't think life is worth living.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER FLYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Father Flynn clasps his hands in his lap.</context>
      <utterance>It means making a very big leap.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sobs hysterically, staggering offscreen to the bathroom; she shuts the door. Mickey walks into view, in the living room, looking after his shocked mother, who continues to cry over the scene.</context>
      <utterance>Why? Oh, my God!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand.  I thought that you would be happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His father walks into view, carrying a teacup and a candy dish. He strides past Mickey towards the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>How can we be happy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, because I never thought of God in my life. Now I'm giving it serious thought.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But Catholicism? Why not your own people?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I got off to a wrong foot with my own thing, you know. B-b- b-but I need a dramatic change in my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gonna believe in Jesus Christ?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know it sounds funny, but I'm gonna try.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But why? We raised you as a Jew.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holding the dirty dishes in his hand, Mickey's father looks at his son.</context>
      <utterance>But why Jesus Christ? Why, for instance, shouldn't you become a Buddhist?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mickey's father walks offscreen again, to the kitchen sink.</context>
      <utterance>A Bud--? That's totally alien to me. Look, you're getting on in years, right? Aren't you afraid of dying?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why should I be afraid?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh! 'Cause you won't exist!</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who thinks about such nonsense? Now I'm alive. When I'm dead, I'll be dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand. Aren't you frightened?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of what? I'll be unconscious.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I know. But never to exist again!</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mickey stops at the bathroom door at the other end of the hallway. He starts to pound it.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it certainly doesn't look promising.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mickey's father comes back on screen; he's carrying a plate of hors d'oeuvres and an empty glass towards the kitchen. He stops and looks down the hall at Mickey, who's now struggling to open the bathroom door.</context>
      <utterance>Who knows what'll be?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll either be unconscious or I won't. If not, I'll deal with it then. I'm not gonna worry now about what's gonna be when I'm unconscious.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom, come out!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You don't believe in God?</context>
      <utterance>Of course there's a God, you idiot!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Why-why were there Nazis?</context>
      <utterance>But if there's a God, then wh-why is there so much evil in the world?  What-- Just on a simplistic level.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mickey, reacting, hits his forehead.</context>
      <utterance>Tell him, Max.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="87">
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sisters laugh and embrace each other.</context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. Where's Holly?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. She's auditioning for a television commercial. She said she's gonna be a little late.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns and walks towards the restaurant entrance.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah? How's she doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They disappear inside. The camera follows them, cutting to the restaurant's interior at the same time the sisters walk in. It's a chic, trendy place, with an Art Deco design and high ceilings. A waiter in uniform stands near its glass and metal doors, holding a tray to his chest; a few people sit at the bar; a large plant in a vase sits in the foreground. The sisters walk toward the coatcheck area, deep in conversation.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, God, you know Holly. When she's depressed, she's manic. I think it was a good idea that we invited her to lunch.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope you tell her it was your idea...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...'cause every time I try to be helpful, you know, sh-she gets so defensive.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hannah walks offscreen, farther into the coatcheck room. She talks offscreen as Lee alone is seen, reacting and speaking as well. In the background, a waiter crosses over to the bar, then walks away.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Hannah, she's-she's just embarrassed in front of you, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, me, I'm okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you miss Frederick?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe Elliot and I can't think of someone nice for you to go out with, you know--</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, how's everything? You doing okay? How's Frederick?  I mean, Elliot.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hannah walks out of the coatcheck room without her coat; it's Lee's turn to disappear and check her things. Now only Hannah can be seen onscreen as the sisters talk. In the background, the waiter once again walks over to the bar.</context>
      <utterance>Y-yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, he's fine. He's-he's, I guess he's fine. I don't know.  He's been kinda moody lately, the last few months.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I-I don't know what's wrong with him. He's just...kind of distant and difficult.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been trying to talk to him about it. He says everything's fine, but I don't know. Automatically, you know, I leap to the worst conclusions.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Hannah answers her sister, Holly can be seen entering the restaurant and walking over to the coatcheck area, an unlit cigarette in her mouth, her sunglasses still on her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, I don't know, he's seeing someone else or something, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hannah mumbles indistinctly as Holly walks over to her sisters.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no! I mean, everyone thinks things like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, hi!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I just came from an audition...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...which I did not get.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awwww...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes off her gloves and scarf, stuffing them in her bag)</context>
      <utterance>So what's new?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy--</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They said I was too offbeat looking, whatever the hell that means.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, what do they know? Holly gives her coat to the coatcheck person.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.  But guess who was there auditioning?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The hostess appears, peeking around the corner of the coatcheck area. She signals for the three sisters to follow her.</context>
      <utterance>April?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, gosh.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holly takes off her sunglasses; her cigarette still dangles from her mouth. Hannah murmurs her sympathy as the trio follows the hostess into the dining room.</context>
      <utterance>You got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was very polite. I maintained my poise.  I said hello. The sisters walk to their seats, at a round table in the middle of the room; the hostess puts down their menus.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They sit down. The hostess leaves. Other diners are seen in the background; a waiter is taking the order of a couple sitting on a banquette; other waiters clear off a table. Diners walk in and out. A low murmur of conversation, as well as the faint clatter of dishes, is heard. The camera moves closer to the three sisters, circling the table as Holly speaks.</context>
      <utterance>Hmm. I never trusted April, you know. She has eyes in the back of her head.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, she and an architect are now a very definite item, which I still cannot believe.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmm.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, God...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, although it's put an end to the Stanislavski Catering Company. Which is why I have to speak to you. And...  you're gonna get impatient, but...I have to borrow some more money.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that...th-that's fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the camera slowly circles the table, Hannah is seen listening to Holly, her hand on her mouth.</context>
      <utterance>But what I decided to do is some writing. Yeah, I think I've had it with acting. You know, these meaningless auditions at cattle calls. And I can't handle another rejection.  Now let's face it here. I gotta, you know, latch on to something in my life. You know--something with a future. I'm not sixteen anymore.  It's just...crazy!  I've got...an idea for a story. More than one. And I just need a few months, you know, or, uh, a year even.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee, her hand on her mouth, glances briefly at Hannah. As Hannah replies to Holly, the camera focuses on Lee's face. She bites her nails; she looks down, involved in her own thoughts.</context>
      <utterance>I've picked up a lot about dramatic structure from doing my scenes in acting class.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that-that's good. It just, uh...it just seems to me that-that six months or a year, if-if you spent it more productively...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee looks up, her hand still on her mouth, watching Hannah, as the camera slowly moves off her to show Hannah.</context>
      <utterance>Well-well, like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't know. We'd uh, uh, um... Didn't Mom mention there was something...something at the Museum of Broadcasting?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that's clerical.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera is back on Lee. She looks around tensely, barely listening to the conversation. She fidgets. An empty table sits in the background.</context>
      <utterance>No. She, didn't she say it was, um...she said it was in the publicity department. That-that can lead to other things.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, I knew you'd be discouraging.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not! I'm not! I'm trying to be helpful. A person doesn't just say one day, "Okay, now-now I'm finished as an actress. Now I'm a writer." I mean--</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you mean not at my age.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, please! We all came to have lunch, didn't we?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holly abruptly picks up her menu.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, okay, right. Forget it.  What's to eat?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy...Holly...Holly.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just want a salad.  You really think I'm a loser, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do--? You're being ridiculous.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are, Holly. Stop it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You treat me like a loser.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puffs intensely on her cigarette as the camera slowly circles to Hannah's face. She is equally intense, looking at both sisters as she speaks.</context>
      <utterance>You never have any faith in my plans. You always undercut my enthusiasm.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not so! No. I think I've been very supportive. I've...I try to give you honest, constructive advice.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmm!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm-I'm always happy to help you financially. I think I've gone out of my way to-to introduce you to interesting single men. There's nothing I would--</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, losers! All losers!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're too demanding.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're crazy! That's not true.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Hannah, I know I'm mediocre.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, will you stop attacking Hannah?!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, now--</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's going through a really rough time right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you so upset?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(sniffing back her tears)</context>
      <utterance>You know, you've been picking on her ever since she came in here. Now just leave her alone for a while! I'm just suffocating.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter with you, Lee? Why are you so sensitive all of a sudden?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look.  Listen. Listen.  You want to write? Write.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Write! Let's just not talk about it anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens her menu, then turns to Lee, reacting suddenly to her sister, who is rubbing her forehead, looking terribly upset.</context>
      <utterance>Take...take a year. Take six months. Whatever you want. Who knows? Maybe you'll, maybe you'll be sitting with a good play.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter? What's the matter with you?  You look pale. You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm-I'm okay. Yeah, I-I-I, you know, I...I'm just, um, I got dizzy all of a sudden. I'm-I'm...I have a headache.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we need to eat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>...as Lee stops on a portico and turns to greet Doug, a professor, who is running over to her, calling her name. They mouth hello, smiling, and begin to walk off together.</context>
      <utterance>Meanwhile...Lee has no direction. She's taking courses at Columbia...but just randomly.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The film cuts back to Elliot in his analyst's office.</context>
      <utterance>I try not to call her, but then she calls me and then...I call and...we try to resist meeting, but...once in a while we meet. Sometimes we argue because I can't break up my marriage. Sometimes we wind up making love and...we both feel terrible.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elliot takes a last drag on his cigarette. The camera follows his hand as he crushes it out in a nearby ashtray.</context>
      <utterance>But it's my fault.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For all my education, accomplishments, and so-called wisdom...I can't fathom my own heart.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KRISHNA LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What makes you interested in becoming a Hare Krishna?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm not saying that I want to join or anything, but...but I know you guys believe in reincarnation, you know, so it interests me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRISHNA LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, what's your religion?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And I, and I wanted to, you know.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I was born Jewish, you know, but, uh, but last winter I tried to become a Catholic and...it didn't work for me. I-I studied and I tried and I gave it everything, but, you know, Catholicism for me was die now, pay later, you know. And I just couldn't get with it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>KRISHNA LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're afraid of dying?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well...yeah, naturally. Aren't you? I-- L-let me ask you, reincarnation, does that mean my soul would pass to another human being, or would I come back as a moose or an aardvark or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRISHNA LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take our literature...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRISHNA LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...read it over, and think about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, okay. Thank you very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRISHNA LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mickey walks off, the Hare Krishnas still dancing and singing on the other side of the fence. He flips through the literature as he walks, then looks straight ahead, pondering. His voice is heard over the screen.</context>
      <utterance>You're welcome. Hare Krishna.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Mickey puts his hand to his mouth as another title appears on a black screen. Autumn chill. Bach's Concerto for Harpsichord is heard as the film cuts to the waterfront at dusk. A bench faces some wharf pilings; the water gently laps against them as Lee walks into view, the wind blowing her hair. She stands and faces the water and the distant skyline across the bay. The view is contemplative, beautiful in the dim light. Lee is alone; her hands are in her pockets. Lee, thinking, is heard over the scene; the harpsichord music plays in the background.</context>
      <utterance>Who are you kidding? You're gonna be a Krishna? You're gonna shave your head and put on robes and dance around at airports? You'll look like Jerry Lewis. Oh, God, I'm so depressed.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The concerto stops and the movie cuts to Holly, leaning into an open phone booth near a subway entrance. She wears a football jacket, jeans, and sneakers; she holds a manuscript in her arms. It's a busy corner. People rush past Holly towards the subway; others are walking up the station steps. Holly smokes a cigarette as she talks on the phone to Hannah.</context>
      <utterance>The nights are really getting cooler. Summer went so quickly. Soon it'll be fall.  My literature professor really likes me. It was fun being out with him last night.  Funny. I feel like I'm betraying Elliot...but that's ridiculous. Why shouldn't I see Doug? Elliot's not free.  Just go one step at a time. Let's see what the next few months bring.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holly hangs up the phone and takes a drag on her cigarette. She looks off in the distance, smiling, as the film cuts to:</context>
      <utterance>Hannah? Hi. Listen, um, you'll be happy to know that your money has not gone completely to waste... No, I have an actual first rough draft of something I wrote... Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, well, I showed it to Lee, and she gave me some good pointers. And, um, listen, I'm pretty near where you live. I wonder if I could just drop it off...and, you know, when you have time, some time, read it, an-and we'll talk when I come over at Thanksgiving. Okay? All right. Okay. Oh, wait, wait.  Listen. Listen. I think Lee met an interesting guy at Columbia... Yeah. Yeah, well, he sounds really nice...  Yeah. Okay. All right. Well, we'll talk at Thanksgiving. Bye-bye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, here...here's a song that Norma sang on that trip we made up to the show in Buffalo. And, oh, was she beautiful that night! The guests laugh appreciatively. A woman comes over to Evan and hands him some wine.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs; the guests laugh with him.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, honey.  Oh, yes, you were, dear. Don't you remember that night?  She was so beautiful...she was so beautiful that when men saw her walking along the streets, they'd drive their cars right up on the sidewalk.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't that right, honey, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guest continue to laugh; they are charmed.</context>
      <utterance>A slight exaggeration.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've been very cold to me tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is something wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee slips past Elliot and walks away. Elliot looks back at her briefly, then, sipping his drink, he turns and looks offscreen at the crowd in the living room.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, not here.  There are too many people around.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="66">
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hannah walks into view, headed for the refrigerator. She carries two tomatoes.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Hannah? You know, I think Lee is really serious about her new boyfriend. Yeah, eh, from what I understand he sounds really nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hannah opens the refrigerator, totally ignoring Holly.</context>
      <utterance>I'm so happy for her. I think she's in love.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, what's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hannah walks over to the table, gathering up more food.</context>
      <utterance>I'm real upset about what you wrote.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My script?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's obviously based on Elliot and me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, so loosely.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not "Oh, so loosely"! Real specifically! Is that how you see us?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well--</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holly walks over to the sink and washes her hands.</context>
      <utterance>Can I, can I not accept gestures and feelings from people? Do I, do I put people off?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's a made-up story. She dries her hands as Hannah, her arms laden with vegetables, strides over to her sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's real exact! The-the situations, the dialogue, everything. It's-it's full of intimate details between Elliot and me! Which I don't, I don't see how you could even possibly know about. A conversation we once had about adoption? Hannah storms out a nearby door as Holly turns away from the sink.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holly wipes her hand on the towel as Hannah reenters the kitchen, carrying even more vegetables.</context>
      <utterance>Well, Lee mentioned that to me, so obviously you discussed it with her. You...  I just took the essence and I blew it up into drama.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hannah strides into the pantry area and flops the vegetables down on the counter. Holly puts the dishtowel down and absently straightens some things on the food-laden table.</context>
      <utterance>I don't see how Lee could know about these things. I don't! I don't tell her everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow, I guess I hit a nerve.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You make it sound like, you know, I have no needs or something. You think I'm too self-sufficient?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We're grateful."</context>
      <utterance>Now, Hannah, that's not what I meant, you know.  Uh, yeah, everybody relies on you for so much. "You're so giving. It's not a criticism. We love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're grateful, but you resent me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y-you mentioned to me yourself that you and Elliot were having some problems.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, we're having some problems, but problems that are my business...which I don't see how you could know about in such detail. How does Lee know about these things? How? They're private! Hannah picks up a large bowl and carries it, as well as her armload of spices, into the pantry area.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, why don't you share them with us?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't...I don't want to bother everyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the point. I'd like to be bothered.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't see how you could know about these things unless Elliot's been talking to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's over, Elliot. I don't know how to make it any clearer. It's over. I can't see you anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh...  I-I-I know. I deserve this.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I'm just as much at fault.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If-if-if you can believe I have such feelings for you!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee goes over to an open door and closes it quickly.</context>
      <utterance>I've got to be honest with you. I met someone else. I've met someone else.  I...I told you I wasn't going to wait forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it hasn't been forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's been nearly a year since our first time and you're still married to my sister, which...I now realize is fine because you're probably much more in love with her than you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but we-we made so many plans.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door opens and Mavis appears, holding a set of candlesticks. She walks over to the dining room table, which is already decked out with a floral centerpiece, glassware, and china. She puts them down as Lee and Elliot stand awkwardly near the door, waiting for her to leave.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Uh, well, sure we did. An- an-and in a way you led me on, because I truly believed you were unhappy with Hannah. Otherwise, I would never have let myself be drawn in. I was very weak. So were you. Now I've met someone else.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dinner soon?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About fifteen minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mavis leaves. Both Lee and Elliot quickly close the door behind her and immediately pick up where they'd left off.</context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh. Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you're in love overnight?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I care a great deal about him, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lee...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sweetheart, I loved your script. I thought it was so clever.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you're my mother. Not everybody's gonna be such a sucker.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holly chuckles.</context>
      <utterance>I particularly liked the character of the mother. Just a boozy old flirt with a filthy mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so proud!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norma steps back out of the kitchen, the door swinging shut behind her. Holly looks at the door, sipping her wine, as the movie cuts back to Hannah's living room. A chubby, friendly uncle sits on a sofa, one child on his lap and several others gathered cross-legged around him on the floor. They lean on the coffee table, which is covered with glasses and a bowl of chips. Other guests mingle in the background; one couple enters the living room, smiling at the scene on the sofa. Mavis crosses the well-lit foyer in the background and opens the door to more guests. The piano plays on.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Mom, thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The children mutter their enthusiastic agreement, picking up their "illicit" glasses of beer.</context>
      <utterance>Now here's a toast to Thanksgiving, all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The uncle pours more beer from his bottle into the kids' outstretched glasses. They cry indistinctly with excitement.</context>
      <utterance>Are we supposed to have beer? Yeeeah!</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laughing, he turns to the little girl sitting on his lap; he clinks his bottle against the bottle she is holding, which is almost as big as she is.</context>
      <utterance>Let me at it!  How's that, Fletcher?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The uncle and the children happily drink their beer as the movie cuts to a wall with subtly patterned wallpaper in Hannah's bedroom. Her face moves on to the screen.</context>
      <utterance>Doll? To Thanksgiving. Here's a little toast, doll.  Come on. Bottoms up.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you been talking to Holly or Lee about us? About our-our personal life?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me? Of course not.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's things Holly wrote about in her script about us that are so...personal they could only have come from you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not accusing. I'm asking. Do you...do you find me too...too giving?  Too-too-too competent? Too-too, I don't know, disgustingly perfect or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elliot walks from behind the partially closed door to an offscreen medicine cabinet.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what is it then? What? Eh, what's come between us? How have I alienated you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hannah, my head is throbbing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You never want to talk about it. I-- Every time I bring it up, you- you change the subject. What is it? Do you-- We're communicating less and less. You sleep with me less and less.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elliot turns back to the sink, once again obscured by the partially closed door.</context>
      <utterance>Hannah, I am very mixed up! Now please!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you talk to Holly or Lee behind my back? Do you? You must. They- they seem to know so much about us.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He dries his hands as Hannah, standing behind him, continues to talk.</context>
      <utterance>Well, maybe I've asked advice once or twice or-or made a joke.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what do you do? Do-do-do you talk to Holly, or Lee, or what? Do you, do you, do you phone them?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He closes the door, briefly obscuring Hannah and himself from view.</context>
      <utterance>Leave me alone, can you?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera moves behind the closed door, into the bathroom.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus, I've told you. I need someone I can matter to.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You matter to me. Completely.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens the medicine cabinet and puts the aspirin bottle back.</context>
      <utterance>It's hard to be around someone who gives so much and-and needs so little in return!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elliot slams the medicine cabinet shut.</context>
      <utterance>But, look...I-I have enormous needs.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaves. Hannah watches him go, reacting. She is stunned.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I can't see them, and neither can Lee or Holly!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="88">
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's so pitch-black tonight. I feel lost.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elliot turns the lamp back on, then turns to Hannah; she is lying on her side of the bed, partially in shadow. He leans over and kisses her.</context>
      <utterance>You're not lost.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They begin to kiss passionately as "Bewitched" starts to play in the background.</context>
      <utterance>I love you so much.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmm, I don't know if you remember me, but we had the worst night of my life together.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I remember you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, you do recall, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I recall you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was walking past and I saw you in here...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and I thought I'd come in and...and we could replay, uh, the whole, uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We didn't hit it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, that's putting it mildly. We did everything but exchange gunshots.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. How are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look wonderful.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, no.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, really. You do. You do.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was a terrible evening.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it was.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(touching his nose again)</context>
      <utterance>Remember slamming the cab door in my face and..  you know, it came very dangerously close to emasculating my nose in a...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd never do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...in a really horrible way.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, well, that was a long time ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look wonderful. You do. What happened to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People change...you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I hope you've changed.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I hope you have, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope so for your sake, because, uh, your personality left something to be desired...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, and for yours. I'm sure you've changed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holly chuckles and turns to look at more records. She walks down the aisle, occasionally glancing at the bins of records. Mickey walks beside her.</context>
      <utterance>...namely a personality.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What are you doing?</context>
      <utterance>You didn't answer my question.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, nothing much. You know...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...just some stuff. A little of this, a little of that, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Is that an embarrassing question? Should I have not asked it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably not.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you, are you out of work or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, well...I've been trying to write.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's interesting. Wh-what kind of stuff?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh...well, you-you're not interested in this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you can tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I am. I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, no, millions of people come up to you and say, "Hey, I have something I just wrote," right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody ever said it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is it. Yeah. This is really--</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, wo-would you be willing to-to read it? Something...that I wrote?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, yes, I would if, uh, if it would mean anything to you. I don't know why it would.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, the reason I ask is--</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've always hated my taste in the past.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I haven't.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't. No, the reason why I ask is I think it might make a great, uh, television script, and, you know, you're so active in television, so--</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not anymore. I haven't, I haven't been in television for a year.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're kidding me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I may, I may have to get back into it, 'cause my accountant says that I'm running out of dollars. But...but, um, no, I haven't, I just sort of dropped out for a year...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mickey walks back onscreen to Holly. The two of them are partially obscured by a large white Jazz sign imprinted with a large red circle as they continue their conversation.</context>
      <utterance>...which is a long, dull story and I won't get into it. But--</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're okay, though, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm-- Yes. Yes, I'm fine. I'm fine. How are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What...what about your script?  So what's it about?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'd love it if you'd read it, actually, 'cause I really would value your opinion.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They emerge from behind the Jazz sign, still walking, still talking.</context>
      <utterance>You have to remember, we-we-we didn't agree on one thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you have to remember while you're reading and you're cursing my name, you know, that this is my first script. Well, it's not my first script.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmm.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, my first script was about Hannah and her husband, but, uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Hannah read it, she got really angry, and... you know, then I felt badly, so I-- She picks up a record.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, well, God, I can imagine what you wrote.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mickey pulls out a record and looks at it.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no! It wasn't anything bad. But she just... you know. I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holly looks hopefully at Mickey.</context>
      <utterance>So, uh...I threw it out, but I have this other one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you know, I-I-I...you know, if you want me to, I'll read it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, gosh, I don't know.  Well, could I come over tomorrow and read it to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must be joking. I've been doing all my own reading since I was forty...you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmm. I think it's lucky I ran into you.  Maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what about me?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, well.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holly chuckles, looking off for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>I should have kept going. I-I have a sneaking feeling, a nagging sensation I should've kept walking and...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a brief pause and the movie cuts to:</context>
      <utterance>...and not begun this conversation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="54">
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"We all go through life playing the hand we're dealt. Craig: And what hand were you dealt?  "Emily: I'm two high pair, maybe even aces up. The problem is, you've got three deuces." Holly closes the script and looks up at Mickey.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mickey smiles and shrugs, not knowing what to say.</context>
      <utterance>That's the end.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you can tell me straight. It's okay. Just, you know, tell me what you think.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's great. I swea-- I'm-- I'm, tch, I'm speechless. I was...I was not in the mood to listen to this thing now.  I don't know what to say. I'm moved and I laughed and I-- Uh, I, you know, I was on the edge of my seat. I just think it's wonderful! I'm, I'm totally...stunned. This is not an insult. I'm amazed that you can...  It was-- I just thought it was great.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes! I was abso-- And...w- what...made you think of that climax scene where the, where the... architect is walking home with his actress girlfriend and-and the ex- wife who's schizophrenic jumps out of the bushes and stabs him to death?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, it just came to me one day.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it was just fabulous! I'm, I, you know...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, gosh, you really think I can write?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought it was wonder-- There's maybe one or two things in there that I would do differently myself, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...but who cares? It was just--  It was fabulous.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holly, thrilled with Mickey's overwhelming response, stands up, her hand on her head. Unable to contain herself, she begins to walk up and down the room, holding her script. The camera follows her; Mickey is now offscreen.</context>
      <utterance>Fabulous, I mean it! I'm so impressed.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, God!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am. You-you made my day.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, wow!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was just great. Uh, I was all set...I was set to be bored stiff.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, gee. Would you like to have lunch? Uh, uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I-I would love to talk to you about, uh, that script. I-I, you know, I think maybe that we could do something with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, and listen, I would like to hear what made you suddenly decide to drop out of life.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, who cares?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gosh, you really went through a crisis, you know that? H-how did you get over it? I mean, when I ran into you, you seemed, you seemed just perfectly fine. Well, you seem fine now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The film abruptly cuts to Mickey's flashback, a visual counterpoint to the story he is telling Holly. A close-up of a nervous, perspiring, and panting Mickey alone in his apartment appears on the screen as his voice is heard.</context>
      <utterance>Well...  I'll tell you.  One day about a month ago...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Mickey raises the barrel of a rifle to his forehead. He shuts his eyes tightly.</context>
      <utterance>...I really hit bottom. You know, I just felt that in a Godless universe, I didn't want to go on living. Now I happen to own this rifle...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The camera moves past the desperate Mickey to a mirror on the wall behind him. Its reflection shows his spiral staircase and some standing lamps. A clock faintly ticks.</context>
      <utterance>...which I loaded, believe it or not, and pressed it to my forehead. And I remember thinking, at the time, I'm gonna kill myself. Then I thought...what if I'm wrong? What if there is a God? I mean, after all, nobody really knows that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The gun goes off with a loud bang. The mirror shatters.</context>
      <utterance>But then I thought, no. You know, maybe is not good enough. I want certainty or nothing. And I remember very clearly the clock was ticking, and I was sitting there frozen, with the gun to my head, debating whether to shoot.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Mickey, holding the rifle, is seen running over to the shattered mirror. The sounds of his excited neighbors, their shouting, a knocking door, are heard as he continues his tale.</context>
      <utterance>All of a sudden, the gun went off.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had been so tense, my finger had squeezed the trigger inadvertently...</utterance>
   <speaker>NEIGHBOR #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's happening? Wh-wh-what's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...but I was perspiring so much, the gun had slid off my forehead and missed me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEIGHBOR #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mickey, still brandishing the rifle, runs into his sunlit living room. He looks around frantically, his shirt loose. Finally, he throws the rifle down between the sofa and the coffee table. The gun goes off a second time. Mickey, standing nearby, jumps, his hands flying to his head. The doorbell rings; the neighbors begin pounding at the door.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I heard a gun. Is everything all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Mickey runs offscreen briefly to answer the door.</context>
      <utterance>And suddenly, neighbors were, were, pounding on the door, and-and I don't know, the whole scene was just pandemonium. And, uh, you know, and I-I-I-I-I ran to the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>He returns onscreen, panting; he looks frantically once again around the living room.</context>
      <utterance>I-I-I-I didn't know what to say. You know, I was, I was embarrassed and confused, and my-my-my mind was r-r-racing a mile a minute...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The film cuts to a West Side street. It's an overcast day. Mickey, walking slowly along the sidewalk, passes several other pedestrians and numerous storefronts, including Klein's Pharmacy and a "Bar-B-Q" take out. Occasionally, he is obscured by a tree trunk on the opposite side of the street; a few taxis go by as he talks over the scene.</context>
      <utterance>...and I-I jus knew one thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The movie cuts to the exterior of the Metro movie theater, with its smoked glass entrance doors and its Art Deco feel. An old publicity photo hangs inside. Mickey's reflection is seen at the almost-transparent doors, as well as the reflection of the street and various cars whizzing by. His reflection walks towards the theater entrance; he continues his story.</context>
      <utterance>I...I-I-I-I had to get out of that house. I had to just get out in the fresh air and-and clear my head. And I remember very clearly. I walked the streets. I walked and I walked. I-I didn't know what was going through my mind. It all seemed so violent and un-unreal to me. And I wandered...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Mickey walks into the movie house. He is seen through the glass doors, which still reflect the street and traffic outside. He makes his way through the lobby into the actual theater.</context>
      <utterance>...for a long time on the Upper West Side, you know, an-and it must have been hours! You know, my, my feet hurt. My head was, was pounding, and, and I had to sit down. I went into a movie house. I-I didn't know what was playing or anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The film abruptly cuts to the theater's black-and-white screen, where the Marx Brothers, in Duck Soup, play the helmets of several soldiers standing in a line like a live xylophone. The sounds of the "xylophone" are heard as the movie cuts to the darkened theater, where Mickey slowly sits down in a balcony seat. The "xylophone" music stops and changes to "Hidee-hidee-hidee-hidee-hidee-hidee-ho" as sung by the Marx Brothers and ensemble in the movie. The singing continues faintly in the background as Mickey continues his tale:</context>
      <utterance>I just, I just needed a moment to gather my thoughts and, and be logical, and, and put the world back into rational perspective.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The film cuts back to the black-and-white movie screen as Mickey continues to talk. The Marx Brothers, as well as the hundred-odd other cast members in Duck Soup, are kneeling and bowing as they sing "Hidee-hidee-ho." They kick their heels up in the air. They sway back and forth, hands clasped, singing "Oh-h-h-h-h-h..."</context>
      <utterance>And I went upstairs to the balcony, and I sat down  and, you know, the movie was a-a-a film that I'd seen many times in my life since I was a kid, an-and I always u-uh, loved it. And, you know, I'm, I'm watching these people up on the screen, and I started getting hooked o-on the film, you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The movie cuts back to Mickey, sitting almost obscured in the dark theater. The Oh-h-h-h-h-h's coming from the offscreen movie are heard as he continues to speak.</context>
      <utterance>...And I started to feel how can you even think of killing yourself? I mean, isn't it so stupid? I mean, l-look at all the people up there on the screen. You know, they're real funny, and, and what if the worst is true?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>As Mickey talks, the film cuts back to the antics of the Marx Brothers on the black-and-white theater screen. The four brothers are now swaying and singing and strutting, their voices indistinct over Mickey's narration.</context>
      <utterance>What if there's no God, and you only go around once and that's it? Well, you know, don't you want to be part of the experience? You know, what the hell, it-i-it's not all a drag. And I'm thinking to myself, geez, I should stop ruining my life...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The film is back on Mickey's dark form in the audience.</context>
      <utterance>...searching for answers I'm never gonna get, and just enjoy it while it lasts. And...you know...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>As Mickey continues, the film cuts back to Duck Soup on the black-and-white screen. The Marx Brothers are sitting on a judge's bench, playing banjos and singing with the other cast members. They jump down from the bench, still singing. Their voices swell.</context>
      <utterance>...after, who knows? I mean, you know, maybe there is something. Nobody really knows. I know, I know "maybe" is a very slim reed to hang your whole life on, but that's the best we have. And...then, I started to sit back, and I actually began to enjoy myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARX BROTHERS &amp; COMPANY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh, don't you cry for me They'll be coming around the mountain..." The Marx Brothers kneel, strumming their banjos, and the movie cuts back to Central Park. The flashback is over. Mickey and Holly continue their stroll as "You Made Me Love You" begins to play in the background. They pass some people, a cluster of buildings that look like castles, and the Manhattan skyline as seen through the trees, as the camera moves back, farther and farther away from them, showing a beautiful Central Park, frozen in time.</context>
      <utterance>"Oh, Freedonia</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um...look, there's something I've, uh, that's been bothering me for a long time, and I just thought I'd just tell you what it was and just sort of clear the deck here, and  that's this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah? What?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That I've always regretted the way I behaved that evening we went out, and, uh...I've, I just thought I'd tell you that because I really made a fool out of myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, don't be silly! No! Don't be ridiculous.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was the, I was... You know, it was my fault. I--  Holly laughs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, so you want to go out to dinner again? I mean, is that, is that... Have, you have any interest in that, or...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. Sure, uh, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you? I mean, are you, are you, are you, are you free this evening?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stroll offscreen. "You Made Me Love You" grows louder and the film cuts to: One year later.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="40">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want ice! Who's got some--  Oh, there it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sounds of Thanksgiving guests in the other room are dimly heard; "You Made Me Love You" continues softly in the background. Mavis passes the table, licking some food off her hand. Hannah, in the background, is busy by the stove.</context>
      <utterance>It's on the table, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Mavis leaves the kitchen, Lee enters, carrying some empty glasses.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, where's Holly? She's late.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's really developed.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Hannah, did you read that last thing Holly wrote? It was great.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, she...she really writes good dialogue.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee walks off, drying her wet hands in the air. Hannah, in a silk dress, moves onscreen, going to the table and pouring herself a glass of wine as Norma enters the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I'll get some ice.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norma walks over to a glass-doored cabinet and takes out a bottle of gin.</context>
      <utterance>Hannah, can I tell everybody you're going to play Desdemona?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Mom, it's only television.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norma unscrews the liquor bottle and pours some into her empty glass as Hannah stops her mashing, reacting.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, but it's public television. And to me, Shakespeare doesn't get any greater than Othello. You with some big black stud! I love it!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Mom!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The movie leaves the kitchen and cuts to the doorway between the dining room and the living room. Upbeat jazz plays over the low din of the party. Two women stand by the partially set dining room table, chatting and arranging some plates, as Elliot strolls into view, sipping a drink. He passes the women and walks through the doorway into the living room, nodding hello to a guest who is walking the other way. He enters the living room, smiling. It is crowded with guests; Hannah's children play in their midst. One of Hannah's boys grabs Elliot's arm. They playfully "spar" for a moment before Elliot laughingly shakes him off, continuing on his way into a connecting room. He stops at the doorway, looking at the crowd. The camera shows his point of view: Guests stand in clusters, enjoying themselves; one woman chats with a little boy; another woman, carrying a drink, walks over to a group of other guests. The film then cuts back briefly to Elliot, holding his drink and looking straight ahead, as it shows his point of view once more. This time he sees a smiling Lee and Doug, talking animatedly; a few guests are seen in the background. Elliot's voice is heard over a close-up of the couple.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, honey!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Lee and Doug kiss each other. They continue talking.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Lee, you are something.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>As Lee takes a sip of her drink, the movie cuts back to Elliot, standing in the doorway and still staring straight ahead. The camera moves in closer to his face as he talks over the scene.</context>
      <utterance>You look very beautiful. Marriage agrees with you. Everything that happened between us  seems more and more hazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The film quickly cuts to a brief look at Lee and Doug, still talking animatedly and smiling. Lee gently pushes back Doug's hair.</context>
      <utterance>I acted like such a fool. I don't know what came over me. That complete conviction that I couldn't live without you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIOT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The camera moves back to Elliot.</context>
      <utterance>What did I put us both through? And Hannah...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(kissing)</context>
      <utterance>Hi! How are you!  Happy Thanksgiving!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't miss dinner, did I?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHILDREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The jazz ends as the record scratches and stops. Evan's rendition of "Isn't It Romantic" is heard on the piano as Holly, shrugging the strap of her pocketbook off her shoulder, walks towards the living room. She is stopped by three guests--two women, one of them wearing glasses, and a man--who are coming out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh? Hi, Marge.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE GUEST #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They kiss.</context>
      <utterance>You look lovely.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE GUEST #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, darling.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Happy Thanksgiving.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE GUEST #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good to see you. Same to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The movie cuts to Hannah, leaning contentedly against a doorway into the living room and listening to the offscreen Evan play the piano. Elliot, holding his drink, walks over to her. They look at each other for a beat; Elliot then hugs Hannah, pulling her towards him. She leans her head on his shoulder, fingering his jacket lapel. They look offscreen together, happily, intimately, at the offscreen guests, as the camera moves across the room, past a few guests, to reveal Evan sitting at the piano. Norma sits at his side, one arm resting on the piano. She holds a drink and looks off in the distance, mouthing the words to "Isn't It Romantic." The camera then moves to the doorway in the living room, where a man, holding a drink, enters and joins the happy crowd. Evan can be seen in the background, playing his song. A child plays near the coffee table. The camera continues to move past the doorway, past a huge grandfather clock, to a second doorway leading to the den. Here, more guests are gathered; a child sits in a small chair by the sofa. He sips a soda as female guest 2 enters the room and crouches down next to him, smiling. She waves to him. He waves back as the camera continues to move past the doorway to reveal Holly, standing in front of a hallway mirror, fixing her earrings. Mavis can be seen in the background, through the doorway into the dining room, lighting the candles on the table. She dims the lights, darkening the room and the hallway where Holly stands in a warm candlelit glow. Mavis leaves the dining room and passes Holly.</context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mavis walks off. Holly, reflected in the mirror, begins fluffing her hair as Mickey enters and wraps his arms around her from behind. The camera stays focused on the mirror; both Holly and Mickey are now seen in its reflection.</context>
      <utterance>It's beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now don't get nervous. It's just your husband.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.  How you doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When'd you get here?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a few minutes ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mickey continues to kiss Holly. She responds, sighing and closing her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Oh.  You look so beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I was talking with your father before...and I was telling him that  it's ironic. I-I used to always have Thanksgiving with Hannah...and I never thought  that I could love anybody else.  And here it is, years later and I'm married to you  and completely in love with you.  The heart is a very, very resilient little muscle.  It really is. I...  It'd made a great story, I think. A guy marries one sister...  doesn't work out...  many years later...  he winds up  married to the other sister. It's, you know, it's a...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tch.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mickey continues to kiss Holly's neck; he chuckles.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know how you're gonna top that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mickey?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmm, what?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The mirror shows Mickey pulling away slightly, reacting. They look at each other at arm's length, Holly grinning. Mickey in shock, then embrace and kiss passionately, tighter and tighter, as the music swells... And the credits appear, white on a black screen.</context>
      <utterance>I'm pregnant.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
