<movie id="264" title="Heathers">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A sudden off-screen bark from HEATHER MCNAMARA causes the pen to recklessly rocket across the written words.</context>
      <utterance>I said You're Beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, come</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From behind HEATHER MCNAMARA emerges a similarly trendily accessorized but noticeably more inhibited waif, HEATHER DUKE. She is clutching a tattered copy of "The Catcher in the Rye."</context>
      <utterance>God, I'm so sure. Don't blame me, blame Heather. She told me to haul your ass into the caf pronto. Back me up, Heather.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, she really wants to talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, I'm going, I'm going. Jesus...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pulling out a crumpled piece of yellow paper, HEATHER CHANDLER smiles. The content of what Heather says is consistently offensive but the tone in which she speaks is sexy, dangerous, and mysterious. She is a mythic bitch.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Heather.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Veronica. Finally. Got a paper of Kurt Kelly's. I need you to forge a hot and horny but realistically low-key note in Kurt's handwriting and we'll slip it into Martha Dumptruck's lunch tray.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit, Heather. I don't have anything against Martha Dunnstock.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have anything</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't think.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both HEATHER MCNAMARA and HEATHER DUKE bend over. HEATHER CHANDLER violently laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Splendid. I'll dictate. Veronica needs something to write on. Heather, bend over.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER MCNAMARA and HEATHER DUKE stand erect, embarrassed.</context>
      <utterance>How nice. Two assholes: no waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA scurries to the contorting HEATHER DUKE.</context>
      <utterance>Heather Duke, back down.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dear Martha, you're so sweet..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KURT and RAM raise their right arms and slam their fists together.</context>
      <utterance>It'd be so righteous to be in a Veronica Sawyer-Heather Chandler sandwich. Punch it in, Ram.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RAM makes a frantic spinning motion. EARL is bored.</context>
      <utterance>Hell yes. I wanna set a Heather on my Johnson and just start spinning her like a fucking pinwheel.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit. Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn right right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, aren't they fed yet? Do they even have Thanksgiving in Africa?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER CHANDLER draws up a clipboard.</context>
      <utterance>Oh sure, Pilgrims, Indians, tater tots; it's a real party continent.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sawyer. Guess what today is?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ouch....the lunchtime poll. So what's the question?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, so what's the question?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Such a pillowcase.</context>
      <utterance>God-damn Heather, you were with me in Study Hall when I thought of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA and HEATHER CHANDLER briskly bop away from the table as a wounded HEATHER DUKE retreats to The Catcher in the Rye.</context>
      <utterance>I forgot.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, this question wouldn't be that bizarro thing you were babbling about over the phone last......</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA shakes her head and looks off. She's suddenly captured by the sight of a JAMES DEANESQUE GUY sitting stark in a long, tan gunslinger coat, behind a</context>
      <utterance>Shut up, it is. I told Dennis if he gave me another topic that was political, I'd spew burrito chunks.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA crouches down, embarrassed and rueful.</context>
      <utterance>Betty Finn. Gosh.....</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm really sorry I couldn't make it to your birthday party last month.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA gently laughs at BETTY's innocent awe.</context>
      <utterance>That's okay. Your Mom said you had a big date. Heck, I'd probably skip my own birthday party for a date.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't say that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BETTY pulls from her purse a picture showing a YOUNG BETTY FINN AND VERONICA SAWYER, arm-in-arm, dressed in Halloween costumes: BETTY is an angel, VERONICA is a witch. VERONICA glows at the photo until HEATHER CHANDLER tows VERONICA away causing the picture to fall face up on the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Oh Ronnie, you have to look at what I dug up the other day.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was talking with someone!</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Color me impressed. I thought you grew out of Betty Finn.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh great. Here comes Heather.</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY'S FRIEND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COURTNEY express elation in spite of yourself as HEATHER CHANDLER delicately takes a tot and turns around to face VERONICA. HEATHER CHANDLER inserts her finger in her mouth doing the "induce-vomiting" signal before devouring the tot and turning back around.</context>
      <utterance>Hi Courtney. Love your blouse. Ooh, let me snare a tater.</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER CHANDLER raises her clipboard. VERONICA closes her eyes and shakes her head with a half-smile.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks. I just got it last night at the Limited. Totally blew my allowance.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A stunned tableau; until Country Club Kid KEITH speaks.</context>
      <utterance>That's pretty very. Now check this out. You win five million dollars from Publishers Clearing House, but on the same day Ed McMahon gives you the check, aliens land on earth and say they're going to blow up the world in two days. What would you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>KEITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's easy. I'd just slide that wad over to my father. He's like one of the top brokers in the</utterance>
   <speaker>KEITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, in two days, my dad could double my money. Triple it.</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I got that money, I'd give it all to the poor. Every cent.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're beautiful.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dennis, my man, run over to Mickey D.'s and get me a Big Mac and some fries.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But that's the Famine Fund money.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, even Bob Geldof's got to eat. If it makes you feel better, bag the fries, and nab yourself an Apple Pie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're going to openly be a bitch....</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, it's just why can't we talk to different kinds of people?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She points to a table of unfashionably dressed and coiffed students. Some wear glasses, some wear braces, some wear both.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck me gently with a chainsaw. Do I look like Mother Theresa? If I did, I probably wouldn't mind talking to the Geek Squad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>RODNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you see that? Heather Number One looked right at us.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG CYNIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It must be love.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAFETERIA THOROUGHFARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>VERONICA confronts HEATHER CHANDLER.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't it bother you that everyone in the school thinks you're a pirahna?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like I give a shit. They all want me, as a friend or a fuck. I'm worshipped at Westerburg and I'm only a Junior.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretend you're a missionary saving a colony of cootie victims.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever. I don't believe this. We're going to a party at Remington University tonight and we're brushing up our conversation skills with the scum of the school.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>GEEK WITH BRACES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No seriously, I'd probably go to the Pyrimads. With a girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEEK WITH GLASSES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>K-Mart?</context>
      <utterance>Where you going to get a girl, stud?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG CYNIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Taking a hooker to the Pyramids on the last day of Mankind. You sentimental old fart.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRACES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Geez, forget it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about you Rodney?</utterance>
   <speaker>RODNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>New haircut. New house. New home.</context>
      <utterance>I told you she knew my name.  I'd change my life. New clothes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA tugs HEATHER CHANDLER away from the table.</context>
      <utterance>How sad! Blowing all your cash on two days of trying to be hip.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA again catches sight of the JAMES DEANESQUE GUY. He wraps his fingers around an egg and unfolds them back. The egg is gone. He smiles. VERONICA smiles back. Her trance is broken by a boisterous HEATHER MCNAMARA and HEATHER DUKE who careen into the two pollsters.</context>
      <utterance>If you're going to openly be a bitch....</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, scan on Martha Dumptruck.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER CHANDLER floats off. A disturbed VERONICA takes a moment to react.</context>
      <utterance>This is the part I hate. The waiting. I'd say we're like twenty minutes from major humiliation. Come on, Veronica.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA follows the leader. She calls out.</context>
      <utterance>Veronica?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do I get out of being friends with losers. I give them a piece of a winner and they stain me with loserness.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKING LOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heavy Metaler MATT grins.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You get five million dollars but some Martians are going to zap you in two days. You hear that, Clyde? That's got to be the most spooky-ass question I've ever heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY FINN'S TABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>BETTY FINN daintily peeps up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY FINN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We could invite</context>
      <utterance>I think we should use the money for an End-of-the-world get-together.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd pay Madonna one million dollars to ride my face like the Kentucky Derby. She should be paying me, though.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FEMALE STONER IN ARMY JACKET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIBRARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ALL-OUT NERD lashes out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL-OUT NERD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is important. With taxes, I'd be only getting 3.5 million and....</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKING LOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heavy Metaler CLYDE turns from his friend MATT.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two Heavy Metal lovers, JACKIE and STEVE, intertwined against the windshield blankly respond.</context>
      <utterance>If you want a good way to go out before the aliens land, get a lion from the zoo. Put a remote control bomb up its butt. When the lion starts tearing you up, press the bomb button. You and the lion die like as one.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE AND STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cool.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just imagine somebody like your quasi-fat, goody-good friend Betty Finn doing a Crest commercial. No one would buy Crest.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't tell me. Crest would be stained with loserness.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER MCNAMARA and HEATHER DUKE burst back between them.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, and who wants that on their teeth?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God, here we go...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER CHANDLER wings a twenty dollar bill into the cashbox.</context>
      <utterance>A dime increases the time! A buck brings good luck! Hi Veronica. A five keeps the neighborhood alive! A ten and you die without sen!</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanted to become a member of the most powerful clique in the school. If I wasn't already the head of it, I'd want the same thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry? What are you oozing about?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That episode with the note back there was for all of us to enjoy, but you're determined to ruin my day.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We made a girl want to consider suicide. What a scream. What a jest.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on you jerk. You know you used to have a sense of humor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ku-urt, let's pa-arty.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER DUKE's gentle off-screen voice slices in.</context>
      <utterance>Ku-urt, I ne-ed an orgasm.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Veronica, could you come back here?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER AND HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gross!</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA reveals her right index finger is cut noticeably short, then walks over to the stalls.</context>
      <utterance>A true friend's work is never done.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grow up, Heather. Bulimia's so '86.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Color me nauseous.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you should see a doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on Heather. We want another look at today's lunch.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Geez, don't listen to them.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did she have the pie or the ice cream for dessert?  And the answer</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>of the way or he's going to get spewed. HEATHER DUKE puts down her book and opens her mouth. VERONICA sticks her finger in.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you better move Holden out</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God Veronica, drool much? His name's Jason Dean. He's in my American History.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As VERONICA walks off, HEATHER MCNAMARA oinks out some amusing sexual noises.</context>
      <utterance>Give me the clipboard.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAFETERIA/JASON DEAN'S TABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>VERONICA saunters to JASON DEAN.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello Jason Dean.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Greetings and salutations. Call me J.D. Are you a Heather?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, a Veronica. Sawyer. This may seem like a stupid question....</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are no stupid questions.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you inherit five million dollars the same day aliens tell the earth they're blowing us up in two days, what would you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the stupidest question I've ever heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCKS' TABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The JOCKS witness VERONICA and J.D.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who does that new kid think he is with that coat? Bo Diddley?</utterance>
   <speaker>KURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Veronica is into his act. No doubt.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's kick his ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>KURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit, we're seniors, Ram. Too old for that crap. Let's give him a scare though.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.'S TABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An intrigued J.D. laconically answers</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER CHANDLER breaks VERONICA's daze of admiration.</context>
      <utterance>How very.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on. VERONICA  Later.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KURT and RAM move into the exiting VERONICA's place. RAM sticks his finger through a piece of pie on J.D.'s plate.</context>
      <utterance>Definitely.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You going to eat this?</utterance>
   <speaker>KURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did your</utterance>
   <speaker>KURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Ram, doesn't this cafeteria have a No Fags Allowed Rule?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It seems to have an open door policy for assholes though, doesn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you say dickweed?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. gracefully stands, reaches into his coat, and pulls out a a .357 Magnum. He fires twice at the viewer.</context>
      <utterance>I'll repeat myself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="35">
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, they won't expell him. They'll just suspend him for a week or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He used a real gun. They should throw his ass in jail.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER CHANDLER knocks her red ball into HEATHER DUKE'S green one.</context>
      <utterance>No way. He used blanks. All J.D. really did was ruin two pairs of pants...Maybe not even that...  Can you bleach out urine stains?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>J.D.? You seem pretty amused. I thought you were giving up on high school guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never say never.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Girls look to the doelike HEATHER DUKE with incredulous faces.</context>
      <utterance>What are you going to do, Heather? Take the two shots or send me out?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you have a brain tumor for breakfast? First you ask if you can be red, knowing that I'm</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn. It's your turn Heather.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER MCNAMARA hits her ball through a wicket and squeals.</context>
      <utterance>No, it's Heather's turn.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyway, I can say never to high school. I've got David.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>King David.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER MCNAMARA misses her next shot.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe when you hit maturity you'll understand the diff between a Remington University man like David and a Westerburg boy like Ram "Wham-bam- thank-you-maam" Sweeney.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER DUKE tries to navigate a shot from the flower bed.</context>
      <utterance>Ram's sweet. Yo Heather, you're up.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way, no day!</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As her friends howl, HEATHER DUKE slams her ball out of the flower bed. The ball bounces off a tree and amazingly goes through a wicket. HEATHER DUKE squeals in delight.</context>
      <utterance>Give it up girl!</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So tonight's the night. Are you two excited?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm giving Veronica her shot. Her first Remington Party. Blow it tonight girl and it's keggers with kids all next year.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crap. So who's this Brad guy I've been set up with? Witty and urbane pre-lawyer or albino accountant?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER CHANDLER again hits her ball into HEATHER DUKE'S.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. David says he's very so he's very.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER CHANDLER slams HEATHER DUKE's ball back into the flower bed. VERONICA'S MOM calls out the back screen door.</context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heather, your Mother's here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the HEATHERS head into the house, VERONICA picks up HEATHER DUKE'S ball and exuberantly throws it back toward the wickets. Veronica's MOM, carrying a tray of pate, and DAD, carrying a Robert Ludlum book, place themselves around a patio table.</context>
      <utterance>Come on whoever wants a ride.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take a break Veronica, sit down.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA sinks into the empty middle deck chair.</context>
      <utterance>All right.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what was the first week of Spring Vacation withdrawl like?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, it was okay, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey kid, isn't the prom coming up?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any contestants worth mentioning?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because you're an idiot.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DAD immediately returns to reading with a wide grin.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah, that's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You two....</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great pate, but I'm going to have to motor if I want to be ready for the party tonight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You going to pull a Big Gulp with that?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, but if you're nice I'll let you buy me a Slurpee. You know your 7-11speak pretty well.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been moved around all my life; Dallas, Baton Rouge, Vegas, Sherwood Ohio, there's always a 7-11. Any town, any time, I can pop a Ham and Cheese in the microwave and feast on a Big Wheel. Keeps me sane.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? That thing in the caf today was pretty severe.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The extreme always makes an impression, but you're right, it was severe. Did you say a Cherry or Coke Slurpee?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA smiles at her Coolness. J.D. returns the smile.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't. Cherry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER CHANDLER sounds her car horn with a grimace. VERONICA glares at her then turns back to J.D.</context>
      <utterance>Great bike.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a humble perk from my Dad's Construction company or should I say Deconstruction company?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Should you?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father seems to enjoy tearing things down more than putting things up. Seen the commerical? "Bringing every State to a Higher State."</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Time out....Jason Dean. Your Pop's Fred Dean Construction. Must be rough. Moving place to place.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody's life's got static. Is your life perfect?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA grows serious as the car horn sounds again.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, I'm on my way to a party at Remington University.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not perfect. I don't really like my friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't really like your friends either.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's like they're just people I work with and our job is being popular and shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The car horn blares again.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's time for a vacation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Throw your coats on the bed, girls.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHINING STUDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That exam was so bogus.</utterance>
   <speaker>COED ONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh I</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excellent. Did you girls bring your partying slippers?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, let's party.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they head out the door, BRAD whispers something in BRAD'S FRIEND's ear causing the pair to snarl off a laugh.</context>
      <utterance>She loves to party.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>VERONICA frenziedly scribbles, trying to get her pen to write. She throws the pen across the room and pulls out another.</context>
      <utterance>Dear Diary, I want to kill and you have to believe.....damn pen!</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to believe it's for more than selfish reasons. More than a spoke in my menstrual cycle. You have to believe me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BRAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, are you a cheerleader?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're pretty enough to be one.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gee, thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They uncomfortably sip their beers. A deadly pause ensues.</context>
      <utterance>It's so great to be able to talk to a girl and not have to ask "What's your major?" I hate that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So when you go to college, what kind of subjects do you think you'll study?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on David, let's go back to the party.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DAVID pushes HEATHER CHANDLER's head down.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, we will. You're just so hot tonight. I can't control myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>DORM HALLWAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>BRAD has given up on conversation.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A BIG AMIABLE STUDENT approaches before VERONICA can show disgust.</context>
      <utterance>So what do you say we head up to my room and have a real party. I've got the best Windham Hill C.D. collection in the dorm.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG AMIABLE STUDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brad-man, Robinson's looking for you. He says he owes you for blow and he just got some product himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're kidding. That pecker actually scored something on his own?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG AMIABLE STUDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's in Sheila's room, guy. Party up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excellent. Veronica, ever do</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Phil Collins? Are you sure he isn't drinking and driving?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeez, right, then why don't I do drugs?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a wink, BRAD squirms off. VERONICA dashes into the room with the coats.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, don't run away now.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA'S BEDROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>VERONICA rampages through her diary.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>J.F.K. the cat jumps onto the Diary.</context>
      <utterance>Seventeen is the last year Mom buys the Twinkies. When you make the jump from working weekends at Pizza Hut to thirty years at I.B.M., you lose something. Not innocence--power.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BRAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's my little cheerleader? Now I know everyone at your high school isn't so uptight, come</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BRAD plops down onto the bed of coats and begins bouncing.</context>
      <utterance>Let's do it on the coats. It'll be excellent.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gee Blank, I had a nice....</context>
      <utterance>I have a little prepared speech I give when my suitor wants more than I'd like to give him....</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I just wanna get laid.</context>
      <utterance>Save the speeches for Malcom X.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA yanks up her coat from beneath BRAD on the bed causing him to slide off onto the floor.</context>
      <utterance>You don't deserve my fucking speech!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your damage? Brad says you're being a real cooze.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heather, I feel awful, like I'm going to throw up. Can we jam, please?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA'S eyes fall shut in a near-faint. She flings herself down off-screen with some ugly retching sounds.</context>
      <utterance>No. Hell no.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You stupid cunt!</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The flickering flames cast HEATHER CHANDLER in a demonic light.</context>
      <utterance>You goddamn bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were nothing before you met me! You were playing Barbies with Betty Finn! You were a Brownie, you were a Bluebird, you were a Girl Scout Cookie! I got you into a Remington Party! What's my thanks? It's on the hallway carpet. I get paid in puke!</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lick it up, baby. Lick. It. Up.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monday morning, you're history. I'll tell everyone about tonight. Transfer to Washington. Transfer to Jefferson. No one at Westerburg's going to let you play their reindeer games.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dreadful etiquette. I apologize.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>S'okay....</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA is simultaneously dismayed and exhilarated. She seems ready to burst out all her anxieties but instead....</context>
      <utterance>I saw the croquet set-up in the back. Up for a match?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. But I'm Blue.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Feminine socks and masculine socks lay crumpled by the next wicket.</context>
      <utterance>Goddamn, no wonder you looked so mangled when I came through the window.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>As VERONICA quiveringly pauses, a stylish blouse and a rugged shirt are revealed mingling by another wicket.</context>
      <utterance>I've always treated Heather's teen queen power plays as bullshit.....</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The viewer's viewpoint moves to a dress and a pair of jeans resting side by side at another wicket.</context>
      <utterance>But I'm really scared. Who am I going to eat lunch with on Monday? I sound like an Afterschool Special.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was my first game of Strip Croquet, you know. I thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>VERONICA'S blue mallet has been staked into the ground. Her panties hang on one end, J.D.'s underwear hangs on the other.</context>
      <utterance>You're welcome. It's a lot more interesting than just flinging off your clothes and boning away on the neighbor's swing set.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>VERONICA and J.D. are finally revealed, entangled in an artful pose upon J.D.'s gunslinger coat. They warmly kiss. VERONICA breaks off to uneasily giggle.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't know. There's something to be said for...Ouch!</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. gently bites in to VERONICA's neck. VERONICA grooves on it, closing her eyes tightly.</context>
      <utterance>What a night.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA slides her head down against J.D.'s chest and gracefully rests on his lap. Gently fighting slumber, she murmurs up to J.D., who showers her face with slow kisses.</context>
      <utterance>What a life. I almost moved into high school out of sixth grade because I was some genius. We all decided to chuck the idea because I'd have trouble making friends, blah-blah-blah.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now blah-blah-blah is all I do. I use my grand I.Q. to figure out what gloss to wear and how to hit three keggers before curfew. Some genius.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heather Chandler is one bitch that deserves to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Killing her won't solve anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A well-timed lightning bolt through her window and Monday morning, all the other heathers, shit, everybody would be cast fucking adrift.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well then, I'll pray for rain.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We murdered our baby.</context>
      <utterance>See the condoms in the grass over there. We killed tonight, Veronica.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, it was good for me too, Sparky.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just saying it's not hard to end a life.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They laugh. VERONICA maneuvers herself into a sitting position.</context>
      <utterance>There's a big difference between the most popular girl in the school and dead sperm.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess I don't know what the hell I'm talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know exactly what the hell you're talking about and you're right, you don't know what the hell you're talking about. Let's just grow up, be adults, and die.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good plan.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But before that, I'd like to see Heather Chandler puke her guts out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MRS. CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are leaving soon for your grandmother's. If you care to join us...</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bag that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the door closes, HEATHER CHANDLER raises her arm and gives her departed Mother "the finger."</context>
      <utterance>Is that a "No" in your lingo?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lingo this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trust me. She skips the Saturday morning trip to Grandma's even when she's not hungover.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA opens the refrigerator. J.D. opens the cupboard beneath the sink.</context>
      <utterance>Then let's just concoct ourselves a little hangover cure that'll induce her to spew red, white, and blue.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. holds up a bottle of Pine-Sol.</context>
      <utterance>What about orange juice and milk? What's the upchuck factor on that?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a Pine-Sol man, myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA and J.D. make queasy eye-contact. VERONICA descends back into the refrigerator with some worked-up enthusiasm as J.D. suavely pours bits of various toxic containers (detergent, scouring powder) into a glass beer mug.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be a dick. That stuff'll kill her.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>O-kay. We'll cook up some soup and put it in a Coke. Sick, eh? Now should it be Chicken-Noodle or Bean-with-Bacon?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. raises the glass filled with what is now a strange blue liquid. VERONICA stares at the glass, scared by her own thoughts.</context>
      <utterance>Man Veronica, pull the plug on that shit. I say we go with Big Blue.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. sheepishly pulls down an identical ceramic cup. VERONICA tears it from him and pours some milk and then some orange juice into the cup.</context>
      <utterance>Just give me a cup, jerk.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Milk and orange juice. Hmmmm. Maybe we could cough a phlegm globber in it or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both start coughing harshly.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, great.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No luck? Well, milk and orange juice'll do quite nicely. Quite nicely.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chick-en.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. turns on his heel and slinks away. VERONICA glares down at the mess of toxic containers. With both arms, VERONICA clumps the toxic containers together and drops beneath the sink to put them away. J.D. swaggers back into the kitchen as VERONICA bobs back into view.</context>
      <utterance>You're not funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. kisses the back of her neck. VERONICA closes her eyes with a grudging smile.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA dreamily reaches out to one of the two ceramic cups. Not the one with milk and orange juice in it.</context>
      <utterance>Bonehead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Like a lion, HEATHER CHANDLER rouses herself up.</context>
      <utterance>Morning, Heather.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Veronica. And Jesse James. Quelle surprise. Hear about Veronica's affection for regurgitation?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We both said a lot of things we didn't mean, last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did we? How the hell'd you get in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. holds out the ceramic cup. HEATHER CHANDLER snorts.</context>
      <utterance>Veronica knew you'd have a hangover. So I whipped this up. Family recipe.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you put a phlegm globber in it or something? I'm not drinking that piss.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew this stuff would be too intense.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Intense? Grow up. You think I'll drink it just because you call me</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER CHANDLER'S eyes slam shut and her limp body crashes through the glass coffee table. VERONICA and J.D. freeze.</context>
      <utterance>Corn nuts!</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something tells me you picked up the wrong cup.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No shit, sherlock. I can't believe it. I just killed my best friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And your worst enemy.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA staggers to a desk. J.D. laughs out of shock.</context>
      <utterance>Same difference. Oh jesus, I'm gonna...</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>"Fuck it if she can't take a joke, Sarge."</context>
      <utterance>What are we going to tell the cops?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop kidding around. I'm going to have to send my S.A.T. scores to San Quentin instead of Stanford.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just a little freaked, all right?  You got what you wanted, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA stares off as J.D. paces like a caged animal. He scopes onto the rubble of the shattered coffee table and sees Cliff Notes for</context>
      <utterance>It's one thing to want somebody out of your life. It's another thing to serve them a wake-up cup of Drano.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like a suicide thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Adolescence is a period of life fraught with anxiety and confusion.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can do Heather's handwriting as well as my own. VERONICA takes some stationery from the desk and begins writing, calling out her words.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"You might think what I've done is shocking..."</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"To me though, suicide is the natural answer to the myriad of problems life has given me."</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's good, but Heather would never use the word "myriad."</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the last thing she'll ever write. She'll want to cash in on as many fifty-cent words as poss.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She missed "myriad" on a vocab test two weeks ago, all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That only proves my point more. The word is a badge for her failures at school.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're probably right..."People think just because you're beautiful and popular, life is easy and fun. Nobody understood I had feelings too."</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"I die knowing no one knew the real me."</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA's smile dies as she looks to HEATHER CHANDLER'S corpse.</context>
      <utterance>That's good. Have you done this before?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL GOWAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any other Principal would take the same position. Keep things business as usual.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUNSELOR HYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heather Chandler's not your everyday suicide. She was</utterance>
   <speaker>KEVIN STAPLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>These are troubled times for the young.</context>
      <utterance>The parents will be sympathetic, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. POPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I must say I was impressed to see that she made proper use of the word "myriad" in her suicide note after brutalizing it in a vocabulary test.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A collective sigh goes across the room.</context>
      <utterance>I find it profoundly disturbing that we are told of a tragic destruction of youth and all we can talk about is adequate mourning times and misused vocabulary words.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL GOWAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Christ.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The school, meaning both students and teachers, must revel in this revealing moment. I suggest we get everyone into the cafeteria and just talk. And feel. Together.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL GOWAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Ms. Fleming. Call me when the shuttle lands...Now is this Heather the cheerleader?</utterance>
   <speaker>COUNSELOR HYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That would be Heather Mcnamara.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL GOWAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn. I'd be willing to go half a day for a cheerleader.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEVIN STAPLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's just pack it in an hour early.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL GOWAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Done. I hate Mondays.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PAULINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said a circle you imbeciles! Forget it! Just sit down. I'm just so</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll pass the suicide note around the room so you can feel its tragic beauty for yourself. Let us share together the feelings the suicide has spurred in us all. Who wants to begin?</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE STUDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard it was really gnarly. She drank Liquid Plumber and Comet and stuff then she smashed....</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, now, we're not here to rehash the coroner's report. Let's talk</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heather and I used to go together, but she said I was boring. I realize now I wasn't really boring. She was just dissatisfied with her life.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA lets out a laugh that she disguises as a sob by putting her hands over her face.</context>
      <utterance>That's very good Peter.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dear Veronica, Heather was your soulmate.....Share.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The class stares to VERONICA as the suicide note is passed to her. She acknowledges it in horror, passes it on, then continues, realizing her ability to create truths for a captive audience.</context>
      <utterance>Heather was cool, but cruel. The good looks and bad manners gave her power, but it could not give her happiness.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PAULINE cries. The PUPILS applaud. VERONICA queasily smiles.</context>
      <utterance>She realized the only way she could be happy was to give up her power and the only way she could do that was death.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God, it's so unfair. It's just so</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watch it, Heather. You could actually be digesting food.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, where's your urge to purge?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER MCNAMARA pulls a Swatch from one of the lockers.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER MCNAMARA tosses the watch to a spooked VERONICA who stands up and solemnly puts it on. The FEMALE STONER IN ARMY JACKET stops next to their bench.</context>
      <utterance>Look, heather left behind one of her Swatches. She'd want you to have it, Veronica. She always said you couldn't accessorize for shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE STONER IN ARMY JACKET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER DUKE bobs up from the world's largest sno-cone.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry about your friend. I thought she was your usual airhead bitch. Guess I was wrong. Lot of us were.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA zombiesquely moves into the shower area.</context>
      <utterance>What a waste.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh the Humanity.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Veronica, what are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SQUEALING GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SQUEALING GIRL runs into the shower fully clothed. TWO GIGGLING GIRLS follow suit. The HEATHERS look to each other, laugh, and run in.</context>
      <utterance>Everyone in the shower!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I deliver or do I deliver?</utterance>
   <speaker>RODNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hurry up, we're going to get caught.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mellow out Geek. Man, I never should have brought you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's see some pus</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>THE GIRLS' COACH'S LOCKER ROOM OFFICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cautiously quiet pandemonium.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does this have something to do with menstrual cramps and shit?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck?</utterance>
   <speaker>RODNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're on Candid Camera, dudes. I can feel it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you deliver or do you deliver?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was seriously warped, Veronica.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the distance, a T.V. CAMERA CREW is interviewing STUDENTS. HEATHER DUKE dashes toward them. HEATHER MCNAMARA freezes.</context>
      <utterance>T.V. cameras!</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER MCNAMARA moans, vibrates, then suddenly races toward the cameras. VERONICA looks down at the soaked, stopped Swatch on her arm. She takes it off and drops it in a nearby trashcan.</context>
      <utterance>Oh God, Veronica. My hair! My clothes!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode>T.V.</mode>
      <context>The image of HEATHER MCNAMARA sitting in the grass talking into a microphone supersedes HEATHER DUKE's.</context>
      <utterance>I choose to remember the good times. Like when we got our ears pierced at the mall.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode>T.V.</mode>
      <context>The image of PETER DAWSON sitting on a rock comes on next.</context>
      <utterance>I can still hear those late night talks on the phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode>T.V.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The day I won her that stuffed rhino at the 4-H Fair, she said to me....</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>VERONICA and J.D. are seen to be crashed on a couch. J.D. pushes a button on the remote control, cutting the sound.</context>
      <utterance>You're an asshole! Mute him!</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mute!</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The silent image of HEATHER DUKE on a staircase talking into a microphone is on the screen.</context>
      <utterance>Next channel, darling.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Country Club Courtney appears wearing a T-shirt reading BIGFUN. VERONICA takes the remote and turns the sound on.</context>
      <utterance>Heather, how many networks did you run to!</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I have to hear this.</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode>T.V.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In my heart, Heather's still alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about? She hated you! You hated her!  What are you smiling at?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heather Chandler is more popular than ever now.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. suddenly looks away from VERONICA with a mischievous half-smile. He inexplicably calls out.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Scary stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D.'s father FRED DEAN, stands before them, handsome and threatening in a shirt and tie. He is rather malevolently holding a rowing machine.</context>
      <utterance>Why son, I didn't hear you come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRED DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FRED DEAN slams down his rowing machine and straddles it before answering his own question. He rows as he speaks.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Dad, how was work today?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was the one with the wheat right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG BUD DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. turns to VERONICA with a bemused smile.</context>
      <utterance>The Save the Memorial Oak Tree Society. Showed those fucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirty Fourth of July fireworks attached to the trunk. Arraigned but Acquitted.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRED DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fucking Kansas. Gosh Pop, I almost forgot to introduce my girlfriend.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Veronica, Dad. Dad, Veronica.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA, with a forced smile, reaches to shaked FRED's hand. FRED DEAN extends his hand but makes no effort to stop rowing hence his hand pulls away from VERONICA. Pop and son laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jason, why don't you ask your little friend to stay for dinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My Mom's making my favorite meal tonight. Spaghetti. Lots of oregano.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice. The last time I saw my Mom, she was waving out the window of a library in Texas. Right,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA walks into view and sits down.</context>
      <utterance>Take a break Veronica, sit down.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what was the first day after Heather's suicide like?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, it was okay, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Terrible thing. So will we get to meet this dark horse prom contender?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because you're an idiot.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DAD immediately takes another drag with a wide grin.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah, that's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You two....</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Greate pate, but I'm going to have to motor if I want to be ready for the funeral tomorrow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FATHER RIPPER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The bald FATHER FAUST finally comes into view.</context>
      <utterance>I blame not Heather but rather a society that tells its youth that the answers are on the MTV video games. We must pray the other teenagers of Sherwood, Ohio, know the name of that "righteous dude" who can solve their problems....</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER RIPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Jesus Christ and he's in the book.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>BETTY FINN makes the sign of the cross, rises, and exits. HEATHER MCNAMARA takes her place on the kneeling podium.</context>
      <utterance>May Heather Chandler rest in peace even though she committed suicide. For-the-kingdom-the-power-and-the- glory-are-yours-now-and-forever-Amen.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>HEATHER MCNAMARA exits and PETER DAWSON moves in her place.</context>
      <utterance>Oh God, this is a tragic thing and sometimes I have a hard time dealing with it and stuff. Please send Heather to heaven and all that. Thanks. I mean, Amen.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>PETER flees and RAM uncomfortably takes his place.</context>
      <utterance>Dear God, make sure this never happens to me. I do not think I could handle suicide and that's the God's honest truth. Pardon the pun. Fast-early-acceptance- into-an-Ivy-League-school-and- please-let-it-be-Harvard. Amen.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>RAM clumsily exits. HEATHER DUKE solemnly kneels in his place.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus God in heaven, uh, why did you kill such hot snatch. That's a joke, man. People are so serious.  Hail Mary, who aren't in heaven, pray for us sinners....so we don't get caught. Another joke, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>HEATHER DUKE departs and VERONICA kneels in her place.</context>
      <utterance>I prayed for the death of Heather Chandler many times and I felt bad every time I did, but I kept doing it anyway. Now I know you understood everything. Praise Jesus. Alleluia.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. I'm sorry. Technically I didn't kill Heather Chandler but hey, who am I trying to kid, right? I just want my high school to be a nice place. Amen. Did that sound bitchy?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Veronica. What are you doing tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mourning. Maybe watch some T.V. Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ram asked me out, but he wants to double with Kurt and Kurt doesn't have a date.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hea</utterance>
   <speaker>KURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We on tonight man?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still got to talk to Heather, dude. Weird funeral, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>KURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geeks RODNEY, FAT CYNIC, and BRACES thrust by KURT and RAM. BRACES obliviously steps on KURT's foot.</context>
      <utterance>Pretty weird.</utterance>
   <speaker>KURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That pudwapper just stepped on my foot.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's kick his ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>KURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cool off, we're seniors.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BRACES gives them "the finger".</context>
      <utterance>Goddamn Geek!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRACES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KURT and RAM turn to each other more amused than angered.</context>
      <utterance>Sit and spin.</utterance>
   <speaker>KURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The bolting Jocks effortlessly catch BRACES and put him into a hunched-over position. The other Geeks look on, ashamed.</context>
      <utterance>That little prick.</utterance>
   <speaker>KURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right you piece of shit fag, do you like to suck big dicks?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRACES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RAM pushes BRACES down harder.</context>
      <utterance>Cut it out!</utterance>
   <speaker>KURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say it man. Say I like to suck big dicks.</utterance>
   <speaker>RODNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. rides by on his motorcycle. He turns to watch KURT, wearing an overwhelmingly tinted motorcycle helmet that reads THE TRUE KILLER across the top. KURT is spooked.</context>
      <utterance>Leave him alone, Kurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say it!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRACES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Unamused, RAM throws BRACES to the ground. BRACES semi-cries.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay, you like to suck big dicks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRACES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like to suck big dicks. Mmm-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Moving into the background, BRACES wipes dirt and blood off his face as his friends glumly watch on.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, Ram's been so sweet lately, consoling me and stuff. It'll be really very. Promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it sleeping, dude?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think so, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>KURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then get over on my side. Oh shit, cowtipping is the fucking greatest.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KURT and RAM slam their knuckles and then lean against the COW, poised to shove. HEATHER MCNAMARA manages a smile but VERONICA glares it away.</context>
      <utterance>Punch it in!</utterance>
   <speaker>KURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Count of three, guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>KURT AND RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An O.S. Moo and the Jocks' laughter is heard as mud splashes against the mortified faces of VERONICA and HEATHER MCNAMARA.</context>
      <utterance>One. Two. Three!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>KURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"When I get that feeling, I need sexual healing....."</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA makes her way up a hill, pausing to compassionately stare at RAM on top of a dispirited HEATHER MCNAMARA. KURT's intoxicated brain has trouble dealing with the incline. Majestically, J.D. appears at the top of the hill. KURT squints up the hill and falls over backwards.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, right, asshole.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this shit?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm doing a favor for Heather. A double date. I tried to tell you at the funeral but you rode off.</utterance>
   <speaker>KURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Feel like making bah da dah bah da dah, feel like making love."</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA clumsily high heels it up the hill.</context>
      <utterance>Another fucking Heather.  I'm sorry. I'm feeling kind of superior tonight. Seven high schools in seven states and the only thing different was my locker combination. We've broke through the peer pressure cooker. So what if we had to kill Miss Popularity..</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what? Don't smile like that, Jesus!</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. solemnly reaches toward VERONICA. She, less solemn, takes his hand. Their bodies disappear over the hill.</context>
      <utterance>Our love is God. Let's get a Slurpee.</utterance>
   <speaker>KURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"And she's buying the stairway to heaven.."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not belittling the Famine Fund Peter, but we're talking teen suicide! Westerburg finally got one and I'm not going to blow it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA breezes in.</context>
      <utterance>Great. Heather gets the headline and I get crammed in by the Taco Bell coupon.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi Guys. I came to check on this week's lunchtime poll topic.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about it, Veronica, sit down. That funeral yesterday must have been really rough.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>YEARBOOK GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were, uh, wondering if maybe you had some poems or artwork that Heather did that we could put in the Heather Chandler yearbook spread?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The what?</utterance>
   <speaker>YEARBOOK GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take a look. We'll have a two page layout with her suicide note up here in the right hand corner.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Country Club COURTNEY and COURTNEY'S FRIEND come in giggling and whispering. Seeing VERONICA, they stop dead, then slide into chairs, laughing softly.</context>
      <utterance>It's more tasteful than it sounds.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. This thing leaves a bad taste in my mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COURTNEY and COURTNEY'S FRIEND explode in laughter.</context>
      <utterance>Like last night, Veronica?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry? I don't get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More laughter.</context>
      <utterance>You did last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY'S FRIEND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kurt told us of your little date.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. And? I left him drunk and flailing in cowshit.</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. He was really detailed.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up, Courtney.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't shut up. I'd like to know just what I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me show you that lunchtime poll topic, Veronica.</utterance>
   <speaker>HALLWAY OUTSIDE WORKSHOP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>PETER tells VERONICA.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Revealed to be lounging on her bed, J.D. laughs out loud. VERONICA throws a book at him.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Kurt? This is Veronica Sawyer. I didn't expect to be calling either. I guess my emotions took over. I was wondering if you wanted all those things you've been saying to really happen. It's always been a fantasy of mine to have two guys at once...... Sure, you can write Penthouse Forum.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right, tonight. In the woods behind the school. Don't forget Ram.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't get the point of me writing a suicide note when we'll just be shooting them with blanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get crucial. We won't be using blanks this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA drops her gun in revulsion and launches off her bed. With a patient smile, J.D. pulls her back down.</context>
      <utterance>You can't be serious? Hey listen, my Bonnie-and-Clyde days are over.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you take German?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. flicks open his gun and pulls a bullet from the chamber.</context>
      <utterance>French.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are Ich Luge bullets. My grandfather snared a shitload of them in W.W. Two. They're like tranquilizers only they break the surface of the skin, enough to cause blood, but not any real harm.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. nods then stands to pace the room, his mind whirring.</context>
      <utterance>So it looks like the person's been shot and killed when they're really just unconscious and bleeding.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA clumsily extracts the note from her purse. She also plucks out the crumpled yellow sample of Kurt's handwriting of the opening note-forge scene. She proudly displays both papers.</context>
      <utterance>We shoot Kurt and Ram. Make it look like they shot each other. By the time Kurt and Ram regain consciousness, they'll be the laughingstock's of the school. The note's the punchline. How'd it turn out?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First tell me this similarity is not incredible.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA pulls back the note and reads.</context>
      <utterance>Incredible similarity.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ram and I died the day we realized we could never reveal our forbidden love to an uncaring and ununderstanding world. The joy we shared in each other's arms was greater than any touchdown. Yet we were forced to live the lie of Sexist- Beer Guzzling-Jock-Asshole.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exquisite, but I don't think ununderstanding is a word.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't want to make them out to be too secretly eloquent. Why would the Germans invent a bullet that doesn't kill people? I mean it</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA swiftly picks up her gun and aims it at the lovable tabby entering the room. J.D. rips it away from her.</context>
      <utterance>Neat. Let's try it out on J.F.K.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't work on small animals!</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. lifts up a feminine shopping bag and gently dumps the contents on the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Uh well hey, let's take a look at the homosexual artifacts I dug up. Now, prepare to be a little disappointed.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've got a Playgirl, a candy dish, a Joan Crawford post card, and lipstick.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must have had fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. reaches in both his coat pockets and triumphantly raises out two bottles of Perrier water.</context>
      <utterance>You know it. Oh man, I almost forgot. The one perfecto thing I picked up...</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perrier water!</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh come</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. laughs then climbs onto VERONICA for a hugging kiss.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, you're so smart. How about a little heterosexuality before we go?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sex and Drugs and HBO is all I ever need! Whoa! Can you hear me! Hello Tokyo! I said Sex and Drugs and...</utterance>
   <speaker>KURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut the fuck up, all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KURT feebly slams knuckles with RAM.</context>
      <utterance>Lighten up, dude. In those woods is some of the finest pussy in the school and we don't even have to buy it a hamburger and a Diet Coke. Punch it in!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>KURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi Veronica.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RAM smacks his hands together.</context>
      <utterance>Hi Guys. Glad you could make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So do we just start fucking?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KURT steps into the scratched-in-the-dirt circle next to him. A confused RAM walks past VERONICA and steps into a circle at the opposite end of the foggy clearing.</context>
      <utterance>I've made a circle on each end of the clearing. Ram, you come over here.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guys pause, then slowly start taking off their clothes.</context>
      <utterance>When you get in the circle, strip.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about you?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was hoping you'd rip my clothes off me, sport.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KURT and RAM awkwardly stand at opposite ends in their undies.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Good idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RAM giggles in anticipation.</context>
      <utterance>Count of three, guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KURT finally cracks a smile.</context>
      <utterance>One.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. suddenly moves next to VERONICA holding a gun in his right hand and the feminine shopping bag in his left.</context>
      <utterance>Two.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. almost non-chalantly shoots RAM in the forehead. VERONICA rips out her gun and swings it toward KURT. Using both hands, she fires, but misses completely. KURT runs away onto the path. VERONICA throws down her gun with a smile.</context>
      <utterance>Three.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. races to VERONICA in a white sweat.</context>
      <utterance>Shucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you miss him completely?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but don't worry, it was worth it just to see the look on....</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA's laughter cuts off like a faucet. Suddenly trembling and confused, she watches J.D. bolt into the woods.</context>
      <utterance>Don't move! I'll get him back!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MILNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard it that time! McCORD Wha?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two officer explode out of the car.</context>
      <utterance>Another gunshot! From the woods! McCORD Shit, let's roll.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kurt doesn't look too good.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A quivering VERONICA puts the gun in KURT's left hand.</context>
      <utterance>Remember he's left-handed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILNER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>J.D.'s head snaps forward. He yanks up VERONICA. They both run into the woods behind RAM's body as the two Cops charge into the clearing, guns raised. Seeing the Jocks, they stop. McCORD Mother of Shit!</context>
      <utterance>Keep going until you hit the clearing!</utterance>
   <speaker>MILNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MILNER looks toward where VERONICA and J.D. ran out.</context>
      <utterance>Call in!</utterance>
   <speaker>MILNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MILNER runs off as McCORD shouts into a walkie-talkie. He is holding the pulse of KURT KELLY. McCORD This is Officer McCord and I've got two dead bodies in the woods behind Westerburg High. Oh my God, one of them's Kurt Kelly, the quarterback.</context>
      <utterance>I heard something out there. I'm checking it out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>THE CLEARING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>MILNER runs back into the clearing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the deal? McCORD Suicide. Double Suicide. They shot each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Kurt Kelly! McCORD Yeah, and the linebacker, Ram Sweeney.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McCORD reaches in the feminine shopping bag and pulls out the bottles of Perrier water.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God, suicide? Why? McCORD Does this answer your question?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh man, they were</utterance>
   <speaker>MILNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a second. How did they shoot each other if we heard two separate sets of gunshots? McCORD Shit, I always hear gunshots when I'm high. Life is one crazy bitch. Don't try to analyze it. The quarterback buggering the linebacker. What a waste.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh the humanity.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KEVIN STAPLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After every touchdown or whatever, they give each other a little slap on the bottom. It seems innocent...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULINE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The elderly MRS. POPE shakes her head at the suicide note.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. POPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at this. "Ununderstanding."</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you shut up! We were in a similar position Monday and I thoughtfully suggested that we get the students together for an unadulterated emotional outpouring. You took the suggestion as an opportunity to play yet another round of "Let's laugh at the Hippie."</utterance>
   <speaker>COUNSELOR HYDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PRINCIPAL GOWAN hoarsely breaks in.</context>
      <utterance>Pauline, if you want a tryout for the school play....</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL GOWAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up, Paul. I've seen a lot of bullshit--angel dust, switchblades, sexually perverse photography exhibits involving tennis racquets, but this suicide thing....I guess it's all on Pauline's wavelength. We're just going to write off today, and Friday she can do her little little love-in or whatever. Whatever.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We killed them, didn't we?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA tugs out the car lighter and savagely brands the palm of her hand. J.D. hurdles into the front seat and bats the lighter away. He lights a cigarette off the scorched flesh of VERONICA's hand as she wails away.</context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. drags on his cigarette. School buses are pulling in outside of the parking lot, in front of the school.</context>
      <utterance>Ich Luge bullets! I'm an idiot!</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You believed it because you wanted to believe it. Your true feelings were too gross and icky for you to face.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did not want them</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did not.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did to.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. launches into a rapid-fire rendition of "did-to's". VERONICA responds by holding her hands over her ears and singing "We're Off to See the Wizard." J.D.'s "did-to's" get louder causing VERONICA to bang on the horn.</context>
      <utterance>Did not.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, young love. The SQUEALING GIRL bounds up to the Heathers.</utterance>
   <speaker>SQUEELING GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you hear? School's cancelled today because Kurt and Ram killed themselves in a repressed homosexual suicide pact.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Football season's over, Veronica. Kurt and Ram had nothing to offer the school but date-rapes and A.I.D.S. jokes.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STUDENTS head back to their cars and the Buses pull back out.</context>
      <utterance>Sure. Can we make an ice run before the funeral?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MR. KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In dark sunglasses, VERONICA wearily leans over to J.D.</context>
      <utterance>If there's any way you can hear me, Kurt buddy, I don't care that you really were some pansy. You're my flesh-and-blood. You made me proud. I love my homosexual son. My son's gay and I love him!</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your son's dead and you love him.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They quietly laugh. VERONICA sees a LITTLE GIRL staring at her. She is wearing Kurt's football jersey and her face is soaked in tears. VERONICA's smile turns into a nauseated grimace.</context>
      <utterance>How do you think Mr. Kelly would react to a son with a limp wrist with a pulse?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How was the funeral?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A young, statuesque blonde appears on-screen. A Super reading WHITNEY JAMES-W.E.T.C. COMMENTARY flashes on.</context>
      <utterance>Superb.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITNEY JAMES</speaker>
      <mode>T.V.</mode>
      <context>A shiny number three flashes on and off in the screen's corner.</context>
      <utterance>It looks like the teen suicide epidemic has hit home in Sherwood as the death toll at Westerburg High rockets to three.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITNEY JAMES</speaker>
      <mode>T.V.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heather Chandler, Kurt Kelly, and Rupert "Ram" Sweeney all had good looks and popularity, but there's one thing they didn't have: Values, Ambition, and Hope.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's three things.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITNEY JAMES</speaker>
      <mode>T.V.</mode>
      <context>The camera pans to an affable ANCHORMAN.</context>
      <utterance>It rained everyday of my Maui vacation, but hey, I didn't kill myself. I'm Whitney James, Commentary.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANCHORMAN</speaker>
      <mode>T.V.</mode>
      <context>Tomorrow's forecast calls for...</context>
      <utterance>Thanks Whitney, but I hate to say it. It looks like you brought that rainy weather back with you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA hangs up and looks to her battered diary lying against the wall. She crawls to the diary and then reaches up to her night table to pull down her monocle and a pen. She sucks a cup of Vodka and begins writing.</context>
      <utterance>No, it's okay J.D., I just kind of wanted to talk.....Oh, a newsmagazine show on Channel 16. Really? On the suicides. No, sounds great. Bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Sitting up against her bed, VERONICA continues writing as J.F.K. laps up Vodka from the Dixie cup.</context>
      <utterance>Dear Diary, my teen angst bullshit has a body count.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>VERONICA drops her head back and closes her eyes, popping out her monocle. She swoons down against the bed onto the floor and curls into a fetal slumber.</context>
      <utterance>The most popular people in the school are dead. Everybody's sad, but it's a good kind of sad. Suicide gave Heather depth, Kurt a soul, Ram a brain. I gave J.D. shit about the Ich Luge thing but what really frightens me is that I'm not frightened by what J.D.'ll do next. It's God versus my boyfriend and God's losing....</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PAULINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the jukebox amusingly grinds to a halt, PAULINE hoists up a bullhorn to her lips and crackles...</context>
      <utterance>Peter, kill the jukebox.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A startled Geek RODNEY splatters milk all over himself. STUDENTS whip their heads around to the front of the cafeteria. MARTHA DUNNSTOCK/DUMPTRUCK warily looks up from her plate. PAULINE FLEMING chants with soaring self-importance.</context>
      <utterance>Could I have your attention?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A tableau of dumbfounded STUDENTS stare at the Bullhorn Woman.</context>
      <utterance>Our school has been torn apart by tragedy. I'm here today to fuse it back together through love! I want everyone to clasp hands. We need to connect this cafeteria into one mighty circuit. Let's begin a new happiness!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PAULINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo, what's the problem? I know you know how to hold hands. Ring-around- the-rosy-a-pocketful-of-posy...Forget it! I'm just so thrilled to announce that Whitney James of WETC News is taping a rap session with students from area high schools</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No or Hell No?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUDENTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frightened and flustered by the fanatic camaraderie around her, MARTHA DUNNSTOCK/DUMPTRUCK quakes for a moment then crawls underneath her table.</context>
      <utterance>Hell no!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fingering her bangs in an attempt at composure, VERONICA steps into the cafeteria and her fellow students boom.</context>
      <utterance>I can't hear you....</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't you see this is a special moment?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just making it more special.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULINE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>VERONICA spins to an electric PAULINE FLEMING glistening in the mouth of the cafeteria, flanked by HEATHER DUKE and PETER DAWSON.</context>
      <utterance>Veronica, there you are!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. looks out through the cafeteria. He sees Martha poke her head out from beneath her lunch table then dart back under. J.D. moves away from the chattering group.</context>
      <utterance>You people are in charge of getting delegates from every clique in the school to be on the Whitney James Teenage Suicide Prevention T.V. Special. Let's be able to say we were the ones who put peer pressure out to pasture.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Westerburg? A happy family?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure you'll work something out.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. We'll work something out.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I swear to God. Won't we J.D.?...J.D.?</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Yes. We'll work something out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shoulda stuck around, jerk. Ms. Fleming wants to redefine the high school experience.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She wants to ignore the high school experience. Our way's better. We scare people into not being assholes.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can be so immature!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRED DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We beat the bitches.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh beautiful. The Beaver's home.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRED DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FRED DEAN crams the cassette in his V.C.R. and hefts up a chest exerciser. He begins pumping away as the image of a shabby building appears on the massive T.V.</context>
      <utterance>Judge told em to slurp shit and die.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRED DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The building blows up. FRED DEAN cackles. J.D. politely applauds. FRED pops out the videocassette and bounces away.</context>
      <utterance>I put a Norwegian in the boiler room. Masterful. When that blew, it set off a pack of thermals I'd stuck upstairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRED DEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's great to be alive!</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you like your father?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. picks up the framed picture that Veronica threw.</context>
      <utterance>Never given the matter much thought. Liked my mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA slowly sits down next to J.D. with dazed concern.</context>
      <utterance>They said her death was an accident. But she knew when the explosives were set to go off. She knew...</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's just...settle down. Ms. Fleming has given us a chance to atone for...</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our sins? What sins? If you put a Nazi in a concentration camp, does that make you a Nazi?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. fires into the radiant image of BIGFUN, destroying the T.V. and disgusting VERONICA, who bolts off the couch. He raucously crawls after her.</context>
      <utterance>We've made MTV.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're breaking up. I am out!</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. playfully tackles VERONICA. This calms rather than angers. She turns on her back. J.D. follows suit.</context>
      <utterance>Wha-at? Come on, there's another T.V. in the kitchen. You know you used to have a sense of humor.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I don't know how to talk to you.</context>
      <utterance>You're getting too cool for me, J.D.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA sighs, then rolls over into a crawling position and eventually into a walking-out-the-door position.</context>
      <utterance>Our relationship's moving fast, I know, but I have real, real respect for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to make this Ms. Pauline thing work. Lines of communication between the cliques. You were a phase....</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Phase my ass! You'll be</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a harsh laugh, she takes in the next photograph. It has YOUNG HEATHER DUKE and YOUNG MARTHA eating toasted marshmallows off each other's sticks.</context>
      <utterance>What the.....</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did you get these?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I just had the</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Heather Chandler was that leader but...</context>
      <utterance>Strength. Westerburg doesn't need mushy togetherness, it needs a leader.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. laughs. She's on the ball.</context>
      <utterance>But she couldn't handle it.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you can. In Catcher in the Rye Holden says his ideal job'd be making sure some kids don't fall off a cliff. He doesn't realize if you pay too much attention to the kids, you'll back off the cliff yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very very. The photographs?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. launches away from his desk with a grin. He places a red ribbon on HEATHER DUKE's desk.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. I'll ask you to do me a favor. You'll get the negatives and everything back then.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the meantime, strength, And hey, there's a little gift.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me get it clear, Veronica. You want yourself a sweet homeboy for this T.V. show so you can show everybody what a loose, Martin Luther Cosby-lovng place Westerburg is.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something like that. Will you do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn, you're a shrewd one. Shrewd.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just want to show different kinds of people can get together and it doesn't have to be Vietnam. You don't get treated badly here do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA hands him a Guest Pass tag.</context>
      <utterance>I don't get treated at all, but hey, don't worry about it. I'll do your thing. It'll give my Mom a smile.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Things are going to change, Earl.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER DUKE impishly blinds VERONICA with her hands.</context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guess who?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER DUKE lets go with a small giggle. VERONICA turns to face her Heather Chandler-looking friend and her smile dies. VERONICA violently pushes HEATHER DUKE away and storms off.</context>
      <utterance>Heather.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Veronica Sawyer, barf on anybody's carpet lately?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA'S BEDROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>VERONICA cringes.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What are you doing....</context>
      <utterance>Is this David? Heather's David?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Can you put Heather on?</context>
      <utterance>I'm delirious for the both of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE'S BEDROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>DAVID proudly looks down off-screen to his lap.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She can't really talk right now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe it. I'm winning.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BETTY bends down to shoot then raises her body back up.</context>
      <utterance>Don't get cocky, girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I missed you. I know I'm not as, as exciting as your other friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BETTY once again bends and raises.</context>
      <utterance>That's bullshit. Just shoot.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ronnie, I'm still a virgin.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BETTY finally shoots. Feebly.</context>
      <utterance>Shoot.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Betty, your daydreams are a lot better than my realities, believe me. I'm afraid though it's time to get your butt kicked.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VEONCIA gigglingly shoots, but misses the wicket. And instead hits BETTY's ball. Disturbed by the sudden dilemma, she determinedly walks to her ball and moves it away from BETTY's.</context>
      <utterance>Ronnie!</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's the only way.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, you're not settling for the two shots are you? Knock me out girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not my style, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA sighs then knocks BETTY's adjacent ball sailing toward the porch and a statuesque HEATHER DUKE who does not budge as the ball whizzes past her.</context>
      <utterance>Nice guys finish last. I should know.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brav-</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER DUKE walks toward the girls followed by a meandering desultory HEATHER MCNAMARA, who picks up a green mallet and fragilely swings it; her early robustness a forgotten memory.</context>
      <utterance>Sure. See ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER DUKE hustles back toward a passing BETTY FINN.</context>
      <utterance>Croquet won't be the same without Heather.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Betty, wait. I almost forgot...The Whitney James Teenage Suicide Prevention T.V. Special isn't going to be taped at the studios. It's going to be done in the Park.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I thought...</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bring some potato salad...HEY, I'M RED!</context>
      <utterance>It's going to be like a big picnic.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER DUKE savagely "sends" HEATHER MACNAMARA's ball into the flower bed.</context>
      <utterance>So did you call people to tell them how to get to the studio tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER DUKE's shot swerves wide of the wicket.</context>
      <utterance>Back off. I called everyone, even that Stoner slut. Felt like giving my phone a bath. I told Betty just now...Damn!</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA blows her shot.</context>
      <utterance>You're so polluted. Talking down to people, making fake notes....</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't see what gives you the right to lecture,</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The depressed and disoriented HEATHER MCNAMARA, laying against a tree, pipes in.</context>
      <utterance>No, you're wrong. It's not even your turn.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's right.....Boy, croquet's not the same without Heather.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PETER DAWSON beams toward her, wearing a Guest Pass.</context>
      <utterance>Ich Luge bullets. I'm such a jerk.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER DAWSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Veronica, I thought we lost you.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA looks at her watch then joins PETER's march down the hall.</context>
      <utterance>I was waiting for my friend Betty.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER DAWSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Teens talking it out on T.V.! Would it be pretentious of me to attach a videocassette of the show on my Princeton application?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They burst through the studio double doors.</context>
      <utterance>Shucks, that's a great idea, Pete.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PETER DAWSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Out of nowhere, a bubbling HEATHER DUKE knots a pink armband around PETER's arm with a giggle.</context>
      <utterance>This is excellent, but I thought we were going to get equal representation on this thind: Geeks, Gearheads...</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PETER DAWSON prances off with a raucous laugh. VERONICA stares dumbfounded at the wicked homogeneity of the STUDENTS as HEATHER DUKE ties a pink armband on her.</context>
      <utterance>They're probably just being fashionably late.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER DUKE tugs VERONICA across the crowded studio floor to where the WETC news set is situated. Smoking casually in her anchor's chair is the beautiful WHITNEY JAMES.</context>
      <utterance>Is this very or what? Oh, you've gotta meet Whitney James! Come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whitney, here's my friend.....</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITNEY JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER DUKE glides away. VERONICA uncomfortably steps onto the news set and moves down next to WHITNEY JAMES.</context>
      <utterance>Ah please sit down.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITNEY JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got a confession to make. My name used to be Heather, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But my name's not...</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITNEY JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People just don't take the name Heather seriously. They should, shouldn't they?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so sorry. I was led to believe there were going to be different kinds of social and psychological types at this gathering.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITNEY JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WHITNEY JAMES tears open a bag of Corn Nuts and showers some into her mouth. She speaks as she sucks and chews.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I was scared of the same thing, Heather. The minute you try to deal with the actual teenagers who have contemplated suicide you're stepping into quicksand. Quicksand filled with bad complexions, bad grades, bad parents, bad drugs, and all sorts of doody nobody wants to hear let alone bend down to clean up.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITNEY JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WHITNEY JAMES titters. VERONICA is a statue of mortification.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not knocking teen suicide. It's exciting stuff. My personal faves are those kids from loaded families grabbing the mike to whine how even though they bagged a B.M.W. on their birthday, they're still quote-unquote depressed. It's ridiculous. People who say money can't buy happiness don't know where to shop.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not people stained with loserness.</context>
      <utterance>The world wants winners, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITNEY JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stained with loserness. Oh, I like it. Can I use that. It'd be dynamite on interoffice memoranda.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all yours, Heather. Now if you'll excuse me, I'm going to go throw up.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITNEY JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. Ciao.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PAULINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone take their places on the stage!  Isn't this thrilling?!</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But Ms. Fleming, it's just not right.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, the wine? I realize you're all under 21, but it seemed like such a perfect touch.  Could we get some more light up here?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PAULINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our schools have been torn apart by tragedy. Let's fuse them back together through</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...with no more suicide...</utterance>
   <speaker>STUDENTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ripping off her pink armband, VERONICA freezes. Standing at the wine and cheese table, gunslinger coat and all, is J.D. He turns around and raises his wine glass for a gleeful toast.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah...</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy traumatic experiences, Batman. I'm sorry you felt you had to put yourself through all that shit. I told you it wouldn't...Hey, it's in the past already, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Devastated, VERONICA sways back toward the TECHNICIAN's console.</context>
      <utterance>No more problems....</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA slams the lever back down forcing the spinning circle of handholding, pink-armbanded STUDENTS to crash to the ground around a taken-aback PAULINE and WHITNEY JAMES.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WHITNEY JAMES playfully lets off a Hendrixian riff before coolly leaning over to her microphone.</context>
      <utterance>Cute.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITNEY JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go for another take.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bargain matinees are for the first show only.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARTHA puts two crumpled bucks through the window. The CASHIER shines a cruelly patronizing smile.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I forgot.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Veronica, how'd that Teenage Prevention T.V. Suicide thing go?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Color me educated. I learned high school happiness is for members only, Pauline Fleming wouldn't know reality if it lived in her uterus, and reality's name's Heather James. Also, J.D.'s a major creep.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>DAN RATHER VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh sure, I'll bet even back when I went to school there were drugs, even sex, but they were simpler times. The Sherwood suicides tell the bitter truth of today's young. What a waste...Oh VERONICA snaps off the T.V.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turn that back on!</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This condescending junk makes suicide seem like a cool thing to do. Hey kids, make your parents and teachers feel like shit! Get the respect in death you'll never get in life.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we're not going to watch that program, can I put on the game?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you trying to tell me it is</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Which is it? Where are your shoes?</context>
      <utterance>I'm lost. You don't get enough attention, you get too much attention.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All we want is to be treated like human beings, not like guinea pigs to be experimented on and not like bunny rabbits to be patronized.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't patronize bunny rabbits.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Treated like human beings? Is that what you said little Miss Voice of a Generation? Just how do you think adults act with other adults? You think it's all just Doubles Tennis. Adults can be horrible to other adults. When teenagers complain that they want to be treated like human beings, it's usually because they</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER DUKE suddenly breezes in the room.</context>
      <utterance>You'll live. Want some pate?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi everyone, door was open. Veronica, you missed it! Pauline and Whitney James were up there doing there suicide rap when the cops come in and announce that Martha Dumptruck tried to buy the farm. She gave the ticket girl at the Colfax theatre a suicide note then bellyflopped in front of a car.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is she dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA slaps HEATHER DUKE in the face.</context>
      <utterance>That's the punchline. She's still alive, in stable condition. Another case of a geek trying to imitate the popular people of the school and failing miserably. Is that pate?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said I was sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are out of control. Heather and Kurt were a shock, but Martha Dumptruck, get crucial! She dialed suicide hotlines in her diapers.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA rubs her feet. HEATHER DUKS shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>You're not funny. Ouch!</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What. A. Martyr. Understand; Martha couldn't take the heat so she got out of the kitchen. Just think what a better place the world would be if every nimrod followed her cue.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hot Probs is on.</context>
      <utterance>Just shut up and turn on the radio.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER DUKE hastens to the radio and flicks it on. Ripping open a bag of corn nuts, she sets herself down next to VERONICA as a TROUBLED MALE VOICE cuts the air. TROUBLED MALE VOICE (Radio) I know it's supposed to be funny that they never get off the island, but still, sometimes I feel like</context>
      <utterance>Oh shit, yeah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>D.J.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dude, you've got to remember if it wasn't for the courage of the fearless crew, the Minnow would be lost. The Minnow would be lost! Next call!</utterance>
   <speaker>TROUBLED MALE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The D.J. rudely clicks off the TROUBLED MALE VOICE.</context>
      <utterance>But Skipper hates me....</utterance>
   <speaker>D.J.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa, they're coming out early tonight. What ever happened to teen pregnancy and acne? You've got the Dogcatcher on W etcetera and you're listening to Hot Probs. Who am I talking to?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER MCNAMARA looks up at a Madonna poster on the wall.</context>
      <utterance>My name is Heather, I mean, not Heather.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER MCNAMARA looks up to her Minnie Mouse lamp.</context>
      <utterance>It's Madonna. Geez, no, not that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>D.J.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, Minnie. Don't tell me, Mickey just confessed he got A.I.D.S. from Goofy at a New Year's Eve Party.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA'S BEDROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A broken-down HEATHER MCNAMARA sobs.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God has cursed me, I think. The last time I had sex, the guy killed himself the next day. I'm failing Math.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>HEATHER MCNAMARA is revealed in the front row wearing her cheerleader uniform. To the left, HEATHER DUKE dishes with some dreamy GUYS. At the back of the classroom, VERONICA, monocle in eye, writes in her diary.</context>
      <utterance>Heather told everyone about Heather.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A HOMELY GIRL is seen reading a note, glancing to a TYPICAL JOCK. VERONICA takes in the wicked panorama of the classroom.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Dear Diary, I've cut off Heather Chandler's head and Heather Duke's head has sprouted in its place like some mythological thing my eighth grade boyfriend would know about. Heather's even doing the old note trick.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>HEATHER MCNAMARA suddenly rises and walks out of the classroom, passing a GRUFF TEACHER in a trenchcoat, carrying a briefcase.</context>
      <utterance>I did it J.D.'s way. I did it Pauline's way. Nothing's changed. I guess that's Heather's way. And jesus, what about J.D.? I can't get him out of my head. Are we going to the Prom? Or to Hell? And where's Heather going?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRUFF TEACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Heather going?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's going to</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER MCNAMARA gets running water from another sink as VERONICA rushes in. VERONICA punches HEATHER MCNAMARA's face causing the pills to explode out of her mouth. HEATHER MCNAMARA slumps against a stall, onto the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Give me a break.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA jumps up and down on the pills on the floor.</context>
      <utterance>What are you trying to do? Kill me?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What were</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're giving your life away to become a goddamn statistic in U.S. Fucking A Today. That's got to be the least private thing I can think of.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what about Heather and Ram and Kurt?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER MCNAMARA wipes tears from her eyes and smiles weakly.</context>
      <utterance>If everyone jumped off a bridge, young lady, would you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably....</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey now, if you were happy every day of your life, you wouldn't be a human being, you'd be a game show host.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER MCNAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Something lame like that.</context>
      <utterance>Let's knock off early. Go to the mall.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COURTNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh great. Here comes Heather.</utterance>
   <speaker>COURTNEY'S FRIEND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>HEATHER DUKE brings down her arms and the petition and turns to VERONICA, revealed to be descending down the steps.</context>
      <utterance>Heather?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Veronica! Color me stoked, girl. I've gotten</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So some people need different kinds of "convincing" than others....  Hey, just sign the petition!</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't talk to me like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was J.D.'s idea! He made out the signature sheet and everything. Now will you sign it?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA slaps HEATHER DUKE with all her might.</context>
      <utterance>Jealous much?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heather, why can't you just be a friend? Why are you such a MegaBitch?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I can be! The same fucking cheek, goddamnit! Why are you pulling my dick? Do you think, do you really think, if Betty Finn's fairy godmother made</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Catch a movie? Miniature Golf?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was thinking more along the lines of slitting Heather Duke's wrists open and making it look like a suicide.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could be up for that. I've already started underlining</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't get it! You were wrong! I was right! Strength, damnit! Come back!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MOM and DAD glance at each other before MOM speaks.</context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your friend Jason Dean just stopped by. He seemed very concerned about you. He said he thinks you might try to kill yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He says we should keep you away from sharp objects, closed garages, toxic...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>VERONICA flops around to see J.D. kneeling over her on her bed reading Heather Duke's copy of The Catcher in the Rye.</context>
      <utterance>"You can't ever find a place nice and peaceful because there isn't any."</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. giddily underlines words then slides into a prone position, tossing the book to an enraged VERONICA.</context>
      <utterance>Nice. It's got that Catcher-in-the-Ryey- I-hate-the-world-and-the-world-hates-me- so-let's-commit-suicide ambience. Give it a try, underline something.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get off my bed, you sick psycho! You think you're a rebel! You're not a rebel! You're a sick psycho! Do you think you're a rebel? Do you think you're a rebel? I wanna know!</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA freezes and J.D. reaches up to her hand where she holds the Catcher in the Rye. Her index finger is curled into the book. Sitting up, J.D. carefully opens the book at that place and peers in.</context>
      <utterance>"You say tomayto, I say tomahto. Let's call the whole thing off...Hold it!</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at that. Eskimo. One word. I love it. I usually go for whole sentences myself, but hey this is perfecto. Eskimo. So mysterious...</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. obliviously underlines the word then pulls the flailing VERONICA up like an enthusiastic camp counselor.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a....You're not listening! I'm not on your side....</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're still not listening! I'm not..</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nag, nag, nag, nag. nag.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This knife is filthy.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What in the hell do you think I'm doing? Taking out her tonsils?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. grabs a dishtowel and vigorously wipes off the knife.</context>
      <utterance>I think I know Heather a bit better than you, okay? If she was going to slash her wrists, the knife would be absolutely spotless.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She can and so can the viewer. Tears well in VERONICA's eyes. She begins to shudder, a shattered smile quaking on her face.</context>
      <utterance>How's this? Can you see your fucking reflection?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow someone else will move into her place. That person could be me.  Ha, there's only one of us who knows Heather's handwriting and if you think I'm doing another suicide note.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't get it, do you? Society nods its head at any horror the American teenager can think to bring upon itself. We don't need gloves and does anyone really care about exact handwriting? J.D. tears his gloves off with a giggle. He takes a pen from the kitchen counter and paper from a cutesy memo pad. He shoves the pen in VERONICA's hand and grabbing her hand, forces her to scribble LIFE SUCKS on the paper.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. pulls out the copy of the Catcher in the Rye and opens a door revealing HEATHER DUKE, asleep in an artful pose on a couch, MTV images from the T.V. flashing against her.</context>
      <utterance>Perfecto. Man, I've even got a marked-up Catcher in the Rye. What else does a suicide need?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you'll excuse me......</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. hops in the adjoinging room and slams the door. VERONICA races to the door wailing. She maniacally rattles the doorknob trying to open the locked door.</context>
      <utterance>No-o!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FATHER RIPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FATHER RIPPER lets the word hang in the air, then holds up</context>
      <utterance>Eskimo.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER RIPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEATHER</context>
      <utterance>On the surface, Heather Duke was the vivacious young lady we all knew her to be. But her soul was in Antartica, freezing with the knowledge of the way fellow teenagers can be cruel, the way parents can be unresponsive, and as she writes so eloquently in her suicide note, the way life can suck. We'll all miss Sherwood's little Eskimo. Let's hope she's rubbing noses with Jesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God Veronica, my afterlife is s-o-o boring. If I have to sing "Kumbaya" one more time...</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here?!</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a squeal, HEATHER CHANDLER plunges VERONICA's face into the plate of spaghetti.</context>
      <utterance>I made your favorite. Spaghetti. Lots of oregano.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER CHANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dinner!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>VERONICA closes her eyes and holds her heart. She suddenly launches to her desk, opens her diary, shoves on her monocle, catches her breath, and begins writing.</context>
      <utterance>Dinner! Veronica! Dinner!</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>VERONICA leans back in her chair, sweating. She reaches in the pocket of a blazer draped over the back of the chair and pulls out the cigarette J.D. had given her eariler in the film. She puts it in her mouth unlit then takes it out and puts it back in the blazer.</context>
      <utterance>Dear Diary, no one can stop J.D. Not the F.B.I., the C.I.A., or the P.T.A. That is to say, no one but me. I know where J.D. is coming from and where he is heading. He's wrong, but I'm going to teach him what's right. I'm going to stop J.D....If it's the last thing I do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. throws the gun on the bed and pulls from his coat the computer printout sheet petition, then savagely rolls it out on the floor. It is filled with signatures of different sizes, styles, and colors. J.F.K. blinks.</context>
      <utterance>I can't believe you did it. I was teasing. I loved you. Sure, I climbed up here to kill you, but first I was going to try and get you back. With amazing petition.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. flicks open a switchblade. He runs the blade beneath the typed paragraph at the top causing it to peel off, reavealing another typed paragraph.</context>
      <utterance>It's a shame you can't see what our fellow students really signed.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen. "We students of Westerburg High will die. Today. Our burning bodies will be the ultimate protest to a society that degrades is. Fuck you all." Not that subtle but neither's blowing up the school. Talk about your suicide pacts. When our school explodes tomorrow, it's going to be the kind of thing that infects a generation. A Woodstock for the 80's. Damn, we coulda toasted marshmallows together.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>J.D. swiftly picks up the petition and heads out the window. MOM enters the room and, seeing her hanging daughter, launches into frantic screams.</context>
      <utterance>Honey, are you all right in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA opens her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Oh God, I knew it! No, no! I want my baby back! I should have let you keep that job at the mall. I was just afraid of you coming home alone at night!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA undos the noose around her neck but still remains hanging for the rope runs all the way down her back beneath her blazer and is tied around her waist. She undos the waist- knot and lands on her bed. She quickly puts a small pillow over the left-behind gun, unnoticed by her dazed MOM.</context>
      <utterance>I made your favorite! Spaghetti! Lots of oregano!</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Mom, why so tense?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRED DEAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need some help with my homework...</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. turns back up his stereo (and the Montage music).</context>
      <utterance>Sorry tiger, I'm a little busy....</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PAULINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Veronica! J.D. told me you committed suicide last night!</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is he? Where's J.D.?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to talk. Whether to kill yourself is one of the most important decisions a teenager has to make.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA storms away to her nearby locker. She swirls her locker combination and opens it. She glances down the hall and freezes. In the distance, J.D. moves mechanically down the hallway carrying a large gym bag, wearing a Walkman. VERONICA climbs into her locker. She closes it until it is barely perceptibly ajar. J.D. strides past the locker and into the Boys bathroom.</context>
      <utterance>Get a job.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rodney, where's everybody going?</utterance>
   <speaker>RODNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Friday.....</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God, the damn pep assembly....</utterance>
   <speaker>RODNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA ignores RODNEY's amiable attemots at conversation to inquisitively move forward through the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, these things are pretty artificial, but at least we all get out of class...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RODNEY (unconsciously) dramatically stops, turns to VERONICA. and says........</context>
      <utterance>Rodney, what's underneath the gym?</utterance>
   <speaker>RODNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA blanches then lunges through the crowd. She topples a couple disgruntled STUDENTS before careening down the staircase beside the gym.</context>
      <utterance>The boiler room.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>J.D. weilds around. A sweating VERONICA moves toward him, pointing the bedroom gun at him.</context>
      <utterance>May I see your hall pass?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew that loose was too noose! I mean, noose too loose! Goddamn you!</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. looks down at the gym bag already on the ground. He folds his arms and smiles. VERONICA forcefully moves closer.</context>
      <utterance>Like father, like son. A serious-as- fuck bomb in the boiler room that'll set off a pack of thermals upstairs. Okay, so let's start by slowly putting the bomb down on the ground.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Put your hands on your head.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay. I knew that. I knew that.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. suddenly kicks out into VERONICA's stomach, doubling her over and causing her to drop the gun. J.D. gracefully retrieves it.</context>
      <utterance>You didn't say Simon Says.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. violently kisses/bites VERONICA. While kissing, VERONICA sees a fire alarm on a nearby wall. She closes her eyes then savagely knees J.D. in the groin. VERONICA bolts to the alarm and pulls it down. Nothing happens. J.D. gasps.</context>
      <utterance>You think just because you started this thing, you can end it?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA rockets her body down and picks up the gun. J.D. grabs her and throws her against the steel boiler room door. A jostled VERONICA raises the gun. J.D. howls then bounds toward VERONICA, causing them both to careen down the steel steps of the boiler room. At the same time, he inadvertently kicks the gym bag/bomb down along with them. The gun spins from VERONICA's hand and slides away. The bomb flies out of the bag onto the boiler room floor. A digital clock on the bomb clicks on at 5:00....4:59....4:58...</context>
      <utterance>You, really didn't think I'd, forget, forget, to disconnect the....</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fully standing, J.D. flicks open his switchblade. He gives VERONICA "the finger," screaming in exploded saliva...</context>
      <utterance>The bomb's gone on, J.D.! How do you turn it off? Tell me!</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seething, VERONICA shoots up at J.D. blowing off "the finger." Shrieking in pain, J.D. drops the knife to hold this sudden geyser of blood. VERONICA achingly stands, pointing the gun. The bomb clicks down to 2:25.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you!</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all over, J.D. Help me to stop it.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA fires the gun at J.D.'s feet. The bomb clicks to 1:49.</context>
      <utterance>You want to wipe the slate clean as much as I do. Okay, so maybe I am killing everyone in the school because nobody loves me. You have a purpose though! Remember? Let's face it, the only place different social types can genuinely get along with each other is in heaven.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you turn the fucker off?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not listening. People are going to look at the ashes of Westerburg and say there's a school that self-destructed not because society didn't care, but because that school</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just push the red button twice. That's what stops it. If that's what you want, babe?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what I want, babe?</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA fires the gun twice into J.D.'s throat. Coughing and moaning, he splatters against a generator.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA saunters to J.D.'s writhing body.</context>
      <utterance>Cool guys like you out of my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. closes his eyes and slumps to the ground. VERONICA turns to the bomb and crouches over it. A lit green light is next to a green button. Above it, an unlit red light is next to a red button. The bomb's digital clock clicks to 00:17. VERONICA presses the red button twice, turning on the red light and stopping the clock. VERONICA falls back into a sitting position and sorely exhales, tears streaming down her face.</context>
      <utterance>But babe, don't worry, these here were Ich Luge bullets.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>J.D. stands starkly in the distance before her, blood spurting from his throat onto his gunslinger coat. He painfully speaks through his assasinated vocal cords.</context>
      <utterance>Color me impressed.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really fucked me up, Veronica.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought I...you..</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. pulls open his coat revealing that the bomb is attached to his torso. The green light is on and the clock says 00:10..00:09.</context>
      <utterance>You've got power, Veronica. Power I didn't think you had. The slate is clean.</utterance>
   <speaker>J.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA takes the unlit cigrette from her blazer pocket and puts it in her mouth. She then folsd her arms.</context>
      <utterance>Pretend I did blow up the school. All the schools. Now that you're dead, what are you gonna do with your life?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>J.D. raises his arms in a crucifixion pose as the bomb clicks to 0:00. Nothing happens. An annoyed J.D. breaks out of his crucifixion stance and raps the bomb with his palm.</context>
      <utterance>Perfecto.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Veronica, you look like hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA tosses away the cigarette. She then grabs HEATHER DUKE by the shoulders and forcibly turns her around.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I just got back.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEATHER DUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VERONICA takes off HEATHER DUKE's red ribbon and ties it around the hair of her own head. She kisses HEATHER DUKE on the cheek, leaving a black stain. VERONICA calls off.</context>
      <utterance>Heather, my love, there's a new sheriff in town.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARTHA DUNNSTOCK/DUMPTRUCK revealed to be in an electric wheelchair, brakes to a stop and looks to Veronica, confused. VERONICA walks up beside her. MARTHA starts up her wheelchair and accompanies VERONICA away into a deserted hallway.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Martha, wait up.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maybe pop some popcorn.</context>
      <utterance>My date for the prom kind of flaked out on me, so I thought if you weren't doing anything that night we could go to the video store and rent some new releases or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like that.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
