<movie id="268" title="Hellraiser Deader">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>YOUNG REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode>O.C</mode>
      <context>Amy is already past him, she throws back a middle finger for a response.</context>
      <utterance>Nice reporting Klein. How `bout you show me what you learned?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>BETTY, 50ish, her glasses hanging on the tip of her nose, sees Amy coming.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe later.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Amy...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morning...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morning? It's half past four.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betty gives a broad gesture over her shoulder, pointing toward the Editor's office across the work space. Amy heads across the way, toward the office. Betty picks up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Mmm...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Rickman... Amy's here. Right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...the delightful and world-famous Amy Klein. Have a seat, angel of light.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eat me, Charles.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's exactly that lack of respect for authority that got you fired from the New York Post.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wasn't fired. I was re-assigned.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course. Where would you be without me? By the way, I don't recall ever being thanked properly for this "re- assignment". Charles makes air quotes with his fingers.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lucky for you I opened my doors to you here as soon as I heard you were "available".</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds up the cassette recorder.</context>
      <utterance>Hey a contract's a contract.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, if all this about me being late with the crack whore story It's all right here -- and it's gold. I was just about to-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what then? Are we being sued again?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmm? Oh no.  Please feel free to have some of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. What is this? General Tso's cat?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He heads back over to the VCR. Amy ditches the Chinese food and picks up her coffee again. She sits, lights another cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>Spare me the "Nothing comes close to New York Chinese" speech just this once. Go on, sit down. Just something I wanted to show you...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He finds the button, presses it and turns back to Amy.</context>
      <utterance>Okay... rewind, rewind? Rewind.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody mailed us this thing around two weeks ago but, in keeping with our usual level of efficiency, Betty didn't get around to opening it `til this morning. Then she brought it to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charles closes the door.</context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter? This X-rated or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something. Amy, with your encyclopedic world-wide knowledge of skank-ology -- have you ever heard of "Deaders?"</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, sure. They're generally in their forties, kind of ex-hippy types. They still think Jerry Garcia is like "really cool" even though he's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dead - ers. D-E-A-D-E-R -- S.</context>
      <utterance>Not dead-heads...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, sometimes they wear ponytails. Dream about how great the sixties were. You see `em in the park sometimes...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Love of my life, go screw yourself. I'm asking you a serious question.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Charles. I've never heard of "Deaders."</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charles goes to the VCR and hits the play button. Amy finishes her coffee and lights a new cigarette with the still- glowing butt of her last one. She leans forward.</context>
      <utterance>Watch the tape.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And here's our deader bed -- this is the scene of the crime. Crime to be... he camera moves in on Winter.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Winter glances up, then dismisses the camera altogether. He looks off screen, then raises his hand. The room quiets. We hear various voices.</context>
      <utterance>And here is the fearless leader of the Deaders... Winter.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Winter looks up and the camera swings toward Katya. She hesitates. A girl next to her starts to prompt her.</context>
      <utterance>Shh. Quiet. We're starting.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you become one of us of your own free will?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>KATYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you afraid?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Fear is the place we go to learn.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My skin isn't real. My eyes aren't real. My muscles aren't real. My bones, my heart, my veins and nerves, and flesh and meat... aren't real. What I see, what I hear, what I taste, what I touch, what I remember, what I think, what I feel, aren't real.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go on.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera swings back to Winter, who gestures for her to come forward, then swings back to see her coming. The various people in the room gather around as she comes to the mattress. The camera moves this way and that, trying to get the best angle to cover the action. People spread towels on the mattress, over the plastic, as Katya, naked, sits down on the towels, then lays back, flat on the mattress. inter looks to the Black Kid standing next to him. He comes up with a big handgun -- maybe a .45.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not real.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera moves in closer as Winter takes the gun and slips it into Katya's hand.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not real...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>he slides the gun over and puts it to the side of her head.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not... I'm not real...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy ... Charles...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just keep watching.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KATYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Winter reaches out, hesitant, and cocks the gun in her hand. Meanwhile, we see other hands, reaching in, pressing a folded up towel against the opposite side of her head. Other hands come in and press a doubled-over pillow against the towel.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not real. I'm not...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She closes her eyes, grits her teeth. Her back arches.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not real. I'm not... I'm not...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just watch...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to know if you've called the pol...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said, "Just watch."</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, man, don't tell me that was some special effect...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is sick...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera is now pointing at Winter. There is a look of deep tenderness in his face as he circles around and kneels down, staring toward Katya, who is lying, as dead as dead can be, on the mattress. Blood has run from the ghastly wound down both sides of the plastic, and towels on the side of the bed catch the mess. Winter reaches down and gently removes the gun from Katya's lifeless hand... and then, light as a feather, lies down on top of her. The camera moves forward and down as Marla, presumably, elbows her way through for a better vantage point. The camera moves in close as Winter stretches out along Katya's body. He places his lips on her forehead, kissing her lightly, then presses his lips against hers -- kissing her -- or maybe something else. It seems almost as if he's breathing into her. His body moves as his lungs expand and expel, and he seems to be struggling toward some non-sexual climax. AMY watches, both repelled and fascinated.</context>
      <utterance>That's saying a lot, for you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>K</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She touches the wound again.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts laughing.</context>
      <utterance>I feel great...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The image cuts off, goes to snow. There is a moment of silence. Amy turns to Charles.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, man! Oh, man...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I said.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you... have you found any of these...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy hesitates, shaking her head, not sure what it's all about.</context>
      <utterance>I haven't done anything. I told you, I just looked at it today. By some chance are you... interested in pursuing this?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy, though, is only half listening, lost in her own thoughts.</context>
      <utterance>Look, Amy. Maybe this is just some kind of bull-shit shot-on-tape gore movie. And since that's all it can be, that's all you're going find, but it sure smells different to me. If it's bull-shit, you'll know pretty fast. If it's not...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How could she...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who said miracles can only happen at Lourdes?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lifts her fingers to the side of her head, duplicating the action of Katya slipping her fingers inside the wound.</context>
      <utterance>Who said they happen there?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amy... you know what my father said once...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That all writers were queers?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, that was a different time. This time, we were driving down the block and there was this fortune-telling place, you know, this gypsy fortune telling place in a store front? And he said, "You know, if I could tell the future I wouldn't be living in any crappy store front." He looks back at the tape.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I could do that, I wouldn't be hanging out in some rundown basement. I'd own the earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe they're just getting started.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What else do we have besides the tape?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up the envelope which is addressed to "AMY KLEIN C/O THE UNDERGROUND". Amy hesitates. Snatches the envelope out of his hand. She reads the return address.</context>
      <utterance>Just a return address on the envelope.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's shocked that he would even know.</context>
      <utterance>Looks like your online fan-base is growing. It's an address in Bucharest. It's where all the Euro-trash kids looking for a good time are heading these days. Amsterdam is so 90's.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why Charles...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She thinks about it. He hands her a thick envelope.</context>
      <utterance>I still like to keep my finger on the pulse, even though I know you think I don't have one.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Your ticket, hotel and per diem.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know me too well.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's what keeps me up at night.  Now here's the part where I'm supposed to say be careful. Be careful.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Always.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She just smirks and exits.</context>
      <utterance>Call me when you get settled.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>Amy leaps up in one quick move to find herself face to face with THE MANAGER, an older man who's a little winded from his climb up here. Between his teeth he clenches a half chewed, three quarter smoked cigar. The smoke seeps through his yellowed teeth.</context>
      <utterance>Have you lost something?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pats her pockets. Then tries another tactic.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I ah.....</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I'm looking for my sister. Marla Chen.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not Chinese.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Manager stares at her in disbelief. Knows she's up to something. Amy sniffs the air coming from the room again.</context>
      <utterance>She's my half sister. Same Mom. Different Dads. I haven't heard from her in two weeks so I got nervous.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Manager blows a bloom of smoke out of his nostrils. He yanks the cigar from his mouth and sniffs. Doesn't seem that bad to him.</context>
      <utterance>Does it always smell like this in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>my pulls a few American bills from her pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Look. Marla is a friend of mine and she's missing.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Manager stares at the money for a beat, then stares back at Amy. He bites down on his cigar and snatches it out of her hand.</context>
      <utterance>I need five minutes in there. Then I'll know what I need to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls out his ring of keys and unlocks the door. Amy enters. The place is dark and cold. Eerily quiet. The manager stays in the hallway, he looks at Amy and taps his watch. Amy nods as he pulls the door closed. She descends down the dark hallway. Her face tightens as she takes in the deathly ripe air. The BUZZING of flies getting louder with each step. As she approaches a room, she recoils, clutching her face from the stench. She inhales -- drawing in the smell to acclimate herself -- and almost vomits. She steadies herself, drawing in breaths through her nose, tentative at first, and finally in larger breaths, until she can tolerate it. he looks back toward the entry door, she is alone.</context>
      <utterance>Five minutes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's dead...</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dead...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Call the police.</context>
      <utterance>Dead! She hung herself in the bathroom.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Manager looks down the stairs for her. He doesn't even attempt to chase her.</context>
      <utterance>Dammit!</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He curses her in his native tongue.</context>
      <utterance>Stop her!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy removes the PUZZLE BOX from her satchel. Stares at it.</context>
      <utterance>I knew you'd come. Course if you're watching this tape, it's already too late for me. But maybe you can stop it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He promised us pleasures beyond anything we could ever imagine. We just had to fight through the pain first. Easier said than done.  Don't open the box Amy. If you do Winter wins, and if he wins-</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone pounds on a door. Marla panics.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The POUNDING GETS LOUDER.</context>
      <utterance>Go to Pletkow station at midnight. Go to the south end of the platform and step onto the last car. Find a guy named Joey who runs the show and tell him I sent you. He'll guide you to them.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marla!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Save them Amy. Please...</utterance>
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Marla leaps forward and-</context>
      <utterance>Marla!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>- shuts off the camera. It goes black for a few seconds, and then cuts to snow. Amy sits, staring at the snow, her face empty. She sets the PUZZLE BOX on the table and stares at it. Takes a sip of her drink.</context>
      <utterance>Those you trust the most -- trust the least.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode>TO HERSELF</mode>
      <context>phone rings. It shakes Amy out of her fugue. She leans over picks up the receiver. An old style phone.</context>
      <utterance>Don't open it. Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know I don't sleep when I'm working. What do you want, Charles?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were supposed to call me.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know me, I dove right in. I was gonna' call you tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The thing is... I started thinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy looks at the Puzzle box on the table. It seems to be reflecting the snow of the TV set in some strange form. She looks closer, it's an ABSTRACT IMAGE OF A LITTLE GIRL SCREAMING. She compares it to the TV set, it shows only white static snow.</context>
      <utterance>You know that's never a good thing Charles.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look. I know the crazy stuff you do for a story.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I get paid for.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charles finishes a pencil and blows off the shavings.</context>
      <utterance>And that's why I hired you. It's just. Just... the thing is, Amy... some things you shouldn't do, you know what I mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I say this to you, but in my heart I know that one time it's going to happen... that you're going to end up, I don't know -- dead or god knows what. But when it does happen, I don't want it to be my fault. She watches the image of the little girl fade.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Charles. I'll make sure it won't be.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, you're messing with my conscience, here. Amy...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charles, I can't do the sensitive thing. I don't know how. I get the message. I knew the message before I got it. Okay, Mommy? You've had a change of heart? You want me to come home? Well I can't. Not until I know the truth. So there. You're off the hook. I gotta go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy waits. But there's no sound.</context>
      <utterance>Charles, I get the message. OK? Your my editor, not my Mommy!  Charles?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A sound comes over the line -- a hoarse gurgling sound - a ghastly wet sound - the same sound Amy heard coming from the throat of the hanged Marla.</context>
      <utterance>Hello? Hello?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ONDUCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Next car.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is Joey on this ride?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONDUCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She enters. The doors slide closed. The train pulls out.</context>
      <utterance>Come on in...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joey is clearly smitten with Amy.</context>
      <utterance>Ahhhh, now here comes a daring soul. A person committed to a just cause. Another seeker of the truth no doubt.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like what I see inside of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you Joey?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He brushes the hair of the woman in his lap, then offers Amy his hand.</context>
      <utterance>I've been called worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy looks at the woman in his lap, declines a hand shake.</context>
      <utterance>And I have the privilege of meeting...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joey's eyes narrow. Something has clearly clicked. He laughs slightly, starts shaking his head.</context>
      <utterance>Amy Klein. Marla Chen sent me. I'm looking for a girl named Katya. Another young girl with red hair and half her head shaved. A guy with glasses named Winter.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the plot thickens. Don't tell me you're mixed up with those mother fuckers. Tell me Amy Klein, do you even know what they're about?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why I'm here. I need you to help me find them.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, jeez. Moral quandary time here... What should he do, what should he do? If he tells her -- the hopefully available and eminently fuckable damsel is thrown into the pit of oblivion -- or anyway is potentially fucked up for life. And that would be such a regrettable waste. If he refrains from telling her... she may yet be saved. A possible trophy awaits me. Angel and devil on the shoulder... hmm. Angel, devil, angel, devil. Oh, the hell with it Entropy's destroying everything anyway. Why shouldn't I do my part?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me what you know about the Deaders.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You first. What do you think they do?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think they bring the dead back to life.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that what you really think?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are they? Where can I find Winter?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some people say Winter's some sort of fucked-up guru, some say he's not human, and others say he's not real. But there is a place they hang out -- those who believe I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joey hesitates. A part of him clearly doesn't want to tell.</context>
      <utterance>Where is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Joey...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Angel, devil, angel, devil.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you don't tell me, someone here will.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you see, now that's the problem. You've got that fucked up self- destructive thing going on.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm already into it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy produces the Puzzle Box from her pack. Joey looks at it like he's just seen a ghost.</context>
      <utterance>Angel, devil, angel, devil</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pushes the woman from his lap. He's more serious now.</context>
      <utterance>This is making me very unhappy...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The "Conductor" shouts from somewhere.</context>
      <utterance>Poteilari and Minvara. On the northeast corner, two doors down, there's a stairway going down into a closed up building. It's always locked, and they're not always there. I don't know where they are when they're not. And once you get mixed up with them -- it's like that story with the tar baby -- chances are you never get loose, and if you do, you never get clean.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONDUCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hands promptly reach up, covering the windows with newspaper. The Conductor goes to the door. The band finishes its set as the light from the station shines through the newspapers. Joey, looking drab in the steady uneven light, stares at Amy.</context>
      <utterance>Coming in!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't take responsibility for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy begins to walk off. Joey leans forward, for the first time he seems sincere, almost foreboding. He shouts over the breaking train.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not asking you to.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other members of the car watch the two of them.</context>
      <utterance>Amy Klein, I'm doing a change of heart thing here, which doesn't usually happen with strangers, but I'm trying to give a little back, it's this whole Karma kick I'm on -- don't do it. Don't go any deeper. Forget about it. Move away. Change your name. Become somebody different.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't do that. I've got that fucked up self- destructive thing going on.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The one door hisses open. Amy stares at Joey for a second, turns and departs, back into the fluorescent lit station. Joey calls after her.</context>
      <utterance>Yes you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only he can bring you back!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy stumbles forward, goes down to her knees and turns. Around twenty feet behind her, standing on the edge of the platform, with his back toward the drop, is- - WINTER, wearing a black trench-coat, cinched at the waist. He looks down the tunnel. Amy does as well. The train is coming into the station. She turns back toward Winter. He stares at her, with malevolent eyes. And as the train comes flying in, he calmly falls backward, directly into its path. Amy screams. In an instant she's up, running alongside the braking train. The doors open, but virtually nobody comes out. The front of the train is still far ahead.</context>
      <utterance>Amy Klein!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The doors hiss and start to close. Finally, Amy reaches the front window of the train. She hammers on it. It opens and a middle-aged WOMAN'S face leans out -- the DRIVER.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! You hit someone! Someone fell in front of the train! Hey! Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody fell... somebody fell in front of the train.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where? Where is he? Where'd he fall?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks back in the direction from which she's come. The bench is now empty.</context>
      <utterance>Back there, way back...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, the men have looked.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And there's nothing there?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't seem terribly surprised.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a sudden hiss. Amy turns as the train doors close.</context>
      <utterance>Hmm?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, you don't seem terribly surprised that there isn't somebody under the train. A</utterance>
   <speaker>MY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what to say. I saw him...</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. That's the thing. Can you tell me again, just what it is that you saw?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um, I was standing on the platform...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But now Amy is seeing something -- through the windows of the moving train. On the platform on the far side, there is a lone figure, the man in the black trench-coat. Amy jumps, looks more closely.</context>
      <utterance>...and, um... I saw this man standing on the edge of the platform, facing away from it.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did he say anyth...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In an instant, Amy is tearing down the platform, heading for the stairs that connect to the platform on the other side.</context>
      <utterance>It's him.!</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy is watching, staring through the moving train windows. The figures are still there. Winter is staring at her -</context>
      <utterance>Hey...</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>n the next instant, the Cop is giving chase, and another Cop, clearly, the "Tomislav" called by the first Cop, further down the station, is rushing in to head Amy off.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, stop! Tomislav! Tomislav!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>n the next instant, Tomislav tackles Amy and she goes down on her face. Even with the rather large Cop on top of her, she's still struggling.</context>
      <utterance>It's them! Over there, over there!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She keeps struggling as the first Cop, and the others on the station, converge on her. She looks toward the far platform.</context>
      <utterance>God damn it, get off of me! Get the hell off of me... Get...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Amy glances up at him, without expression.</context>
      <utterance>Is this where they keep the cheaper whores?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ, you're lucky to have a boss like me. Once again, I have saved your small but relatively shapely behind.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Least you got to travel. What were they going to charge me with, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charge you? They were thinking of shipping you to the government asylum for observation -- and believe me if you go in there, you don't come out. But through my mastery of international negotiations I managed to convince them that you were merely irresponsible. You got your stuff?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why'd you give me this story?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who else would have taken it? Either they're going to think it's bull-shit, or they're going to be too afraid of it. But Amy Klein... Tell me it's real Amy.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's real -- or I'm crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, either way, it's a good story.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got leads. I'll know in the end.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, Amy dearest, for the average person, hunger for knowledge is like hunger... for food. We want to know just enough to take the edge off our appetite. Then we're satisfied, and we stop. But you... you're like a glutton. You can't help over-eating.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't see you complaining.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you see, that's the point. That's why I need you. Because all that stuff I don't eat... I still want. So I send you in to do the eating for me, and so I get to experience it, without actually suffering any mental indigestion.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's for me...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody's forcing anything down your throat. Correct?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see, Amy, you never grew up with all this Catholic god and guilt stuff. It doesn't mean anything to you. I worry about god and heaven and hell. Not during the day, you understand, but around three in the morning, it keeps me up. I want to know what's coming. What's up in heaven and down in hell, or even if there's nothing. It's useful, when you're making plans. So go find out and we'll tell the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, Charles, there's something vaguely demonic about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you know, the word "demon" comes from the Greek word for "knowledge." As in "demonstrate."</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charles shakes his head, disgusted.</context>
      <utterance>No, I didn't know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're in front of Amy's Hotel now. Charles flags down a</context>
      <utterance>American education.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then back to your room, lie down in your coffin until the hours of daylight have passed, as is your wont -- then go get me my story. A</utterance>
   <speaker>MY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to worry.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never do. I'm not here to save people and I'm not here to judge them. I just take `em as they come. And use them as they pass by. I'll be at the Soffitel.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at the pipe again, and then starts to squeeze past it. It's a tight fit. She has to squirm to get through.</context>
      <utterance>Christ...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pops free and comes out the other side. She holds up the lighter. Still the light cannot reach to the end of the passage. Steeling herself, she moves on. But as she does, the space seems to get progressively narrower and narrower. From ten inches to nine, to eight, until both sides of her body are scraping against the walls. She holds the lighter out. The wall continues to narrow. At the end of her outstretched arm, the walls are only around five inches apart.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome to club anorexia...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amy Klein.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy pauses, unsure, then moves forward and takes a seat opposite him.</context>
      <utterance>I chose you.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was a hell of a way in. Makes me think that you don't want...</utterance>
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People come in here the way they want. If it was difficult, then that was the way you wanted it. A little danger. A little mystery. That's what you expected. That's what you found.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were you afraid, Amy? Just now? And during your little "rite of passage" through the walls?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Winter smiles, he displays amusement to Amy's suspicions.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Was it real?</utterance>
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And were you afraid when you saw Marla Chen? Of what you found in the bathroom?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Winter studies Amy.</context>
      <utterance>You took something from her?</utterance>
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Amy opens her bag and produces the Puzzle Box. She lays on the table between them.</context>
      <utterance>Do you have it with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My great grandfather created that box. He left it as a...gift. A way to cheat death, an entrance to everlasting pleasures, and it belongs to me. Though there are others who would disagree.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marla warned me about it, about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? Should I be honored or afraid that you are here, Amy Klein. Do you really think you can just go along with us for a little ride and then get off when it suits you? Like your new friends on the train? You're not going to find it so easy to get off this train.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I shouldn't get on?</utterance>
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your already on it. Don't dance with me, Amy Klein. Don't think for a second that you aren't in danger. You are in more danger than ever imagined possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Winter leans into Amy's space.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell does that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>INTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anything at all. I'm one of those things.</context>
      <utterance>Listen to me. There are things that are true in the light of day. There are other things that are no less true, that live in the shadows. When you shine a light on them, they disappear. They stop being true. That's because it is the uncertainty of the dark that makes them possible. If the dark is deep enough... anything might be happening in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to Marla Chen? What did you do to her? He stands and walks away from Amy.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marla? Why, I accepted her, that's all. That's all I've ever done for the people who come to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She didn't want to become one of you, whatever the hell you are. That's why she killed herself.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Winters studies Amy face.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, but she did. And what makes you so sure she's dead?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>48</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>WINTER The more she doubts, the deader she becomes. But she'll never really die, because she's not really alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She raps on the table with her middle finger, palm up. She then lifts her hand up keeping her middle finger towards Winter.</context>
      <utterance>That doesn't mean anything. What I saw in that room was real. What I smelled was real. Real like this table.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In a flash, almost supernaturally , Winter passes seemingly through the chair and is front of Amy, her hand held tightly by his. He reaches up with his other hand and uncurls Amy's fingers.</context>
      <utterance>Real like, like this hand...</utterance>
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He begins to move his fingers over her hand, enumerating the various parts.</context>
      <utterance>You say this is real?</utterance>
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The process is taking on an oddly seductive quality.</context>
      <utterance>Epidermis. The dorsal fascia. Transverse carpal ligament across here...</utterance>
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He begins to move his fingers through the spaces in between her fingers. Amy is frozen still.</context>
      <utterance>The median nerve underneath it. Down here, the carpal bones... And do you think that all those parts are what makes a hand? I'll show you what makes a hand... here...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BACK TO SCENE.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Close on Amy's hand, trembling in Winter's grip.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This thing here isn't a presence. It's an absence. It's a place where things are missing. In all essential qualities, it is less than nothing. In all essential qualities, we are less than nothing. Not solid, not here, not real. Amy finds herself responding, falling under his spell. Flashback:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you see?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you afraid of, Amy?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not afraid of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For a moment she appears to consider his offering. Then, as if waking up... she shoves herself back away from Winter.</context>
      <utterance>Yes you are, but still you can't run -- you won't run.  I wonder why that is?  I'm no devil. I'm no monster. Amy, I'll never hurt you and I'll never leave you. Amy doesn't answer. Winter extends to her a knife. WINTER  Accept my gift. No more fear. No more questions. No one can ever hurt you again.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But now the Dead are there, surrounding her, reaching out for her. They begin to chant. Winter takes the PUZZLE BOX and places on a makeshift altar at the head of the mattress.</context>
      <utterance>No, get... get away...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEADERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My skin isn't real. My eyes aren't real. My muscles aren't real. My bones, my heart, my veins and nerves, and flesh and meat... aren't real-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lie down Amy. It'll only hurt for a second. I promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEADERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- What I see, what I hear, what I taste, what I touch, what I remember, what I think, what I feel, aren't real.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Deaders start to grab onto her. She starts to panic a little. AMY (cont'd) No! She fights her way from the group and...</context>
      <utterance>No more pain. Only pleasure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amy it's Charles, I know it's not too late.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just can't go too long without hearing my voice.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy grabs the PUZZLE BOX off the table. She spins it in her hands.</context>
      <utterance>Guilty. Look, Amy, I've been thinking about the story about what happened, maybe this isn't for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charles, you know I value your opinion-</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- she said with condescension-</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- but if there was ever a story I was born to write, this is it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it's too dangerous, for a lot of reasons.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't like you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. I'm going to hate myself in the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just a little... fucked in the head. That's all. It's just a funk, but I'm fine. All I need is some sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OK. I just thought I'd put it out there to see if you'd bite. I should've known better. It goes against my instincts.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I love about you. I'll call you tomorrow.  Hey, Charles, did you know that the word "demon" comes from the Greek word for knowledge.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes I believe I've heard that somewhere before.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hangs up, and shuts off a light on her way to bed.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I wish somebody had told me about it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She clenches her eyes... opens them. Her fingers feel desperately for the metal tip between her breasts. It's still there.</context>
      <utterance>It's not real... it's not real.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts slapping her hands against the side of her face -- not gently, hard slaps. But she isn't "waking up." She grabs her hair, pulls hard. Nothing. She's still there. The knife is still stuck, impossibly in her back. She sits on the closed seat of the toilet... not knowing what to do. She reaches again for the knife, but she can't touch it. She buries her face in her bloody hands.</context>
      <utterance>Wake up... wake up... wake up...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"--to all of us - there comes the closing of the doors - the entrances - the exits - so that one may pass no more out or in..." He closes the book, turns toward her.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Walt Whitman. I like your taste in books.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy puts the phone back on the table.</context>
      <utterance>Came with the room. Along with the uncomfortable couch.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you? Why did you do this to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't. Believe me, when I want to hurt you, it will be more than a scratch.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why the hell are you here? Why are you in my room?</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't your room. It's mine...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is my room, my building, my street... my world. You still can't believe that you're in the "real" world, can you? I mean... you've just had a A knife run through you. Shouldn't it hurt?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a dream. I'm dreaming...</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Dreams come to an end. Nightmares are forever. He approaches her. She backs away.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've been recruited as a soldier in another man's war. A war he will never win, that I can assure you.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you're talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will. Soon enough. But one shouldn't worship false Gods. Especially when that false God is themselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not a believer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looks down at the blade jutting out from her chest.</context>
      <utterance>Oh you will. Tell me, do you believe in Hell?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Starting to.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grabs up the phone, flings it. It hits the far wall and falls to the floor. Winter's gone. She reaches a hand behind her, to her back, brings it back, red with blood.</context>
      <utterance>You opened a door. He pulled you in. But the only way out -- is through me. He steps towards her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well look who's back. What now?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need... please... please help me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy hesitates an instant, then tugs open her shirt, revealing the gaffer's tape that holds the rolled-up towel to her back. She works at it. Finally, it tears. She tears it straight down the front of her chest as Joey watches, passive. Her chest is stained with blood. She licks her fingers and wipes the blood away from the middle of her chest. Joey's eyes narrow. He leans forward to study it. He leans in closer, hesitates, then leans back, looking Amy in the eye.</context>
      <utterance>Help you with what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow, are those real?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amy doesn't react.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, you're not in the mood for my light- hearted banter. What the hell, this isn't my idea of paradise either.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand. Why aren't I dead? Or am I? Please...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Life, death, they're not all that different, really. You can find your death in your life. You can find your life in your death. Round and round and round you go.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, help me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am helping you.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets in his face.</context>
      <utterance>Then explain what the hell is going on. Why did I have a knife buried in my back? Why am I seeing dead people walking around? Why is there a guy with Pins in his head stopping by in the middle of the night for a chat.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a jolt as the train starts to pull into the station. The light from the station begins to illuminate the inside of the car more clearly. Joey leans back from her.</context>
      <utterance>Why am I not DEAD!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa. It's time to give in Amy, you're just fighting it too hard. Forget about the truth, forget about reality, just sit back and enjoy the ride. There's nothing you can do anyway. We're all just piece's in Winter's little puzzle.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The box.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're willing to do anything to find the truth.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>63</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's what I find most attractive about you. Well, that and the fact that you have a great ass. You and I are the same really, we're both willing to take it as far as it will go, to the edge, to the extreme. (beat) You know what our biggest problem is Amy Klein? Neither of us know when to get off the God damn train. The train jerks to a stop, tossing Amy a little. She regains her footage and turns back to Joey but in the flickering fluorescent light, Joey's skin suddenly looks sickly pale.</context>
      <utterance>JOEY</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't answer. He doesn't move.</context>
      <utterance>Joey?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He still doesn't move. Amy reaches out a shaky hand and takes his glasses off.</context>
      <utterance>Joey come on. Let's get off the train. Right now, you and me.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joey's eyes are empty, glazed. He's dead. Not only is he dead, it's clear that he's been dead for awhile. Then she freezes when she realizes the sound has completely dropped out around her. All she can hear is her heart beating. She slowly turns around to find that all of Joey's Celebrants on the train are also dead and surrounded by the familiar buzz of flies. Some of the dead are hung from the hand rails by HOOKS AND CHAINS, their throats slashed, eyes gouged, bullet holes in the head, etc... A large female cenobite is sewing the filleted skin from one Deaders throat open to reveal his vocal chords. He makes a sound at Amy and his chords vibrate. But there's this one COKE HEAD GUY who was snorting a line when Amy got on the train.</context>
      <utterance>You and me...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COKE-HEAD GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly all she can her is the LOUD ROAR OF THE TRAIN. Amy stumbles back, turns to run into the next train car and smacks right into- MARLA CHEN. A horribly decaying Marla Chen. At first Amy is confused but then something clicks behind her eyes as she shoves Marla back down the train car.</context>
      <utterance>Looks like the party's over.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The trains screeches into the station and the doors HISS</context>
      <utterance>Why did you do this to me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to go...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy looks down at her shirt as BLOOD begins to soak through it.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't have any other choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's happening to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla grabs her hand and starts to pull her along.</context>
      <utterance>You're dying.  Like me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. We've got to go!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy looks around the platform, as if deciding what to do. There's a little panic in Marla's voice.</context>
      <utterance>That's for you to decide.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see, that's the problem right there. I'm supposed to help you. Like... Like Winter helped me. But I don't know if I can.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why are you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To try... Because I have no other choice. No turning back now-  Know what I mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla gives her a comforting smile.</context>
      <utterance>No, I don't. I don't know one God damn thing anymore.  I just want to go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They jump down to an abandoned track and head into the darkness.</context>
      <utterance>Then let's go home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla's eyes are wet with yellowish tears.</context>
      <utterance>I put my head through a noose and I jumped ten feet down. They cut me down, and Winter breathed into me, and I was alive. And everybody was happy... and like, congratulating me...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And for a while, it was great. But it's like being a tightrope walker... you're walking along on this rope, and then all of a sudden, it's like you realize -- I'm walking on a rope a hundred feet up in the air. And that's when you fall.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode>( struggles to control herself)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tried to end it. That's when you found me.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you doing this? Why am I here?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The tunnel starts to take some weird twists and turns. They stop and Marla turns amy in her direction. The place starts to tremble, a train is approaching from far off.</context>
      <utterance>For the reward from it all.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it isn't enough for somebody else to stick a knife into you. You have to come to the point where you can do it to yourself -- that's the acceptance. The final preparation before you give your soul to it. Willingly.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But why? What it is all for?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the missing link. That part he keeps to himself. But he promises an eternal paradise filled with the ultimate pleasures. We just can't be afraid. And we can't have any doubts.  Guess I screwed up on that part.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy spins back to her. "Huh?"</context>
      <utterance>Fear is where you go to learn.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy's attention is on the train, it roars in at full throttle.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry. I told you there's no turning back Amy. Only he can bring you back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All roads lead home.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a sip of coffee. She struggles with the straps.</context>
      <utterance>Good morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes dart around the room in a panic.</context>
      <utterance>Amy don't fight it, it's only going to make things worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell happened?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She remembers.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't hear from you. I went over to your hotel. You were lying on the floor... covered in every kind of stuff that can come out of a human body...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy looks down at her gown, expecting a large red stain, but there's no blood.</context>
      <utterance>The blood...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Every other kind.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't... I mean I didn't...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy takes a look around the psych ward. PATIENTS walking aimlessly, mumbling to themselves, arguing with unseen opponents, rocking back and forth in catatonic states.</context>
      <utterance>You were sort of... having a psychotic episode, sweets. Major mental blow-out. And frankly, it's about time. Jesus you were tied down for a day and half.  Listen, I'm trying to get you out of here, back to London, but with the damage to your hotel room... They're not going to be so quick to let you go.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy feels a sudden rush of relief. A little nervous laughter.</context>
      <utterance>Look, Amy, you probably won't have to stay...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Charles, Charles... this is the best news I've had in a long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, there you go. A whole new definition of optimism.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Marla Chen? The story?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They found her dead in her room. She hung herself.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They found her. You mean the police?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. She'd been there awhile. Probably did it right after she sent us the tape.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, I don't know. Does it matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I guess not.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somebody pulls the curtain aside. It's an ORDERLY. His name tag identifies him as M. KIRCHER. This guy's a little out there, like maybe he's been dipping into the medicine cabinet a little too much. His eyes nervously scan the room, like somebody's watching him.</context>
      <utterance>But this is a good story too. Call it, "My Psychotic Episode" -- or, wait, maybe "Psychotic - Episode One." Or "Psychotic Pilot Episode." You know, some play on words with episode.  Look, there's a lot of raw material around here. Emphasis on the word "raw." Maybe they'll let you use a felt-tip pen or something to take notes.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She motions to the straps.</context>
      <utterance>Well look who's back. How we feelin?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trapped.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. They're for your own protection. The way you were flailing around when they brought you in -- somebody was bound to get hurt.  Get it. BOUND to get hurt.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>70</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amy doesn't laugh. Doesn't even crack a smile.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't quit your day job.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's say we lose the charm bracelets for now?  Unless of course you somehow find all of this -- stimulating.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kircher obliges and scribbles something on a folder at the end of the bed. Charles leans over, gives her a little peck on the cheek. As he does, he whispers to her.</context>
      <utterance>Don't drag me into your fantasies Charles.  Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands, winks at her.</context>
      <utterance>I'll see about getting a camera in here...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When you get a chance, check out the public area. It's a swinging place. I mean, like, they're literally... swinging. He heads out. Amy watches him go. She waits a beat, and then hops out of bed. She looks around for Nurses and Orderlies but there's no one around. She exits frame.</context>
      <utterance>Feel better.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mind if I join you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. I'm drawing pictures.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can see that, they're lovely.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want me to draw your picture?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Little Girl stares at Amy and focuses in on her features. We can't see what she's drawing as her little hand starts to move across the sketch pad. But there's something a little off. Her hand doesn't move like a six-year-old would draw, it moves with the confidence and control of an adult's. Amy tries to get a glance at the portrait. The Little Girl pulls it close to her.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like that very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No peaking.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a few more strokes the drawing is complete. The Little girl studies it, pleased with herself. She spins it so Amy -- but not the audience -- can see it. CLOSE ON AMY -- her eyes wide with terror.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, you're right.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>72</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's Amy's face as a CENOBITE, twisted and stretched in a way that begins to reveal the skull around her DARK EMPTY EYES. There's also that nasty knife wound in the center of her chest with hooks stretching the skin back and to the side.</context>
      <utterance>AMY'S POV as we get our first good look at it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>Amy backs away from her, trembling.</context>
      <utterance>I only draw what I see... Amy.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Little Girl giggles. Amy turns to the other drawings that the Little Girl has taped to the walls.</context>
      <utterance>How do you know my name?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy gets up to run but then she freezes when she sees- MARLA sitting on the opposite side of the room. But here's the thing. She looks fine. Amy walks over, hesitant, confused.</context>
      <utterance>No... this isn't happening.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla doesn't seem to recognize her.</context>
      <utterance>Marla?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marla! You're alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla takes a long quiet look around the room and then leans in close, unable to keep up her charade.</context>
      <utterance>You say that like it's a good thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know he's watching us.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Winter. This is where he sends all the trouble makers. Tries to show us who's boss. Tries to make us believe.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So it is real?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As real as you want it to be. We all have our own version of the truth, some are just more screwed up than others. But you wouldn't know that, because you still don't know the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla pokes a finger at Amy's heart. Right on her wound.</context>
      <utterance>You will. You see that's the point. All this, "Deaders", "Cenobites", whatever you want to call it, it's all about solving the puzzle. Part of that puzzle is you. Finding the secrets that are hidden within you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- in there. And as soon as you find that, as soon as you face it, you'll be free. Once and for all. he pulls back into her chair.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me -- I'm still looking.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what is it all for?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla stares at Amy deeply. The breaks into a smile.</context>
      <utterance>Ultimate pleasure -- more than anyone, even those who have solved the puzzle before us, have ever known. Conditions of the nerve endings the likes of which your imagination could not hope to evoke.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...at Least that's what they say.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's trying to give Amy a clue without tipping off anyone who might be watching her.</context>
      <utterance>Bingo baby. Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla looks down at Amy's chest. Amy follows her stare to find blood starting to soak through her hospital gown. Amy's eyes begin to glaze over.</context>
      <utterance>He has to be there for you Amy. And he will be. Like he was for all of us. That's the key. Without him, you can't come back. It's you he wants. Its you he needs. Remember that above all.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy leaps up from the table and suddenly Marla is gone. In fact the whole room is empty and dead quiet. A pool of blood lies beneath her seat. She staggers a bit as she moves forward.</context>
      <utterance>Looks like you're running out of time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>78</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>My bones, my heart, my veins and nerves, and flesh and meat... aren't real. What I see, what I hear, what I taste, what I touch, what I remember, what I think, what I feel, aren't real. With a glance she can see that the PUZZLE BOX, in its solved configuration, sits on a make-shift altar at the head of the mattress. WINTER is towering over her at her feet. He holds out a knife -- THE FAMILIAR STILETTO -- for her to take.</context>
      <utterance>DEADERS</utterance>
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy has a sudden look of resignation, mixed with a little relief. She reaches out and slowly takes the knife from Winter.</context>
      <utterance>You've gone through this before Amy. Go through it again -- with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The chanting continues.</context>
      <utterance>That's it. I knew you were the one. The second I saw you, I knew you were the one.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEADERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy looks at Marla. She looks deader then ever. She chants with the others. Winter holds the knife closer for Amy. Amy looks at the PUZZLE BOX. RAYS OF LIGHT start to stretch out like hands and swirl from the PUZZLE BOX.</context>
      <utterance>My skin isn't real. My eyes aren't real. My muscles aren't real. My bones, my heart, my veins and nerves, and flesh and meat... aren't real. What I see, what I hear, what I taste, what I touch, what I remember, what I think, what I feel, isn't real.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy's hands start to tremble.</context>
      <utterance>Say it with us Amy. You have to say it with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Deaders break the circle around Amy as more ARMS reach out from the void. The VOICES OF TORTURED SOULS, twisted and warped, scream out for help in the wind that BURSTS out of the void. HOOKS AND CHAINS reach out and grab the outstretched arms, dragging them back into the VOID. Back into Hell. The Deaders turn to Winter -- they're all a little freaked out. From the look on their faces it's clear that this isn't at all what they expected.</context>
      <utterance>Yes you can Amy. You're one of us now, all you have to do is take this final step and let the pain go. And welcome a world of ultimate pleasures. AN ARM, bluish white, stretches out from the VOID trying to grab Joey who ducks it's grasp.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are the naked chicks? The oil? The orgies? It's not what Winter expected either.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finish it Amy.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy steels herself with sudden resolve.</context>
      <utterance>Finish it!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see that evil does run in the family. inter is plays it tough. But it's all an act.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your lineage is of a craftsman. You should have stayed in the family business. I sacrificed my mortal self for that box.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's mine now. It belongs to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's where you're painfully wrong. We belong to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It created you, and it can destroy you.  Amy, finish it!</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pinhead takes in the Puzzle Box on the makeshift altar, the Deaders, Amy.</context>
      <utterance>When it is done with me -- perhaps -- but I'm afraid one's own personal hell is eternal, as you will soon see.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The box is not just the map of the road -- it is the road itself.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ultimate experience.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Experience is a funny thing boy, it likes to test us first and teach us later. Are you sure you can pass the test? Are you sure you want to?</utterance>
   <speaker>WINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pinhead smiles.</context>
      <utterance>You can't hurt me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not the first time I've heard that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Winter's screams subside as a rush of pain surges through him, numbing him. He's just able to turn his head to Pinhead and crack the slightest "fuck you" smile. Winter tries to talk, but the skin around his mouth is stretched too tight.</context>
      <utterance>And it won't be the last.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When you attempted to challenge evil you entered into my domain. There is no way in but through me. Pinhead gets in close to Winter's face.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now we can see the terror in Winter's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Careful what you wish for.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Winter screams as he is finally torn apart by the chains. Pinhead turns his attention to the DEADERS.</context>
      <utterance>It just might come true.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And out of the darkness an oversized MENACING CHAIN comes FLYING OUT, HARPOONING straight through the midsections of all the deaders lined on the right side of Amy. Piercing</context>
      <utterance>This world, it obviously disappoints you all. Perhaps that's why you choose to begin this journey. And as long as you so willingly accepted, allow me to finish off what he started.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then another chain HARPOONS the Deaders on the left side. The Deaders look like fish on a stringer. They dangle there, suspended by the chains.</context>
      <utterance>them at all different levels.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And as for you. You opened the box, you brought us all together. You chose wisely. I'm pleased.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy looks to Marla, she's got the fear of god in her. Pinhead sees Amy looking for help.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't want any of this. They used me to open the box. I didn't choose to do anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's one of us now Amy. Now a guide to the far reaches of pleasure. To a world where suffering is taken to higher level.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You opened the box.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean to. I only wanted the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And now you have it. But knowledge comes with a price -- and it's time to pay.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about them?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy grabs the knife from the floor and points it at Pinhead.</context>
      <utterance>They belong to me now. They offered themselves willingly through him to me -- And now it's time for you to do the same.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>These words pierce through Amy. She looks at Marla, now barely hanging on to any signs of liveliness. Her head lifts up to Amy.</context>
      <utterance>It won't be that easy this time. But yes, your Father is with us too. And he's waiting for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla looks at the knife. Amy gets it, she only has one way out. Marla can see the uncertainty in her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>You're here to stop this Amy. He needs your soul willingly. Don't let him take you. Don't go willingly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marla looks to Pinhead, then back to Amy. They both know what she has to do.</context>
      <utterance>Its over. Winter is gone. You can't come back. You won't become a Deader...or one of them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy points the knife at what's left of Winter.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't give my soul to him...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that Amy thrusts the knife into her chest. Pinhead screams out.</context>
      <utterance>...and I'm not giving it to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The room starts to fill with a BRIGHT LIGHT. The Puzzle Box starts to close as- Pinhead and the boys are sucked back into the void, which closes behind them. Amy looks up from the knife planted deep in her gut- - AND SMILES. She tips out of frame as the screen bleaches white and we-</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just talked to the Police. Still, nothing. She's just gone. Left her hotel, left her clothes, left her money. No sign of her anywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See no Amy. Hear no Amy...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just like Marla Chen. Apartment just left empty. No trace. The police say its to early to file an official report.  Do you think they she with foul play?</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
