<movie id="266" title="Hellbound Hellraiser II">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where am I?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Remember? You and your boyfriend... ?</context>
      <utterance>You're in the Malahide Institute. It's a psychiatric hospital. But, hey, don't feel judged - it was just the nearest place to bring you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Steve...</utterance>
   <speaker>RONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts a cigarette in his mouth and lights it.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. He's O.K. We sent him home hours ago. Jeez, what a story.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don't tell me acid's back in fashion?</context>
      <utterance>What was it, kid? Smack? Angel dust?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about? Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RONSON reaches in his jacket and flashes an I.D.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, excuse me...</utterance>
   <speaker>RONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY'S eyes prick with tears. She looks away from RONSON. KIRSTY (to herself) Daddy...</context>
      <utterance>Ronson. Homicide. I'm this district's slash and dash expert. Made a career of the nasty ones. That's why I was at your Dad's house. Jesus, what a mess.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CORTEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CORTEZ prods at the corpse with his night-stick, attempting to turn it over. A stream of maggots pours from the mouth and the cavity that used to be its throat. CORTEZ jumps back in disgust and knocks against one of the several wardrobes in the cluttered room. Another corpse flies out at him, as decayed and flvblown as the first. CORTEZ draws his gun and empties it blowing the corpses head off, scattering flesh, mucus, and bone - but no blood - everywhere before realizing it is already dead. He realises what he has done and lowers his weapon sheepishly.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus...</utterance>
   <speaker>CORTEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. shit...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>RONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds out his hand towards KIRSTY in a theatrical manner.</context>
      <utterance>We got two missing people and a house full of corpses.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY swings her legs off the bad, but remains sitting on it, her feet on the floor. She doesn't look directly at RONSON but begins to take in the (few) details of the room for the first time.</context>
      <utterance>Talk to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought Steve had talked to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY closes her eyes, almost wincing, as memory comes. KIRSTY opens her eyes. Consciously, she slows the rhythm of the dialogue down.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, pardon me. I obviously didn't convey my hesitation to take his story at face-value. No, YOU talk to me. But - do me a favor? - none of this DEMONS crap.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He talked about Demons, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY turns her head to look directly at RONSON.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RONSON stares at her, impressed by her conviction and intensity. There is a second of shared silence. Suddenly, a shocking ELECTRONIC CRACKLE shatters the mood. RONSON starts, then realises it is the radio at his belt. He snatches it up and speaks into it.</context>
      <utterance>It's true. All of it. It's all true.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ronson.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KUCICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kucich here,sir. We just found another one, though it suffered a little... KUCICH looks at CORTEZ, who looks embarrassed.</utterance>
   <speaker>KUCICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...er, accidental damage in discovery. Anyway, just about the only portable evidence we've got here - apart from human remains - is the mattress. Looks like someone was messed up real bad on it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KUCICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RONSON throws KIRSTY a look of exasperation with his colleague. The camera stays on KIRSTY's face as RONSON speaks.</context>
      <utterance>Can we send it downtown?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without waiting for a reply, RONSON switches the radio off and clips it back to his belt.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you asking me for? Tag it. Move it. KIRSTY  The mattress... The mattress... JULIA.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Polite laughter from several students.</context>
      <utterance>We can bring them back properly more often than scientific orthodoxy dictates, ladies and gentlemen. And the knife, far from the enemy of of analysis, is often its greatest ally in solving the puzzles of psychosis. Analysis isolates and massages. Surgery pinpoints and corrects. ... though you've got to know what you're doing, of course...</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He prods in at a specific area.</context>
      <utterance>Some things are obvious. Here, for example, ...</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The PATIENT begins to blink in time with MALAHIDE'S prodding. The affect is half-comical, half-distressing. Perhaps MALAHIDE carries it on just that half-second too long for innocent demonstration. But the students give impressed murmurs anyway.</context>
      <utterance>...are the optical motor nerve control centers.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he speaks, MALAHIDE injects a syringe directly into the PATIENT's brain. Her face spasms momentarily. MALAHIDE stands back slightly. His face is serene, calm, and confident. He takes a small, motorised drill and sets to work on the brain.</context>
      <utterance>Now. This case. A deeply-buried psychosis severe enough to produce frighteningly frequent hysteria and aggression. Incurable. Say others. Not so. Analysis isolates. The knife exposes. Medication controls.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks around at them all, smiling slightly.</context>
      <utterance>And then, ladies and gentlemen, we REBUILD. With all the care and knowledge that our years of training have given us ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INTERCOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MALAHIDE steps back briskly and begins to peel his cloves off. He nods at a nearby student.</context>
      <utterance>Dr. Malahide, the new arrival is awake, and appears very distressed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MALAHIDE and KYLE leave the room.</context>
      <utterance>My part in this is over. You may tidy up for me. Kyle, you come with me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>RONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy, easy. Whatever happened, whatever you saw, it's not here now.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw it...him. But I got away. And I took the box. And I solved it. And they came.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares directly at RONSON, daring him to disbelieve.</context>
      <utterance>The Cenobites.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RONSON stares back, perhaps a glimmer of belief in his eyes. On the soundtrack, the sudden and shocking sound of a door being slammed open and hitting the wall. KIRSTY screams. Even RONSON is startled. In the doorway are DOCTOR MALAHIDE and KYLE. MALAHIDE advances into the room, smiling apologetically as he does so.</context>
      <utterance>The Demons.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MALAHIDE holds his hand out, as RONSON nods in response.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry. Must get that door fixed. Detective Ronson?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man shake hands. MALAHIDE gestures behind him.</context>
      <utterance>I am Doctor Malahide.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MALAHIDE speaks quickly, as if to get the formalities out of the way. As he says her name, he smiles benignly at KIRSTY who, still distraught from her memories and shocked at the slamming of the door, simply stares at him. MALAHIDE turns his attention back to RONSON, drawing him away and speaking to him in a lower voice. Meanwhile, KYLE walks over to KIRSTY and smiles at her - long enough to embarrass her into smiling back.</context>
      <utterance>My assistant, Kyle Macrae. And this must be Kirsty?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RONSON looks over his shoulder at KIRSTY. He then looks carefully at MALAHIDE and then nods slowly.</context>
      <utterance>I've read the boy's statement. Quite the adventure they believe they had. I'd like to talk to her alone. Do you think ... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RONSON looks back at KIRSTY.</context>
      <utterance>Mmmm. O.K. Frankly, I think she's more your territory than mine. Shame.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY nods vaguely and then, just as RONSON reaches the door, calls out to him.</context>
      <utterance>Kirsty. Doctor Malahide's going to look after you now. Maybe we could talk some more tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RONSON smiles helplessly at her, then glances at MALAHIDE with a "you see what I mean" expression, and leaves the room. KIRSTY (to herself) The mattress ... MALAHIDE stares at her briefly, with a strange expression on his face and then abruptly follows RONSON through the door. KIRSTY is too absorbed to notice this odd behavior, but KYLE stares incredulously as MALAHIDE leaves the room.</context>
      <utterance>Wait! The mattress. You've got to destroy it. She DIED on it, you see. The mattress. It's haunted now. She can come back... like Frank. SHE CAN COME BACK.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He follows to the door and stands in the doorway, looking down the corridor.</context>
      <utterance>Uh...excuse me a moment.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So...You're Kirsty, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KYLE smiles again.</context>
      <utterance>You a doctor, too?</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY draws a deep breath, temporarily calmed. She even manages a smile.</context>
      <utterance>Nearly a doctor. I'm Kyle Macrae. Call me Kyle.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MALAHIDE re-enters the room.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Kyle.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY looks at him warily.</context>
      <utterance>Now, Kirsty...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The cop. He didn't believe me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suspect not. But that doesn't necessarily mean you're wrong, does it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MALAHIDE offers a re-assuring laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Do you believe me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>YOU believe this is the truth.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't know yet. However, you're not lying.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, the door opens again. An INTERN is standing there. For the briefest of moments, MALAHIDE looks furious and then, catching himself, assumes his calm demeanor.</context>
      <utterance>It IS the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well?</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MALAHIDE sighs.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Dr. Malahide. But it's Tiffany. She's escaped ... again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks down at KIRSTY.</context>
      <utterance>Very Well.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MALAHIDE and KYLE follow the intern from the room, KYLE giving a last friendly smile as the door closes behind them.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Kirsty. Kyle will come back with something to help you sleep. We shall speak tomorrow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MALAHIDE.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The image of MALAHIDE (and we shouldn't he sure yet if we're looking at a reflection or the real man) puts its hands out, palms up.</context>
      <utterance>Everything stops.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All the TIFFANYS move quietly toward him until they all disappear from view. Then the real TIFFANY comes into shot, her back to us, and walks toward what we now see to be the real MALAHIDE, who is standing in a doorway deliberately framed like a mirror to confuse the customers. TIFFANY places her hands docilely on to MALAHIDE's outstretched ones.</context>
      <utterance>Tiffany. Come.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>KYLE.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>KYLE raises his hand in apology.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY nods and gives a nervous smile. KYLE, still embarrassed by his foolishness and eager to change the subject, nods towards the glass panel.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jesus, I'm sorry. God, if anyone should know not to do that, it's me. I'm sorry. O.K.?</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sad, huh? She's been here six months. Her name's TIFFANY.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter with her?</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Almost complete withdrawal. She hasn't said a word for nearly two years.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, that's terrible.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KYLE ushers KIRSTY back into her own room.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Doctor Malahide's got her doing these jig-saws and things, though. Says it's helping to bring her out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY looks up at him sharply. He is proffering a pill and grinning facetiously.</context>
      <utterance>Anyway, let's concentrate on you for a moment. Wanna suck on this for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KYLE's face falls. He blushes. Pressing the pills into KIRSTY's hand, he backs off to the door, apologising.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, good joke, Kyle. Do you always come on to the mentally ill?</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He exits hurriedly, closing the door behind him. KIRSTY grins despite herself. She looks at the pill for a second or two and then puts it firmly back in the box. Realising there is no bedside table, she puts the box on the wooden chair.</context>
      <utterance>Shit. Sorry. Here's the pills. Red face. Door. Bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is about to lie down on the bed, when she senses something is wrong in the room. KIRSTY is instantly tense again. She swings her head to the side and tenses in horror, stifling a scream. In the corner of the room, against the wall lying in a pool of blood, is her skinned father LARRY. KIRSTY emits a pained moan of pure anguish as she realises what she is looking at.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus, I'm glad I'm not paying for this place.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The thing in the corner raises its arm weakly from its side and begins to write on the wall in its own blood. It writes : I AM IN HELL; HELP ME. KIRSTY covers her eyes with her hands and begins to sob. KIRSTY takes her hands from her eyes. The figure has gone. The pool of blood has disappeared. But, on the wall the words remain. KIRSTY makes herself rise from the bed and walk slowly across the room. Her eyes full of tears, she stretches out her arm and touches the word 'I'. As her fingers make contact, the words instantly disappear. She presses her bloodied finger quickly to her lips before that last trace of her father can vanish, too.</context>
      <utterance>Daddy...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He-doesn't stop his progress but walks straight through the room and into the corridor. As the door closes behind him the WHEELCHAIR PATIENT scowls.</context>
      <utterance>Better? Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>W/CHAIR PATIENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>105 years and he still doesn't know my name.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I...I had a visitor.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jesus. I can't explain. It's ...it's. I don't know how to help! I have to save him and I don't know how to help!</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kirsty, I'm sorry... don't understand. I...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KYLE responds quickly to this. His faith in MALAHIDE is strong, despite that curious incident of the previous night when MALAHIDE followed RONSON out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>I know. No-one can. But I have to save him. Where's the other doctor? He said He'd listen. He promised.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KYLE stands up, making soothing motions with his hands, and heads for the door.</context>
      <utterance>Dr. Malahide. Yes. Look, I'll fetch him. You take it easy. I'm sure he can help.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Help. No, no-one can help. I just want someone to listen or I WILL go crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY turns and gives KYLE a strange look as he opens the door.</context>
      <utterance>If anyone can help, HE can.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? He got a ticket to Hell?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear the phone click. KYLE waits a moment and then walks swiftly through the door, speaking as he does so.</context>
      <utterance>Officer Kucich? Yes, Doctor Malahide. You've spoken to Ronson? Yes ... That's right. The mattress ... No, I'll meet you by the side entrance. No, no, my HOUSE. Yes, let me make that clear. The house, NOT the hospital. ... Yes ... Fine, and thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doctor Malahide ... ?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her voice trails off. We pull out to see KIRSTY sitting up on her bed. MALAHIDE on the wooden chair, and KYLE standing by the door. MALAHIDE's voice pulls her back.</context>
      <utterance>It must have been going on forever...</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY snaps back and continues to speak in a more normal voice.</context>
      <utterance>Kirsty...?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But the part I know about, That must have started with my Uncle Frank...</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then let us speak of it ...</utterance>
   <speaker>DISSOLVE TO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We TRACK in slowly towards a modern house that we will learn is MALAHIDE'S, up the drive, towards the front door.</context>
      <utterance>36 EXT. MALAHIDE's HOUSE TWILIGHT</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We assume he has visited MALAHIDE'S house before, but he has clearly never seen this room. He stares at the mattress with incredulity, as if he still can't believe his superior has had it brought here. Then he begins to look around the room in more detail. He approaches the glass cases and bends slightly to look at their contents. KYLE shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ. Jee-sus-kerr-ist!</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her voice is perfect. MALAHIDE stares at her, his fascination intense. He crosses the few yards that separate them. He looks at her, lying beside the hollow shell that was CHEYNEY. Her eyes stare back, brilliant, sparkling, alive.</context>
      <utterance>Help me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MALAHIDE realises her temporary vulnerability; all the life force she has absorbed from BROWNING has made up her body, but it will take some moments for the strength to return to her. Fascinated and sympathetic as he is however he cannot yet quite brine himself to touch this creature. Instead he moves the mattress nearer to her, allowing her to crawl back onto it and lie down again. MALAHIDE stares down at her. He attempts a smile, but is too nervous to make it convincing. He is trembling slightly. This contact with the beyond is something he has dreamt of for years, but nevertheless the physical reality is overwhelming. JULIA treats him to the approximation of a smile. She is far from nervous. She studies herself. Her figure is fully formed, her womanliness undeniable. All she is missing is a skin. She stretches her arms. She lifts her legs. She writhes on the bed in pleasure, like an X- ray photograph of a calendar girl. MALAHIDE stares at her, following the sensual movements of her body. He swallows, a little embarrassed by his response to the naked display he is privileged to watch. JULIA'S eyes twinkle at him.</context>
      <utterance>Help Me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks away and continues her stretching and wiggling, more conscious of it now as an erotic display. The strength has flooded through her body as she rises to her feet, and stops off the mattress, smiling at MALAHIDE. MALAHIDE backs away from her as she moves towards him, doing his best to return her smile. After a few steps, JULIA stops and simply stares into MALAHIDE'S eyes. He too stops and returns the gaze. The camera circles them slowly several times, studying them - the dressed, nervous man and skinned, confident woman.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be embarrassed. You're my friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MALAHIDE says nothing. Perhaps he swallows nervously. The camera continues its circling movements. The scene FADES TO BLACK and JULIA begins to laugh, small, sensual giggles at first building finally as the blackness comes into an almost hysterical crescendo of raucous joy.</context>
      <utterance>Well?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She was angry, relieved, and amused when she realized it was KYLE and all these showed in her voice and face. Now they drop away completely, replaced by a nervous apprehension as she becomes aware of the blank horror on his face.</context>
      <utterance>Shit, Kyle. This is getting to be a habit. What is it, some kind of shock-therapy?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KYLE opens his mouth a few times, as if unsure what to say.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jesus. What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all true.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MALAHIDE'S nervousness has retreated a little, he manages to smile. He nods his head slowly a few times.</context>
      <utterance>Well?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... Yes. You look...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Surreal? Strange? Nightmarish?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JULIA doesn't wait for an answer. She crosses to the table and takes up his glass of wine. She downs it in one. MALAHIDE stares at her, a little surprised.</context>
      <utterance>No. You look... He pauses, lost for words.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles strangely at him and then moves closer. Slowly, keeping her eyes on his, she reaches into his breast pocket for his packet of cigarettes and places one in her mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I still like WINE ...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For a moment, MALAHIDE's face is stone. Then, slowly, he returns her smile and, drawing his lighter, lights her cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>... and more.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MALAHIDE does so. He understands and tries to console her..</context>
      <utterance>Close it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a beautiful dress...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JULIA lifts her arms slightly to look at them and then touches her bandaged face. She turns towards MALAHIDE. The camera begins the same circling movement it made around them the previous night. MALAHIDE'S nervousness has practically disappeared. He has helped this woman. He has bandaged her and dressed her. He is slightly in awe of her, but it is now tinged with excitement, not fear. The camera's circling grows faster.</context>
      <utterance>There...</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JULIA walks towards him, slowly raising her hands. When she is close enough her hands cup his cheeks. She pulls him towards her, and, tipping her head to one side, kisses him. Her body moulds itself to his. She leans her head back. Were they have kissed blood has pressed up onto the bandage from her skinned flesh. It looks like smeared lipstick.</context>
      <utterance>Well?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MALAHIDE puts his arms around her waist. They kiss tenderly. Slowly, almost nervously, he lowers his hands until they rest on her buttocks and presses her in towards him. They begin to spin themselves now, echoing the camera movements. They cross the room, kissing blindly, until they come to rest against the wall that bears JULIA's bloody palm print. JULIA twists their bodies so that MALAHIDE is pressed against the wall, and begins to move her hips forcefully and sensually against</context>
      <utterance>Well?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>You O.K.?</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The bathroom door opens and KIRSTY Comes into the main room, dressed in a toweling robe that is clearly a 'hers' not a 'his'. She crosses the room to a mirror, rubbing at her wet hair with a towel.</context>
      <utterance>Kirsty? You 0. K.?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No bad dreams.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY gestures at the sofa.</context>
      <utterance>So you slept O.K.?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KYLE glances meaningfully at the bed as he replies.</context>
      <utterance>As much as that bed of nails allowed.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, the sofa isn't often used for sleeping on...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KYLE grins.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah? On your own a lot, Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY returns the smile via the mirror. KYLE crosses the room to sit at his dining table. Empty coffee cups, the remnants of a loaf and some cheese suggests their breakfast was simple and finished some time ago. KIRSTY gathers her clothes from by the sofa and moves back into the bathroom to dress. KYLE waits a few moments and then speaks.</context>
      <utterance>Like the robe?</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY emerges, fully dressed, her hair still damp.</context>
      <utterance>I think I need to talk. About what I saw.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KYLE spreads his hands wide.</context>
      <utterance>You thought I was crazy, didn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grins wryly. KIRSTY moves to the sofa and sits down.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus, yes! What do you expect. I mean, God, I still do! It's just that now I'm crazy too.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you're sure it was a woman?</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY grins at him.</context>
      <utterance>God, I wish I could say no. This is going to do terrible things to my attitude, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about it. Your attitude sucks anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For a moment, they laugh together but then stop. KIRSTY stares downward and then suddenly bursts into tears.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, so for it. Don't let pity stop you. I'm down. Nail me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KYLE joins her on the sofa. He offers an arm but she shakes it off.</context>
      <utterance>What can I do? How can I save him?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The box. I need the box.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY's tears suddenly stop. She looks at KYLE.</context>
      <utterance>The box? Like in your story? Like in his house?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Boxes. In the House. I told you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The boxes! I TOLD you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You DIDN'T tell me. Do you mean Malahide's got...</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY heads instantly for KYLE'S door.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. The things you were talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KYLE runs across the room and puts a restraining hand on his door.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY nods and pulls at the door handle.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute. What do you mean, 'I'm going?' TO the HOUSE?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get out of the way.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you crazy?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, Kyle. You're the fucking expert. Now get out of the way!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a two-second silence between them as they stare at each other. Finally, Kyle backs away from the door, raising a finger.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to get my father.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rushes across the room, grabs a jacket, and moves back to the door.</context>
      <utterance>Two seconds. Just two seconds. Don't move.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>O.K. Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kyle, you don't have...</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY stares at him, her face at first blank then suffused with emotion. She leans across and plants a chaste kiss on his lips then pulls back. There is a beat while they simply stare at each other and suddenly they are tight in each other's arms, kissing fervently. But the kiss is fuelled, not by passion, but by fear and their mutual need for human solace in the face of the unknown. As the kiss continues, the camera pulls back from them.</context>
      <utterance>I KNOW I don't have to. It's just my time of the month to be a complete fucking idiot. O.K.?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sssh. I think it's still here.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JULIA nods.</context>
      <utterance>What? The...The thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It ...It's just TERRIBLE.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. I had to stop you going in there because I knew you'd cry out. Any normal person would.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KYLE swallows, nods, and gently, pushes the door open. He walks into the room.</context>
      <utterance>No. Not now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KYLE stares all around him. All eight victims have been sucked dry. He is surrounded by dead husks. His face is ghastly. He looks like he is about to faint. He nods. His voice is a cracked whisper.</context>
      <utterance>Was I right? Is it terrible?</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JULIA crosses the room rapidly towards him. Her face is a picture of concern.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Yes, it's terrible.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she speaks, JULIA's arms are opening out to him. KYLE sees the comfort offered and advances towards her, too. As they come together, the camera moves around them and we see, for the first time, that JULIA is still incomplete; Her entire back is still glistening raw flesh, the naked bones of the spine still clearly visible. Their arms go around each other just as JULIA completes her speech;</context>
      <utterance>Oh. You look awful. You poor boy. Come here...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As KYLE's hands touch the sticky, mucoid meat of her shoulders, it is instantly clear to him what has happened. For a moment he freezes in terror. His arms fly from her and he throws his head back. But JULIA is very strong now and her grip does not relax. Kyle's expression is a mixture of terror and confusion as he stares into the beautiful face of the monster. JULIA smiles at him, a hungry, aroused smile.</context>
      <utterance>...Come to Mother ...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KYLE can hardly speak for fear.</context>
      <utterance>What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kyle...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She raised one hand from his back to the back of his head and presses his face to hers. JULIA plays it exactly as a sensual, passionate kiss, her mouth wide open, her head moving rhythmically and sinuously. KYLE's reaction is somewhat different; his arms flail in panic (though only from the elbow - JULIA'S grip prevents anything more) and his head makes jerking, backward movements against her pressing hand. The camera moves around the embracing couple until it is behind</context>
      <utterance>I'm JULIA.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She folds up the photograph and puts it in her pocket. She crosses to the door and opens it. She does not go through it immediately but stands in the doorway for a moment, her hand still on the door, cocking her head slightly as if listening.</context>
      <utterance>Kyle...?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She can't hear anything, but she regards that as a bad sign, not a good one. She leaves the room.</context>
      <utterance>Kyle?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JULIA glances meaningfully at the dead thing that lies beside her feet and then back at KIRSTY.</context>
      <utterance>Kirsty! How nice of you to drop in.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY's fear and disgust are momentarily displaced by a furious rage as she realises what JULIA has done. Her face erupts into anger and she screams out.</context>
      <utterance>You have surprisingly good taste in men.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She flings herself across the room at JULIA even as she speaks. JULIA is completely unphased by this attack and simply raises one arm. She siezes the wrist of the arm that KIRSTY has raised into a clenched fist and effortlessly throws KIRSTY bodily back across the room. We realise for the first time the immense physical strength that JULIA now possesses. KIRSTY smashes into the door and falls to a sitting position against it. She is shaken and slightly hurt enough not to get to her feet immediately but she stares at JULIA with undimmed hatred. JULIA throws a look halfway between a smile and a sneer.</context>
      <utterance>Kyle! No! I'll kill you, you...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you can try it, you little bitch. I'd love you to try it. But I'm not just the woman I was.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, you mean you're something more than a whore with a vicious streak?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JULIA snaps this first line but then holds her anger in check. She shakes her head and an amused smile plays across her lips.</context>
      <utterance>I mean I'm something more than human, you little shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The smile disappears and she delivers the next line with an utterly straight face. It is, after all, the truth.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Kirsty. They didn't tell you, did they? I'm afraid they've changed the rules of the fairy tale; I'm no longer just the wicked step-mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now I'm the Evil Queen. The hatred and the heat returns to her voice.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY scrambles to her feet and again charges at JULIA. JULIA steps forward to meet her advance and delivers a single back-handed swipe across KIRSTY's face with such force that not only is the girl knocked off her feet but is actually knocked unconscious. KIRSTY rolls onto her back and lies at JULIA's feet. JULIA stares down at the unconscious body. When it was awake, it was KIRSTY and her attitude to it was based on personal enmity. Now, it is simply another body and she judges it differently; it is firm, full, healthy, and young. We see the expression on her face change from hatred and triumph to pure appetite. She licks her lips and her eyes glisten. She begins to bend slightly towards it.</context>
      <utterance>So come on; Take your best shot, Snow White.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door to the room opens. JULIA straightens up and looks as MALAHIDE stands in the doorway. Her eyebrows question this interruption. A second later, and it is explained. He leads TIFFANY into the room.</context>
      <utterance>Julia!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MALAHIDE doesn't take his eyes from the window.</context>
      <utterance>You're sure this is what you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pauses. Perhaps he is being ungallant. He turns slightly towards JULIA and takes her hand.</context>
      <utterance>It's what I've ALWAYS wanted. A view of ... beyond.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were almost enough, Julia but...I have to see. I have to</utterance>
   <speaker>KNOW.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>JULIA smiles indulgently. She nods.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I quite understand.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's done it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She certainly has.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MALAHIDE turns away to meet her eyes. There is a beat or two where absolutely nothing happens. The mirror explodes inwards into the alcove.</context>
      <utterance>It certainly is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The FEMALE stops and looks questioningly at PINHEAD. PINHEAD, at a more leisurely pace, crosses towards TIFFANY and looks down at her. She stares back at him, the remnants of her insanity a temporary defense against fear, her face registering nothing. PINHEAD looks up.</context>
      <utterance>Wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The FEMALE looks across at him.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>CENOBITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PINHEAD shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>No?</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances down at TIFFANY again.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up and stares directly at the shattered two-way mirror.</context>
      <utterance>It is not HANDS that call us...</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... It is DESIRE.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY begins to move into the room slowly and shakes her head gently.</context>
      <utterance>Wait. Wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY is rewarded with a small recognizing smile from TIFFANY, KIRSTY returns the smile.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, remember me? From the hospital? I was in the next room?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TIFFANY turns her head once more to look down the corridor and then turns back to KIRSTY. For a second it looks as if KIRSTY's persuasions have succeeded, but MALAHIDE's training has been too thorough; TIFFANY knows a puzzle when she sees one. She smiles once more at KIRSTY and then suddenly turns and disappears into the corridor. KIRSTY stands still for a moment, as if she can't quite believe that TIFFANY has done it. She shakes her head - half in disbelief and half in despair.</context>
      <utterance>You don't want to go down there. You REALLY don't want to go down there.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pausing only to pick up the LAMENT CONFIGURATION from where TIFFANY has left it on the floor, She heads straight for the corridor and follows TIFFANY in.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her voice has an unpleasant ring in the acoustics of these corridors and echos horribly. KIRSTY pulls a face and doesn't shout again. She increases her pace slightly. Suddenly TIFFANY makes a sharp turn and enters an intersecting corridor. KIRSTY is forced to increase her speed even more. KIRSTY too makes the turn into another corridor. Even as she does so, she sees TIFFANY disappearing again into yet another intersection. KIRSTY follows and, again, the same thing happens. This happens several times and, always, KIRSTY never quite loses sight of TIFFANY but never quite catches up with her either. In short, TIFFANY's instincts were absolutely right; this too is another puzzle. The girls are lost in a concrete maze, full of twists and turns and labyrinthine windings. After enough turns have been made to completely confuse KIRSTY's sense of direction, she makes a final turn into one corridor and sees something different. At the end of this corridor is a blinding white light. As soon as KIRSTY sees the light, the air is filled with beautiful birdsong. TIFFANY disappears into the light as soon as KIRSTY sees it. Despite the light, despite the birdsong, KIRSTY is still suspicious and shouts out.</context>
      <utterance>Tiffany. Wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But it is too late. The girl is gone. KIRSTY follows-and vanishes into the light.</context>
      <utterance>Tiffany! Don't trust it! Don't Trust it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY puts down the photograph of her family and looks around the room again. A troubled look crosses her face. Despite the aparent Summer light in the room, KIRSTY suddenly realises what it is that is odd. She looks from wall to wall with mounting distress on her face. There are no windows in the room. And no door. At this point, the odd discordant note in the birdsong becomes apparent. It is nothing too obvious at the moment - the total effect is simply less sweet than it was. KIRSTY looks back at the photograph and snatches it up, with a look of concern. The photograph has changed. It is now a wedding photo. The wedding of LARRY and JULIA. Suddenly the photograph begins to bleed. Blood pours from the paper itself, pressing up and smearing against the glass-so that it is momentarily framed blood, without a single trace of the picture showing. The blood begins to escape out of the frame, trickling over the lip that holds the glass in place and dripping onto KIRSTY's fingers. With a cry of horror, KIRSTY drops the frame. It lands on the floor and the glass shatters. The blood continues to flow. In fact, now that the glass does not restrain it, it fairly fountains out, spreading across the floor. KIRSTY steps back and glances at the dresser. Blood is flowing from every frame, pooling on the dresser and overflowing onto the floor. By now, the discordant elements in the birdsong are very much predominant and, as KIRSTY sweeps all the frames off the dresser and onto the floor with a scream of anguish, the birdsong gives way completely to a hideous, dissonant shrieking. KIRSTY throws her hands to her ears.</context>
      <utterance>Mommy...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rushes at one of the walls and begins beating it with her fists. The walls are soft and pulpy and give slightly as her fists strike, like flabby flesh. KIRSTY stands back in disgust. The wall visibly bruises before her eyes, swelling and purpling. The light in the room, like the birdsong, has changed utterly. It is not dark, but simply dull, featureless, and depressing. KIRSTY turns away in disgust and finds that the whole room has given in to decay. The sofas and chairs are mildewed and rotten, the wooden furniture is ridden with woodworm and rot. A skinned rat runs across the room beside the buckled and chipped skirting board. A rotten leg gives way under a small chest and the bottom drawer spills out, freeing a whole family of quite large spiders which run wildly across the floor. Suddenly the room begins to fill with smoke, churned up by an ever-increasing intensity of wind. The smoke obscures the screen.</context>
      <utterance>Nooooo!</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY swings round in terror. As the mist continues to clear, she sees, advancing to join PINHEAD, the FEMALE CENOBITE and the CHATTERER. Beyond them, it is now revealed, that this chamber has no fourth wall; it gives directly onto the corridors</context>
      <utterance>Ah, Kirsty. And we thought we'd lost you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE CENOBITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY begins to work furiously at the BOX she has brought from MALAHIDE's house. It sent them away at the end of HELLRAISER. She obviously hopes it will work again. PINHEAD raises a hand and the box simply flies out of KIRSTY's hands and hovers in the air between them. KIRSTY stares, open- mouthed.</context>
      <utterance>So sweet of you to come back.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We're already here. And so are you. Suddenly PINHEAD works at the box himself - by remote control and with dazzling skill. He turns the box rapidly through positions KIRSTY and we have never seen before - even opening it out at one stage into a large, two-dimensional square. Finally, it closes itself down - but in a wholly new shape; a white, multi-faceted, diamond shape - and drops back into KIRSTY's hands. He stares at KIRSTY and makes a small gesture with his brow. It is ALMOST cute. If anything, it resembles the cocky, aren't-I- clever look STEVE gave KIRSTY after swallowing the cigarette in HELLRAISER. Then his face assumes its normal deadly blankness. KIRSTY shakes her head dumbly and begins to back into a corner, hoping that if they converge on her, she might just be able to slip around them and get back to the labyrinth.</context>
      <utterance>How can it send us back, child?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! You... You can't! It wasn't me...I didn't do it! I didn't open the box!</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE CENOBITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't open the box. And what was it last time? Didn't know what the box was. And yet we DO keep finding each other, don't we?</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Kirsty; so eager to play, so reluctant to admit it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE CENOBITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>To some extent, KIRSTY's ploy is working. The CENOBITES are moving closer together as they advance to the corner in which she stands.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps you're teasing us. Are you teasing us?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I didn't open it! I didn't!</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why are you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY shouts this with brave defiance. PINHEAD laughs in response, a very unattractive sound.</context>
      <utterance>I've come for my father!</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly KIRSTY makes her break shouting out as she does so.</context>
      <utterance>But he's in his own Hell, child And quite unreachable.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It seems for a moment she has succeeded. She swings around the side of the CENOBITES and begins to run across the chamber. The CENOBITES do not move but suddenly, from nowhere a hook flies across the room, attached to a metal chain. The hook buries itself in the wall only inches in front of KIRSTY's face, the chain pulled tight and barring her path. The wall begins to bleed. KIRSTY screams. The CENOBITES turn to face her, but make no attempt to cross the room to her new position.</context>
      <utterance>I don't believe you!</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just as you are in yours.</context>
      <utterance>But it's true, He is his own Hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PINHEAD almost smiles at the naivete of the question.</context>
      <utterance>And what about you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's different for us.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE CENOBITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've always been here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, as quickly as it came, the hook withdraws from the wall and flies back into nothingness. PINHEAD puts out his hand in an expansive gesture.</context>
      <utterance>We have no more surprises.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, please; feel free. Explore. We'll always be here...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MALAHIDE shakes his head crazily from side to side and begins to back away. JULIA looks at him and walks toward him slowly. She smiles. She strokes his cheek. She moves closer, gently slipping her arms around him and molding her body to his. She extends her tongue and licks lightly at his lower lip. He opens his mouth and returns the kiss, pressing her body more firmly to him. The kiss becomes quite passionate.</context>
      <utterance>Come. I have such sights to show you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY stops walking and catches hold of TIFFANY's arm. TIFFANY stops, looks at the hand holding her arm, and then looks into KIRSTY's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Do you see? You were RIGHT. This IS a puzzle, too. But WE'RE CAUGHT in the puzzle.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TIFFANY smiles directly at KIRSTY and then returns her nod.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TIFFANY nods again, more emphatically.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY throws her arms around TIFFANY and hugs her.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JULIA smiles at him.</context>
      <utterance>Enough. God, that's enough. We HAVE to go back.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MALAHIDE's jaw drops.</context>
      <utterance>Go back? What an earth makes you think we can go back?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to go back!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MALAHIDE, with a glance back at the maggot pool, turns after the now departing JULIA.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, friend. No day trips to Hell. Here you are. Here you stay. And forward the only way to go. JULIA turns back and walks an down the corridor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY stops dead in her tracks. She looks at the door and moves toward it, walking slowly down the corridor. TIFFANY follows.</context>
      <utterance>Kirsty!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Only a low moan comes from behind the door.</context>
      <utterance>Daddy...?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leaving TIFFANY in the corridor, KIRSTY opens the door and steps in.</context>
      <utterance>Tiffany. Wait here. If I'm not back real soon - get out. Get home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A low moan comes from the far end of the room. KIRSTY assumes it issues from the figure hidden beneath the blanket and walks nearer, lifting her arm in readiness to remove the blanket.</context>
      <utterance>daddy...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is no response. KIRSTY arrives at the mattress and pulls the blanket back. She leaps backwards, her hand at her mouth stifling a scream. Lying on the bed is a husk like figure, vaguely female in shape. Despite its appearance of long decay, it is dressed in vaguely sexual garments of leather. Suddenly, the eyes pop open, revealing a vague remnant of life.</context>
      <utterance>Daddy. It's Kirsty...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY hurriedly, throws the blanket back over it. A voice issues into the room. It sounds like LARRY but, as we shall see, it is not.</context>
      <utterance>Oh God.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY walks carefully around the screen, giving it a wide berth in case of a trick. There is a figure standing against the wall behind the screen. It is deeply shadowed by the screen itself but is clearly male. KIRSTY gulps back a sob and her eyes fill with tears.</context>
      <utterance>No. Over here. Behind the screen.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The figure leans slowly into the light, speaking as he does so.</context>
      <utterance>Daddy... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY stands still. There is a second where her face registers nothing. Then she screams.</context>
      <utterance>That's it, baby. Come to Daddy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY's anger at being tricked wins over her fear and distress and she shouts at FRANK in fury.</context>
      <utterance>What's the matter, Kirsty? It's only Frank. It's only Uncle Frank.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FRANK sneers.</context>
      <utterance>I should have known! I should've known he wouldn't be here! This place is only for filth like you!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, right. Daddy's died and gone to heaven, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FRANK pauses and smiles. Then he begins to move more fully into the room, shifting his weight as he does so and dragging what was hidden into the light. KIRSTY screams again. FRANK's white shirt is cut off at the left shoulder. His arm is bare and, from the elbow down to the wrist, joined to another forearm. The flesh is completely fused, like that of siamese twins. As FRANK moves into the room, the owner of the other arm is revealed. It is his brother, LARRY. KIRSTY's father. LARRY, like his brother, is dressed in a white shirt (cut off at one shoulder) and jeans and, like his brother, has his skin back. His face is frozen into a permanent expression of terror and he seems incapable of any independent movement, simply being pulled along by FRANK. KIRSTY steps back in horror.</context>
      <utterance>Shit. Bull. Shit</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See? He's here. You should learn to believe your Uncle Frank.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! He SHOULDN'T be here! It SHOULD'VE been a trick!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY's fear of FRANK is now outweighed by her contempt for his argument.</context>
      <utterance>'Fraid not, baby. He belongs here. With me. We're the same. Brothers. Equal and opposite. Pure appetite. Pure banality. Too much feeling. None at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY's voice breaks.</context>
      <utterance>You're full of shit, Frank Cotton. My Dad wasn't like that at all. He could feel. He could love. He loved ME.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He...he loved me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her hatred for FRANK gives KIRSTY her strength back.</context>
      <utterance>Don't waste your tears. Look at him!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FRANK begins to move towards KIRSTY again, LARRY dragging behind him.</context>
      <utterance>He loved me, you bastard! He Loved me, he loved my mother. He even loved that bitch you betrayed him with!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FRANK is very close to her, now. KIRSTY attempts to run across the room. FRANK siezes her arm and throws her back against the wall. He moves in close and presses against her. His voice is midway between arousal and anger.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, Julia. She hasn't been to see me recently. That's why it's so nice to have you here, baby. Daddy's little girl. So pretty when she's upset. Come to Daddy,</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY screams and stares pleadingly, at the still frozen LARRY.</context>
      <utterance>Now don't be naughty, Kirsty. Or I'll have to punish you first. Perhaps you'd like that. Would you like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Daddy! Daddy! I love you! Help me!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FRANK leans in to kiss the terrified KIRSTY. Suddenly, a hand appears at FRANK's throat and hurls him off KIRSTY. It is LARRY, roused by his daughter's cries.</context>
      <utterance>I'm your Daddy now, Kirsty.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, the room, previously full of slow movements and tension, is full of furious, violent action as the fused brothers kick, tear, and punch at each other in a paroxysm of killing hatred.</context>
      <utterance>Get your fucking hands off my daughter, you bastard!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! No! Julia! Help me! MALAHIDE is held in the air as JULIA replies.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she says this two of the thing's facets part to reveal a raw and gaping cavity lined with angry, sore-looking purple flesh directly behind the dangling MALAHIDE. The purple and pink walls of this flesh gash peel apart and open in various places to reveal blades, hooks and needles at the end of various vestigial limbs. The limbs holding MALAHIDE draw him back inexorably into this cavity. He has one last moment to meet JULIA's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>But you WANTED this. You wanted to SEE. You wanted to KNOW. And here it is. The heart of Hell. Leviathan.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MALAHIDE is now held within the walls of the gash. He opens his mouth for one final scream but one of the tiny needle-topped limbs flies at his mouth and sews his lips together with heavy blue wire before he can utter it. His eyes widen in both agony and horror. JULIA smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Why do you think I was allowed to go back? For YOU? No, it wanted souls. And I brought you. And you wanted to KNOW. Now you're both happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The gash heals itself, closing MALAHIDE within. Despite the gash having closed over MALAHIDE, the leathery flesh that covers that area is a mass of movement, ripples and bumps. Small rips and gashes appear and disappear on its surface, allowing us occasional and partial glimpses of MALAHIDE and what is happening to him. At one stage MALAHIDE's hand and forearm appear. A long deep, running cut has been made down the arm and the flesh peeled and folded back, revealing the meat and the muscle beneath. As we watch, two of the tiny operating limbs sew the flaps of flesh, still folded back, to the rest of the arm, leaving the wound open and un-healable. Another gash opens and MALAHIDE's face is visible. Here too the needles are at work, diving into and out of his flesh in a complicated sewing pattern that is finally pulled together beneath one ear, leaving MALAHIDE's features permanently pulled out of shape and decorated with running stitches of metal wire. Again, MALAHIDE's torso appears, naked. Two large triangular blades make deep parallel slashes down his chest. Two different limbs appear but these have sucker-like tips rather than metallic ones. They fasten onto the new cuts, as if battening. Instead they are injecting - as becomes apparent when MALAHIDE's skin turns blue. The blueness, the conscious disfigurement, and the almost decorative open wounds should serve to convey that what is happening to MALAHIDE is not simply torture; he is being transformed into a CENOBITE. JULIA watches with avid interest.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Doctor. It's been real.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY comes through and gasps as she sees the walls.</context>
      <utterance>How convenient.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay there, baby. Don't come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FRANK lands a powerful blow to LARRY's jaw. It straightens LARRY up and FRANK slams the flat of his hand against his brother's chest. LARRY flies backwards. He flings out his arm to balance himself but he is nearer to the wall than he thinks and the impetus of his fall drives his arm onto the knives. LARRY cries out. FRANK grins and prepares to force his wounded brother completely onto the knives. Suddenly KIRSTY flies across the room at FRANK and beats at his back with her fists. FRANK snarls and, without turning around completely, flings her away from him. KIRSTY goes flying but lands just safely short of the deadly walls. LARRY, in the pause KIRSTY gave him and galvanized by her example, has found more strength. He pulls his arm painfully forward, clear of the knives, and throws himself to the side, forcing FRANK onto the knives. With a vicious push, LARRY impales his brother completely. FRANK howls, loud and long. Without pausing, LARRY pulls a knife free from the wall and, with one vicious slice, separates himself from his brother. LARRY rushes to KIRSTY and helps her to her feet. They embrace. There is a cry of horror off-camera. We pull out. TIFFANY has followed her friend. She stares in shock at LARRY's wounded arm and at the impaled FRANK.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Stay there. I'll be with you in a minute. LARRY and FRANK trade blows.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, well. All my family together again. How very sweet.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Julia.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew you'd come.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You knew?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. You're a girl who remembers her promises.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FRANK grins, his grin taking in LARRY, KIRSTY and TIFFANY as well as JULIA. He extends an arm to JULIA.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I do. I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JULIA does not move.</context>
      <utterance>And I know how much I mean to you. Come here.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances meaningfully at the others, perhaps stroking a blade of one of the knives in his chest.</context>
      <utterance>Come here. Kiss me. And then...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, surprisingly, LARRY laughs. He is genuinely amused.</context>
      <utterance>... we'll have a real family re-union.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JULIA still has not moved.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ, FRANK. I don't believe you. You don't know her at all do you? You still think you're in charge.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JULIA begins to cross the room to him.</context>
      <utterance>Of course I am. She BELONGS to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JULIA doesn't pause. FRANK grins.</context>
      <utterance>For God's sake! He KILLED you!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JULIA is now next to him.</context>
      <utterance>She's forgiven me that. Haven't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FRANK laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Do you really need to ask?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JULIA glances at the knives. FRANK shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Show them.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JULIA shifts position so she is standing behind him. She wraps her arms around him, one stroking his belly, the other across his shoulders. FRANK leans his head back and twists it slightly. They kiss. JULIA removes her arm from his stomach and slips it behind him. Nothing happens for a second and then, suddenly, FRANK's whole body spasms. We almost think it may be with pleasure until he breaks from the kiss and we see the confused expression on his face - and the blood bubbling at his mouth. There is a ripping, bursting sound and JULIA's hand emerges from his chest, covered in his blood. Clutched in her hand is his ruptured, still pumping heart.</context>
      <utterance>Just a small inconvenience, babe.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shepherds the girls quickly through the door to the corridor. FRANK's body begins to twitch. JULIA holds it tightly.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus! Out. Out!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute. Why are we following her? Who is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Tiffany KIRSTY shrugs.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... She's good at puzzles.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They take the turn TIFFANY has indicated.</context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without ceremony, she bursts the heart with one quick squeeze.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing personal, babe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera moves around them to take in what they see. They are of course in the central chamber of LEVIATHAN. LEVIATHAN is spinning again, the black beams flying around the chamber. TIFFANY screams. KIRSTY grabs her.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. My. God.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TIFFANY is frozen.</context>
      <utterance>Tiffany, listen. You've solved it. But we've got to solve it the OTHER way. See? See? We've got to get out.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LEVIATHAN spins, the beams fly.</context>
      <utterance>Come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TIFFANY nods. They are just about to leave when LEVIATHAN stops spinning. A large beam flies down , carrying an object which lands on the catwalk before the HUMANS, who all take a step or two backwards. The beam withdraws. The object at first resembles a large and bloody plastic bag, but then internal movement begins to rip at this covering. Hands appear out of the rips and complete the removal. We realise that the bag-like thing was a kind of caul, a membranous after-birth that some creatures produce their young in. The thing inside completes its escape and stands clear of the shredded caul. Like a new-born child, it is stained and soiled with amiotic fluids and blood. But it is not a new born child. It is a NEW CENOBITE. And it used to be MALAHIDE. The transformation we caught glimpses of is now complete. Its skin is entirely blue, its head entirely bald. The decorative wounds and tortures we saw being applied are all present; its flesh is peeled back in various places, its features are threaded and distorted by, wire, its eyelids are stapled open. For a second it stands and regards the HUMANS before it. TIFFANY gasps in recognition. KIRSTY too knows what it was.</context>
      <utterance>Please! Tiffany, Please! Get us out! Take us home, please!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For some reason, KIRSTY draws from her pocket the photo she took from the OBSESSION ROOM. She stares at it.</context>
      <utterance>Malahide ...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The MALAHIDE CENOBITE stretches its arms and flexes its fingers.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ! Of course ...</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It looks at the HUMANS again, its gaze finally settling on the still shocked TIFFANY.</context>
      <utterance>And to think I hesitated ...</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It reaches out its hand to her.</context>
      <utterance>Tiffany. Come. I have a whole new world of puzzles for you to enjoy ...</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TIFFANY, confused and used to obeying her doctor's voice, tentatively stretches out her arm to meet the MALAHIDE CENOBITE's. LARRY suddenly walks between TIFFANY and MALAHIDE. The expression on his face is strange; it is not fear, nor defiance. It is simpler than that. He is really, really pissed off.</context>
      <utterance>A whole new world of pleasures for you to endure.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Who the hell are you?</context>
      <utterance>No. I've had enough of this shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LARRY waves a hand at her, but keeps his eyes on</context>
      <utterance>It's ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points a finger at MALAHIDE's face, which is attempting a version of PINHEAD's imposing glacial stars, but frankly, isn't quite making it.</context>
      <utterance>Never mind. Never mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, he forms a fist with his unwounded arm and smashes it straight into MALAHIDE's face. MALAHIDE is completely decked. LARRY grabs TIFFANY by the shoulders and speaks urgently to her.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you and the horse you rode in on.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>O.K. You've done it before. You can do it again. GET US OUT OF</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God, it's her room!</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts urging the girls down the corridor - a long and very narrow one - but KIRSTY shows some resistance.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before they can discuss it, a new rushing sound is heard. They look back. Hurtling towards them is the ENGINEER from HELLRAISER. TIFFANY screams.</context>
      <utterance>No. No, there's something wrong...</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They begin one last panic-fuelled run down the narrow corridor, the ENGINEER at their heels. The sequence is equivalent to KIRSTY's pursuit by the ENGINEER in HELLRAISER, the twist here being that as they approach the entrance into TIFFANY's room the walls of the corridor, already thin, begin to close together. LARRY is bringing up the rear (the corridor is now so narrow only single file is possible) and he can almost feel the ENGINEER'S breath on his neck.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus. O.K. No more arguments. Just RUN!</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finally, almost impossibly, they reach the gap in the wall. TIFFANY tumbles through, then KIRSTY, and finally LARRY. Less than a micro-second after LARRY has made it, the walls seal themselves. 104 INT. TIFFANY'S ROOM (2nd VERSION) DAY As we see clearly the room they have come into, we perhaps share the feeling that KIRSTY expressed in the corridor; Something Is Wrong. The tiles that make up the floor are patterned as before but the individual tiles are larger. The room itself seems more spacious, the ceiling higher. There is a bowl of flowers by the window. The flowers were in full bloom before their trip to Hell but now they seem long dead. The audience have to notice most of this for themselves because LARRY, KIRSTY, and TIFFANY are too relieved by, and tired from, their escape to take this in immediately. LARRY seats himself in the chair, KIRSTY perches on the end of TIFFANY's bed. TIFFANY however walks straight across to her window. She is the first to notice anything. She stares at the flowers.</context>
      <utterance>Go. Go. Go. Go. Go!!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY rises from the bed and joins TIFFANY by the window.</context>
      <utterance>Tiffany ... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LARRY rises to his feet. Just as he stands, a fleeting expression of bewilderment crosses his face. He strokes at his right arm with an unconscious gesture as he crosses the room. KIRSTY doesn't look at her father right away.</context>
      <utterance>But these were ... Daddy?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at her father. A sea of sweat has broken out on his brow and face as he stares intensely at the flowers. KIRSTY's voice slows, begins to trail off.</context>
      <utterance>These flowers. I saw them just...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LARRY's eyes close. His entire face screws up as if an excruciating pain just hit him. He clamps his arm across his chest, the hands clutching his shoulders. He opens his eyes and looks at KIRSTY for a second, his expression one of surprise. Then his eyes roll up into the sockets and he collapses to the floor. TIFFANY has hardly had time to turn from the bowl of flowers before KIRSTY is kneeling by her father.</context>
      <utterance>...the day ...before... yesterday Daddy? Daddy!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LARRY is unconscious. TIFFANY gasps. KIRSTY looks up at her.</context>
      <utterance>Daddy!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TIFFANY's eyes widen. She rushes to the door and disappears into the corridor. Within two seconds we hear an emergency alarm go off and TIFFANY re-enters the room.</context>
      <utterance>Get help.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TIFFANY does so and KIRSTY places it under the head of LARRY, whose lips are now blue and who is breathing very shallowly. KIRSTY looks up at TIFFANY, despair in her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Pass me a pillow.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, the door to the room flies open and two INTERNS - maybe Stan and Ollie from the carnival sequence - come in, complete with stretcher and gurney. They assess the situation with a glance and it is serious enough to make one of them break their professional silence.</context>
      <utterance>What do you do? I just don't know what to do. TIFFANY shakes her head helplessly.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are good at their job - within seconds LARRY is secured on the gurney and they head for the door, KIRSTY and TIFFANY behind them. The following exchanges are spoken on the move.</context>
      <utterance>Coronary arrest. Let's be quick.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he going to be 0.K.?</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We just can't say. O.R.'s on standby. They'll do what they can.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The INTERNS exchange a glance and decide honesty is best.</context>
      <utterance>But it's bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. It's bad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>INTERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The double doors part and close, giving just a glimpse of the operating room beyond, all lights, monitors and whirring machinery, and the several gowned and masked experts attending to LARRY. As the doors close, KIRSTY turns to TIFFANY, expecting a long wait before anyone comes to speak to them. Surprisingly, though, the doors open again almost immediately and two figures step through. They, too, are masked and gowned in surgical green and very little of them is visible.</context>
      <utterance>Wait out here. A doctor will talk to you when we know more.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY staggers visibly, shocked by this bluntness.</context>
      <utterance>Is he going to be all right? 1st GOWNED FIGURE  No. He's not going to be all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>1st GOWNED FIGURE No. He's going to die. He's got a ruptured aorta. He's going to die in agony. As he makes this speech, the mask of his colleague stains rapidly with blood, as if it is literally pouring from its mouth. Simultaneously, his own mask is slowly pierced by a score of nails bursting through from beneath. TIFFANY screams. The 1st GOWNED FIGURE pulls the mask and cap away from its face - It is PINHEAD. His colleague does the same. It is the FEMALE</context>
      <utterance>Wh...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slams her fist against the elevator wall. The elevator stops. Its lights flicker.</context>
      <utterance>Faster, you bastard, faster!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The elevator starts again.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jesus. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I didn't mean it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The lift stops, but this time it's where they want it. KIRSTY's finger hesitates over the DOOR OPEN button.</context>
      <utterance>It's 0.K. They can't beat an elevator. Not upstairs. It'll be O.K.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She presses the button.</context>
      <utterance>It'll be O.K.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs, and the sound is far from human. KIRSTY and TIFFANY stare at him.</context>
      <utterance>The Doctor is in!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIFFANY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY looks sharply at TIFFANY for a second, as if she is about to comment on her re-found voice, but instead simply nods. She takes her friend's hand and the GIRLS begin to walk very slowly backwards to the far end of the ward. MALAHIDE is too enraptured of his new power to pay attention to specific victims and so makes no move to stop the GIRLS' slow retreat. Suddenly his palms erupt into a writhing mass of tentacle-like limbs as his head tips back to emit a wide band of LEVIATHAN's black light at the ceiling, accompanied by, renewed inhuman laughter. Taking this as their cue, the GIRLS turn and bolt for the doors at the far and of the ward and exit through them. The limbs extrude from MALAHIDE's palms only twelve inches or so and are all quite thin, but they all have independent movement and they all have various surgical-like, gleaming tips. MALAHIDE floats over to the nearest bed. He looks at the patient and then looks at the bladed tips of his new limbs and, as if addressing them, speaks.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is another burst of laughter as the limbs fly at the patient, writhing, twitching, slashing, and slicing.</context>
      <utterance>I recommend amputation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. No Boxes. Such a shame.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE CENOBITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No more delays, Kirsty. No more teasing. Time to play.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY looks at his unforgiving face and then her eyes suddenly widen as she thinks Of something.</context>
      <utterance>Time to play.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No more deals, Kirsty. It's your flesh we want to experience, not your skill at bargaining.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No strings. Just information.</context>
      <utterance>No deals! Just information. Information. Free of charge.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carefully, making no fast movements, KIRSTY reaches into her pocket where she placed the photograph from MALAHIDE's OBSESSION ROOM. She brings out the picture that she realized earlier was of PINHEAD and hands it to him. He takes hold of it and looks, his face registering nothing.</context>
      <utterance>Go on. But trick us again, child, and your suffering will be legendary even in Hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this? Someone else you think escaped us, like Frank?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, No, this one didn't escape. You told me you'd always been in Hell. You were wrong. Look at it. LOOK. IT'S YOU.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nonsense, I...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The FEMALE CENOBITE strides across the room.</context>
      <utterance>It's you! You HAVEN'T always been as you are. You were HUMAN. Remember. Remember all your confusions. Think!</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE CENOBITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She raises her hand towards KIRSTY. PINHEAD's arm flies out and stops her.</context>
      <utterance>Enough!</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is staring at the photograph, that great immobile brow finally puckering, as if something is stirring.</context>
      <utterance>Wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>PINHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I...remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other three CENOBITES stop moving and stare at KIRSTY. Any advances they were making on KIRSTY or TIFFANY stop as the same dim, distant, recollection begins to stir within them. Suddenly, the door bursts open. MALAHIDE is there, still floating, his voice still a mixture of hideous threat and insane joy.</context>
      <utterance>You were ALL human!</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns his palms downwards, mirroring his gesture in the hall of mirrors. TIFFANY lets out a moan of terror and shakes her head. One of the snake-like limbs from MALAHIDE's palms flies towards TIFFANY's face. Before anybody can react, its scalpel tip has sliced an inch or so off several strands of her hair.</context>
      <utterance>Tiffany. Come.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIRSTY throws her arms around the cowering TIFFANY and snarls at her tormentor.</context>
      <utterance>Tiffany. Come.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MALAHIDE makes no reply, but suddenly several more limbs fly towards the GIRLS and begin to weave in front of KIRSTY's face like snakes awaiting their moment. At this stage, the camera CUTS TO the watching PINHEAD. He lets the photograph of his past life flutter to the floor. MALAHIDE looks up at the tiny noise this makes and his eyes meet PINHEAD'S. He turns more fully to face PINHEAD and the other CENOBITES who are now standing with their leader, and a strange smile crosses his face</context>
      <utterance>Leave her alone, you asshole!</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, the air is full of flying chains. MALAHIDE is hooked everywhere. It is like a high-speed version of FRANK's final re- capture in HELLRAISER. The chains start tugging almost instantly. Is MALAHIDE about to be ripped apart? With contemptuous, dismissive speed, the limbs that ooze from MALAHIDE's palms have sliced the chains to pieces and, almost before we have time to realise that, three of them have lengthened, thickened, and hardened and have skewered the FEMALE CENOBITE, CHATTERER II, and BUTTERBALL to the walls. The three limbs detatch themselves from MALAHIDE. The three CENOBITES are all well above the floor, pinned and twitching like the rats in FRANK's attic. As they die, they suddenly revert; there are three human corpses on the walls of the room. A woman, a fat man, and a little boy. MALAHIDE smiles. Be looks at PINHEAD again and advances. Suddenly a heavy torture pillar smashes into him, knocking him slightly off-balance. PINHEAD is backing across the room, weaving pillars in front of him as he moves. MALAHIDE moves forward, knocking them out of the way. As each pillar is knocked aside, PINHEAD's face is more and more human. Finally, when the face we see is nearly that of the ENGLISH OFFICER from the opening, he turns his head slightly away from the advancing MALAHIDE and finds KIRSTY's eyes. A look passes between them. Understanding? Gratitude? Friendship? Whatever emotion lies beneath it, it is clearly a cue and KIRSTY and TIFFANY make a break for it, bursting through the door. Simultaneously to this, MALAHIDE and PINHEAD find each other's eyes a final time. For a second, everything is still then a single bladed limb flies across the space between them and neatly and calmly slices PINHEAD's throat open. The thin red line becomes a torrent of blood and the former lord of Hell falls dead at the feet of his successor.</context>
      <utterance>Oh,good. A fight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PATIENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shaking their heads at the insanity, they run up the corridor. TIFFANY looks slightly distracted and when she speaks it is half to herself.</context>
      <utterance>So what, girls? It's O.K. for an ego-trip but it doesn't got the job done.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIFFANY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to go back. Or it'll never stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIFFANY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got to finish it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Even as KIRSTY says this, TIFFANY has moved past her and is resuming her run down the corridor.</context>
      <utterance>Finish what?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They turn back into the main section of the corridor that contains their own rooms, TIFFANY still four or five yards in front of</context>
      <utterance>Tiffany! Wait! KIRSTY starts after her friend.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TIFFANY bends down and retrieves the white diamond BOX from the empty fingers.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, gross.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TIFFANY looks at the BOX in her hand. When she speaks, it is not to KIRSTY but to herself.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing? What are WE doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIFFANY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't do it here. I have to go to it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>TIFFANY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm scared.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The GIRLS press on. Whether LEVIATHAN is oblivious to their presence or simply doesn't consider them a threat, the beams stop striking the GIRLS' faces. Nevertheless, the mood remains ominous. The audience should feel something is about to happen. They are six feet from the lip of the catwalk. TIFFANY kneels and, holding the white diamond BOX in front of her, begins to move her fingers over it. The music box tune begins to play as the BOX begins to move. That 'something' that the audience was waiting to happen, suddenly does; MALAHIDE flies up from the abyss beside the catwalk. The vastness of the limb that seals him to LEVIATHAN is now directly apparent; instead of merging into black light, the limb itself trails through the air over the huge distance to LEVIATHAN itself. One of the limbs from MALAHIDE's palms flies out and knocks the BOX from TIFFANY's hands. It rolls perilously close to the edge of the catwalk. KIRSTY grabs TIFFANY and, dragging her to her feet, pulls her further back down the catwalk as MALAHIDE floats to a landing between them and the BOX.</context>
      <utterance>No. Don't let it. You've come this far.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The blades on the end of his limbs twitch eagerly.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, girls. And how are we feeling today?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The limbs fly forward. KIRSTY screams and both girls run up the catwalk. About halfway back up, however, TIFFANY stops, turns around, and begins to walk back. KIRSTY calls out.</context>
      <utterance>You have your whole lives behind you now.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera stays with TIFFANY as she makes her way back. KIRSTY's voice stays on the soundtrack for a time, imploring her friend to turn back and then simply stops. This should be abrupt enough to make the audience notice but smooth enough to avoid their attention leaving TIFFANY. MALAHIDE waits, happy to see a patient so keen on the knife. Very slowly, TIFFANY moves forward, inch by slow inch. This is something she HAS to do; the expression on her face is not determination but terror. And MALAHIDE is very happy to encourage this.</context>
      <utterance>Tiffany! No!</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His scalpels flick in the air, making small slicing motions.</context>
      <utterance>Surgery is open, Tiffany. What was today's agenda?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Still TIFFANY comes forward, closer and closer until she is surely close enough to be grabbed. Suddenly, she is grabbed. But from behind, and by a human hand. TIFFANY gasps, and turns to see who has seized her. She screams. It is JULIA. The limbs retract into MALAHIDE's palms. He smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, yes. Evisceration.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JULIA, having presumably just replaced her skin, is not quite as perfect as before; there are bloody lines like scars beneath her ears and chin as if the skin required some adjustment before being put on. JULIA moves forward, her left arm still holding TIFFANY, her smile returning MALAHIDE'S.</context>
      <utterance>Doctor. I've missed you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALAHIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew you'd come back.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JULIA is right next to MALAHIDE now. Smoothly, she releases her grip on TIFFANY and embraces MALAHIDE sensuously. He returns the embrace. They kiss. Unseen, TIFFANY moves to the edge of the catwalk and picks up the BOX. Her fingers move over it, finding its solution. Suddenly, LEVIATHAN's breath becomes a roar of anger and fear. MALAHIDE breaks away from his kiss, his face a mixture of confusion and rage. JULIA plants both hands in the middle of his chest and pushes. He falls over the lip of the catwalk but, almost before he drops from sight, he is suddenly pulled backwards through the air, screaming, as LEVIATHAN's limb retracts. JULIA jumps back. shouting.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a girl who keeps her promises.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TIFFANY's fingers fly over the BOX and suddenly we see what is happening. The mountain-like LEVIATHAN is following the movements of the small replica in TIFFANY's hands. As TIFFANY inverts the new configuration back towards a closed BOX, LEVIATHAN too is being twisted and turned. Being closed. The whole centre of Hell shakes as if suffering a mild earthquake. JULIA and TIFFANY almost lose their footing, but TIFFANY continues working. She is nearly, there. LEVIATHAN is halfway between its white diamond, majesty and a huge closed BOX. TIFFANY takes her hands from the BOX. It is done. The larger BOX operates a few seconds behind it's control, so that we can inter- cut the final sliding and creaking into position with the following human drama; As LEVIATHAN makes its final closing, the mild tremors of before become larger. Hell shakes violently and this time TIFFANY does lose her footing. She looks set to tumble into the vast abyss to the side of the catwalk but just manages to catch hold of the edge with one hand. The small BOX flies from her hand and hurtles down into the miles of blackness below. TIFFANY dangles over the edge, her feet kicking wildly for a foothold that doesn't exist. Suddenly, a hand extends to her. She looks up. It is JULIA. For a second, nothing happens.</context>
      <utterance>Do it, Tiffany! Do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TIFFANY lifts one hand off the edge and grabs at JULIA's proffered wrist. JULIA begins to pull up and for a moment it seems the crisis is over. Then a terrible and familiar ripping noise is heard: The skin of the arm that TIFFANY clings to begins to rip free at the shoulder. Gradually, like a shirt's threads unraveling, it comes off. TIFFANY's weight pulls it clear like a very long and very tasteless evening glove and it seems she will finally make the long drop. At the final second, as the arm-skin comes off, the entire skin flies from the body and falls with its arm into the abyss. TIFFANY screams. She is going to die. But suddenly the two arms that have Just lost their skin fly out again and catch her fingers. TIFFANY is hauled over the edge and staggers to her feet, staring into the-bloodied face of KIRSTY, who had donned JULIA's skin to help her friend. The two girls share a quick and joyous embrace and then run rapidly up the catwalk. The camera stays with LEVIATHAN. The rumbling stops. And the mountainous BOX creaks into its final, sealed position.</context>
      <utterance>Trust me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TIFFANY gives a smile.</context>
      <utterance>So. What're you going to do? Open up a games-shop somewhere? Sell jigsaw puzzles?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIFFANY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a slightly awkward pause.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well ... G'bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIFFANY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They share a rueful knowing smile, like the smile of soldiers back from a war who say goodbye on a dockside and know they will never meet again. TIFFANY turns and walks down the long path to the hospital gates. KIRSTY watches her for a few moments and then turns and re-enters the institute. The camera TRACKS back to the window of the RECOVERY ROOM and we watch through the window as KIRSTY enters the room. She bends to kiss her father's cheek. LARRY slips an arm around her shoulders and they embrace. The camera moves away again. 122 INT. HALLWAY MALAHIDE's HOUSE DAY The camera TRACKS slowly up MALAHIDE's hallway. The hallway is lined with packing cases filled with items from the house. A WORKMAN is shoving something into one of the cases. As the camera moves past him, he speaks.</context>
      <utterance>It's been Hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORKMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera reaches the doorway of the OBSESSION ROOM as an answering voice is heard. 2nd. WORKMAN Not our problem... The TRACK continues into -</context>
      <utterance>So whose was all this shit?</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
