<movie id="267" title="Hellboy">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>OLD MATLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Super: CPL. GEORGE MATLIN, combat photographer.</context>
      <utterance>Is he real? Oh yeah -- Absolutely.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MATLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matlin smiles as he paws through a box of old negatives.</context>
      <utterance>I haven't talked about it for years, you know?  Everyone called me crazy...</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MATLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Someone turns on the darkroom's red safety light for an eerie, dramatic effect.</context>
      <utterance>But I have the negative.</utterance>
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get ready, 3-2-1... Roll tape.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MATLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It all started back in 44. I was a Corps photographer aboard an allied submarine...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OLD MATLIN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SGT. WHITMAN, 44, tough as nails, pushes through, his uniform soaked in sweat.</context>
      <utterance>...off the coast of Scotland. Classified mission. I was 21...</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MATLIN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whitman continues down the passageway until he reaches a small...</context>
      <utterance>We had an English civilian on board. Not much older than me but already an advisor to President Roosevelt. "Paranormal" advisor, I kid you not --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>OLD MATLIN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His name was Trevor. Profesor Trevor --</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TREVOR "BROOM" BRUTTENHOLM is a gaunt, olive-skinned man in his late twenties. In his hands, a tarot deck. He turns the cards face up: THE FOOL, THE MOON...</context>
      <utterance>-- Broom! Topside, now.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Broom grabs a worn-down wooden box full of books and amulets. It has a leather strap that allows him to carry it, much like a carpenter's tool box.</context>
      <utterance>The sooner we're done, the better.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is an important mission, Sgt. Whitman. I hope you realize that.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves away. Broom takes a small box and a few amulets. Before exiting, he pauses and tensely turns the last TAROT</context>
      <utterance>Oh -- you don't wanna know what I think. Topside, now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>INT/EXT. SCOTLAND - TUNNEL - NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's raining like hell now. Soldiers move through a short tunnel carved into the mountain. Whitman signals his men to spread out, then comes alongside Broom.</context>
      <utterance>Super: OCTOBER 9, 1944, SCOTLAND.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sgt. Whitman!! Sgt. Whitman!! May I have a word??</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In private, if you don't mind...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whitman scowls and huffs. A life-sized wooden Christ contemplates the scene from above.</context>
      <utterance>Your men -- They'll need these --</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are a Catholic??</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whitman locks and loads an automatic.</context>
      <utterance>Amongst other things, yes -- but that's hardly the point.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here. You'll need one of these.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I abhor violence.  Sergeant Whitman, I hope you don't think me mad --</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves away. Broom looks up to the wooden Christ: It has no eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Three days too late for that one, "professor."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WHITMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're wasting our time: There's nothing on this island but sheep and rocks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ruins. Not rocks. The remains of Trondham Abbey. Built on an intersection of Ley Lines, the boundaries between our world and the other --</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a load of crap. Hell, a week ago I hadn't even heard the word parabnormal --</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Paranormal"  But -- you read the transmission.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Half transmission. Nonsense -- German ghost stories!</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have seen ghosts, Whitman.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reaching a slope, Matlin sets down his camera. Turning, he sees lights.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'll bet you have.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drenched, Broom and Whitman look down upon an impressive ROMANESQUE RUIN. Under worklights, dozens of NAZI SOLDIERS swarm among thick stone walls and archways.</context>
      <utterance>Sweet Jesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They must be here for the sheep.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WHITMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The freak in the gas mask --</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Karl Ruprecht Kroenen, one of the Reich's top Scientists. Head of the Thule Occult Society.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If he's here, this is worse than I thought.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The RADIOMAN cranks a transmitter to life.</context>
      <utterance>Air and sea backup. What's closest?</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Londonderry, sir. Forty minutes away.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't have forty minutes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ILSA, a severe, ageless Aryan beauty, reverentially drapes an embroidered robe over his bony shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>No matter what happens to me, you must carry on with the work.</utterance>
   <speaker>ILSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will not leave you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, you will... Leave me. Deny me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ILSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands her a small LEATHER-BOUND BOOK. It contains hand- drawn notes and illustrations.</context>
      <utterance>Never --</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls her close, the clouds of their breath mingling.</context>
      <utterance>This will guide you back to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He dips his fingers in a wooden bowl full of blood, then wipes her tears away with a crimson thumb, both a consolation and a ritual. VON KRUPT, an acrid German General, wearing dark SCARLET glasses and LEATHER GLOVES, appears. Looks at his pocket watch. On the gold lid: a SWASTIKA.</context>
      <utterance>I grant you everlasting life, youth and the power to serve me.</utterance>
   <speaker>VON KRUPT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VON KRUPT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He strides alongside Grigory and Ilsa, who holds an umbrella to shield her master from the pouring rain.</context>
      <utterance>Five years of research and construction, Grigory. Five years!!</utterance>
   <speaker>VON KRUPT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The furhrer doesn't look kindly on failure.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kroenen mutters excitedly as he opens a polished oak box containing a massive gold and copper MECHA-GLOVE. Grigory extends his hand so that KROENEN may fit him with the contraption, which is attached to cables and hoses.</context>
      <utterance>There will be no failure, General. I promised Herr Hitler a miracle. I'll deliver one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GRIGORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks down at the machine and whispers --</context>
      <utterance>Tonight, We will open a portal and awaken the OGDRU JAHAD: The seven Gods of chaos.  Our enemies will be destroyed. In an instant, all impurity in this world will be razed and from the ashes a new eden will arise.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He flexes his fingers and in response -- -- the two metal rings swing around the machine's central axis. TCHINK!!! WHIRRR!!! STEAM escapes from the ducts and pipes. An invisible blast of energy forces the falling rain to swerve momentarily away from Grigory's body. Ilsa signals TWO NAZI SCIENTISTS standing at a control panel.</context>
      <utterance>Ragnarok, Anung Ia Anung.</utterance>
   <speaker>ILSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of them inserts a 20 inch SOLID GOLD CYLINDER into the machine. Two openings remain vacant next to it. A blade of light opens in the air! Burning symbols slash the air, like living serpents of fire.</context>
      <utterance>More Power!! Don't let the level drop!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>fierce whisper, to</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITMAN)</speaker>
      <mode> WHITMAN)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to me!!! The portal is open!!! We have to stop them!!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MATLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's almost over!!</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up a sample of white, viscous goo from the outer rings of the smoking machine. Whitman approaches.</context>
      <utterance>No. It's not.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cordon off the area. Something came through.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Broom glances at a 13th century FRESCO depicting heaven and hell.</context>
      <utterance>From where??!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>MATLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you believe in hell?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is a place -- a dark place where evil slumbers and awaits to return. From there it infects our dreams. Our thoughts. Grigory gave us a glance tonight --</utterance>
   <speaker>MATLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grigory -- That's Russian, right?  Thought they were on our side...</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grigory Yefimovich Rasputin --</utterance>
   <speaker>MATLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon -- Rasputin??</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spiritual advisor to the Romanovs.  In 1916, at a dinner in his honor, he was poisoned, shot, stabbed, clubbed, drowned and castrated.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A rustling sound reaches their ears. Matlin readies a handgun as Broom scans the walls with his flashlight. Something moves, accompanied by a loud scrape. Matlin cocks his pistol and nervously approaches a crumbling statue. SCREEEECH!!!! A RED THING jumps into the air!! Instinctively, Matlin shoots at it. The RED THING leaps from arch to arch, followed by a trail of bullet hits. Whitman and other soldiers join them --</context>
      <utterance>That makes him more than a hundred --</utterance>
   <speaker>MATLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell was that? An ape?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. It was red. Bright red.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you two talking about??</utterance>
   <speaker>MATLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A red ape.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hear the labored breathing of a living creature.</context>
      <utterance>It's-not-an-ape --</utterance>
   <speaker>MATLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's got a big stone -- in its hand --</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hissing, the thing cowers between a gargoyle and a stone saint. WHITMAN points his gun at the scarlet shape above. Broom stops him from firing.</context>
      <utterance>I think that is its hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In deep shadow, the RED THING observes with bright, golden eyes veined with streaks of burnt sienna. Broom slowly fishes a BABY RUTH candy bar from his pocket. Peeling back the wrapper, he slowly waves the candy. The RED THING shrinks back. Broom bites into the candy and chews, noisily smacking his lips. Offers the candy again. This time, out of the dark comes a small FACE, not very different from the stone demons around it. The creature extends its right arm: it's solid stone with tiny runes engraved around the thick, cylindrical wrist. Four articulated stone fingers wiggle, reaching for the chocolate.</context>
      <utterance>Wait --</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whitman moves closer. On the wall behind him, a shadow shows the RED THING climbing into Broom's arms. Broom tenderly covers it with a blanket. The stubby fingers snatch the candy. Broom smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus! would'ya look at the size of that whammer!</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a boy. Just a baby boy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OLD MATLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matlin finally pulls an old 8x10 from a battered portfolio. He smiles, full of memories.</context>
      <utterance>and no one has ever seen it. They keep saying he's not real, but I want to set the record straight before I go.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MATLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here. The real picture, not the retouched one in LIFE magazine.  This is him. The very same night we found him. The night Broom gave him that name.  Can I say it on TV? He called him --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HEAD OF SPECIAL OPERATIONS.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Manning on a TV SHOW a la Regis Philbin.</utterance>
   <speaker>TV HOST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As the head of your division, you -- You have seen dozens of pictures like this!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>MANNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shows a blurry picture.</context>
      <utterance>Exactly -- so, why is it that they're all out of focus? C'mon!! God knows, people manage to get good pictures at a wedding!!</utterance>
   <speaker>MANNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The audience applauds.</context>
      <utterance>That's the alleged best man -- ?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DOCTOR 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Malignant sarcoma. In the lungs... the spine, liver...</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Approximately... how long??</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Broom impassively takes in the information.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe -- six weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can arrange for hospitalization, pain management. Make the time more bearable -- Broom pensively shuffles his tarot cards.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd rather... stay home, you know. I'll be making arrangements --  For my son.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Broom looks down: first card off the deck: DEATH.</context>
      <utterance>You can always get a second opinion.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That won't be necessary.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son...</utterance>
   <speaker>TV HOST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mister Manning, what about the "Bureau for Paranormal Research and Defense?" The FBI has been known to conceal --</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM MANNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That word -- conceal --</utterance>
   <speaker>TV HOST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>from the American public --</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM MANNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Phil -- Phil -- hold your little green horses. Let me tell you and the American public one thing -- this "Bureau for -- what was it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TV HOST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paranormal Research and --</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM MANNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Broom smiles.</context>
      <utterance>-- Defense, right, well -- I'm here to clear up this once and for all.  There-is-no-such-thing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>INTERCOM VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John Myers, F.B.I. Transfer from Quantico. A beat, then -- WHIRRR!!! An EYEPIECE and an LCD screen scanner pop out.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERCOM VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Myers looks into the eyepiece. On the screen, Myers' cornea is scanned. TWO VIOLET FLASHES. His ID and badge numbers appear. CLACK! The gate opens.</context>
      <utterance>Look at the birdie, son.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, I'm --</utterance>
   <speaker>LOBBY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Late. Five minutes late.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I --</utterance>
   <speaker>LOBBY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Section fifty-one. Step back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pardon?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOBBY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Confused, Myers picks up his suitcases and complies. He realizes he's DEAD CENTER on a giant B.P.R.D. Logo: A HAND</context>
      <utterance>Two steps back, please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Myers jumps, then moves closer to the glass.</context>
      <utterance>Turn the pages, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the tank, ABE SAPIEN, a FISH-MAN glides in and out view.</context>
      <utterance>Over here... if you don't mind?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Myers looks at four BOOK STANDS facing the glass. Each supports an open volume. He leans close to the glass, peering intently. Abe reappears. He is slender, dolphin gray, with dark patterns streaking his soft skin. Bright blue eyes shine with intelligence. Behind a thin wound-like mouth, gills are bubbling.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ!</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abe nods. Through a side door, Broom enters.</context>
      <utterance>These -- ? You're reading these -- ?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Myers extends his hand in greeting --</context>
      <utterance>Four books at once. Every day -- as long as I'm here to turn the pages.  My name's Broom. Professor Trevor Broom.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BAM! Abe presses his webbed hand against the glass, closes his eyes -- all three lids. Abe's voice surges from the speaker.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, I'm --</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Agent John T. Myers, Kansas City, 76. "T" stands for Thaddeus, mother's older brother. Scar on your chin happened when you were ten, you still wonder if it's ever going to fade away.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did it --</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- He. Not "it."</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Points at a small piece of antique paper, framed on the wall.</context>
      <utterance>Abraham Sapien. Discovered alive in a secret chamber at St. Trinian's Foundling Hospital, Washington.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They took his name from this little inscription that was stuck on his tank.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Icthyo Sapiens, April 14, 1865.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Broom uncovers a tray by the tank: Four greenish eggs. Myers gags and reels back.</context>
      <utterance>The day Abraham Lincoln died. Hence "Abe" Sapien.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abe smiles and takes a subaquatic bow, gracefully nabbing the eggs as they float through the hatch.</context>
      <utterance>Rotten eggs, a delicacy. Abe loves them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How does he know so much about me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Abe possesses a unique frontal lobe.  "Unique." That's a word you'll hear quite a bit around here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where am I -- exactly, Sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As you entered the lobby there was an inscription --</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On the desk, yes. In Latin.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Impressive. Do you remember what it said?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"In absentia luci, tenebrae vinciunt..."</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"In the absence of light, darkness prevails." For there are things that go bump in the night, Agent Myers.  We are the ones who bump back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>1937: Hitler joins "The Thule Society" -- a group of German aristocrats obsessed with the occult. He points to an ANCIENT, BROKEN LANCE.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gestures at an ancient LANCE. Next to it: a silver and gold reliquary.</context>
      <utterance>1938: he acquires the Spear of Longinus, which pierced the body of Christ. He who holds it becomes invincible.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They go through a series of pneumatic doors.</context>
      <utterance>Hitler's power increases tenfold.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Workmen are replacing two of the doors. Big dents from an oversized fist have deformed the 2-inch thick metal plates. Myers stares.</context>
      <utterance>In 1943, President Roosevelt decides to fight back. THE BUREAU FOR PARANORMAL RESEARCH AND DEFENSE is born.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>1958, the occult war finally ends when Adolf Hitler dies.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>1945, you mean. Hitler died in '45.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They reach a FINAL DOOR. Stainless steel, like a BANK VAULT. Waiting there is AGENT CLAY, a burly guy in a suit, with a cartful of BEEF AND MASHED POTATOES. A dinner pile at least 4 feet high.</context>
      <utterance>Did he, now?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Broom hands Myers two BABY RUTH bars and walks away.</context>
      <utterance>Agent Myers, this is Agent Clay. Follow his lead.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Broom signals "no."</context>
      <utterance>You're not coming?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door closes behind him.</context>
      <utterance>I hand-picked you from a roster of over seventy academy graduates. Make me proud.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're not speaking. Professor Broom had him grounded.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grounded? Who's grounded?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Myers nods.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. You saw the fish man, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clay uses an odd-shaped ELECTRONIC KEY to unlock the door. Three solenoid locks turn. Two steel vertical PISTONS open up.</context>
      <utterance>Well, come on in and meet the rest of the family.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>CLAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He gets fed six times a day. He's got a thing for cats. You'll be his nanny, his keeper, his best friend. He never goes out unsupervised --</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clay points at a torn comic book: HELLBOY, THE UNCANNY. Myers picks it up, looks at the cover: it shows Hellboy -- in a U.S. Uniform, fighting a monstrous ape. Myers watches, amazed, as a bright red TAIL waves in and out of a pool of light about ten feet away. One of the cats playfully paws at it.</context>
      <utterance>Who?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're kidding --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The voice is a deep baritone, chesty and powerful.</context>
      <utterance>Those comics -- They never got the eyes right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jesus!! Hellboy -- ?? Is real --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agent Clay blushes as he hides his scalp.</context>
      <utterance>What's with the hair, Clay?? Finally got those implants??</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On a nearby pile of junked TV sets, a loop of Fleischer cartoons and home movies cycles endlessly. One subject appears over and over: an ATTRACTIVE YOUNG WOMAN with a pale face and raven-black hair.</context>
      <utterance>It'll fill in. Where do you want your dinner, Red? By the couch?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's the squirt?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Agent Myers is your new liaison.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got tired of me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BANG!!! Hellboy lets the dumbbell drop. Instinctively, Myers jumps.</context>
      <utterance>Nah. I'll be around, Red, just back in the field.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Myers remembers he's holding the Baby Ruths.</context>
      <utterance>Manning says I'm too soft on you --  The candy. Give him the candy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Uh. Hello. I -- I have these. For you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father's back?  Still angry?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you did break out --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanted to see her.  It's nobody's business.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is. You got yourself on TV again.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Myers", huh? You have a first name??</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try not to stare. He hates when people stare.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-oh -- John.  Staring at what?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His horns. He files 'em. To "fit in."</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hellboy finally enters the light. He's awe-inspiring, with chiseled features, patterned red skin and deep-set golden eyes. Involuntarily, Myers recoils. In spite of himself, Myers is staring at the horn stumps.</context>
      <utterance>His what??!!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatcha looking at, John??</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An ALARM sounds, and a red light blinks on the wall. Myers looks around, bewildered.</context>
      <utterance>Oh-n-no -- I --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, hey, hey. They're playing our song.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're on the move.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Champ! Happy Halloween!!! You're taking me for a walk!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at them ugly suckers, Blue. One sheet of glass between them and us.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Story of my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I break it, they see us, Happy Halloween. No more hiding.  Outside. I could be outside --</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hellboy straps on a huge utility belt heavy with amulets, rosaries, horseshoes. From an ashtray he grabs a handful of stogie stubs. Lights one, puts the rest in a pouch.</context>
      <utterance>You mean, outside... with her.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't get psychic with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hellboy unlocks a STEEL BOX (STENCILED ON ITS LID: "THE GOOD SAMARITAN") and extracts the meanest-looking, custom-built, double-barrel, blue-finished, handgun ever made. A veritable cannon.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing psychic about it. You're easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How am I ever gonna get a girl?? I drive around in a garbage truck</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Liz left us, Red. Take the hint.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't take hints.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From a nearby roof, Agent Lime signals all clear.</context>
      <utterance>All areas secured.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The truck stops, Clay pulls a lever. Myers watches as the dumpster loader hinges down like a drawbridge, revealing HELLBOY and ABE.</context>
      <utterance>Seal the doors. Red and Blue are coming in.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abe, Clay and Hellboy activate lights on their belts. They BEEP and blink. Hellboy starts walking.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, boys, let's synch up our locators.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CLAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At nineteen hundred hours an alarm tripped. B&amp;E. Robbery. Six guards dead --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold on -- hold on -- I thought we checked this place. Fakes, and reproductions.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Broom stands at the base of the marble staircase.</context>
      <utterance>Apparently not everything was fake.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Myers observes as the red Goliath sheepishly averts his gaze from that of the fragile old man.</context>
      <utterance>Father...?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A 16th century statue was destroyed. Saint Dionysius the Aeropagite.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who wards off demons.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smuggled into this country by an overzealous curator. The statue, however, was hollow --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reliquary --</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hellboy selects a clip full of bullets and a speed loader.</context>
      <utterance>A prison. The Vatican deemed its contents dangerous enough to include it on the List of Avignon. Of which we hold a copy.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would'ya look at this babies? Made 'em myself. Holy water, silver shavings, white oak: the works.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abe quickly starts scanning a few leather-bound volumes of ancient magic.</context>
      <utterance>Behind this door. A dark entity -- Evil, ancient and hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As HELLBOY opens the big doors, a flickering amber glow illuminates him. He steps inside.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, well. Lemme go in and say "hi".</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. Stinky. Kitchen's closed.  Whatcha havin'? Six library guards, raw? Plus belts and boots? Man, you're gonna need some heavy fiber to move that out --</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Red, I found something --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all for you, Sammy.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah -- he's taken care of.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ABE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>hound of resurrection --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See? I don't like that --</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hellboy looks back at the corpse: it's gone!</context>
      <utterance>-- Hound of resurrection?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>harbinger of pestilence, seed of destruction --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Skip to the end, willya? How do I kill it -- ?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BAMMM!! From out of nowhere, Sammael appears and swings an arm!! Hellboy CRASHES into the brass doors!</context>
      <utterance>It doesn't say --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GRIGORY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hellboy looks up: standing in the alley, like an apparition, is Grigory, in a black suit and overcoat, his eyes shielded by pitch-black sunglasses</context>
      <utterance>Child...</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hellboy's in shock, confused.</context>
      <utterance>All grown up, I see.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That voice --</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I sang the first lullaby you ever heard, my child. I ushered you into this world.  I alone know your true calling, your true name.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hellboy catches sight of his big gun, lying on the ground. He goes for it but, BAMMM!!!! SAMMAEL lands before him.</context>
      <utterance>Don't tell me, it's Zeppo.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WSHHHP!!! A 7-foot tongue lashes out from Sammael's mouth like a whip. It's arm-thick, with yellow sacs billowing from its sides. It wraps around Hellboy's right arm. Hellboy falls to the ground, writhing, grinding his teeth. The tongue squeezes and pulls. Smoke pours from Hellboy's skin.</context>
      <utterance>I can see that you're still young and don't know your place.  Teach him. Before Hellboy can reach the weapon --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Myers proudly shows him the gun.</context>
      <utterance>What do you think you're doing??</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Helping you -- I just --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs his gun and tries to reload, but his arm hurts too much.</context>
      <utterance>No one ever helps me. It's my job.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands him the gun and a fresh clip. Reaching into his belt, Hellboy extracts a vacuum-sealed packet.</context>
      <utterance>Damn -- Okay. Here --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the packet: A SINGLE BULLET.</context>
      <utterance>-- Then load this.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KLANG!!! The tongue punches through the steel like a ramrod. Again and again... Hellboy and Myers can barely dodge it. Myers cracks a safety pin. The glass head on the bullet glows like a chemical flare.</context>
      <utterance>It's a tracking bullet. Crack the pin. Load it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's looking at Hellboy's smoking arm. Inside a bloody gash, a big, black stinger is gleaming. Hellboy pulls it out, then steps on it. It pops like a ripe grape.</context>
      <utterance>Jeez... What the hell is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hellboy steps from behind the container. Sammael's tongue instantly wraps around the gun's muzzle. BAM! BAM! Hellboy shoots repeatedly. His face lit weirdly green as the tracking bullet lodges within the gun. Then --</context>
      <utterance>Lemme go ask --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WORKER 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without slowing down, Sammael jumps onto the trailer, denting the roof then jumping off and into a CROWDED CARNIVAL area. A small carrousel and refreshment stand flank a pumpkin patch. Full of curiosity, Sammael pauses a second to inspect a Trick- or-treater dressed as a GOLDEN DRAGON. Hellboy catapults himself onto the trailer's roof.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell is that??</utterance>
   <speaker>3 WORKERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hellboy jumps and lands heavily on top of the driver's cab:</context>
      <utterance>Whoa-whoa-whoa-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Myers opens his eyes, nods.</context>
      <utterance>Are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves after Sammael.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Stay here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A train horn blares. A headlight approaches!! Hellboy smiles and puts away his gun.</context>
      <utterance>Waiting for me, Sammy?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-oh -- between a rock and a hard place -- But Sammael sprints towards it!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sammael unhinges a long, scythe-like bone from his forearm, then jumps at the front car --</context>
      <utterance>Aw, crap --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up. Sammael hangs from the ceiling, then drops. Then the creature lifts Hellboy in a ferocious bear hug. Hellboy twists around and cracks open the jaws of the creature, like King Kong and the T-Rex. Sammael staggers back and -- in an impossible maneuver, re- knits his jaws together! Then he uses his bone scythe to tackle Hellboy and -- TCHAKKKK!! -- pin his shoulder down. A deep wound. Sammael's mouth starts to open! Hellboy looks at the sparking THIRD RAIL a few feet away. Sammael's tongue rears back, a snake ready to strike.</context>
      <utterance>Aw, I forgot --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hellboy grabs the rail. An electrical discharge consumes both creatures and burns the frame like flashpaper. Hellboy lets go, his hand and body smoking. Sammael -- very crispy -- is convulsing in a cloud of smoke. He grows still. Wreathed in smoke, Hellboy shakes off the shock and uses a flame on his arm to light a cigar.</context>
      <utterance>Screw you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm fireproof.  You weren't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Myers??? How's your arm?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Myers moves away from the POLICE OFFICERS.</context>
      <utterance>My arm is fine. Where are you??</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you???</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, no, it's fine: I do my job, I take a break.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Stop. Don't do this -- Listen to me -- Tell me where you are --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Myers?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns off his belt locator and moves away into the darkness of the tunnel. In the foreground: BLACK light escapes from Sammael's charred body.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He closes his fist.</context>
      <utterance>Sammael has fulfilled his destiny... Die in peace and be reborn again and again...</utterance>
   <speaker>ILSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rasputin stands, his neck and shoulders rising, engorged by moving flesh beneath his human skin. Ilsa stares in fascination.</context>
      <utterance>Only seven more days to the eclipse, Grishka...</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind him, in the darkness of a tunnel: TWO SAMMAEL silhouettes appear.</context>
      <utterance>The child will be there. And so will we all -- Won't we?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>MANNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every time the media get a look at him, they come to me. I'm running out of lies, Trevor.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you liked being on TV.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do.  How many escapes? This year alone: five!</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tom -- he's our guest, not a prisoner.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your "guest" happens to be six foot five, bright red, and is government funded.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Manning moistens and lights a fine cigar, using a kitchen match.</context>
      <utterance>He's just going through a phase --</utterance>
   <speaker>MANNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ABE SAPIEN listens while pacing the exhibition hall, palm open.</context>
      <utterance>A "phase"? What do you think this is, "The Brady Bunch?" These... freaks --</utterance>
   <speaker>MANNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These freaks, Trevor, they give me the creeps. And I'm not the only one. You're up for review. You and your petting zoo.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Manning watches as Abe finds a sharp dagger embedded in the floor.</context>
      <utterance>I know where to find him. I'll get him back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, fishstick -- don't touch anything -- Abe silences him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to touch it to "see"...</utterance>
   <speaker>MANNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See what??</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The past, the future, whatever this object holds.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he serious??</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abe holds the dagger in his hand, turns to Broom.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about fingerprints. I never had any.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were over here, Professor.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Broom examines the dagger: a RAGNAROK symbol crowns the hilt. The dragon and swastika.</context>
      <utterance>Oooh!! Who was here? Nixon? Houdini? You mind sharing your mystic insights?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He solemnly extends his hand. As soon as Abe takes it, the room...</context>
      <utterance>Show me, Abe... show me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ILSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She uses her hammer to destroy the glass case. The ALARM shrieks. Warning lights come on. Kroenen pulls out a double-ended BLADE. It spins, like a giant bone saw, slicing across the statue. No apparent damage until: CRACKKKKK!!! a diagonal line appears and the top half falls. KROENEN reaches for a small crank embedded in his chest and winds himself up. Ilsa reaches into a hollow portion in the wooden statue and removes a large reliquary jar containing Golden sand. Six guards hurry in. They point their flashlights and guns at Kroenen.</context>
      <utterance>Move.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kroenen starts shaking, as if in a seizure and readies two</context>
      <utterance>You! Don't move! Hands up!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GUARD 6</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Something is clearly stopping him. His hand breaks, twisted by an unseen force!! The flesh on his neck pushes upwards, held by an invisible force. He starts floating in mid-air. The blinking lights of arriving police cars tint the windows red and amber. They outline a figure formerly submerged in shadows. GRIGORY. He gestures with both hands, as if holding an imaginary doll. His arm muscles twitch under his skin, shifting, changing, gaining strength. With a quick gesture Grigory twists the lower and upper parts of the guard's body in opposite directions. With a wet CRUNCH, the guard's shadow on the wall goes limp. Grigory looks at Ilsa.</context>
      <utterance>Don't --</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ilsa opens the reliquary jar and pours a circle of sand onto the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Ready the welcome, my love --</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grigory slices the air with his open hand, creating fleeting glyphs... and a small BLACK flame dances on his open palm. He deposits it in mid-air, at the center of the circle. Then, the sand begins to move, like liquid mercury. Lines fuse into a pile. It melts and bubbles, growing and foaming. Bones are formed, tendons and ligaments join together,</context>
      <utterance>Salt. Gathered from the tears of a thousand martyrs. Restraining the essence of Sammael, the hell hound, the seed of destruction.</utterance>
   <speaker>GROWING, GROWING, INTO SAMMAEL.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It roars!!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Professor..? You -- are very sick --</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Broom turns around, gently pushes Abe's hand away.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want Hellboy to know --</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sixty years ago Abe, they tried to destroy the world. And they are back -- in my lifetime, they are back. To finish the job.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DOWN'S PATIENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a big red guy down there!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR MARSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's fine, darling, Santa's not here for another month.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOWN'S PATIENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hearing this, Liz stops. She closes her eyes, tugs at one of the rubber bands on her wrist and lets it snap against her skin. She winces and peers out the window. The garden below seems empty.</context>
      <utterance>Not Santa. Big and red. With gold eyes. And he has beer!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Visible in the branches, a leg and part of Hellboy's overcoat. His tail emerges, dangling the six-pack.</context>
      <utterance>Back so soon?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Liz shoots a Polaroid.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, I brought beer.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shyly, he climbs out from the bush. She sees the bloody arm.</context>
      <utterance>To wash down my lithium pills?  I may get a few perks, H.B. But I'm still a patient.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You better have that looked at.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Liz sighs.</context>
      <utterance>Just a scratch.  I wanted to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We miss you at the Bureau. Abe's crazier every day. And Father's still mad at me --  Come back, Liz. Come back. I --</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Around her right hand a faint BLUE AURA of fire blooms, crawling over her fingers like a velvet haze. She stares at the pale flame.</context>
      <utterance>No. Not this time, H.B. It's been months since I've had an episode. And you know what? I'm learning to control it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm learning where it comes from.  And for once in my life I'm not afraid. She clenches her fist and puts the flame out.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The garbage truck and the two black sedan cars have pulled into the hospital grounds. A dozen agents climb out of the vehicles.</context>
      <utterance>Looks like your ride is here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Nanny Squad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, may I go first??</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not so fast. He barely knows him --</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then he should make it his business to change that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGLE - THE BENCH - CONTINUOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Liz stands up, puts her hand on his shoulder.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hellboy smiles sadly. She walks away.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, H.B. I've got a chance out here. If you truly care about me, don't come back anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodnight, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She doesn't turn back.</context>
      <utterance>Goodnight.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Feeling light-headed, he stands up. On the bench and at his feet, a pool of his own blood. He sees Myers tentatively approaching.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I gotta go, too. Lots to do --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What took you so long?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, time to go home. Tape you up.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you, a Boy Scout?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I never was.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, champ. You look a little woozy, there.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Liz stands at the hospital door and sees Hellboy keel over. A few of the agents help him to the vehicles. Myers looks back at Liz. They hold each others' gaze, their unfamiliar faces filled with curiosity. Eventually, she goes inside.</context>
      <utterance>This -- ? This is nothing. You know what'll kill me?  Her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were burned by some organic acid.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Using a scalpel, Abe probes the gash. Hellboy lets out a</context>
      <utterance>I'm lucky that way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son. About Rasputin --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. I'll get him soon enough --</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to me. This time is different. There's more at stake than ever before.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How hard can it be? I punched the crap out of that thing that he sent -- ouch!!</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I worry about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me?? C'mon --</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I won't be around forever, you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, stop that --  Damn! Be careful, there --</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Red. How long was it latched onto you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dunno, maybe five seconds -- ow!</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want me to hold him down?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right, Stud, hold me down.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Broom moves to Abe's side of the table. Abe is poking at the depths of the wound.</context>
      <utterance>Professor...</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't look! Turn around.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Broom comes closer, eyes wide: inside the wound on Hellboy's forearm, nestled like ticks, are 3 translucent EGGS. Hellboy jumps as Abe plucks the first one out. Abe deposits it in a glass container.</context>
      <utterance>Is it bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Touched you five seconds. Laid three eggs.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't even buy me a drink.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abe picks up an egg with a pair of tweezers, passes it on to Hellboy, who sports a bandage on his arm.</context>
      <utterance>The eggs are very sensitive to heat and light. They need a humid, dark environment to breed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Down there. Did you ever loose track of him?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, let's see -- there was that moment, when I had a train on top of my head -- Broom frowns, worried.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't risk it: You'll go back to the tracks tomorrow with a group of agents, search the area, top to bottom. Myers observes, repelled, as inside the egg a small foetal THING wiggles.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm in way over my head, I know that much.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the last book stand, Broom glances at Abe, who is sitting in the shadows near the door.</context>
      <utterance>You're doing fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Discouraged, Myers heads for the door.</context>
      <utterance>No, I'm not. He respects Clay. Not me. I don't know why you chose me, Sir. But I'm not qualified.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shocked, Myers looks over at Broom.</context>
      <utterance>I'm dying Agent Myers.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And as a father, I worry about him.  In medieval stories, Agent Myers, there's often a young knight, inexperienced but pure of heart...</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, please. I'm not "pure of heart."</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I ask from you is -- Have the courage to stand by his side after I'm gone. Help him find himself. Who he must be.  He was born a Demon... You will help him become a man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gently caresses the scar on her forehead. Under his skin, a hideous movement, a writhing rearrangement of muscles. His fingers start to glow.</context>
      <utterance>The Master is calling your name now, my girl. We are all part of his plan. You must return to the child... So, once again...</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Liz convulses. A small ripple of heat rises from her forehead.</context>
      <utterance>...dream of fire.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BLONDE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Liz turns to see them.</context>
      <utterance>Freak!</utterance>
   <speaker>BLONDE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Liz shies away from them.</context>
      <utterance>See? She knows her name.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLONDE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start throwing stones. One hits the steps. Another misses her by inches. A third hits her in the shoulder. Scared, Liz turns but a rock catches her full on the face. She falls down, blood trickling from her forehead, splattering the pavement. She starts sobbing. Another rock sails across, but this time, in mid-air, it catches fire and turns to ash. A ripple of heat starts crawling up Liz's hands. Soon a pale blue flame rings her entire arm.</context>
      <utterance>Go home, you freak. We don't want you here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Firelight glints off the crucifix.</context>
      <utterance>Not again, please, not again...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mother sees...</context>
      <utterance>Mommy! Mommy!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mother screams, horrified.</context>
      <utterance>Mommy! Help me! I'm burning!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She then explodes. A white-hot supernova engulfs the courtyard. Her mother's body burns like flash paper. Then the rest of the people are --</context>
      <utterance>Help meee!!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many buildings does she have to burn? She belongs here!</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Myers enters, deliberately clearing his throat. They ignore him.</context>
      <utterance>That's not how she feels. She may never feel it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's her choice --  She's human --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hellboy stomps over to a mirror and -- using a hand-held belt sander -- savagely shaves his horns. Sparks fly every time he goes at the round stumps.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, as opposed to -- ? Broom grows silent.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmmh -- "Pamcakes." We're going out --</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Professor, that girl you were talking about --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. You: think twice --</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I can help -- Talk to her -- I can bring her back.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Myers murmurs --</context>
      <utterance>What landed you this job, pushing "pamcakes"? Punctuality? What was your area of expertise?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was that??</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hellboy's face lights up.</context>
      <utterance>Hostage negotiations.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Liz turns away.</context>
      <utterance>Miss Sherman? I'm Agent Myers, FBI.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miss Sherman? I'm Agent Myers, FBI.  The hospital called us. They don't feel they're capable of caring for you any longer, and -- Silence.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Liz -- can I call you Liz? It's a beautiful name --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him. He offers his hand. She looks away.</context>
      <utterance>It's still impressive by my standards: My name's John.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Broom asked me to invite you back to the Bureau. No special precautions, no security escorts. You and me in a taxi. Like regular folks.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't sounds like him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Liz turns to the 2-way mirror. Both their reflections are there.</context>
      <utterance>Miss Sherman, he's asking you back, but it's entirely your choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Choice, huh? That's cute. I've quit the Bureau thirteen times. I always go back.  Where else would I go?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>QUARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're in the cellar of the Benjamin Institute. Turn-of-the-century orphanage. Closed since they moved the sewers in '51. Abe removes his gloves, hyperextends his palm and senses the air. Then the surface of the water.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Debris and dust seem to float from the water's surface and towards Abe's hand.</context>
      <utterance>There's a pulse. And it's coming from --</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>there -- They point their flashlights at a bulkhead.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They move some filing cabinets and stare at a blank concrete wall.</context>
      <utterance>cistern on the other side. Most of the eggs are there --</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT QUARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way in.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BAMMM!!! Hellboy's stone hand cracks the concrete. He starts pounding, again and again, like a jack hammer.</context>
      <utterance>We should go back and request permission to --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clay smiles uncertainly back. Hellboy moves in.</context>
      <utterance>Are you coming or not?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You two, check this dump, then join us --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abe ties the reliquary around his hand.</context>
      <utterance>There you go, Doctor. This should cover your tailfin -- On loan from the Vatican, a bone from Saint Dionysius. Ugh. Looks like a pinky.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remind me why I keep doing this.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rotten eggs and the safety of mankind.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As transparent nictomembrane lids cover his eyes, Abe dives.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, right --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CLAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, something moves. Hellboy shines his light into an adjoining tunnel. Kroenen is standing there, like a deer caught in headlights.</context>
      <utterance>See? It's thicker. Isn't it? It's not that doll-hair thing --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The figure darts away. Hellboy tears after it, gun in hand.</context>
      <utterance>Son of a -- !</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clay tries his radio. Static.</context>
      <utterance>Red, wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls out his gun and runs after Hellboy.</context>
      <utterance>Red's on the move!! I'll cover him!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He climbs out of the crater. Sammael growls.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Chunk-face!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hellboy rips off one of the turnstile bars and hits Sammael again and again.</context>
      <utterance>You can do better than that. Big monster like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sammael blocks the last hit and throws the bar away. It embeds itself in the tile wall. Sammael punches Hellboy, a hard uppercut. Hellboy flies up, crashing through the plate glass of a second mezzanine above the platform. He skids on the tile floor, scraping a jagged line with his stone hand. He slides past a group of BYSTANDERS and into a row of backlit subway ads. He lands in a shower of glass and debris on a wooden bench, breaking it in two. Sammael climbs up into the mezzanine. Hellboy gets up -- his back bristling with glass shards -- and hears a WAIL: a YOUNG GIRL is pointing at A BOX OF KITTENS abandoned on a bench.</context>
      <utterance>See? It hurts! You shouldn't hit people!</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUND GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My kittens!! My kittens!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sammael charges!!! Hellboy scoops up the box, holds it high!! Using his bone blade, Sammael pulverizes the bench. Next, Sammael slashes at Hellboy, scattering a dozen shrieking citizens. Illuminated by sparks and shorting lamps, Hellboy advances, blood dripping from his forehead and nose. Hellboy starts to reload, but -- Sammael's tongue shoots out. Hellboy throws the kitten box in the air and -- traps the tongue with his stone hand --</context>
      <utterance>Aw, crap.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- while catching the box with his tail. The kittens are fine. Using the tongue, he throws Sammael out a glass window. Sammael dangles above the tracks, but he re-joints himself and grabs a handhold on the train wall above the tunnel. From here, he pulls on Hellboy, sliding him toward the jagged glass. Sammael pulls harder, enters the tunnel. Hellboy fights to free himself, but his sweaty face is millimeters away from being sliced by the glass. All seems lost, when... WHAAAAA!!!!!! A train appears out of nowhere heading straight for Sammael. It splatters the thing against the tunnel wall and plows on. Sammael's body sprawls motionless at the side of the tracks.</context>
      <utterance>Second date. No tongue!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives the cats to the young girl --</context>
      <utterance>I hope that hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My job.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MOSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus -- Their locators light up.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly -- a noise! The agents leap up and sweep their flashlights over the columns... Nothing there.</context>
      <utterance>Abe --</utterance>
   <speaker>QUARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then, TWO SILHOUETTES cast long shadows. Powerful footfalls boom like thunderclaps. Agent Quarry raises his gun and fires at the dark shapes. Useless: the things plow on. Moss hurriedly straps on his flame thrower. After a few seconds, a green light beeps, READY. The muzzle of the flamethrower vomits a 30 feet long gout of fire into the blackness. The men pause: silence! Quarry turns on his flashlight, hand trembling.</context>
      <utterance>Moss, what the hell was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BAM!!! SAMMAEL'S TONGUE uncurls from the shadows and lands on Quarry's face, pulling him into the dark. His flashlight bobbles and strobes, lighting up a nightmare: TWO SAMMAELS stand in the tunnel. One of them gleefully squeezes Quarry. The man's screams are muffled by the creature's fleshy lips wrapping around his head. Moss runs as fast as he can, jumping and tumbling through an obstacle course of beams. Turning, he readies the flamethrower. The SECOND SAMMAEL lands on Moss's back, breaking his spine.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever it was --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HELLBOY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's there? Clay? Come in, someone.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind Clay, Kroenen drops down from an overhead pipe, through shafts of gray light. He brings forth his customary long blade. Clay turns in time to see Kroenen coming at him. He fires. Kroenen stabs. Twin rivulets of blood run from Clay's nostrils.</context>
      <utterance>Clay, Code 30, this is Clay, over...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He can't hear her over the music. Myers knocks on the bulletproof acrylic divider.</context>
      <utterance>It feels good to be outside!! It's been so long...</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey!! The music!! Turn down the music!!</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He merely changes the radio station; the music stays at the same volume. Myers looks back at Liz. She is halfway out the window, sitting on the door.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, yeah, music!!</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes another Polaroid and passes it down to him. Myers looks at the Polaroid, then smiles. He climbs out of the other window, hands her the photograph.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus! That's not -- That's not safe, Miss Sherman -- Miss Sherman?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He waves at her. For the first time, she smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Nice view --</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes his picture. With the cold morning wind blowing Liz's hair and the sun on her face, she looks beautiful.</context>
      <utterance>A smile, huh? That's good.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Myers taps his fingers on the roof, to the beat of the music. He can't take his eyes off her. They drive towards the BPRD.</context>
      <utterance>Don't get used to it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MANNING'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'll make it -- Hellboy turns, Manning is there:</utterance>
   <speaker>MANNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But not everyone was so lucky.  Two agents died today. Clay probably won't survive the night. You're reckless.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew those men better than you did --</utterance>
   <speaker>MANNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to leave. Hellboy gets up.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, I see. That makes it all alright then.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it doesn't make it right, but I stopped that creature, didn't I?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what you do. That's why we need you. You have an insight.  You know monsters.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you trying to say?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the end, after you've killed and captured every freak out there -- there's still one left: you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome back.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's only for the weekend, Professor Broom. Then I'll be on my way --</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CRASH!!! Liz screams and Myers draws his gun. Smashing through a glass partition, the mangled steel LOCKER lands in the middle of the hall in a rain of glass and aluminum studs. Next, Manning appears, retreating but unharmed.</context>
      <utterance>Come and go as you please.  Find your way back. We've made quite a few changes --</utterance>
   <speaker>MANNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He flees.</context>
      <utterance>I want that thing locked up, starting now -- Now!!! You hear me??!!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She spins on her heel and walks off. Hellboy turns to Myers.</context>
      <utterance>Liz? Liz!!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Myers holsters his gun and follows Liz. Hellboy is all alone now.</context>
      <utterance>You!!! You did it, buddy --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Woo hoo!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sits by her side on the bed.</context>
      <utterance>A little something I learned in therapy. I'm depressed --  One rubber band. I'm impatient: two rubber bands...</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll get you a fresh pack.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do you --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Myers sets the tray on the table.</context>
      <utterance>Shh! Just a second.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Myers, you're a talker. What's a good word -- a solid word for "need" --</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Need" is a good, solid word.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah, sounds too "needy."</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he goes out, Liz appears in the doorway. Hellboy quickly stops writing.</context>
      <utterance>Start in, you got nachos coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Liz plays with a cat. Hellboy lifts the piece of paper, which looks like a postage stamp in his stone hand.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, my God... Look at them all! Who had babies? C'mere, Tiger...!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um... Liz -- I -- there's something I'd like you to -- something I need you to hear.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well. Is it long?? I'm going out, but --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out? Out out?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For a cup of coffee, but go ahead, read.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going alone?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hellboy stands up, walks towards her.</context>
      <utterance>No. Myers is taking me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Him!! Why him? Why not me? Myers walks back in pushing a tray of nachos.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, your chili's getting cold --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hellboy folds the paper.</context>
      <utterance>What did you want me to hear -- ?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's nothing. Just a list -- It's not finished --</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leaves. Myers smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, okay then. Maybe later then.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything else you --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not from you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well good n-</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The visible areas of the body make us grateful for the sheet covering the rest.</context>
      <utterance>The subject: Karl Ruprecht Kroenen --</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The silver hand and harness lie on a table.</context>
      <utterance>Suffered a masochistic compulsion known as surgical addiction.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He finds the small pieces of paper Kroenen planted in his pouch.</context>
      <utterance>Both eyelids were surgically removed along with his upper and lower lips, making speech impossible. The blood in his veins dried up decades ago. Only dust remains.  Four pulverized vertebrae. A steel rod inserted into his pelvis held him up.  What horrible will power could keep a thing like this alive?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I admire him. He's a force of nature.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's just pushy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... He's determined. Unstoppable --</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cocky.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Strong.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A brute.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Liz half-smiles, sips her coffee.</context>
      <utterance>My uncle used to say... we like people for their qualities but love them for their defects.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He -- loves you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they walk down the street. A red streak jumps over roof tops.</context>
      <utterance>Don't know. Really. I grew up with him.  I've missed him too, but now, every time I see him, I get confused. Hardly a day goes by he's not in my mind. Even now, I feel he's here --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes the coffee, waves off the half and half.</context>
      <utterance>No cream and sugar, moron. She takes it black.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trying to feel superior, Hellboy chuckles. As they walk, Liz gestures vigorously. His smile fades.</context>
      <utterance>Toldya.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's freezing, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>By now, all the shops are closed. They approach a small park near a train track.</context>
      <utterance>Coffee's warming me up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do we do now? Newark, New Jersey, entertainment capital of the world. She cleans off a wet, dirty bench, sits down.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Myers is falling for her.</context>
      <utterance>You offered me a cup of coffee. I've got one, so just sit down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kid stares at him.</context>
      <utterance>Hi...</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're Hellboy.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shh. I'm... on a mission. He watches as Liz and Myers sit on the bench.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't tell anyone, huh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LIME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Broom motions for him to stop. It's useless,</context>
      <utterance>Should we send out some scouts?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Enough. He will never change -- always a child. Always.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sits by Hellboy's side as he watches Liz and Myers chatting and laughing.</context>
      <utterance>My Mom baked 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hellboy grabs three cookies off the plate and scarfs them down.</context>
      <utterance>That's it: she's laughing. I'm done.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't look like spies.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Below, Myers yawns. Hellboy slaps his forehead.</context>
      <utterance>Come on! Look at him, those shifty eyes, that -- phony grin...!!  You gonna eat that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, the yawning trick. That's so 1950's! Watch his arm -- He looks around, picks up a pebble, hefts it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Myers stretches and places his hand and arm behind her back. Something hits him in the head.</context>
      <utterance>We all have a side that we try to hide...</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets up, annoyed. No one in sight.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! What the hell?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TCHK!! A noise -- Broom turns in time to see Kroenen delicately descending a spiral staircase, blade in hand. In spite of all his experience, Broom is shaken.</context>
      <utterance>It's Rasputin's mausoleum.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the dark, a voice hisses --</context>
      <utterance>I see the puppet. But -- where is... the puppet master?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Broom turns. Grigory steps from the shadows.</context>
      <utterance>Very good, Professor Broom.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was you: The scraps of paper, Liz's sudden relapse and return...</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIGORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bread crumbs on the trail. Like in a fable. They both distract him and guide him exactly where I need him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Moscow.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He touches Broom's forehead, lightly --</context>
      <utterance>His destiny.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You raised the child. Nurtured him. So, In return... Would you permit me? A brief, brief glimpse? Of the future --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Broom is speechless.</context>
      <utterance>If only you had him destroyed sixty years ago, none of this would come to pass. But, then, how could you have known?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rasputin stands, the flesh of his neck and shoulders heaving and twitching beneath his human skin.</context>
      <utterance>Your God chooses to remain silent. Mine lives within me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the frozen waters of the Malaya Nevka, in the darkness of the void: every time I died and crossed over, a little more of the Master came back with me. He disclosed to me the child's true name... Would you like to know it??</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Discreetly, Broom removes his rosary and places it on the book. Kroenen settles in behind him.</context>
      <utterance>I know what to call him. Nothing you can say or do will change that. I call him son.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kroenen's knife goes in.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Now, I'll add two crumbs more:  Grief and revenge...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just go down there and tell her how you feel!  My mom says --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not that easy, okay?  Plus, you're nine. You're not old enough to give me advice.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TWO of the black B.P.R.D. Sedan cars rounds the corner. Agent Lime bounds out of one of the vehicles, grabbing Myers, talking rapidly. Liz screams, covers her ears.</context>
      <utterance>Who are those guys?? Hellboy turns and sees --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something's wrong --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Manning herds everybody out. From the door, Liz blinks back tears as the red giant kneels by the body: a dog with a lost master.</context>
      <utterance>Father -- I'm back. I'm back. I'm back.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wasn't here. You died alone --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles faintly.</context>
      <utterance>I've never seen him like this. Never.  Should I stay? With him, I mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their hands almost touch, separated only by the glass.</context>
      <utterance>Listen -- I'm not much of a problem solver...  Three decades and I've only gotten two sides.  But I know this much: if there's trouble -- all we have is each other. And I'm stuck here.  So -- Take care of the big monkey for me, will you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MANNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In a meeting room, Manning stands at a polished obsidian desk. A group of agents -- Myers among them -- listens attentively.</context>
      <utterance>We've collected and destroyed thousands of eggs. No trace of this "Sammael" or this "Rasputin" character. But we have this address --</utterance>
   <speaker>MANNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sebastian Plackba 16. Volokolamsk fields, fifty miles from Moscow. We leave as soon as we get clearance and equipment --</utterance>
   <speaker>MANNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Myers spots Liz walking past the conference room.</context>
      <utterance>Hellboy's coming --  But I'll be in charge this time. Either we wrap this up or I'm closing this freak show for good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to her. She slowly comes towards him.</context>
      <utterance>Hi --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've changed my mind. I'll come to Moscow. If you -- are still going -- Hellboy nods, then clears his throat.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am.  But -- I have something to say, too.  I never had the guts before - He looks her in the eye.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I understand what you don't like about me. I do. What I am makes you feel out of place -- out there --</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Red, I --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen. I'm not like Myers. He makes you feel like you belong. And -- that's good. It really is. I -- wish I could do something about this --  But I can't.  I can promise you only two things... One: I'll always look this good. Two: I won't give up on you. Ever.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like that...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>GENERAL LAPIKOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The warehouse contains a world of bric-a-brac: a towering marble LENIN HEAD, Old Master paintings, tanks, warheads, missiles, etc.</context>
      <utterance>I have accumulated many objects of great interest. Preserving our heritage.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL LAPIKOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stop before a cargo container. With a butane torch, a soldier melts away the lead Kremlin seal, then open the doors.</context>
      <utterance>Many -- like me -- believe Mother Russia to be very close to a historic rebirth.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rebirth? I like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAPIKOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty tons of stone. This thing fell from the sky into Tungaska forest.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grigory's fingers brush over its smooth, perfect surface. At the center -- -- TWO CIRCULAR IMPRINTS that match Hellboy's four-fingered stone hand.</context>
      <utterance>June 30th, 1908. It burned hundreds of square miles of forest. The Romanovs took possession of it immediately. The Czar guarded it jealously -- I have wanted it for ages.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, finally, it's mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL LAPIKOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are aware, of course, there's no way you'll get it out of Russian territory.</utterance>
   <speaker>ILSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ilsa brings out a chrome box, full of gold.</context>
      <utterance>He is aware.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL LAPIKOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grigory's voice drips with serene brutality.</context>
      <utterance>It's a pleasure doing business with you. Perhaps you have other interests.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enjoy the bright metal you've earned. There will be no further transactions.  Only closure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"One falls, two shall arise." So: you pop one, two come out. You kill two, you get four. You kill four, you're in trouble. We have to nail 'em all at once. And the eggs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MANNING shows them a set of GRENADE BELTS.</context>
      <utterance>When we do: No mumbo-jumbo. Double- core Vulcan-65 grenades.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've installed a very handy timer. Set it, walk away. Cable pulls the safety pins, K-boom! Easy to clean, easy to use...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those things never work. Never.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Each of us gets a belt.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Manning looks at Hellboy, irate.</context>
      <utterance>I won't take 'em. They never work.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll carry his -- Hellboy wraps Broom's rosary on his wrist.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy Scout.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HELLBOY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sparky?? Who came up with that? Myers?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're almost there.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Motors are turned off. The crate is opened. Liz peeks in.</context>
      <utterance>This better be the place or I'll puke.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come out and see.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MANNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gestures and all the agents head for the vans.</context>
      <utterance>Forget it. This is practically a city. And it stinks, and it's muddy. We'll go back, check into a hotel, regroup after breakfast. We'll have to make a grid, go by quadrants. Maybe satellite photography.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me ask for directions.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The corpse fidgets on Hellboy's back. Its bony hand weakly points, as if in confirmation.</context>
      <utterance>Sixty feet further, comrades, and three rows in...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The corpse mutters again. SUBTITLED: GO THAT WAY, RED MONKEY.</context>
      <utterance>This here is Ivan Klimentovich: Say "hi" Ivan.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, someone's expecting us. Turn on your locators -- Anyone sees anything...</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marco...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the other side of the panel, Myers takes the radio from Liz.</context>
      <utterance>...Polo.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Liz and Myers move off. Hellboy shines his light down the tunnel on the left. Agent Lime picks up the corpse and follows.</context>
      <utterance>On a scale of one to ten: two. But --  -- she'll take care of you, Myers. She's a tough one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MANNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hellboy motions for silence. The CORPSE mutters: "IT'S</context>
      <utterance>What's that --</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMETHING BIG"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They stare into the darkness.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should go back -- you -- you could tear that door apart --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't move. We --</utterance>
   <speaker>MANNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- should go back. Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Don't --</utterance>
   <speaker>MANNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hellboy yanks Manning just in time. BAMMM!!!! A gigantic metal pendulum swings past and demolishes one third of the bridge a few feet from their feet. It takes Lime and the CORPSE with it. Another door on the far end of the bridge shudders downward.</context>
      <utterance>I'm in charge. We go back!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whoosh! The PENDULUM swings back. It destroys more of the bridge. Manning sprints for all he's worth and crawls under the door. Hellboy runs, but chunks of stone disintegrate under his feet. The pendulum swings back taking out the final piece of the bridge just as Hellboy rolls under the door -- -- and makes it into the hexagonal building.</context>
      <utterance>Son of a --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hellboy yanks it away and bends it like a twig. BAMMMM!!!! He punches Kroenen in the face, crumpling the steel mask, smashing its lenses.</context>
      <utterance>Screw that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kroenen staggers back with each blow. Finally, the mask falls off.</context>
      <utterance>You killed my father -- BAMMM!!!! another hit.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An asthmatic wheeze erupts from his scarred face. Kroenen is laughing.</context>
      <utterance>Give your soul to God, Your ass is mine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Manning nods weakly. Hellboy brings out a cigar and fires up his Zippo.</context>
      <utterance>Are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd better stay here. I'll find a way out. We'll come back for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You call that thing a cigar??</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yup.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He digs out one of his fine cigars, cuts it and hands it to</context>
      <utterance>You never, ever light a cigar that way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MANNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lights it for him. Hellboy grins.</context>
      <utterance>Use a wooden match. It preserves the flavor.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My job.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A few bones roll by. Wet earth drops onto their shoulders. They draw their arms close to their bodies, pointing their flashlight beams straight down. A moment of strange intimacy.</context>
      <utterance>So, he thinks that you and I... That's why he's mad at me --</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it's not true, is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What -- ?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That you feel that way about me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to know -- Now -- ? Here? Red, white, whatever -- Guys are all the same.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His light shorts out. She shines her light past him.</context>
      <utterance>Watch out. It's slippery...</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Myers turns. His flashlight comes back on, revealing a complex natural cavern. An entire WALL IS COVERED with translucent eggs. SAMMAEL is there, gnawing on a dry arm bone, with the hand still attached. When the light hits his face, his milky pupils constrict. A snarl... A SECOND SAMMAEL emerges from the water. It shakes itself off. A THIRD ONE raise its head. Myers and Liz try to back away, but a metal wall rises right behind them KLANKKKKK!!! They are trapped!! Myers goes to grab a set of explosive belts. Tries to set up the timer. Zipp! -- one Sammael snatches them away. Myers falls to the ground, clothes torn, injured.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, my God...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hellboy scoops up Myers and deposits him next to Liz. Lit by Myers' flashlight, two of the creatures jump. One clamps onto Hellboy's back, the other onto his leg. Hellboy howls. The third one joins in, like lions dragging down a zebra. This time, though, the zebra fights back. Hellboy pulls out his gun and fires a round into the chest of a Sammael. Two eggs glow -- two new Sammaels are born. They're FIVE. Hellboy's torso is covered in blood. He falls to the ground. A fourth and a fifth creature spring onto him, biting. Hellboy is in trouble. Liz watches and shivers. A ripple of heat shimmers over her body.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry. Just couldn't leave you two alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hit me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Liz is desperate, crying.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hit me --  All of my life I've run away from it... Now I want it to happen! Do it. Hellboy screams. Water explodes under the fighting bodies. Two of the Sammaels turn their attention to Liz and Myers.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't, I -- Liz slaps him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat of silence, then Myers slaps her across the face, once. Hard. The heat ripple builds. The air vibrates around her. Her pupils kick back light, like an animal's.</context>
      <utterance>I know now: I love him. I've always loved him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Myers ducks behind a rock as Liz's arms blaze with fire. The two approaching Sammaels are ready to pounce. On top of Hellboy, one of them turns its head, like a lion hearing the hunter's gunshots. A staggering Hellboy sees Liz's body shake in a surge of white-hot energy.</context>
      <utterance>Go now.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The water at her feet blows away as a concave shockwave of fire expands. The fire engulfs the creatures. Devours them all.</context>
      <utterance>Liz...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hellboy tenses, rage building. The yoke creaks, but doesn't bend.</context>
      <utterance>"And I looked and beheld an Angel, and in his hand the key to the bottomless pit..."</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These were the words I heard as a peasant boy in Tobolsk. And now, the door -- Sent by the Ogdruh Jahad so that they might at long last enter our world.</utterance>
   <speaker>ILSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hellboy studies the stone sculpture, its three HAND IMPRINTS --</context>
      <utterance>You are the key! The right hand of doom!</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ilsa kicks Myers in the face.</context>
      <utterance>Don't do it!! Don't do it!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ILSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The open dome above reveals the moon. An eclipse is beginning. The altar's clockworks monitors its progress.</context>
      <utterance>Silence!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ILSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Imagine it: An eden for you and her --</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grigory turns to Hellboy.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In torment, Hellboy, shakes his head: no.</context>
      <utterance>No?  In exchange for her life then, open the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans over Liz, whispers in her ear: Her body arches, her mouth emits a plume of energy. Grigory greedily inhales it. Then she goes limp.</context>
      <utterance>As you wish.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He struggles again. One of the cuffs snaps. He swats Ilsa with his free hand. She stumbles backwards. Now Hellboy fights to free his other hand. Indifferent, Grigory watches the eclipse.</context>
      <utterance>Noooo! Noooo!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His head and heart racing, Hellboy struggles for an answer. Can't find one... the moon is almost totally eclipsed. He drops his gaze. His voice a hoarse whisper.</context>
      <utterance>Her soul awaits on the other side. If you want her back...  Open the door and claim her.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grigory moves close to Hellboy. Rips the rosary off his wrist. It lands near Myers.</context>
      <utterance>For her.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Names hold the power and nature of things. Mine for example. Rasputin: "The crossroads."  And crossroads I have become.  Your true name: Anung-un-Rama. Repeat it. Become the key.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anung-un-Rama...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hellboy puts his hand inside, CLACK!!! Before he can turn it, Myers reaches the rosary. Ilsa lunges at him. He clobbers her full in the face. She staggers back and down.</context>
      <utterance>The final seal. Open it!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will never fulfill your destiny. You will never understand the power inside you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He breaks Myers' chains, helps him up.</context>
      <utterance>I can live with that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Child... Hellboy turns. Grigory, on his knees, smiles.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up. In his empty eye socket, fleshy tendrils shift lazily.</context>
      <utterance>Look what you've done --</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He uncovers his abdomen. Long, fleshy pseudopods spill out of the wound, like intestines. A large entity erupts from Grigory's torso and claws the air.</context>
      <utterance>You've killed me -- an insignificant man... but you have brought forth a God.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRIGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Covered in steamy slime, a seven foot, multi-tentacled shape -- BABY BEHEMOTH -- lands on the stone slab. The squirming flesh surges up like greasy pink foam. Growing exponentially by the second. Ilsa kneels and embraces Grigory's corpse. Kisses him on the mouth. A gargantuan tentacled shadow looms above them.</context>
      <utterance>Behold, my master, Behemoth. Guardian of thresholds, destroyer of worlds.</utterance>
   <speaker>ILSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A tower of flesh disdainfully crushes them both.</context>
      <utterance>Hell will hold no surprises for us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep her safe. No matter what. I'll deal with whatever's back there.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alone?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As if in response, a massive tentacle fills the tunnel, reaching for him. Oil lamps hanging from the ceiling smash onto HELLBOYS head as he is pulled back at breakneck speed, finally confronting --</context>
      <utterance>How big can it be?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They never work -- He wraps them around his stone arm.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls the pin on all the explosives. BEHEMOTH drops him into a squid-like beak and gulps him down. After a moment, a weird gurgle emanates from the creature's innards. Then --</context>
      <utterance>Ugh -- Now, this is gonna hurt --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the dark -- I heard your voice -- What -- did you say -- ? He looks at her, lovingly caressing her hair.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Myers smiles. Liz looks at Hellboy for the first time as what he is: the man she loves. A warm, gentle fire rims her body. Manning watches. Agent Myers smiles a sad smile, illuminated by the flames. Hellboy and Liz kiss. The fire haloes them and builds as Tom Waits' CINNY'S WALTZ fills the air.</context>
      <utterance>"You, on the other side: let her go. Because for her, for her -- I'll die. I'll cross over."  "And you'll be sorry I did."</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
