<movie id="270" title="Henry Fool">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where the hell have you been?  Mom, come on and eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary is a manic-depressive, still in her bathrobe at six in the evening.</context>
      <utterance>Then why'd I cook!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fay holds her head in her hands and sighs. She glares at her brother.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know why you cooked! I don't know why you bother!</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon sits at the table and Fay slams down before him a bowl of some sort of gruel. He hesitates, then lifts his spoon. Supper is horrible and he screws up his face in disgust. Fay gives him a sideways glance and he leans back down over the bowl and eats some more. Pushing the bowl away gently, he reaches out for the container of milk on the table and drinks straight from it. He suddenly jumps back and spits out sour milk all over the table. The container drops to the floor and thick globs of cheese roll out. He stands back against the fridge, holding his stomach while... Fay and Mary look on in disgust.</context>
      <utterance>Sit down and eat, Simon.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fay snaps shut her compact, straightens her skirt and sighs.</context>
      <utterance>God, I wanna get fucked.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon loses track of what he is hearing and relaxes. He looks back at his sister. Fay fluffs out her hair and walks off.</context>
      <utterance>You OK?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon watches her go, but is still drawn to something he seems to hear up the street in the other direction. He cocks his head, sits perfectly still and listens. He hears it now. We do, too. Footsteps. Big ones. Like a giant somewhere in the distance. The neighborhood trembles. Titles begin. Simon tries to figure out where it's coming from; the sky, the house, the highway at the end of his block... Finally, he focuses on... The blacktop right before him, smeared with his own blood. Music starts. He kneels out slowly into the street and stares at the pavement. He stretches out his hand and places it flat on the road. The pounding is louder now, becoming the beat of the music over the scene. Simon lowers his face to the pavement, closes his eyes and... Puts his ear right down against the road. He hears... The steady tread of somebody very much larger than life. Kneeling forward, with his ear to the ground, Simon opens his eyes and sees... A man approaching. The music swells up full. Simon lifts his head slowly from the road, looking off in wonder at... This stranger coming towards him; an oddly handsome freak striding over the crest of the distant intersection with a windswept mane, two over-stuffed suitcases and a crumpled tie fluttering back over his broad but crooked shoulders. Simon rises till he's kneeling up straight in the road. Henry Fool finally reaches him and stops. Titles finish. Simon says nothing and watches as Henry looks off at the house. Satisfied, but wary, Henry Fool looks around the neighborhood and then down at Simon.</context>
      <utterance>See ya later.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tosses the suitcases down in front of Simon and walks off towards his new home.</context>
      <utterance>Get up off your knees.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="45">
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say something.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's mute.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy looks back at Gnoc, snarls, then follows the cashier's gaze to the door. Simon enters. Clutching Henry's cash, he stops dead in his tracks when he sees... Warren and Amy. He steps forward and approaches the beer cooler. Warren and Amy hover around, just out of reach, like a couple of vampires. Dragging a six-pack out of the cooler, Simon crosses to the counter. Warren and Amy hang back, silent and threatening. Gnoc rings up the purchase and glances over at... Amy, staring a hole into the side of Simon's skull. Gnoc hands Simon back his change and he makes for the door, but... Warren shoves himself between it and Simon. Simon freezes. Warren is expressionless. Simon looks back at Amy. She turns away, reaches up under her skirt, jerks down her panties, then leans forward on to the counter. Leering back over her shoulder, she hisses...</context>
      <utterance>She don't -- you know -- talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon is nonplussed. Gnoc presses a button on the wall that sets... A red light flashing above the stockroom door. Warren grabs Simon by the neck and drags him over to Amy's bare behind. Amy laughs as Simon is forced to his knees and has his face shoved up right into the crack of her ass. But then... Simon throws up all over her. Warren falls back in disgust. Gnoc covers her face with her hands. Amy looks around at herself, realizes, and starts screaming bloody murder. Simon falls back on to the floor, clutching his stomach, as Amy staggers around with her vomit-strewn underwear down around her ankles. Then Gnoc's father, Mr Deng, appears at the stockroom door holding a shovel and ready to fight.</context>
      <utterance>Kiss my ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr Deng comes running at them and Warren drags Amy from the store. Simon crawls out of the way as the old man throws open the door to the parking lot and screams at the retreating delinquents...</context>
      <utterance>Oh, shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR DENG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at this! What's going on here? Simon, get up off the floor! Is this beer paid for?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do you come from?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He winks at Simon, then struts around the room, hugely impressed with himself.</context>
      <utterance>Nowhere in particular.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I go where I will and I do what I must.  That's why I'm in trouble. I'm sort've what you might call... 'in exile'.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you in trouble?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry pauses, looks aside, drinks, then grins demoniacally. He steps forward and comes face to face with Simon. He lifts his finger and points to... Simon's name stitched upon the breast of his work shirt. Realizing this, Simon moves off and thinks. Henry throws more wood on the fire, glancing back over his shoulder, laughing mischievously.</context>
      <utterance>How do you know my name?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am not retarded.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... I'll take your word for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon looks at him. Henry stands and grabs a notebook from off the mantelpiece. He tears out a few pages and shoves them in his pocket. He hands the now fresh writing tablet to Simon.</context>
      <utterance>I see.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He searches his pockets and finds a pencil.</context>
      <utterance>Here. Take this. And...</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon hesitates, then accepts the gifts. Henry goes for another beer while his new friend studies the dozens of notebooks on the mantelpiece.</context>
      <utterance>...this. Keep them with you at all times. You ever feel like you got something to say and you can't get it out, stop and write it down. OK?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are these?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This? This is my life's work. My memoirs. My 'Confession'.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry drinks and looks down into the raging fire.</context>
      <utterance>What have you done?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been bad. Repeatedly.  But why brag? The details of my exploits are only a pretext for a far more expansive consideration of general truths.  What is this? It's a philosophy. A poetics. A politics, if you will. A literature of protest. A novel of ideas. A pornographic magazine of truly comic-book proportions. It is, in the end, whatever the hell I want it to be. And when I'm through with it, it's gunna blow a hole this wide straight through the world's own idea of itself! He smokes. Simon is impressed. They hear a bottle smash outside in the street and Henry goes to the window. They're throwing bottles at the house.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon jumps up.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, let's go break their arms!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry stops. Simon looks away and sits back down.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry sees this and settles down. He considers his new friend with genuine care as he gets himself a new cigarette. He lights up, thinks, then grabs another chair and sits close by Simon. They sit there in silence a while, then...</context>
      <utterance>If I'm quiet. He is ashamed of himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry stares into the flames and falls silent. Simon is riveted. He leans forward, on the edge of his seat...</context>
      <utterance>Once. I forget where I was. Central America maybe. Somewhere hot. Stupid job. Bad pay. Dangerous location and water so foul the natives wouldn't even piss in it. This crowd of drunken motherfuckers hired by the local drug cartel shows up at my hotel room and threatens to tear me limb from limb. And I say, listen, hombres, OK, you've got me outnumbered four to one and you're gunna kill me here tonight and not a soul in this dimly lit world is ever gunna notice I'm gone. Fine. But one of you... one of you... one of you is gunna have his eye torn out. Period. Silence. I repeat myself. One of you poor, underpaid jerks is gunna have an eye ripped out of its socket. I promise. It's a small thing, perhaps, all things considered. But I will succeed. Because it's the only thing I have left to do in this world. So why don't you just take a good look at one another one last time and think it over for a few minutes more.  They sober up a little, look at their shoes in confusion, then step out into the hall to talk among themselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, here I am, still, after all.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon says nothing. He looks down at his feet.</context>
      <utterance>They were throwing bottles at the house.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's got some ex-con in there she met at the bar. Tattoos all over himself and a big red bloated nose.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now she says nothing. She smokes and looks away. Simon steps into the bathroom and gets her medication. He runs a glass of water and brings it in to her. She swallows the pills and washes them back with water.</context>
      <utterance>Did you take your pills?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks away, unconcerned and cynical.</context>
      <utterance>You want me to tell her to be quiet?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She throws the blanket over herself and turns off the light. Simon stands there in the dark.</context>
      <utterance>What's the use? She might as well get it while she can. She's not always gunna have the ass she has now, you know. That's just how life is.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon rubs the sleep from his eyes, blinks, disoriented and reaches for his wallet.</context>
      <utterance>Good morning, Simon! Glorious day, huh? Here, have a donut. Can you lend me twenty dollars?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. Where's the library in the scruffy little burgh?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Down the highway about a mile and a half and then make a left.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lifts up Simon's notebook.</context>
      <utterance>Excellent! I'm polishing up the final chapters of my 'Confession' and I need a reasonably well-stocked reference section.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon hesitates, shyly.</context>
      <utterance>What's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives up, sighs and gazes at the floor. Henry flips through the book, impressed. It is full from cover to cover, every page dense with Simon's cryptic scrawl. Henry frowns, intrigued. Then...</context>
      <utterance>I thought. Um. I was. I wanted to. Maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon looks up, terrified. But his friend puts him at ease.</context>
      <utterance>Can I take this?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll correct the spelling.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One of you is gunna lose an eye! Warren stops. Amy steps back and lowers the gas can. Simon turns with effort to face them, adjusts his glasses and continues...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Warren watches him blankly, then is burned by the torch which is too hot to handle. He drops it. Amy giggles, then stops, excited, but confused. Simon grips the rusted chainlink so that it cuts into his hands and stares straight at Warren.</context>
      <utterance>One of you. I promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Warren is transfixed. He shivers and looks at Amy, who steps back, scared, and puts down the gas can. She turns and walks away. Warren looks back at Simon, troubled. He hangs there still, glaring at him. Further away, Warren rejoins Amy and stares at his hands. Amy looks ill.</context>
      <utterance>You can set me on fire. But one of you is gunna have an eye torn out of your head. I promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take me home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="134">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Simon! Who did this to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was gunna tear out their eyes. I knew I could do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whose eyes?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He passes out. Henry looks at Mr Deng.</context>
      <utterance>I told them. Like you said. I told them. And I knew I could do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR DENG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry nods, agreeing, then lifts Simon off the floor. Mr Deng holds the door open as Henry carries his friend out into the parking lot. Meanwhile, Gnoc gathers up the classics from the floor and places them beside Simon's notebook, where it still sits open on the table. She looks at it, then reads. She lifts it off the table and reads further, immediately and deeply engrossed. Mr Deng watches as Henry departs with Simon, then comes back into the store and stops, startled, when he sees... Gnoc sitting there, staring off into space, the notebook open in her hands before her, singing quietly.</context>
      <utterance>You should take him home. He smells like a toilet.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit, Mom, we gotta get him to a hospital!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry is at the kitchen table with Mary. She watches him suspiciously. He lets her.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, shut up! Turn around.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This kinda thing has happened before.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She watches him as he walks around the room, browsing.</context>
      <utterance>It won't happen again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops and lifts a small framed photo of a soldier off the piano.</context>
      <utterance>How do you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Violated somehow, she gets up and snatches it out of his hands. She puts it in a drawer and cringes as Henry plays one note on the piano.</context>
      <utterance>This your husband?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He fixes her with a steady, knowing stare which causes her to gather the collar of her bathrobe up around her neck. She steps back, exposed, when there's a knock at the door. They look over to see... Mr Deng enter with the notebook.</context>
      <utterance>Stop that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR DENG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr Fool, what is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's poetry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR DENG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry comes over, takes the notebook from him and shoves it in his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Are you sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course I'm sure. I corrected the spelling myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR DENG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It made my daughter sing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, you know -- that's what poetry does.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR DENG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meanwhile, back in the bathroom...</context>
      <utterance>But she has never spoken in her life.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Owww!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep still!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom! Simon's got a broken rib, his shoulder's dislocated or something, and he won't let me disinfect the gash in his head!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fay, just take him to the hospital, will ya!</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But he won't go!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry sits on the edge of the bathtub and takes the notebook from his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>We gotta talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon just looks at him, not certain what he means.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell were you trying to do when you wrote this thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you know you wrote it in a kind of iambic pentameter.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Iambic what?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He scratches his chin and smokes.</context>
      <utterance>Verse.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>notebook on the floor and points at it with his cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>Look, in my opinion, this is pretty powerful stuff. Though your spelling is Neanderthal, and your reasoning a little naive, your instincts are profound. But the whole thing needs to be given a more cohesive shape. It can be expanded. Followed through. Unified.  You see what I'm getting at? Simon just stares at him, overwhelmed. Henry drops the</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon just blinks, looks away and wonders.</context>
      <utterance>Are you willing to commit yourself to this? To really work on it? To give it its due? In the face of adversity and discouragement? To rise to the challenge you yourself have set?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And don't gimme that wonderstruck 'I'm-only-a-humble-garbage-man' bullshit, either.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It hurts to breathe.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course it does. Simon coughs and Henry leans back and smokes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. No. OK?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't move! Fuck. There.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure that's right?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon does.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Now shut up and lie back.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this gunna hurt?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pauses, then leans back.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon nods and stares at the ceiling. Henry hands him a towel.</context>
      <utterance>You gunna be alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here. Bite on this.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon nods. Henry grabs hold of the arm, swallows and braces himself. Simon waits, then Henry tugs the arm straight.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. You ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fay turns and runs down the stairs. Mary backs away into her room and shuts the door.</context>
      <utterance>Aaagghhh!!!!!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, do you have, like, you know, a girlfriend, Henry?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They drink again in silence. He lights her cigarette and they watch each other closely. Finally, Fay leans on the table and twirls a strand of her hair between her fingers.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you find me attractive?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I look young for my age, don't I?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How old are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How old do you think I am?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look young.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How young?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Young.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drinks and studies her. She presents her profile. Finally, he leans back.</context>
      <utterance>But how... I mean, do I look more like twenty, or... you know, thirty?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fay jumps up, furious.</context>
      <utterance>Thirty.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grabs her bag and storms out of the house. Henry watches her go, then chuckles deviously and splashes himself another drink.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, you geek, after a couple of drinks plenty of people mistake me for eighteen!</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Warren, are you a registered voter?</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Unruffled, she hands him a flyer.</context>
      <utterance>Bug off, Vicky!</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Saving America From Itself.' What the fuck is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tokes deeply, then...</context>
      <utterance>It's everything you need to know about the upcoming elections and congressman Owen Feer and all the really good things he wants to do for our country.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah, like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Warren looks over the flyer, then reconsiders Vicky.</context>
      <utterance>He wants to win back this country for us Americans, Warren, and restore some kind of cultural-moral standard to our way of life.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What time's your kid go off to school?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nine o'clock.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vicky sighs, troubled. She adjusts her waitress uniform and looks mildly offended.</context>
      <utterance>How about I come over and visit you later?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Warren gets up, too.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't know, Warren. I mean...</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vicky is hard-pressed. She wants to believe him, but knows better. She thinks about it while... Henry passes by and approaches the store.</context>
      <utterance>Come on. I mean it. I'm trying to change.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR DENG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's poetry.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's pornography! The product of a diseased mind! You oughta be ashamed of yourself, Mr Deng!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR DENG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It made Gnoc sing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, Simon, there are three kinds of there. There's 'There'. T-H-E-R-E. There are the donuts. Then there's T- H-E-I-R; which is the possessive. It is their donut. Then, finally, there's 'they're'. T-H-E-Y-'-R-E. A contraction, meaning they are. They're the donut people. Get it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry lifts up one of Simon's newly acquired classics...</context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And look, if you're gunna read Wordsworth you've gotta get a more up-to-date edition. This odoriferous tome you're so attached to doesn't even have all fourteen books of the Prelude. And you need notes. Commentary. I'll go to the library and find you the best edition they have.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, but that's OK. I'll stop there on my way back from work. Well, yes, maybe not today, but, you know, tomorrow, probably.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quit.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My job?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need time to write, Simon. To study. To reflect.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I like my job.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon looks past him and Henry follows his gaze to find... Mary standing at the foot of the stairs, listening to them. She says nothing. She looks Henry up and down, then shakes her head disdainfully and grunts. She throws herself on the couch and turns on the TV, casting acid glances over at the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>We all have to make sacrifices. A vocation like ours, Simon, is not a nine to five thing. You can't put a fence around a man's soul. We think and feel where and when we can think and feel. We are the servants of our muse and we toil where she commands.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's clinically depressed.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, and what's that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry wanders out to the road, checking his wallet, then...</context>
      <utterance>I guess it means it's not her fault.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever think of leaving?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To go where?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon looks off, thinks it over and slowly nods.</context>
      <utterance>Out there. You know, into the world. Where ever.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Opportunity will step away and make room for a man to pass it by.'</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that from your book?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls the tiny piece of crumpled advice out from one of his pockets and shows it to Simon.</context>
      <utterance>No. I found it in a fortune cookie.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I read your confession?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Not yet. Soon. We'll see.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it almost finished?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He carefully finishes writing a word, then looks up and pauses.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing there, Simon?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary looks at Fay, who looks up from her magazine and considers her brother. Then they break out laughing. Simon looks on. They laugh and laugh and laugh...</context>
      <utterance>I'm writing a poem.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what? It ain't so great.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy nods 'Yes', then leads them towards Simon. Simon scribbles away.</context>
      <utterance>That him?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up, sees her, panics and slides away on the seat. Amy looks down and bites her lip, contrite. She sighs.</context>
      <utterance>Pardon me, Simon.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uhm. Look, ah... I'm the editor of the high school newspaper now and...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One of the editors.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One of the editors, and we...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon looks around at them all, threatened.</context>
      <utterance>I... wanted to know if we could print your poem in this month's issue.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I think it's great.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who cares what you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a drag.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A well-known drag.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon fumbles with his pencil, ill at ease and self-conscious. Then, to get rid of them, he nods his consent.</context>
      <utterance>Please?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary is lying on the couch. She drags her eyes from the TV and glances lazily at Fay, then back to the TV.</context>
      <utterance>Ma, you take your medication?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sits at the kitchen table and lifts her magazine. Henry shows up at the kitchen door with a pile of library books. His eyes brighten when he sees... Fay sitting there wearing only her towel. He knocks. She looks back over her shoulder and sees him.</context>
      <utterance>Guess so.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evening, Fay.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns away.</context>
      <utterance>I've got these books for Simon.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He comes in and stacks the books near the sink. Fay pretends to ignore him, but rakes her fingers through her wet hair anyway, to show more shoulder. This is not lost on Henry, who tarries and leans back against the counter, salivating. Fay flips through her magazine and Henry steps closer and leans against the fridge. She casts a bored glance in his direction, then returns her attention to the TV. She senses him step aside and follows his movements without turning. Suddenly his hand appears from behind her and gently strokes her hair. She freezes, waits, wonders... He leans his face down beside her. She looks at him. He looks at her, then down to... Her bare legs crossed before her on the kitchen chair. His hand moves down and slides itself deep in between her things. Her mouth drops open. He looks back up at her. He grins. Fay jumps up and away, breathlessly clutching the towel around herself. Henry casts a glance over her body, throws his hair back out of his face and shivers with lust. Fay steps back and grabs hold of the staircase banister, making an unconvincing gesture of injured pride. Henry comes closer and she steps backwards up the stairs. He stops, loosens his tie, holding her with his gaze. She readjusts her towel, throws back her wet hair, sighs defiantly, then sashays into her room, leaving the door ajar. Henry waits there at the foot of the stairs, reaches down, grabs his crotch and repositions his hard-on. He takes a step up the stairs, then stops. He looks over to the couch and sees... Mary, lying there, sedately amazed. He pauses, then grins. Mary blinks and smiles sleepily.</context>
      <utterance>Well, leave 'em there on the counter, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon hesitates, but then nods uncertainly. Warren hands him a flyer. This year when you go to the polls, I want you to consider Congressman Owen Feer. He wants to restore America to its position of unmatched wealth, power and opportunity; to revitalize American civilization and lead the human race to even greater levels of freedom, prosperity and security! He's a good man. He steps over to the register and pays for his beer. Mr Deng glares at him, distrustfully. Warren stops on his way out and snarls at the old man...</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Simon, you a registered voter?</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaves. Simon looks down and studies the flyer.</context>
      <utterance>Immigrant.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens the door and looks out into the hall. He's not there. She steps out into the hall and listens.</context>
      <utterance>Where is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nothing. She comes to the top of the stairs and hears faint activity from down below. She proceeds downstairs. She sees no one in the kitchen, then looks in the living- room and stops. She goes white, her mouth falling open in horror. Henry and Mary are screwing one another on the couch. Sloppy, impassioned, brute sex.</context>
      <utterance>Henry?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They fall away from each other in terror and fatigue. Mary clutches wildly at her bathrobe as Henry falls over the coffee table, stumbles to his feet and pulls up his trousers. Fay is crushed. She breaks out in tears and runs upstairs. Henry catches his breath and starts after her, but stops, uncertain and confused.</context>
      <utterance>Mommy!!!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You bastard!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get out!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon takes this in, then looks down at his hands and proceeds carefully.</context>
      <utterance>Listen. I know a man. He's a big shot in the publishing business. Angus James. Smart, adventurous and tons of integrity. When this thing is ready, I'll recommend he reads it. He'll respect my opinion.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A man was here today looking for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What man?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry throws his eyes heavenward and pulls his hair. Jumping to his feet, he paces maniacally.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. He drove by the house a few times.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A customer a few tables away gets nervous and leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Why do they torment me like this? Why? They're like a bunch of fucking mosquitoes!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do they want from you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some kid named Tim, sitting at another table, turns around and asks...</context>
      <utterance>They want to suffocate me, Simon! They wanna extinguish me like a flame!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But why?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drinks, then returns and sits beside Simon.</context>
      <utterance>They're afraid, that's why! They're afraid of what I might do! What I might say! Think! They're afraid of my ideas!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You and I are alike in this way, Simon.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drinks, burps, then slams down the can. He glances over at Tim who is still looking on.</context>
      <utterance>We're outsiders. We think and feel too much and too deeply. And the world can't handle that. Our mere existence is a threat to its illusion of security. Sure, they'll name a wing of a new library after us when we're dead! But now... Now, when we're alive... Now, they wanna burn us at the stake!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tim hesitates, but then obeys. He gets up and leaves. Henry returns to Simon.</context>
      <utterance>Scram.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon blinks. Henry adds...</context>
      <utterance>For example, I made love to your mother about half an hour ago and now I'm beginning to think that maybe it wasn't such a good idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon is deeply confused. He looks ill. He stands and takes a few steps away, staring at the floor.</context>
      <utterance>I mean to say, I think Fay may be jealous.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to think about this.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon stops and looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Bad move, Simon.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon pauses, then comes closer to Henry and stops.</context>
      <utterance>A poet has got to be able to think about anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry jumps up, strides around the store and speaks at the top of his voice.</context>
      <utterance>Am I really a poet?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks to the door.</context>
      <utterance>Of course you are! A great poet! But you need experience. You need to do something to be ashamed of every once in a while, for cryin' out loud.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon stands there, stunned and looks at Mr Deng as the old man wipes off the table with a wet rag.</context>
      <utterance>Come on! Let's go out! There's a den of iniquity right across the street! You got any money? He strides out of the store.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That man's a bad influence.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets up and storms into her room.</context>
      <utterance>On who?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="32">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry trudges back to the kitchen, where he whips out his red pen and immediately begins to correct Simon's poem. Simon rolls off the couch and makes his way to the table. Seeing the computer...</context>
      <utterance>Simon. Hey, Simon.  Come on. I got ya some coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches into his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>It's a computer. You write on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon looks over the computer and flips through the manual.</context>
      <utterance>Here's the manual.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd you get it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I stole it. Now listen. Remember how yesterday we discussed the relative desirability of cadence in relation to the readability of...</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fay is on the stairs, hungover and disgusted. Henry throws up his hands and gets up to go.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, shit! Not you again!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Simon, I can't work under these conditions.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah! Get outta here, you freak!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get a life!</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary throws open her bedroom door.</context>
      <utterance>Eat shit and die, Henry!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beast! Fiend! Rapist!</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fay stomps back upstairs. Mary slams her door shut. Simon runs out after Henry.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, shut up, Mom!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Henry, wait up!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Officer Buuel enter World of Donuts.</context>
      <utterance>I am not a rapist! But Henry stops short, seeing...</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he runs down the street in the opposite direction. Simon hangs back, but then follows...</context>
      <utterance>Shit. Come on, this way.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon does, but then...</context>
      <utterance>Keep a look out. Tell me when he's gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Henry, what's going on? Who is that guy? What's he want?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pats his pockets, looking for his smokes. Simon looks on, baffled. He comes closer.</context>
      <utterance>He wants to help me! He wants to be my friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Help you with what?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hears something, stands and moves further into the church. Simon hesitates, but then follows. They hear someone crying. Finally, in a pew off to one side in the shadows, they find... A young priest named Father Hawkes. He's a wreck. He looks up from his quiet sobbing and sees... Henry and Simon standing there looking on with embarrassed distaste. He lowers his head in shame. Henry moves closer and sits beside the distraught priest.</context>
      <utterance>Shhh!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The priest sighs hopelessly.</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER HAWKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry leans back with a sigh and reaches for his cigarettes.</context>
      <utterance>I doubt.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He offers a cigarette to the priest and he accepts.</context>
      <utterance>So, you're an honest man. Why beat yourself up about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER HAWKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know if there are grounds for faith. Is my vocation relevant? Does it make a difference?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A difference in what?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER HAWKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The world. The way it is. Is this a way to help relieve suffering?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your vocation makes a difference.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER HAWKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you be so sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because vocation is the difference. Only someone who really cares doubts. Listen, father, as I was about to tell my friend Simon here, I am, without doubt, the biggest sinner within a hundred miles of this parish. But still, I've gotta stay up late at night to outdo the unending parade of mundane little atrocities I see committed every day right out in the open spaces of this loud and sunlit culture we call home.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER HAWKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You seem to me to be a sensitive and generous man.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like to think so. But the fact is I appreciate depravity. Nevertheless, I insist your vocation makes a difference, because to hold out anything other than a spiritual yardstick to reality is to be jerking off grandly into the abyss. Listen, have you got any money? Let's go have a drink.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="100">
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, miss, are you a registered voter?</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God, really I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'd like to give you some information about Congressman Owen Feer. This man is gunna make a big difference in the lives of every American in the years to come...</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A man, Bill, steps up...</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, sure. I gotta go, thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pardon me, sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck off!</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Warren stands back and loosens his tie. He looks over at Pearl age seven, who is sitting outside the store.</context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She doesn't respond. He shakes his head and approaches. He sees Fay exit the store...</context>
      <utterance>What time's your mother get off work?</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fay, are you a registered voter?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you dare talk that way to me! And keep your hands off my brother. Pearl, what are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fay figures it out and approaches.</context>
      <utterance>I'm watchin' her.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You and Vicky get back together?</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lifts a flyer and reads.</context>
      <utterance>I gotta regular job now and everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw this retard on TV this morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's gunna be the next president of the United States of America, Fay.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep dreamin' Warren. The guy's a Nazi.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like him!</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gimme a light.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a decent man. He takes complicated issues and totally simplifies them. And I appreciate that.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You still sell dope?</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She studies him a moment more, lost, then shakes her head and helps the child off the car.</context>
      <utterance>No. You know what the problem is with this country, Fay? Me. I'm the problem. We live in a culture of poverty and crime, where the work ethic is undermined and male responsibility is made irrelevant.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Pearl, let's go play at my house.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She gives you any trouble, Fay, you just let me know.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER HAWKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think human beings are innately bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon falls off his bar stool.</context>
      <utterance>Worse than bad! Monstrous! But I love that about them.  Wake up, Simon!</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ, Simon, you're letting yourself go to hell! You read that flyer I gave you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon is lost.</context>
      <utterance>Simon, wake up and smell the coffee, huh! It's up to guys like you and me to help create a better tomorrow!</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would I steal a computer from the campaign office?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whack!!! He slaps her...</context>
      <utterance>I'm not saying you did, I'm just saying one was and since you do have this criminal background...</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon runs out of the store and limps away towards home as Buuel storms out in pursuit. Simon tries to run, but Buuel catches him easily.</context>
      <utterance>Don't judge me!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon ceases to struggle, but shakes himself free and stands looking down at his feet. Buuel stands aside and watches him a moment, then reaches in his jacket and brings out his badge.</context>
      <utterance>Look, I know you know him. People have seen you around together.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon studies the badge and waits a little, before asking...</context>
      <utterance>I'm his parole officer.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did he do?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not supposed to talk about that stuff with people.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buuel pauses, then puts away his badge and looks around the parking lot.</context>
      <utterance>He's my. Friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon doesn't corroborate this. He looks away and readjusts his sling. Buuel scratches his head, satisfied and prepares to leave. But first...</context>
      <utterance>Mr Deng says you're some sort of a poet, or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buuel waits a moment, then steps away and gets back in his car. Simon watches as the parole officer drives away and passes...</context>
      <utterance>You tell Henry to call me -- Officer Buuel -- pronto! Or they're gunna chuck his ass straight back into jail! Got it? Simon shrugs.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vicky, look I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you even come near me!</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, you quit?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I quit my job.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are things I want to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon thinks of trying to explain, but then decides not to.</context>
      <utterance>Like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Opportunity will step out of the way to let a man... pass it by.'</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you drunk?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you have to go out and get a job!</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am not gettin' a job!  Who's gunna look after Mom!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fay looks at the ceiling and sighs.</context>
      <utterance>I will.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They wait as the child goes outside. Mary listens, unseen, from her bedroom door. Fay comes over and frowns at her brother. She's about to lecture him, but he cuts her off.</context>
      <utterance>Pearl, go outside.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fay tries to control herself. She sighs tiredly and attempts to reason with him...</context>
      <utterance>If you treat Mom like a sick person, she's gunna stay like... you know, a sick person.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Simon, don't be retarded...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fay steps back, startled. Simon stands, but can't decide which way to go. He sits back down.</context>
      <utterance>I am not retarded!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary turns away from her door and sits on her bed. Fay leans over the stove, where a large pot of water is beginning to boil.</context>
      <utterance>I can see with my own eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon is frustrated and lashes out.</context>
      <utterance>Mom can't be left alone with no one to keep an eye on her.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fay's mouth falls open and she staggers back, hurt. Simon regrets it already and stands to leave, scared. But Fay grabs the pot off the stove and hurls it at him, splashing boiling water all over his back.</context>
      <utterance>Well, who's been keeping an eye on her while you've been out getting fucked by every OTB winner in town?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Outside, Pearl turns and looks back at the house. Simon lies gasping on the floor of the kitchen. Fay falls back against the stove, terrified and drops her head into her hands.</context>
      <utterance>Aggghhhh!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to her, Simon? How did she get this way? Will it happen to me too? Huh? Why are we so fucked up? Simon has no answers. But he reaches out and touches his sister's hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Henry?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Simon! What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry sighs and sits back down.</context>
      <utterance>Henry... Your parole officer, Officer Buuel, came by again today.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He told me to tell you that if you don't call him they're gunna put you back in jail.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Simon...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He gave me this number...</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Simon...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was talking to Mr Deng too, and, well, you know, I was thinking...</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon blinks and looks down at his feet, unable to respond. Deeply hurt, he simply turns to walk away. But Henry reaches out and grabs his arm. Simon stops, pauses and looks back at his friend.</context>
      <utterance>Simon, just shut the fuck up!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lets go and turns away on his stool.</context>
      <utterance>Forgive me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon comes back over to him.</context>
      <utterance>Forgive me, Simon.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry gives in slowly to the inevitable. He sighs deeply and stands, handing Simon a book...</context>
      <utterance>Call him, Henry. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OK. Look, do me a favor. You got a library card?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon looks at the cover: Paradise Lost.</context>
      <utterance>Check this out for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A young woman passes by, scanning the stacks. She and Henry have a split second of eye contact, then she turns and moves away. Henry straightens his tie and watches her go.</context>
      <utterance>Milton. Seventeenth century. English. You see, Simon, it's important my 'Confession' dig up the past, comb previous evidence and help chart the historic -- even the aesthetic -- inevitability of my ideas. And...</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This place is crawling with chicks, Simon. Wander around. Leer a little. Cop a feel. Impose yourself on 'em. See what happens.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I make girls uncomfortable.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bullshit! You've got a rough hewn charm that sets 'em on edge. Now, listen, I gotta go.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry stops and turns. Simon pauses, then...</context>
      <utterance>Henry?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry watches him for a moment, then swaggers closer...</context>
      <utterance>What did you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon waits for more but is disappointed. With one final cracked grin at his friend, Henry throws back his shoulders, slicks back his hair and strides off. Simon watches him go and frowns, not comforted. He flips through the pages of Paradise Lost.</context>
      <utterance>I got caught.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Whereto with speedy words the arch- fiend replied Fallen Cherub, to be weak is miserable...'</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why is it this beautiful girl makes me sad? Does she know how beautiful she is? Do people tell her? Does she ever feel stupid? He looks back over at her. She happens to look up and their eyes meet. She smiles. Horrified, he looks down.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He watches her again, thinks, then writes...</context>
      <utterance>Why don't I smile when she looks at me? I look away. Ashamed of myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He writes a few moments more, scribbling across the page, then stops and looks back over at the girl.</context>
      <utterance>Her figure makes me violent. I want to somehow break her. But tenderly. How is this possible? Ask Henry.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tears out the page and folds it in half. Then he gets up and crosses the room to where the girl is busily engaged in her work. She looks up, sees him, and removes her headset with a pleasant smile. He places his note on the table before her, then turns and walks quickly away. The girl watches him go, confused, then lifts the note and reads...</context>
      <utterance>I can't breathe.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do I do this to myself? And why do I reduce you to only one possibility? These are not even questions anymore. I know the answers myself. This isn't a page of notes. It's a letter. A letter to you. A desperate act. You are a miracle to me. I can't breathe. By now, Simon is gone from the library. The girl finishes reading the letter and looks around in astonishment.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you, Henry?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peachy. Gimme a light.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry just glares at him and smokes.</context>
      <utterance>Have you found a job?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How 'bout those Alcoholics Anonymous meetings, did you go over and visit them yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buuel looks down, disappointed.</context>
      <utterance>What happened to this assistant librarian position you were supposed to set me up with?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tried, Henry. I really did.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Henry, with your background... Well, I mean, with your record, they didn't think it'd be right to have you at the neighborhood library.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry sits back, offended.</context>
      <utterance>They thought you'd be a bad influence on the kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So my word is not enough. My promise worthless. The fact I've served my time nothing but the emblem of my continuing guilt.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry leans back and sighs, furious and indignant.</context>
      <utterance>Apparently.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's up?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shoves a sheath of papers up under his nose and he backs away in disgust.</context>
      <utterance>I'm creating my rsum. This computer's got a program especially for it. I bought some special stationery too. It's scented. Look.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon takes his notebooks from a cabinet above the fridge.</context>
      <utterance>It's roses.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you type my poem into that thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's your poem?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drinks, then looks at Simon and adds...</context>
      <utterance>I was caught. Yes, I was caught... once. I was caught in flagranti delicto screwing a thirteen-year-old girl named Susan. She was an ugly and mean-spirited kid, but she knew how to play upon my weaknesses which, I admit, are deep and many.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You appear shocked.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry stands and leans over the fire.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He comes over and takes a beer. He strides around the room, thinking, reflecting.</context>
      <utterance>It was a pathetic little conspiracy. A transparently desperate attempt to discredit me and my ideas; to label me a mere pedophile. As if I'd be ashamed of such a thing. As if Socrates himself hadn't been taken out of circulation for corrupting the youth of Athens!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stops, drinks declares...</context>
      <utterance>Seven years. Seven years for one afternoon of blissful transgression. But what of it? Who cares? Prison's not so bad; particularly if one's a sex offender, free from the popular and conventional horror of sodomy.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He approaches the notebooks lined up on the mantelpiece.</context>
      <utterance>They were not 'lost years'.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances over at Simon, who sits gripping his beer, watching, rapt.</context>
      <utterance>I put them to good use. I began my major work. My opus.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pauses and swills back some beer. He brightens up, gets excited...</context>
      <utterance>Believe me, Simon, this incident with the girl, prison... It pales to insignificance in the wider context of my career.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drinks sloppily, burps, wipes his mouth with his arm.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing in comparison to the day my 'Confession' is unleashed.  What an orgy we'll have then, huh? What shouts of outrage from the offended populace, from the sanctimonious purveyors of culture and quality, the righteous defenders of what ever inane and haphazard notion of progress then in vogue. They'll be beside themselves with fiercely reasoned critical analysis. Apoplectic with indignation!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smashes the bottle in the fireplace.</context>
      <utterance>Their feelings will be hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs a new beer and twists off its cap.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, like a mirror which reflects only the inside of the person before it, my 'Confession' will lovingly render humanity's common monstrosity in all of its lurid wide screen glory.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drinks, sighs and sits back down.</context>
      <utterance>Why should I blush or feel shame before the common lot of humanity, anyway, for a few banal and, again I admit, inelegant transgressions?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon sits back in awe. He waits a moment and thinks. Finally he stands and approaches the 'Confession'. He reaches out and drags his hand across the notebooks.</context>
      <utterance>After all, really, I'm doing civilization a favor.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry sits staring into the flames again. He pauses, then...</context>
      <utterance>When can I read it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER HAWKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon listens and carefully considers all the priest says.</context>
      <utterance>We are told not to judge. But to forgive. Not to look into our neighbor's eye to find the bad, but to find the good.  Now this is difficult. I admit.  But having a good friend is not always easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Father Hawkes pauses, then comes closer and sits.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, but... do you think Henry is... dangerous?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER HAWKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He needs help. Our help. Yours especially.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what can I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER HAWKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The best parts of himself come to the surface when he's helping someone learn. I've seen this. Let yourself be taught. Show your appreciation for his guidance. In this way, you know, perhaps. Well. There's hope for everyone. Even. Even Henry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="52">
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gnoc gets the Kleenex while Fay overhears two kids near Simon's poem...</context>
      <utterance>Gnoc, gimme a value pack of Kleenex, will ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The violence of the imagery reminds me of early Clash, while the lyricism of the verse recalls, for me, Walt Whitman.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIBI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fay pays for her tissues and makes her way to the back of the store where she finds Simon with Henry, who is holding forth to his friend and the small coterie of high school students surrounding them...</context>
      <utterance>I would have said Dickinson, maybe even Eliot, and so on. But I agree with the punk roots...</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The greats all say the same thing: little. And what little there is to be said is immense. Or, in other words, follow your own genius to where it leads without regard for the apparent needs of the world at large, which, in fact, has no needs as such, but, rather, moments of exhaustion in which it is incapable of prejudice.  We can only hope to collide with these moments of unselfconsciousness. This divine fatigue... this...</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry takes the typed manuscript from her and continues...</context>
      <utterance>Push over.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As I tried to make plain in Paris: 'Nous savons que nous avons chut parce que nous savons qui nous sommes.' 'We know we have fallen because we know who we are.'</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When were you in Paris?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fay blows her nose and Simon is concerned.</context>
      <utterance>That's beside the point. But did they listen to me? Of course not!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You alright, Fay?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy's girlfriend, Chris, leans forward studiously and asks...</context>
      <utterance>For is this not the best of all possible worlds? Are not the evils of this world necessary components of a cosmos that could not exist without them?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, do you believe in God?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unfortunately.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but when were you in Paris?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At. One. Time.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon looks from her to Henry. Henry winks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Simon, can I have your autograph?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon signs the girl's book.</context>
      <utterance>Go ahead. But never let yourself be flattered.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what about this friend of yours, Hot Shot? The publisher.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Angus James.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry seems a bit put upon.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Angus James. How about sending this poem to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because it's not done yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When's it gunna be done, Simon?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you oughta be home writing instead of hanging out over here with all your groupies.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I'm not a groupie.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pardon me, swivel-hips. Is that your PowerBook?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fay and Amy talk tech as...</context>
      <utterance>Can I see it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The thing to do is to send parts of it to different magazines and literary journals first. That kinda thing. You know. Substantiate it.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry sips his beer and looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>What's 'scatalogical' mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Filth, child. A preoccupation with excrement. Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry reaches across the table and shakes Simon's hand.</context>
      <utterance>That's what the Board of Education called Simon's poem, yesterday; scatological.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'm listening.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Intrigued, Fay steps over to the door with her spatula. She looks Edna over, studies her ID, then steps away and screams upstairs.</context>
      <utterance>My name is Edna Rodriguez and I write the human interest column for the Queens County Examiner and I was just wondering if I could have a word with Simon Grim?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Simon!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fay comes back over near the door, waving her spatula.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No response.</context>
      <utterance>You can't talk to him for, you know, too long or anything, 'cause he's gotta, you know... he writes all day. That's all he does. Can you believe that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon finally shuffles into the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Simon! Get down here!</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Simon, this is Edna. She's from the newspaper.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon says nothing. He just stares at her.</context>
      <utterance>Simon, the Parents' Association at the local high school are calling your poem pornography. The teachers are defending the students' right to exercise their critical tastes and sensibilities. The county agrees with the Church and considers the poem emblematic of modern society's moral disintegration. How do you feel about these controversial reactions to your poem?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon just looks away, thinks, then wanders back upstairs. Mary passes him on his way out of the kitchen and comes up to Fay and Edna at the door.</context>
      <utterance>Simon, answer the woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need my prescription filled.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom, this is Edna. Edna, Mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs Grim, what was Simon like as a child?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We all thought he was retarded.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone did.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never said a word.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He masturbated constantly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Had no friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Till he met Henry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that's when all the trouble really started.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="42">
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dear Mr Grim, we here at the magazine consider ourselves and the publication open-minded and cutting edge and have consistently printed the work of the most brilliant and farseeing young talent of the day. Every week we are forced to return writing which we can not for one reason or another publish and include a brief but polite refusal. But this tract you've sent us demands a response as violent as the effect your words have had upon us. Drop dead. Keep your day job. Sincerely, The Editors.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>De gustibus non disputandum est.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't argue with taste?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon gives up and pushes the letters away, beaten.</context>
      <utterance>About taste. You can't argue about taste. God, Simon.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry drops his razor and stomps out into the hall.</context>
      <utterance>The other twenty-five are almost as bad. I don't know why I bother.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean you don't know why you bother? You bother because you know the poem is excellent!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course you do!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not so sure sometimes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon holds the stare, overwhelmed.</context>
      <utterance>Can you sit there, look me straight in the eye, and tell me you don't think this poem is great? That it is not at once a work of great lyrical beauty and ethical depth? That it is not a genuine, highly individual, and profound meditation on the miracle of existence?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I, ah...</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon looks away, thinks a moment, then looks back at Henry.</context>
      <utterance>Can you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes back into the bathroom. Simon thinks a while, then...</context>
      <utterance>So, you see, you have no choice!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No response.</context>
      <utterance>Can you recommend it to your friend, the publisher?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Still no response. Simon gets up and stands in the bathroom doorway. Henry is shaving.</context>
      <utterance>Henry? Can you recommend the poem to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, I think it's finished and, for better or worse, it is book length.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That might not be as easy as it seems.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's been a long time. My name might not carry as much weight as it once did with Angus.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But he's your friend, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were close at one time.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry puts down his razor and looks at Simon in the mirror.</context>
      <utterance>You said he respected your opinion.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sees Simon looks worried.</context>
      <utterance>Look, Simon, opinions come and go.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks around the bathroom, gesticulating.</context>
      <utterance>To be honest; my ideas, my writing, they haven't always been received well or even calmly. They're upsetting. I'm a controversial man.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon patiently absorbs all this, then walks through the kitchen and looks across at the 'Confession' notebooks.</context>
      <utterance>You see, what I'm doing is too radical. Too uncompromising. It'll take time for people to see its value. It's ahead of its time, perhaps, or maybe just...  A recommendation from me might do you as much harm as it does good.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Henry, why can't I read the 'Confession'?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because certain work needs to be experienced all at once in order for one to appreciate the full force of its character.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Simon, wake up! The guy's in a dream world!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's afraid that his reputation will prevent people from giving my work an honest chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His reputation as what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As a writer.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gimme a break.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's kinda like in exile. Marginalized on account of his ideas.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If he's such a great big fat genius, why doesn't he write books? Like you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He has. He's written a book. It's almost completed. He's been working on it for years. It's just not published.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I bet. It's probably disgusting.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a quite serious and difficult piece of work, apparently.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you read it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Not yet. Soon. Certain work needs to be experienced all at once in order for one to appreciate the full force of its character.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets up to go. She's wearing a smart outfit.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, what ever. Listen, Simon, forget Henry. Go straight up to this Angus James character yourself and make him read your poem.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gunna apply for a job at the one- hour photo joint and then go over to the Mall to see about that job in the bank. Make sure Mom takes her pills. See ya.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares him down a moment longer, then looks away and closes the piano. She returns to the couch and switches on the TV. Simon comes closer. He sits.</context>
      <utterance>Please don't stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was nice what you were playing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon waits. Eventually...</context>
      <utterance>Yes, it was nice. But it was unremarkable.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does that matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets up off the couch and goes upstairs. She slams her bedroom door and leaves Simon alone on the couch. He thinks. Then, he gets up and goes into the kitchen. He takes the typed manuscript of his poem from the cabinet above the refrigerator and goes to the door. He pauses, clutches the poem and goes out.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. It does.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="54">
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon steps back defensively.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, I'll take that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't you the messenger?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you here to fix the plumbing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm here to see Mr. Angus James.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura steps back, cocks her head and removes her designer eye-wear.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not a plumber. Or a messenger. I was once a garbage man. But now I'm a poet.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The book, as we know it, Angus, will be a thing of the past within the next few years. Novels, articles, newspapers will all be downloaded on to our personal computers anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're telling me to get out of the publishing business?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura knocks.</context>
      <utterance>No. But we've got to re-invent the publishing business for the electronic age.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Laura?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry to disturb you, gentlemen, but... Angus, there's a particularly wound-up young garbage man out here who seems to have written a poem. A long poem. And I recall how, at last month's meeting, you stressed the need for us to be on the look-out for more marginalized verse from unestablished quarters of the American scene.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Steve and Barry nod.</context>
      <utterance>Did I say that?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. You did.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twice.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, OK. Make an appointment, Laura. Sometime next month.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she's gone.</context>
      <utterance>Right-e-o.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, anyway, how is the digital revolution going to help me sell books?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why can't I see him now?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up, pauses, then...</context>
      <utterance>Be reasonable.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think people are going to prefer reading books on television, Steve.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It won't be television!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll be interactive.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Angus, look, we have a number of charts here...</utterance>
   <speaker>BARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In every home in America the PC will be where the TV used to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And it'll be a direct connection to all forms of media.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An unprecedented transformation of American social life...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura re-enters...</context>
      <utterance>We'll all become better informed, more literate, increasingly productive, and... Well, and, like I said, we have a number of charts...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry to disturb you again, gentlemen, but... Angus, I'd like to call security for this one. Though, before I do, I just wanted to ask just how marginal the as yet undiscovered voice of American poetry should be?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretty damn marginal, I'd think.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Down right controversial, probably.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's he strike you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's been denounced by his local Board of Education.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I read about him in the paper. Hangs out in a delicatessen somewhere and writes pornography.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs the envelope and sees no title.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, and why do you think I should take valuable time out of my busy schedule to read...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon is stumped. He looks over at Laura, who purses her lips and tilts her head. He twists a button on his shirt, thinking, then returns to Angus.</context>
      <utterance>This?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because it's a masterpiece.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you hearing this?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's adorable.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't want to waste your time.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure you wouldn't and I appreciate you being so straightforward.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon looks over at Laura.</context>
      <utterance>I assume you can take straightforward criticism?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just say 'Yes'.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get him a coffee, Laura.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have a seat, Mr Grim.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold my calls for the next half hour.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Steve?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He doesn't drink coffee. Steve, do you drink coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Angus, listen to me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy types away, fascinated by Henry's intelligence.</context>
      <utterance>In the infinite amplitude of his love, God wants to create the largest number of best elements that can exist together in one cosmos... OK.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stops, zeroing in on his point.</context>
      <utterance>In an instantaneous calculation made in eternity, God computes the best possible world and creates it. Fine. This 'decision' by God is uncontingent and eternal rather than temporally or ontologically sequential.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you spell that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ontologically.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>O-N-T... Don't you have some kinda spell-check on that thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smokes, drinks, paces some more. Amy waits with bated breath, devastated by his obscure profundity. He comes back and sits beside her, reaching his conclusion.</context>
      <utterance>It is impossible for every perfect good to be compatible with every other perfect good. The intense beauty of the mountain must be set off by the fertility of the plain, so to speak.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry sits thinking and Amy watches him reverently. She leans over close and whispers in his ear. He turns and looks at her, alarmed.</context>
      <utterance>The good of freewill must entail real choices for sin. She gazes at his profile, in love.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Amy, back off. I'm on parole.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry jumps up and looks around, paranoid. He keeps his voice down and points at her.</context>
      <utterance>You feel the same way. I can tell. I can see it when you look at me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! I don't look at you.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes you do. In the street. In the parking lot yesterday. That night on the highway.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Disappointed, Amy turns away and sulks.</context>
      <utterance>I look at a lot of people that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry sees she's genuinely upset and feels bad. He sits back down and lays his hand on hers.</context>
      <utterance>You think I'm stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, as a matter of fact, I think you're a real bright kid and I like that about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now Henry tries to scare her away. He leers at her.</context>
      <utterance>You do?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She just stares at him, blinks, then looks away and tries to imagine this. She takes her laptop and leaves, confused and blushing. Henry watches her go and grins, satisfied with himself.</context>
      <utterance>I like it so much I've got half a mind to do perverse things to you. Right here. Right now. Things you might just learn to like.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon looks pale as Angus strides towards the elevator.</context>
      <utterance>This is really quite unbelievably bad, my friend. I mean, I'm all for experimentation and I've made a career out of a healthy disregard for convention, but... Look, this is profoundly irrelevant material. This is only my opinion. But it's an opinion I value highly. Goodnight, Laura. Call Norton Press. We're still on for tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They reach the elevator and stop. Simon tries to catch his breath.</context>
      <utterance>I've been wrong before as a publisher. But I refuse to admit I've ever been wrong as a reader. You have talent, I admit. You have an innate sense of the musicality of language. A good ear, maybe. But you do nothing significant with it. And this twisted reasoning that poses as... conviction or insight, it's... well, it's embarrassing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did you bring this thing to me, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A friend of mine spoke of you. He said you had a lot of integrity.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon hesitates, almost decides against it, but then...</context>
      <utterance>Yes, well, of course, I do. But I'm not crazy, am I? Who is this person? Do I know him?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angus looks aside, thinks, then shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Henry Fool. Angus looks back at him. Simon waits.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon just looks at him blankly, confused. The doors slide open and Angus gets in the elevator. He's gone. Simon sinks into a chair and stares at the carpet. He is so surprised and hurt he gasps for breath. His poem slips from his hand and falls to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Never heard of him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon doesn't register this right away. But then he looks up and over at the receptionist. Laura stands and comes around her desk. She pauses, seeing his disappointment, then comes closer and picks up his poem. Handing it to him, she explains...</context>
      <utterance>I remember Henry.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He just stares at her, demolished.</context>
      <utterance>He used to be the janitor here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MR DENG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Henry, put those magazines back.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just looking at the pictures.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR DENG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry flips through pages and nods, impressed.</context>
      <utterance>It's not good for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I learn so much from these magazines, Mr Deng. I refuse to discriminate between modes of knowing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR DENG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry looks up, outraged.</context>
      <utterance>And you can't smoke in here anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR DENG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry throws his cigarette to the floor, steps on it and returns to his magazine.</context>
      <utterance>It's the law.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This place is losing all its charm, Mr Deng.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR DENG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry shakes his head in dismay and studies a centerfold.</context>
      <utterance>Business is good. The kids, they hang out all day and drink coffee, talk about art and read poetry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just a fad, Mr Deng. These kids today, they're just slaves to fashion.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stands on the stairs and hears the water running in the bathroom.</context>
      <utterance>Anybody home? Mom?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer. She discovers she's out of cigarettes.</context>
      <utterance>Ma, that you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Mr Deng! How much do I owe you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR DENG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty-five dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Warren comes in.</context>
      <utterance>That can't be right! And so what? My credit's good.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Henry!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Warren reaches for his wallet.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Warren, you gotta couple of bucks I can borrow?</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Henry, I wanna remind you to vote this Thursday.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, yes, of course. When noble minds shrink from the task of leadership scoundrels will rush in to fill the void.  Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry pays Mr Deng for his beer.</context>
      <utterance>It's every American's right. A blessing. Yet another opportunity to save America from itself.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer. She tries the door. It's open. She hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Henry, you in there? Gimme a cigarette.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes quietly in.</context>
      <utterance>Henry?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry smokes.</context>
      <utterance>Henry?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's more than he can stand. He holds his head.</context>
      <utterance>What kind of... Well, I mean... What kind of... perverse things would you do to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take a powder, cupcake.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, really.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crushed, she breaks out in tears and flees.</context>
      <utterance>Evaporate!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I was a janitor! So what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry shrugs and qualifies...</context>
      <utterance>But Angus James said he didn't even know you!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I mean, we weren't like bosom buddies or anything. But we used to talk sometimes. In the elevator. In the morning. He said he liked my ideas. Being a janitor's a good job if you're a writer. Especially the night shift; all that time to think and develop my ideas.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry pulls the lever and the garbage gets crushed.</context>
      <utterance>Do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyway, he hated my poem.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what the hell does he know? He wouldn't know a vital piece of literary art if it came up and bit him in the leg. To hell with him! He's not the only publisher in the world!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But nobody likes it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's true. A prophet is seldom heeded in his own land. Remember that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry is about to pull the lever again, but sees something in amongst the garbage...</context>
      <utterance>Do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry steps down and leans over into the garbage. Simon joins him as he lifts something that is either a ring or a stray piece of machinery.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, look, treasure!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brass maybe. Some kinda copper.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a ring. Jewelry.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry puts it in his pocket, satisfied and Simon jumps on the back of the truck as it turns the corner and rolls away. Henry starts to walk off in the opposite direction, but stops when he sees Pearl age seven.</context>
      <utterance>I think it's a gasket. A fitting from off of that old refrigerator over there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="74">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Warren, I found Pearl wandering around by the garbage dump.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He lost.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Warren rests. He sits up on the bench and takes a toke off the joint he has waiting.</context>
      <utterance>Who lost?</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Congressman Feer.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Well, you know. Somebody's gotta lose.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry pauses, then leads Pearl age seven towards the house. Warren lies back down and continues his lifting.</context>
      <utterance>What's the fucking use. You make sacrifices. You try to be a decent human being. Try to contribute something meaningful to society. And what happens? They lose to a bunch of cultural elite liberal fuck-ups. I don't give a shit anymore. People deserve what they get.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer. He comes in and finds her sitting on the couch with a drink. She's got a black eye.</context>
      <utterance>Vicky?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a good man, Henry. Nobody's perfect.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess not.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's terribly disappointed.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pearl comes over and stands beside her mother.</context>
      <utterance>I found Pearl wandering around with no shoes on her feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. She gets scared.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vicky caresses Pearl's hair, then drinks and looks over at Henry.</context>
      <utterance>And you don't?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love him.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's the beer?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR DENG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry looks at the man, disgusted, then falls in to a seat and motions to Gnoc, who is now the waitress.</context>
      <utterance>No more beer. Coffee. Espresso! Cappuccino! Caf au lait. Carrot juice. Herbal tea.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A double espresso and a jelly donut, Gnoc.  You mind paying? My credit's no good here anymore, apparently.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you go to the employment agency today, Henry?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, but it's OK. Simon's gunna try to get me a job on the garbage truck.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, I'm a little concerned about your friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Simon?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seems he gave an obscene note to a girl in the library.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get outta here! When?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It couldn't have been Simon.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He unfolds a print-out of the letter. Henry reads and Buuel leans over, pointing out...</context>
      <utterance>It almost certainly is. He mentions you. Look...</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry thinks this over, gulps back some espresso and nods his approval. Then...</context>
      <utterance>'Her figure makes me violent. I want to somehow break her. But tenderly. How is this possible? Ask Henry.'</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buuel, this is obviously a love letter.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've had complaints.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did you get it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She posted it on the Internet.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, the slut!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was trying to warn other girls about a potential rapist.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is all this true about the Internet? About how you can get pornography on it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, yeah, sure. It's a big problem. You can send dirty pictures and everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On the Internet?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry is impressed.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buuel gets up to go.</context>
      <utterance>No kiddin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See you on Thursday, Henry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is having ideas.</context>
      <utterance>Sure. See you.  Gnoc, gimme one of these double espressos to go, will ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Fay.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go away.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns and glares at him.</context>
      <utterance>You gotta get outta the house, Fay. You can't blame yourself for not being here. You did all you could for her.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry stops, pauses, looks away. Then...</context>
      <utterance>Is there something you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got the Internet on that contraption?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He changes the subject again, preoccupied and continues tenderly...</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. So what?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look Fay, about, you know, between us -- what happened...</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sighs and drinks his coffee, then looks back at her.</context>
      <utterance>I don't wanna talk about it, Henry!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Type a part of Simon's poem onto the Internet.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Fay. It's a great idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know if he would want us to do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fay is tempted.</context>
      <utterance>Sure he would. Just the first ten verses.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frowning, she reconsiders. She gets up and takes the notebooks from the cabinet above the fridge. She flips through the pages but suddenly stops and turns to the door with a nicer attitude.</context>
      <utterance>He'll thank you for it later.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he's gone. It's as if he has vanished into thin air. She sighs, sits back down, and begins typing the poem onto the Internet.</context>
      <utterance>Henry...</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr Deng starts to make him one and sees him with the magazine.</context>
      <utterance>Gimme another one of those tall double espressos, Mr Deng.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR DENG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gunna buy that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just looking.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR DENG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well then put it back.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr Deng shakes his head and frowns.</context>
      <utterance>There's this fascinating story about a famous rock band and how they tied a friend of theirs to a bed in their hotel room and inserted a live fish into her vagina.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They say she had numerous orgasms.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR DENG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Henry, you need to do something with your life. Get a job, or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr Deng brings over the coffee. Henry is surprised to notice he is not riveted.</context>
      <utterance>I mean, it wasn't the entire fish, it was just, you know, the nose. The nose of the fish.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't find that interesting?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR DENG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry closes the magazine and puts it back. Leaning on the counter, he sips his coffee and ponders.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever wonder what it would be like to have sex with an animal, Mr Deng?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR DENG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That coffee is free. Just take it and get out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr Deng just goes back to work, leaving Henry there at the counter thinking big thoughts.</context>
      <utterance>I mean, some dogs are almost as big as people and often more attractive.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="47">
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you see him?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He came by this afternoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you talk?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He comes over and sits beside her. He thinks a moment, then...</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got to tell him, Fay.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she starts crying again. Simon awkwardly touches her shoulder, then moves his hand away. Fay pulls herself together, sniffles and goes into the bathroom.</context>
      <utterance>He thinks I'm a slut.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Henry?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Simon, I don't feel so good.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon lifts the coffee container and smells it.</context>
      <utterance>I feel all kinda clammy. And damp.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry tries to remember. He squints.</context>
      <utterance>How many of these did you have?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon puts the container down and sits at the table.</context>
      <utterance>Seven.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Henry, we have to talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I use your toilet?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry grabs his stomach. He presses his hand against his chest, holds his head, then stares at the ring.</context>
      <utterance>Fay's taking a shower.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at Simon.</context>
      <utterance>How much you think I can get for this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Henry, Fay's pregnant.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry lets this sink in. He stands and the room tilts. White with fear, he clutches at his rumbling gut.</context>
      <utterance>Fay's pregnant with your child.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry sweats and moans as he empties his bowels in a violent and messy blast of noise and foul air. Fay covers her face and whimpers sickly. Finally, he's done. He hangs with his face out over his knees, sick, exhausted and in shock. Fay wraps herself in a towel and steps out of the shower. She creeps carefully around him and flushes the toilet, growing increasingly concerned.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Henry!</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is destroyed, staring down at... The 'ring' he still holds in his hand. Fay sees this, looks at Henry, then kneels and takes it from him. He doesn't resist. She lifts it up and breathlessly admires it. Totally misunderstanding, moved beyond words...</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Henry. You OK?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she throws her arms around him as he sits there, sweating and spent, on the toilet.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Oh, Henry.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER HAWKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I, Henry, take you, Fay to be my wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I, Henry, take you, Fay to be my wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER HAWKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And do promise before God and these witnesses...</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And do promise before God and these witnesses...</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER HAWKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To be your loving and faithful husband.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To be your loving and faithful husband.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER HAWKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In plenty and in want.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In plenty and in want.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER HAWKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In joy and in sorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In joy and in sorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER HAWKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In sickness and in health.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In sickness and in health.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER HAWKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For as long as we both shall live.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The gasket everyone is now mistaking for a ring is lifted high before the altar.</context>
      <utterance>For as long as we both shall live.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER HAWKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The gasket is placed on Fay's finger.</context>
      <utterance>Bless, O Lord, this ring, that he who gives it and she who wears it may abide in your peace and continue in your favor until their life's end.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER HAWKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The doors of the church swing open with a tremendous creak and everyone turns from the altar to see... Amy enter. She steps in and stands there, alarmed, clutching a long scroll of fax paper.</context>
      <utterance>Whom God has joined, let no man separate.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon walks down the aisle to see to Amy. The guests watch and wait. As Simon reaches her, Amy looks away from the altar and shows him the fax scroll.</context>
      <utterance>Simon, do something.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He studies the fax and recognizes his poem. He grows concerned.</context>
      <utterance>Look.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did you get this?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fay and Henry. They look away, caught.</context>
      <utterance>It's all over the Internet. Simon looks up the aisle at...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Confused, Simon starts for the door, shoving the fax in his pocket. Fay steps down from the altar...</context>
      <utterance>They're even talking about it on the TV news.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amy hurries along beside him.</context>
      <utterance>Simon?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a guy from the radio station over at World of Donuts and a story in the newspaper about some kids burning down a school near Boston!</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fay leads the neighbors in the dance...</context>
      <utterance>It all started right here in Queens, Jim, at World of Donuts about one year ago today, when local garbage man, Simon Grim, put pencil to paper and began to compose what many have come to regard as vicious, antisocial and pornographic poetry -- 112 lines of unrhymed free meter verse which would one day serve to spark the flames of controversy across the nation and -- indeed -- the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>OWEN FEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry and Fay dance, surrounded by the dancing neighbors...</context>
      <utterance>This is outrageous! Measures must be taken. Have we debased our culture to such an extent that a garbage man with a head full of sick ideas is legitimately referred to as a poet, and where the filth he spews can be accessed by any child old enough to turn on a computer? Is this what we have come to? Not the transmission of our highest ideals, but a cynical, atheistic delirium!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="32">
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm willing to negotiate, Simon.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, it's just...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've had other offers.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, yes. But.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why have you reconsidered?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I think your writing will be tremendously successful.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you don't like it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's growing on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to the fans outside.</context>
      <utterance>What made you change your mind?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon thinks this over, but says nothing. Angus comes over and lays his hand on his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Other people's responses. I don't live in a vacuum, you know. Two months ago I didn't have the proof of your poem's appeal. Now I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon nods.</context>
      <utterance>Consider my offer carefully. Get some professional advice. I'll call you tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER HAWKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What were the terms?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A hundred thousand in cash up front.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER HAWKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Royalties?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A seventy/thirty split.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER HAWKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that could be better. But it is a hundred thousand dollars up front. Guaranteed money. You could use that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So it's a good deal?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER HAWKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course it's good.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I should take it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER HAWKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Try to get him up to a hundred and fifty thousand.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He collapses extravagantly.</context>
      <utterance>I've let myself down, Simon! I've let myself be caught in the bloody maw of banal necessity! How did I get here? How did this happen to me? I'm going to be somebody's father! I need time to think. To write. Time to finish my 'Confession'! I can't work for a living! It's impossible! I tried once. My genius will be wasted trying to make ends meet!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is how great men topple, Simon. Their hearts are in the right place too much of the time! They get sidetracked! Distracted. Oh! How could I have been so careless!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Henry, please, let me read the 'Confession'.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Not now. It's not done. I'm all washed up. I'm finished!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry glances back at his friend, digesting this. He thinks it over, then...</context>
      <utterance>Angus James is convinced my poem is going to make him incredibly wealthy. He'll read your book and seriously consider publishing it. If I ask him to. I'm certain.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Having finally got through to him, Simon comes forward, anxious to help Henry.</context>
      <utterance>Really? You really think so?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He paces back and forth, thrusting out his chest, for the first time in his life displaying something like pride or arrogance.</context>
      <utterance>I'll insist he publish the 'Confession'.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon stares off into the distance.</context>
      <utterance>You'd do that? You'd do that for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry is moved. He stands and comes forward. He grabs his friend by the shoulders and turns him around.</context>
      <utterance>You saved my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you realize what you're saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry steps away, considering, then looks back at Simon and extends his hand.</context>
      <utterance>I owe you everything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's really that bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's terrible.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've read this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you want me to consider publishing it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As part of our deal?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Simon, this book, it's... It's really quite bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angus pauses and figures. He changes the subject.</context>
      <utterance>That's what you said about my poem.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm offering you a very real expression of my faith in your writing. Two hundred thousand dollars and a sixty/forty split.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But just exactly what is the nature of your faith in my writing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is at a loss for words.</context>
      <utterance>Look, Simon, you don't require my admiration. You require my experience as a publisher. And that experience leads me to believe your poem will make more money than any book of poetry ever published. In history. Virtually make you a household name within two years. You'll never have to work on a garbage truck again, I assure you. Or do anything else for that matter. Whereas this 'Confession' by Henry Fool...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The most I can say for this is... The man is a scoundrel.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He taught me everything I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon waits a while, staring at his shoes.</context>
      <utterance>No! He encouraged all that was expressive in you to become manifest. He inspired you to act. He influenced your perception.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about if my advance is only a hundred thousand?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not about money, Simon.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We could split the royalties seventy/thirty.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon sits and lets this sink in. Angus waits, then...</context>
      <utterance>I will not publish Henry Fool's 'Confession'.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon continues looking out at the city. Angus waits, but there is no response. Finally, Simon turns, pauses and slowly crosses the room. He sits at the table and looks down at the contract. He signs.</context>
      <utterance>Will you sign the contract?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="47">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sits up and Simon sits beside him.</context>
      <utterance>Simon? You're here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Fay?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon sits back, relieved. Then he remembers the rain-soaked shopping bag he has with him. He pulls out a couple of cans of beer and hands one to Henry.</context>
      <utterance>She's alright.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look around, seasoned conspirators and make sure the coast is clear. Then they pop open the beers and toast. They drink. Then...</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon pauses, scared, then gets up and crosses the room. He looks out of the window and gathers his strength.</context>
      <utterance>How did it go?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry looks at Simon blankly, then blinks and looks away.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, Henry, Angus James didn't like your 'Confession'.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah. I see. Well, what now?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. Simon comes back and sits again.</context>
      <utterance>Did he suggest changes?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. He didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, after all, there are things I can do to make it more accessible.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Accessible?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon just stares at him blankly, then sighs and shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>I can soften up some of the language and make it read easier. Take out some of the more intratextual references and popularize the underlying Sturm und Drang, so to speak. I can change its mode. Make it more of a conventional novel instead.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon comes over and lays his hand on Henry's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Simon, don't be such a purist! I appreciate your protectiveness, but the integrity of the work gives it a durability that can sustain such things.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Really, Henry. Don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you saying; that it doesn't merit revision?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps away and sits. Henry pauses, then approaches and leans down over him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm saying... Angus James didn't like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, did you tell him what you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I think doesn't matter.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, it does. You've got to use your influence with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gave it to him to read and he hated it. What more can I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can refuse to let him publish your poem.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said you would.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was before I read your book.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry stands there a moment longer, then lowers himself into the nearest seat, weakened.</context>
      <utterance>I signed the contract, Henry.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Henry, what did you expect?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... I don't know. Honesty, perhaps.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, if I had told you, when at first I read it, that I thought it was no good, what would you have done?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would have respected your opinion.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And insisted that there's no accounting for taste.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon's words catch in his throat. He turns away, frustrated.</context>
      <utterance>Well, is there?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I didn't bring it to Angus because I thought it was good. I brought it to Angus because you're my friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh how perfectly enormous of you, Simon.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Henry, I did it! I wrote. I wrote poetry because you told me to! I worked! I worked while you sat back and comfortably dismissed the outside world as too shallow, stupid and mean to appreciate your ideas.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that such a priority? Is that some sort of measure of a man's worth? To drag what's best in him out into the street so every average slob with some pretense to taste can poke it with a stick?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry just stares at him, stands, then turns on his heel and waves him off.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe. Maybe it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon hangs his head, destroyed.</context>
      <utterance>You must be pretty impressed with yourself, huh? The all too obviously talented new man, the important new voice, the early clue to a new direction, or whatever, etc., etc., etc! A popular new trend conveniently packaged for the distracted young herd! You want to be liked more than you know, Simon Grim! You'd be nowhere without me and you know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry is scared all of a sudden. But he puts on a defiant exterior.</context>
      <utterance>I'm leaving.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands, drinks and walks over to the window...</context>
      <utterance>Yes. It's time you left.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw you for what you were in the beginning, Simon. I hold no grudge and I'm certain you will, in time, leave some serious and small dent in this world.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry take advantage of Simon's disillusionment and puts on a big show of secure wisdom.</context>
      <utterance>The world is full of shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon sits there a moment, numb with grief. Henry, red in the face, stares at the floor. Suddenly, Simon stands and walks out. Henry looks up and watches him go. He can hardly believe it. He almost raises his voice and apologizes, but can't. He lowers his head again and covers his face with his hands, listening to Simon's footsteps receding through the halls. Simon walks on, away from us, down the hospital corridor.</context>
      <utterance>The world is full of shit. It's true. And you have to walk through it. That's your part. I'm sorry. But you're no good at it. Perhaps I'm not. Perhaps I wasn't made to walk through shit. Go on now. Leave. Do what you're good at. Go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="70">
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kid sits still, obviously guilty of some unspeakable mischief, as Fay storms back into the house. He looks around, bored, then brightens up when he sees... Henry, coming up the street, hanging from the back of a garbage truck.</context>
      <utterance>Play!</utterance>
   <speaker>PATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Henry, what did I tell you about bringing the kid in here!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say hello to Patty, Ned.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She suddenly becomes all soft and cuddly.</context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods and Henry stands him on a stool at the bar.</context>
      <utterance>How you doin', sweetie? You wanna Coke?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>So what did you learn at school today, Ned? Anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands Ned a cigarette and lights it for him. Ned takes a drag and coughs.</context>
      <utterance>Here, I'll teach you something.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned nods in agreement.</context>
      <utterance>Horrible, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It burns.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he offers the kid his whiskey.</context>
      <utterance>See. That'll teach ya. Here, sip this.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ned! She comes out to the street and looks around.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ned!</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pearl turns defiantly away and walks into the street.</context>
      <utterance>I'm warning you, Pearl!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some other guy down the bar is reading a newspaper...</context>
      <utterance>That's it. That's it. Perfect!</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry looks over. The guy, Bill, shows him the article.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Fool, it's about your friend -- what's his name. Your brother-in- law.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about him?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The controversial and reclusive American poet Simon Grim has been awarded the Nobel Prize in Literature. The Swedish Academy, who will confer the award late next week, praised Mr Grim for works of great and difficult striving, for the rendering of the desperate, the ugly and the mundane in a language packed with our shared human frailties...</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, they must be hard up for geniuses to pin medals on because, listen, I gotta tell you, when I first met this guy he didn't even know what an iambic pentameter was.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a fraud.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep a lid on it, Bill, you're outta your league.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stir things up so as to stay in the newspapers. That's his racket.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a great American poet, you dumb fuck!</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Poet, my ass! I could puke all over a piece a loose leaf and be more profound than he is!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come over here and say that and I'll cripple ya in three different ways, you boozed-up Philistine!</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry and Ned crouch and quiver -- caught. Fay strides up to the bar and grabs the kid.</context>
      <utterance>Henry!</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kid checks with Henry then looks back at Fay and nods. Fay looks at her husband, outraged.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, you degenerate, I've had about enough of this!  Ned, have you been drinking?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she storms out with the kid. Henry snaps his jaw back into place, then looks at Patty and Bill and shrugs. He knocks back his drink and motions for another.</context>
      <utterance>Henry, don't come home tonight! I'm warning you! Don't come home at all! Ever!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's winning?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR DENG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry gestures to World of Donuts...</context>
      <utterance>Nobody.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR DENG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We gotta have rock 'n' roll shows these days, Henry. The poetry readings just don't pay the bills no more.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did I tell you! It was just a fad. I told you that! I told everyone!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR DENG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you hear about Simon? It was on the news today.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah yeah yeah. So what? A Nobel Prize. Anybody can get one of them these days. That's the problem, with this world, Mr Deng... Nobody's got any standards anymore. You seen Fay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR DENG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You better sleep in my office tonight, Henry. She was very angry. You've gotta let her cool off.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't sleep in there with that racket!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR DENG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry considers his options, then...</context>
      <utterance>Suit yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here, Pearl?</utterance>
   <speaker>PEARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want some?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pearl comes towards him. He is kneeling with his face at her crotch level when she reaches him. She holds out a bottle of cheap rot-gut wine. Realizing, he takes it and drinks. He winces.</context>
      <utterance>Some what?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pearl laughs and falls back onto the couch, her sweater hanging off her shoulder and her skirt hiked up and displaying her underwear. Henry stands and searches for something to sit on.</context>
      <utterance>Shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>PEARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He comes over, eyeing her carefully and sits. He hands back the bottle. She drinks, winces and sits staring at the flames.</context>
      <utterance>Come sit here. She pats the couch beside her.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what my dad always says.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>PEARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry looks away, uncomfortable. She slides her gaze over to him, their eyes meet, and she pins him to the spot.</context>
      <utterance>'You want some?'</utterance>
   <speaker>PEARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People say you were once in jail for having sex with a girl my age.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets up and stands at the window. Pearl age fourteen watches him closely as she drinks, then...</context>
      <utterance>That was a long time ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks over at her and she slides her coat off her shoulder. Henry is sweating.</context>
      <utterance>You want some?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You oughta get outta here, Pearl.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was here first.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he starts to leave. But Pearl sits up...</context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry stops and looks back at her.</context>
      <utterance>Wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>PEARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>PEARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry holds his head, tries to sober up. He looks around the room, then focuses on the girl.</context>
      <utterance>He beat her up again.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pearl stares at the floor. She glances over at him, then back down at the bottle gripped in her hands. She nods. Henry pauses, then comes across the room, lowering himself tentatively to the couch.</context>
      <utterance>Warren beat up your mom?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She says nothing for a moment, then...</context>
      <utterance>Is she alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>PEARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry lifts his hand and covers his face. He looks up at the ceiling and sighs. He returns to Pearl...</context>
      <utterance>Do you think I'm pretty?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pearl reaches over and grabs his thigh. Looking up at him, with tears rolling down her face, she suggests...</context>
      <utterance>Does she need help?</utterance>
   <speaker>PEARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry jumps away from her and Pearl throws herself down on the couch, covering her face.</context>
      <utterance>I'll suck your cock if you kill him for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs through the house, checking the rooms. He throws open the door to the bedroom and finds... Vicky, sitting on the edge of the bed, smoking. She has a black eye and a swollen cheek.</context>
      <utterance>Vicky! Vicky, it's Henry from across the street! Vicky!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vicky?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think you're doing, you idiot!</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry looks over and sees Warren stumble drunkenly out of the bathroom. What are you doing in my house?</context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vicky looks troubled. She sits back down with a sigh.</context>
      <utterance>It's about Pearl.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mind your own business, Henry.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Warren is stabbed in the heart. Henry can't believe it. Warren can't believe it. He stands there in the middle of the kitchen, amazed, with the screwdriver sticking out of his chest. Henry, semi-conscious and severely beaten, falls against the back door and coughs up a few of his teeth. Vicky steps into the hall from her room and shudders. Warren sits at the table, stunned. He looks from the screwdriver to Vicky, then...</context>
      <utterance>Ah.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He falls to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>LAWYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is true your husband served seven years in prison for statutory rape.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. It is.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And when was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was... I dunno. Fifteen... Sixteen years ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And when were you married?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were married seven years ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were you aware at all of the victim's relationship with his daughter?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pardon me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fay is overwhelmed.</context>
      <utterance>The girl, the daughter, Pearl. She had been having sexual relations with her father.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know that. No.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fay just looks at him blankly, overwhelmed, confused. She starts to cry quietly.</context>
      <utterance>Pearl claims she offered your husband sexual favors if he would kill her father.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fay trembles and catches her breath trying to take this all in. A cop hands her some tissues. She takes them and tries to concentrate on what the lawyer says.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just repeating what she said, Mrs Fool. The victim's wife, Vicky, claims your husband broke into the house and forcefully entered her bedroom.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fay, I know this isn't easy. But we need your help here. The girl claims she asked your husband to kill her father in exchange for, well, I guess the promise of sexual relations with her.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks at the bedspread and looks at the ceiling, then...</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, honey. Leave me alone a minute, I gotta think.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What!</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is Dad in trouble?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks around to the other side of the bed and waits a moment before...</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Ned, he is. He's in big trouble. Now just be quiet for two minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm warning you, Ned.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fay sits up, pauses and studies her son.</context>
      <utterance>Mom, can I be a mailman when I grow up?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned is happy to hear this. He shuffles out of the room and Fay falls back on the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Sure you can, honey. You can be anything you want.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CONCIERGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, what do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My uncle.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONCIERGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's his name?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The concierge looks through his book as Ned waits.</context>
      <utterance>Simon Grim.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONCIERGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned pulls the envelope from his pocket, unfolds it and shows it to the concierge.</context>
      <utterance>There ain't no one here by that name.</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The concierge studies the envelope and hands it back.</context>
      <utterance>Room 423.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONCIERGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Disappointed, Ned takes back the envelope and stands looking at his sneakers.</context>
      <utterance>This is post marked five years ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONCIERGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does he look like?</utterance>
   <speaker>NED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONCIERGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned steps away from the front desk and moves towards the door. But then he stops and looks back at... The concierge, sitting back in his office, returning his attention to the TV set. The boy heads for the elevator. The concierge looks up and sees him.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, kid. Can't help ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONCIERGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned checks his step and runs for the service stairs. The concierge goes after him.</context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He does.</context>
      <utterance>Get up off your knees.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Promise me you'll be on that plane at seven, Simon.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They kiss. The taxi pulls away. Simon comes down beside Ned, takes the boy by the shoulders and whispers in his ear. The kid takes off. Simon looks over at World of Donuts and sees Gnoc waiting there at the door.</context>
      <utterance>I'll see you in Stockholm.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon thinks about this and looks away.</context>
      <utterance>Look, Simon, the world's a scary place. I admit it. But it's not my fault. I swear!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Henry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be. You had things to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry thinks about that, sighs and looks away.</context>
      <utterance>So did you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned does. He has his own Zippo lighter and he proudly lights his dad's cigarette. Henry smokes, hugs Ned, then leans back and pauses. Finally...</context>
      <utterance>Gotta light?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ned nods and Henry pats him on the shoulder. Then he stands before Fay and looks at his feet. With her arms folded across her chest and her hip cocked, she taps her foot impatiently and waits for his last line of crap.</context>
      <utterance>Take care of your mom and don't start trouble you can't finish.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you, Fay.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But then she looks at him and softens. He leans in and kisses her passionately on the mouth. Moments later, they all help Henry into Buuel's car and Simon gets in behind the wheel. The doors slam shut and Simon steers the car slowly up the alley. Henry gazes out at Fay running along beside the car with the rest of the neighborhood, some of them laughing, some of them crying...</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, tough.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>AIRLINE TICKET CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry hands them over. He glances back at... Simon, waiting. The clerk compares Henry to the picture in the passport, checks again, then...</context>
      <utterance>Passport and ticket, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>AIRLINE TICKET CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's an honor to meet you, Mr Grim. Really. I mean, God. Congratulations on the Nobel Prize.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>AIRLINE TICKET CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know all your work by heart. It changed my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well. Look, thanks, but..</utterance>
   <speaker>AIRLINE TICKET CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She types something more into the computer, then looks up urgently.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>AIRLINE TICKET CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll have to hurry, sir. They're holding the plane for you on the runway.</utterance>
   <speaker>AIRLINE REP #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they are ushered up towards the gate, Henry stops and looks off at the security guards and ground crew waiting for him, certain they can spot him as a wanted criminal.</context>
      <utterance>This way, please, this way! This way, Mr Grim! This way! Excuse me!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry is ushered through security. They take his ticket and check his passport again. They take his suitcase and place it on the conveyor belt. He passes through the metal detector. They pass the metal detector wand over him and he stands there with his hands outstretched, as... Simon waits and watches. The suitcase rolls out from the x-ray machine and as Henry grabs it, he stops and looks across the security checkpoint at... Simon, standing there. He steps forward anxiously. Henry lingers, speechless, but the airline representatives are at his side...</context>
      <utterance>Go on.</utterance>
   <speaker>AIRLINE REP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They drag him away, but Henry looks back as... Simon stops and watches.</context>
      <utterance>Mr Grim, please, the plane is waiting! We have to hurry!</utterance>
   <speaker>AIRLINE REP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Runway technicians rush to their positions, but Henry hangs back and struggles across the tarmac, looking back over his shoulder at... Simon, behind the huge plate glass window of the terminal. He stops and waits. Simon raises his hand in farewell and... Henry raises his in reply. Then Simon, unheard behind the gigantic glass wall, silent amongst the roar of the runway, says...</context>
      <utterance>This way, Mr Grim! This way!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Henry understands. He lowers his hand, waits just a moment, then turns and looks out at... The airplane. The airline representative is shouting at him from the foot of the stairs and waving him on with her walkie- talkie. He glances back once more at Simon. Then... Henry is running, struggling towards us, forcing himself towards the plane, getting stronger and running faster with every step he takes.</context>
      <utterance>Run.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
