<movie id="293" title="I ll Do Anything">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRANTIC ACTRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence, then:</context>
      <utterance>I can't hear over this shhing.</utterance>
   <speaker>TV CRITIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...a play about guess what? That's right, young people.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>HANDSOME CONTEMPORARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't look.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He begins to walk, the Handsome Contemporary falling into step. Everyone they pass is straining, upwards, at the TV.</context>
      <utterance>Good idea, let's not.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANDSOME CONTEMPORARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can we not listen to this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment, the rest of the party-goers turn from the TV as one, looking mugged. (One girl briefly gets our attention because she is particularly distraught; tears streaming down her angry face. The mixture of tears and rage are, of course, the chemical components of incredible sexiness. Her name is BETH.) A TORTURED MALE DANCER offers an incantation.</context>
      <utterance>We'll know all we need to from the reaction.</utterance>
   <speaker>TORTURED MALE DANCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He should be shot, he should be dead, he should rot in hell, then come back as the soap cake in a urinal.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANDSOME CONTEMPORARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The DIRECTOR moves through the group, bucking up spirits.</context>
      <utterance>He didn't like it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. He doesn't count. We'll just wait for the papers.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beth looks at him, puzzled.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, no matter what this review says, the play was a great experience for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, it is about process, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANDSOME CONTEMPORARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beth turns from the conversation, finding it preposterous, then rivets her attention on the Director, walking towards them, holding a ridiculously thick sheaf of papers. Beth begins to sob in anticipation.</context>
      <utterance>Matt's right. Good Lord, it is what we're alive for.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've just got to be tougher than this.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Director reaches them.</context>
      <utterance>Tougher than this?!?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I took it all down over the phone. It's quite bad. And, unfortunately, it's very, very long. I've got a broken heart and writers' cramp. He...</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's nuts.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He savages everyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to hear anymore. Let's dance.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all look at him.</context>
      <utterance>Except you, Matt.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANDSOME CONTEMPORARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You filthy bastard.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Director hunts for the paragraph.</context>
      <utterance>What did he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't read it.</utterance>
   <speaker>OTHER ACTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, please. You can't wait to run out of here, buy a flashlight, and then go into some dark alley and drool over every word.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're wrong. I'm maybe relieved and curious. That's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did they say about him?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...'in the midst of this delirium of pretension...'</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't. This divisive crap won't...</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you get in here--for God's sake?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Ma, how could I show up tonight when my union is boycotting the Emmys? Look, I have to hang up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode>O. S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's on right now... right now... right this second! You will miss it!!</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt hangs up and tear-asses into the living room. Beth screams as his name is read.</context>
      <utterance>I gotta go. Watch!</utterance>
   <speaker>TV VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and Matt Hobbs for 'Caine Mutiny Court Martial'... And the winner is Powers Boothe for 'Jonestown--Story of a Massacre.'</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit! Fuck! Shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was good.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit! Shit! Shit! Fuck! Shit! Look, he even showed up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That took courage. I wonder if they send you something for just being nominated?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of all the pathetic questions.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've been going back and forth on our status for so long. I was hoping that if you won, it might mean something for us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is waving her hand in a circle... he is puzzled.</context>
      <utterance>Look, Beth... the only...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please go fast. I can't take you dragging it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The only reason I haven't...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I promised myself I wouldn't be so bossy. Take your time!! Was that bossy too?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The only thing I have against getting married is that it might not be fair because I'm going to stay with acting forever and you know how erratic the money's been and there's no resolve...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I get to vote? I'm going to tell you something I never told you before. Your feeling towards your work is one of the things I love most about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe the most.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They kiss, then break, murmuring to each other.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, then we have no problem here. Marry me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stinker, I almost gave up on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just worried whether I could make you happy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you doing? What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On Matt's expression...</context>
      <utterance>My mother said you were flirting with the doctor during the delivery.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could you get her, honey? I have that big reading tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I have a lot to do tomorrow, too. I have to borrow on our Christmas Club, I have to...</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about money anymore.  I didn't want to tell you, because it may sound a little strange when I say it out loud. You know me, I'm never that cocky. But I'm going to get 'Spider Woman'. It's me or Raul and I've never been so sure. It's weird, but I just know it. I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, am I reassured. What good news. Isn't that a load off?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am gonna get this part, Beth.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't stand this anymore.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what? I'm being a sort of gutless wonder here. I'm yelling back at you because I'm embarrassed. I won't be able to take the kid when I said... Why don't you listen for a second? He rubs his head with both hands, including the one holding the phone. This allows us to hear his ex-wife repeat the same sentence over and over again.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode>V. O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...You're taking her... You're taking her... You're taking her...</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beth turns angry again. Matt finds, unfortunately, that he's got one more act of bravado left.</context>
      <utterance>Beth, I know exactly how long it's been and I feel strange as hell not seeing her but this isn't a choice. I'm broke. It's the driest spell of my life. I'm not saying it's your problem, but it's no place for a six- year-old. What can I do? The only full-time job I seem to have is not showing how scared I am. What? No, that's not something I said before.  Well, thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up.</context>
      <utterance>Beth, Hey... hey. Never mind, I'll do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I must get work. I will take anything. I must get work. I must not be embarrassed by these pep talks to myself...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MIDDLE-AGED ACTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What am I, a duck?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER ACTRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MUSIC BECOMING MORE INSISTENT as we approach the building-- the mumbling of the actors taking on the SOUND of a Wailing Wall...</context>
      <utterance>Sure I'll tell you... Favor first... Do a nice middle-aged lady a favor... A fair trade... tell you what you want to know in return for a...  ...a pity fu...</utterance>
   <speaker>VARIOUS YOUNG HYSTERICAL ACTRESSES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...the height of ego. You think your he-manness can make me get on that elevator even though I'm phobic?... I CAN'T GET ON THAT ELEVATOR. I don't care if... they catch us. DO YOU</utterance>
   <speaker>THREE HYSTERICAL ACTRESSES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>SINGING the dialogue...</utterance>
   <speaker>SINGING ACTRESSES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...can't get on the elevator... can't get on the elevator... even if you make me... even if you make me. Do you get it?... do you get it?...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi... See, I did recognize you. You didn't have to wait for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I wanted to introduce you. As if knowing me would help.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a ridiculously awful movie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, challenge. I wasn't sure you'd remember me... let alone help...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop. You're good. I'm doing them a favor by getting you in.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They reach the casting assistant, CLAIRE.</context>
      <utterance>Well, that's a fresh slant.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Matt is handed a set of sides, we SHOOT PAST Matt as he watches Cathy move back down the stairs before he can say another word. She moves with wit. He is struck by her. He looks back at Claire, who has an intricate hairdo and a ready smile.</context>
      <utterance>Claire, this is Matt Hobbs.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. Sorry. We're running behind... Please forgive us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Matt Hobbs... This is John Earl McAlpine, the director.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCALPINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He speaks with an Australian accent, gets half-up and extends his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Good to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and Burke Adler, the producer.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, what have you been doing with yourself...  ...the last few years?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm real bad at interviews, so, if you don't mind, I'd really prefer to just read first.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the way you want to do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe we shouldn't even read. I'll just take your word that you're good.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I'm serious. There's all different ways. Did you know Woody Allen never reads actors? He just looks at them, feels around a little and then decides who he wants. That's his way. Doesn't hear them do a line. I also have a way. What I do is interview first-- then read--maybe do it all over again the next day. I call up people the actor has worked with--check him out. If he's famous, I do an opinion survey to test how much people like him. If he's not famous, I put him on tape and show it to everyone I can grab. I believe in screen tests; I believe in replacing if the dailies are bad, in cutting people out if the previews aren't there. Because I'm not doing movies for theaters where they serve cappucino in the lobby. I'm doing popcorn movies. You want to know what I like? Come to my house, look at my lamps... you won't find it in my movies. In my movies, you'll find out what I know. I know how to do detail. What I don't know, I discover. Yesterday we finished mixing a movie--the last scene is in a field of windmills which blows up and all the blades of these windmills slice through the air, one of which hits a four-story tank of propane gas. A humongous explosion scene. I kept on saying 'louder', and they finally said to me they couldn't go louder without distortion. We went louder. We had to discover a thing, a filter, but we went louder. I don't question doing these things. I do them. So if you want to know if it's okay to do it differently--not to talk--to just read first... I say...  Ask him--he's the director.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, let's do it. Do you have any questions?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They only gave me these two pages. I'd like to give this my best shot. So if I could read the script and come back...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This part works tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burke indicates Martin.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Who will I be reading with?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I read from here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt rises uncomfortably. A SECRETARY enters and hands a note to the director.</context>
      <utterance>I want you to do it wherever you're comfortable, but I'd prefer it if you were comfortable standing up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt looks astonished as the director leaves the room.</context>
      <utterance>Time for my buns to have visitors.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead? The director left.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's okay, he trusts me, uh... And we're just doing the first page.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Okay, darling Harry, here it is... If someone were breaking up with me, I'd like it short and sweet. What about you?'</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Incredibly drawn out...'</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'I can't take care of you right now. What am I, your mother?'</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he gets into the scene he begins to experience some release of the desperate feelings he's been harboring.</context>
      <utterance>'Well, what am I? Your duck?'</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'We've been together two years and you act like all you're doing is blowing away some feathers. So what I'm asking...'</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't do the quack.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The stage direction says for him to quack.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, but why would he quack when someone's breaking up with him?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hopefully because it's funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't a comedy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then we're in trouble, because they're already fall down laughing at the teaser-trailer in fifty-two hundred and thirty theaters.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A comedy?  I think I have to make an adjustment here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. I just finished. I'll have my coverage right over. It's past derivative... it's photocopying. What a hoot! You're kidding, right? There is truly active bidding for this book? Really? 2.3 million? Okay, see you. She hangs up and begins to alter the form changing the STORY/POOR to STORY/EXCELLENT, and all the other POORS to GOOD... and now the Recommend section.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The pen is poised.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>MALE D PERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even the title "Little Dick"--it means so many things.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE D PERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Story, story, story, story, story.  You loved it, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had some problems.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE D PERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you know, it's a little garbagey.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE D PERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So it has to be cast right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE D PERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If Cathy doesn't like it, we know it's a smash.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd it go?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't get it. He did say something about wanting me back.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. His saver is he means what he says.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods and starts to turn back towards her office.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I just wanted to say thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and I wanted to ask you out. The other people in the office stare at Matt.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For when?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any time.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never know when I'm free.  It sounds like I'm just... but it's true.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Thanks again. I felt funny asking.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, don't please.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I meant asking you to get me the audition.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods and starts to go. She looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Oh... well, don't please.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt smiles in astonishment and exits.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be sad.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE D PERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I was auditing this acting course and he filled in teaching one night. He did a scene himself and he was awesome. For some reason, he can't get arrested.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE D PERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. He does seem to have a layer of loser dust on him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at me. You'd think I was a writer.  I hired this kid as a production assistant. His father's a business manager... a few good clients.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's been driving for me two weeks... all he has to do is pick me up on time... he's twenty minutes late and I have a test screening in the valley. Everybody's gone from the office. Burke flails at himself as Matt looks at him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that it? You need a lift?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt starts to lead him back, then realizes he's alone, Burke having seen his car finally arrive.</context>
      <utterance>I'm right over here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's get moving; you said you'd give me a lift.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you talking about? Not in your car... I've got my own.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The driver gets out.</context>
      <utterance>I'll give you a hundred and twenty dollars to take me... and it will still be a favor.  Get out. Come on.  Please. This is very important.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A guy got shot on the freeway... Traffic's tied up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should leave time for that kind of thing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you need me for? Don't you drive?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I drive. I don't like to look for parking.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yoga shit. I feel like barbed wire. I don't know if you keep track, but I'm the sixth independent producer ever to have two big pictures scheduled for Christmas, and tonight we're testing the first one for the first time... You get it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. It's important to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I don't think I would have put it that way... but, yes...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're 34 minutes late. The studio is appropriately wild... people are beginning to leave... but I knew how upset you'd be if we started without you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he pays her no mind as MUSIC CONTINUES and he moves towards the line. Nan approaches the car.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is he tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know him, so I have nothing to compare it to.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, how would you say he is, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not quite himself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they enter.</context>
      <utterance>Let them in.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she says this:</context>
      <utterance>The name of the picture you'll be seeing is 'Ground Zero'... There may be some scratches... some of the colors may be off, there are no final titles, and it has not been finally mixed for sound, and the music is temp, that means temporary...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boss is startled--jumps. BURKE eyes him... there must be some way to profit from these stolen moments with a powerful man.</context>
      <utterance>I'm glad you came yourself instead of sending your staff.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't be surprised if tonight's screening is a monster.  Could happen, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUDIO HEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves back to Matt and Nan at the rear of the audience.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Incredibly, Burke turns and gestures to her that the sound of her small voice is interfering with the cacophony of his movie. Nan is clearly stricken by her lapse as she whispers to Matt.</context>
      <utterance>Please, God, let tonight give him peace.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're short two card-counters, can you two help out?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GROUP CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt, his tally finished, squats on the floor, waiting. The Group Captain approaches.</context>
      <utterance>Who has young males? Young women? Older males?... Older males?...</utterance>
   <speaker>GROUP CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt looks blank.</context>
      <utterance>Older males... older males?</utterance>
   <speaker>GROUP CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt now realizes that it is his category and hands over the older male cards and exits.</context>
      <utterance>Older males... over 25?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long since you've seen your daughter?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little over two years.  My wife insisted on moving back to the Midwest--then I was in the Philippines on the mini-series and...</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, please. It's one thing being a son-of-a-bitch, but you don't have to be a stupid son-of-a-bitch. People move heaven and earth to see their kids. I don't care if she moved to Pluto, it's abandonment.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, we just met.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make a guess how we did.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wouldn't mean anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An OLDER WOMAN approaches them.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing good that happens can make it worth feeling the way I do now. Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the hell are you? This is private.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Mr. Eisner's mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Can I get you some water?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Group Captain approaches and hands Nan a sheet.</context>
      <utterance>No, thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STUDIO HEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His smiling face takes us:</context>
      <utterance>I don't need the numbers. I loved it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Burke, ninety in the top two boxes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never thought it would do this well. There were so many holes; I told everybody it wasn't going to do business. Why am I so public with my opinions?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You might be right.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not with that score. You know, maybe tonight's the night I'm losing my entire mind, but weren't you in 'Platoon?'</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Incredible. I was only there for a minute in the rape scene, moving past Charlie Sheen when I left the hut... I had a great scene cut out... I was...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But there was that one long close up-- where you seemed ashamed of yourself but still arrogant.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's exactly what I was going for.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hefts the bag--puts it back down--crosses her eyes, burlesquing the weight of the bag. He helps her put it on her shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>It reminded me of my last boyfriend.  Got to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to read all that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beast of burden.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come you haven't said anything? This is great, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What no?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans against the car for support.</context>
      <utterance>The definite recommends are way off for a score this high and, even for action-adventure, it's just too low for women.  I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was such a good score.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know... And, unfortunately, yesterday's tracking wasn't...  I'm sorry... They just don't seem in the mood for action-adventure right...  Sorry... May I tell you one more thing?  I think it's so wonderful that you don't worry about even trying to act strong.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. You want to eat something sometime?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm, uh... I'm blushing from head to foot.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Burke moves to his car. He SEES the Group Captain paying Matt.</context>
      <utterance>Good. I'll call you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GROUP CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burke is looking at Matt with some surprise.</context>
      <utterance>Thirty-two, thirty-three.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to do this regularly for me? I was gonna offer, but I thought it would humiliate you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt gets behind the wheel, thereby ending the day as a full- fledged chauffeur. They drive off.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, I got the cards to look at--I think I'll ride back here.  Maybe I'll drop by your place tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, thanks for lunch. I hope this leads to an evening date. Though I have to stay home with my daughter, Leslie, on Saturdays.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, okay. You were very interesting to talk to. I swear to God. Honest. No kidding. You really were.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I believe you.  And I was very surprised what you were like when you weren't working. There was absolutely no difference. You want to see where we do the tracking?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it okay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burke hardly hears. He is awed as if by a cathedral.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody ever wants to see how we do the polling, but they're like little starved puppies when the data comes in--running at you, scrambling to...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love this. This is what counts and this is where you count it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the same way I feel.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You phone all over--you know what movies they're waiting to see, whether your TV spots are working. You know what the country thinks.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...what feelings do you have about Cher as a singer, an actress, or potential date...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and it's accurate.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Within six-point-eight percent.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you can't fix it... right?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... no... Sometimes just for myself, I can't resist asking America a personal question.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When do you feel more worthless-- mornings or afternoons?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They pause by a workers to say goodbye.</context>
      <utterance>I gotta get back.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Assume Michelle Pfeiffer is the woman-- which of these 67 actors would you most like to see her with... Patrick Swayze, Keanu Reeves, Dustin Hoffman, Johnny Dep, the guy from 'Major Dad'...</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's something I meant to tell you. You may have noticed something unusual about me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta get back.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could never find the right time to...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this urgent?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, maybe not urgent, but immediately significant and necessary to tell.  You see, there's these pills...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Cause I gotta go. I'm listening with an eighth of an ear now.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He exits as the telephone pollster continues with the list of prospective Michelle Pfeiffer male co-stars.</context>
      <utterance>So long.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you Matt?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lights a cigarette, takes three quick drags, then flicks it away before walking inside behind Matt.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't know if we could wait much longer. Come on in.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's a real nut on smoking anywhere near the kid.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello--did you two meet?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not really. Is she ready? I have the taxi waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just have to say goodbye. You have no idea how difficult that is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's three weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not three weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Several beats--Beth and the man staring at Matt.</context>
      <utterance>No, it's not.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He doesn't know?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are not taking her for a visit. You are taking her for a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just because you want to go off with him doesn't mean I...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're getting the wrong idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so. No matter how you put this...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, look, I'm a United States Marshal. I'm here because she didn't show up yesterday to start serving her time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns and starts for the other room.</context>
      <utterance>I don't have a choice. You don't have a choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did she do?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I loved, helped and supported in every possible way a business man who committed the terrible crime of being financially imaginative with a pension fund. She exits. He sits down, stunned in the headlights of his fate.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>BETH'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, listen carefully, Jeannie. Be still. Now, what's the most important thing in life to know?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt and the Marshal exchange a look of mutual horror.</context>
      <utterance>No one will ever love me as much as you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Marshal and Matt shift uncomfortably.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Now, concentrate with all your muscles and remember everything I'm about to say to you...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't talk to strangers. They may be killers. Take your vitamins so the poison in the food can't hurt you. What else now?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Teeth.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Marshal and Matt can stand no more--they each call to her... "Beth... Beth... Mrs. Hobbs... Beth." She looks out and then walks to them.</context>
      <utterance>Right. Thank you. Brush right after you eat or your gums will start to bleed in your sleep and choke you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? I'm giving Jeannie her reminders.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reminders?!? You can't say things like that to a little...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Don't. No. Don't dare. Don't criticize the way I mother or I think I'll start to scream and never st...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Hobbs.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I've been involved with this sort of thing for a long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not going to criticize me, are you? Not in front of him--because all he's done is send Jeannie these long, stupid letters. He doesn't even realize she can't read. He sends letters to someone who can't read.  It's almost funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you'd read them to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not faulting you. You love your daughter and this is a very tough thing to go through. You feel guilty and caring and it all gets mixed up so that there's so much important stuff going down that there's no sure way of dealing with it, but the best thing you can do is just make sure you love her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But I understand what you're trying to say. Thank you. Can I have another minute with her? She returns to the doorway which still only provides us with glimpses as she SINGS, "DON'T TALK TO STRANGERS." The CAMERA MOVES down the hallway to INTRODUCE JEANNIE, trying to puzzle things out as she sits amongst a ridiculous number of suitcases.</context>
      <utterance>Typical cop talk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, hi, hi, hi, hi, hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, monster-poop.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beth stops him with a look, then bends down.</context>
      <utterance>She has her mother's sense of humor.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, love, Mommy's going to help others who need her for a few years, and you're going with Daddy as I explained.  We'll all have to help with the luggage.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beginning now, you must give less value to your own happiness and well- being, then hopefully, you will reach the point where you give that no value whatsoever. Give her everything. There's no such thing as spoiling a child.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even if you have to steal to do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't really want to mess with me, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, sweetie. We have to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to go with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tears fall from Jeannie's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Can't, pretty-heart. I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not even a compromise?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The compromise will be that you don't have to ride in back; you can ride up front with the driver... okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Beth buckles Jeannie into the front seat, Matt gets in the back, alone, feeling preposterous. Beth nods to the Marshal, who surreptitiously handcuffs her.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we please go?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's going to be okay. I'm you're dad, you know? So it will be okay. You and I will make it okay. You ever ridden in a plane before?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yesssss!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't stare at me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to put on my yellow dress now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And just that quick, Jeannie screams.</context>
      <utterance>It's underneath the plane. We can't get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Other passengers turn around. This is pretty raw stuff we're into. Temper in all its wildness, MUSIC UNDER... electric guitar beginning to match the energy and naked emotion of the child.</context>
      <utterance>I want to put on my dress. I want to put on my dress.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeannie's feet start kicking in front of her--the person in that seat turning sharply around.</context>
      <utterance>There's no way we can get the dress-- it's impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't kick the seat!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is crying now.</context>
      <utterance>I want the yellow dress.  Give me a compromise.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As soon as we land. That's the compromise.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WOMEN IN ROW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't hit her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, I didn't hit her--she hit her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FLIGHT ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeannie takes advantage of Matt's being stopped and moves into the toilet, locking the door behind her.</context>
      <utterance>You'll have to sit down.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeannie, we have to sit down. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll be having some turbulence for the next twenty minutes or so. Will the cabin attendants please take their seats?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLIGHT ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A sudden bump and Matt falls. He yells to the locked door.</context>
      <utterance>I have no idea what to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeannie, you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLIGHT ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Matt makes his way back, the Flight Attendant uses a hidden latch to open the door. Music building--then calming, the worst is over. Matt makes his way back to his seat, shell- shocked. The Attendant leans over him.</context>
      <utterance>Go back to your seat. I'll get her.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLIGHT ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He just nods.</context>
      <utterance>She wants to be alone. So we're upgrading her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are the wrong jammies.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeannie mimics him perfectly under her breath. She goes to an open suitcase and throws things on the floor until she finds the right jammies.</context>
      <utterance>Okay... so what do we do?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do I sleep?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She surveys her pitiful choice; then points to the sleeping bag.</context>
      <utterance>I have a sleeping bag and bed. Which one do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets into it. He zips her up--then she says something remarkably unexpected.</context>
      <utterance>That.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amazed, Matt hugs her. A half-beat, then:</context>
      <utterance>Hug.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He does--then stands and looks down at her. She looks back, mocking his stare with one of her own.</context>
      <utterance>Let go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves quickly to him.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I thought you took off in the middle of the night.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I just had to call home. Is that why you're sad?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. It's Everett. This kid who used to work for me. He was always crazy to do his own movie.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen. I'm tremendously worried about 'Ground Zero' because of the bad 'want to sees' you sent over. But that's just me being nervous over nothing, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He eyes her, then:</context>
      <utterance>No. That's just you correctly assessing the situation. So stop being so hard on yourself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How're you doing? I'm from next door. I see you with your kids in the laundry room...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeannie is a bit shy.</context>
      <utterance>Hello.  ...Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, 'Hello, I'm your new neighbor now too.' Jeannie says nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeannie says nothing.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Lucy Crisala... What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The form of the conversation is forged. Jeannie not answering anything. Matt bending over to Jeannie while he forms her answers to Lucy.</context>
      <utterance>Say, 'Jeannie.'</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a little girl too.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, 'Isn't that nice... How old is she?'</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's four and a half and I have a little boy who is not yet one year.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, 'That's nice... I'd like to play with them... My Daddy didn't know your phone number, so we just decided to...'</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can I do for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say 'Daddy has to go to work tonight and...'  I need someone to help me and her on short notice. I've seen your around with your kids and hoped you knew someone in the building or close by. I've got this new job that starts now. Do you know anyone?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm always here. I could maybe do it myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, this is so great. Let's work out a full-time schedule and...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeannie walks into the apartment past her father.</context>
      <utterance>Wait. Jeannie, why don't you come in for a minute and meet Ricky and Essa. Come on, we're making fruit bars.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you leave her for a while and then we talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sort of a test?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll just see how it works.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry I bothered you.  Jeannie...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could I have her a little bit longer? My little boy just fell and Jeannie is the only one he let hold him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your little boy fell, so he's screaming. And you want her to stay. Lucy, confused by his buoyant reaction, nods.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Seven dollars an hour?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tries to kiss her, but she shuns him. Lucy, now having an official status, turns to admonish her.</context>
      <utterance>Great. Thank you. See you later, Jeannie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, that's okay. I'm fine with it. I feel fine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing good that happens tonight can make it worth feeling the way I do right now. Nothing.  What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To be honest, I had problems with 'Ground Zero.' But this 'People Get Hurt' one, while it might not be my exact, exact thing, I think will really work for an audience. It's so over the top, you have a great time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you think it'll score big?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. My daughter used to throw fits in supermarkets when we first moved here. It's all so perfectly normal. Plus I know a great psychiatric children's group.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what breaks your heart. Jeannie's problem is that she's so down on herself.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, she's lucky to have a daddy who cares, believe me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know if lucky's the word. I'm hoping she's asleep when I get home so I won't have to deal with her... I'm actually afraid of my own kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt laughs. In the b.g., the counting is completed.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, my. I've had exactly that feeling and never said it out loud. See, there are men who talk my language and I'm just cursed that I'm not attracted to them because they are so nice they remind me of myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>GROUP CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excellents?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL COUNTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seven.</utterance>
   <speaker>GROUP CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very goods?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GROUP CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Poors?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND GIRL CARD COUNTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(finishes counting)</context>
      <utterance>Just a second...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are they doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I began taking anti-depressants when we moved here from Washington. I had some small reactions--sleeping 14 hours, no libido, I gained 17 pounds in nine days--that sort of thing. So they gave me pills to deal with the side effects. And then pills to deal with the side effects I was getting from those pills. All this besides the stuff the nutritionist was giving me. The combination formed some sort of potion so that I keep telling the truth. I don't have a choice. That's why I was so rude to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your doctor says this?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cathy has joined them.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes. He's excited, but only because he sees glory for himself in it... See, ordinarily I wouldn't say that about my doctor, but I can't help it, it's the truth. He's monitoring me for a while longer before writing it up for this medical journal...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Burke's going crazy waiting for the score.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt shifts, figuring out his answer.</context>
      <utterance>How are you, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nan looks down at the score.</context>
      <utterance>It's a tough one, huh? Me too.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts for Burke.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, my. Matt, I'd better drive him myself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can fix this... Get some narration written. . .  You'll cut 30 minutes. It will come out like butter.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're only 77 minutes now...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...a 47-minute movie... no, that won't work...</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE STUDIO EXEC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to go. I have a nanny problem. Priorities, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses his cheek and leaves. A beat of silence... Burke turns to Nan.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the support.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Exactly the moment Nan has been waiting for... she does have a valuable observation to offer at this dark moment.</context>
      <utterance>Can you help?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I can.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Burke looks at her from the depths of his pain and sees her confidently believing that she has imparted something of value, the movie's marquee lights go off giving us a:</context>
      <utterance>It's only a movie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let go. Please, Lucy, don't make me go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone's tired. You can come back tomorr...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to me, Jeannie...</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to live here with these people. God, let me live here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe if she stayed tonight she...</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now her father's last words have registered on her--she immediately stops crying, though tears still roll down her cheeks.</context>
      <utterance>I love it here so much that...</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeannie wriggles away towards Lucy's doorway. Lucy takes several steps toward Matt, who obviously fears the looming exchange.</context>
      <utterance>Daddy says I can stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt is very much like a fighter taking a great deal of punishment, knowing he is beaten, but being told by his corner he must make a fight of it. He nods his head repeatedly in agreement...</context>
      <utterance>I no think you can give her what pleases when she act like this... Because then she think...</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now he sniffs the air in quick rhythm, hoping to draw in some courage and resolve. He moves to Jeannie.</context>
      <utterance>I know... I know...</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll see Lucy in the morning. We're going home.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I'm not! STOP!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>MILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will somebody take a minute to look over my casting list before Burke gets here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE D PERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't so great, Millie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I wanted to put in people we had a shot at getting.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE D PERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>F. Murray Abraham, Jeff Daniels, Ed Harris, John Lithgow, Rip Torn, Willem Dafoe, John Malkovich... For an action lead?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could you at least take it one person at a time instead of...</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE D PERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt can take it no more. He hears a loud voice coming from his own throat. He wigs out.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Let's play 'State the Obvious'... F. Murray Abraham has a nose as long as an Aspen ski line, Ed Harris is losing his hair, Joe Mantegna has never played the lead in a big movie... Willem Dafoe's teeth... Bob Hoskins looks fur bearing when he takes off his shirt... Malkovich...</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't stand it anymore. I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong? What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, in God's name, are you doing in this job you have?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As they all start to answer at once.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean him. What, in God's name, do you know about casting?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE D PERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt rises and walks towards the Male D Person.</context>
      <utterance>Me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. What do you know? About anything? You don't even know you have a habit of touching your tongue with a finger like you want to lick yourself.  Yet, you talk like you actually know something... So I want you to tell me...  ...what you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE D PERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not going to be drawn into this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been an actor most of my life and this is the first time I've ever heard what the people calling the shots sound like when they're casting. So I really want to find out what, if anything, you know because what if nothing you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE D PERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think the yelling is necessary.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you couldn't be more wrong. And I'm not talking to you. And I don't like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE D PERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt is very close to him--he shakes his chair.</context>
      <utterance>How about you just mind your own business?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're minding my business. That's the problem... so, just tell me, what do you know?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just tell me and I'll shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE D PERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First of all, I've been going to movies since I was six, for God's sake...</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you know is the size of a schnozz. What you don't know is that these guys...  ...are for real...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...that they can make something happen, and even they don't know what that is till they get in there and play a little... they can make something happen that you can't even imagine... and it's not your fault, this stupidity... 'cause you're just this scared little prick who gets to say he's making movies, and the only thing they ever taught you is that what you like doesn't matter.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE D PERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The anger leaves Matt. He is depleted.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for understanding.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cathy rises and begins to exit.</context>
      <utterance>But isn't it almost good manners for you to feel a little shame?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She exits. The D Person's Colleagues have taken advantage of the beat to egg him on.</context>
      <utterance>If you didn't, you sure should have.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE D PERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You talk about manners--are you actually so bitter you don't realize how you acted just now? You're gone, pal. But at least know that we can't help that we're making it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, shit. You win. You got lucky with 'bitter.' That word just scares me to death.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look down.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. I appreciate the support.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not down for you. I'm down about myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. What if 'Ground Zero' doesn't do well this weekend?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods, but she pauses, disconcerted.</context>
      <utterance>Please listen to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just got this feeling of seeing myself talking to you and how this is the most important moment of... ever.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Good. What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been watching this company make movies that cost tens of millions of dollars and all the while I've known about this wonderful script which we can somehow own and we could make for about $14,000,000... $3,000,000 if you can live without stars or a name director.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that it? Okay, send me...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've sent you coverage on it nine times. I swear to you, Burke, it will work. You've never heard me say that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about last night?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know anything about action- adventure!!  I have no idea where that came from. Hey, I know everyone thinks I don't have any commercial sense because of what I said at the 'Gremlins' preview and all... And you think I can't put myself on the line. Well, if this picture doesn't work, fire me. Have me killed if it doesn't get good reviews. If this doesn't get a 70 percent definite recommend from women 49 and under, I promise to be your sex slave until they drop ticket prices back to five bucks and start enforcing the R rating.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're selling very excellent. Very excellent presentation.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got to do this. I think this movie can save me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, please... What's the script?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Mr. Deeds Goes to Town.'</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why couldn't you even look at the way I dressed Ricky?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I don't want to talk about it. I just had a real rough day... so just let it sit there, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what was it? Tellll me... Compromise... You sad?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.  Now, I really need to be quiet.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't even remember the words... I am stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you're not. You're not stupid and I'm not bitter... and you know why? Because there's no cure for either one and we've got to believe in some cure for each of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am stupid. I can't even remember the words to some baby song.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jeannie... I just can't do this now. The phone rings... As he goes to answer it...</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She decides, with some difficulty, to let him continue.</context>
      <utterance>Jeannie, please... be quiet for one second... this is very important for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeannie mouths the words, "Who is it?" Matt holds up a finger asking her to wait.</context>
      <utterance>So? Wow. Good for you. Congratulations.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me? This is great. I'll come right over and pick up the script. Okay. If you want to. Bring it over. Goodbye.  We might make it yet, kid.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MATT'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cathy?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the b.g. WE HEAR Jeannie loudly imploring her father to make the person wait till she's finished dressing. There is the SOUND OF the buzzer. Cathy hurls herself at the door a good four times before finally timing it right and gathering the necessary strength to spill through.</context>
      <utterance>I'll buzz you in. You've got to be quick and push hard.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>JEANNIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But why can't I stay just a little while?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cathy knocks. Matt opens the door.</context>
      <utterance>Because this is a very special friend of Daddy's and I need privacy... Be fair... I let you wear that dress.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps aside so Cathy may enter... The place is tidied up. He has changed his clothes and Jeannie is wearing a lace dress, fit for a young princess, complete with flowered tiara and ballet slippers, with trailing blue ribbons at the heels and a velvet cape.</context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is my daughter, Queen Elizabeth. Jeannie, this is Cathy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi... What a pretty dress.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. That's nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you going to a party?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I going to a party, Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember our compromise? You're going next door to Lucy's to play and you'll show the kids your dress and I'll come get you later and we'll go out someplace and I'll buy you anything you want for under seventeen dollars?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts for the door, doubles back, and kisses a surprised Cathy full on the lips... The gesture is beautifully, even movingly carried off. It is totally false.</context>
      <utterance>I remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodbye. I love you...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeannie is on the run... as she passes her father.</context>
      <utterance>Well,... thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeannie nods acknowledgment as she flies past.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a little winner, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh...?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is my favorite project. And it looks like we're going ahead with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Mr. Deeds Goes to Town?' Oh, it's a remake...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, come on, what's original? And this is a wonderful rewrite. It's funnier.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And there's a part in it for...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... Burke says I can test whoever I want. He wasn't even surprised when I mentioned you. So, if you could read this rewrite now and if you like it, we can make a test deal...  they can make a test deal... we can tell them that they can make a test deal.  I think it's important for me to steer clear of the business end.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay... which part?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Longfellow Deeds.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Deeds?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt takes this in... takes this miracle in.</context>
      <utterance>Who goes to town, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are we kidding? I'm even having trouble getting short parts--I'm going to say I love it no matter what you've done to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop being so creepy honest. I really have an instinct about you for this. I'm going home--call me when you finish reading it.  Or... come on over.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nan hauls herself into view, climbing back onto the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Why not? If you can test movies and premises and want-to-sees, why can't you test screen tests?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't deal with your self-centered dribble right now. I have just had the biggest orgasm of my life and I'm trying to figure out if I'm in love with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She closes her eyes in a characteristic and touching gesture, as the scientist in her struggles to be precise.</context>
      <utterance>Whoops. Tell me what made you rush over and pick me up and bring me here at six o'clock. I mean we seem to have...</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...this unspoken agreement not to talk about why we're together when we're together and I don't think it's good to let that become a pattern for us. She focuses again on Burke. Prepared for, at last, some verbal intimacy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did I rush to you? Because I felt like I had to... be with someone and you were closest.  What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not at all aware that you've just said something...  ...unattractive?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I'm sorry if that came out...</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not looking for an apology.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just trying to say that one of the things I'm not great at is...</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's not make this about your shortcomings. I'm sure you've had enough of those conversations to last you a lifetime. What I'm...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I haven't.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you haven't what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Had a conversation about shortcomings...</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No woman has ever told you that you have an almost barbaric insensitivity? That you seem to have lapsed into some final cynicism, where you actually believe that, not only does everyone think the way you do, but only you have the courage to express it? That you seem horribly certain everyone else is sort of pretending when they talk about love or seem to care for anything outside their own anus? No one's ever said that sort of thing to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah... But I didn't get what you meant by 'shortcomings.' Hey, if you think things like that, what are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm here for the same reason 86 percent of older women loved 'Beauty and the Beast.' I would like to believe that underneath the creature, there is a sweet, caring guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nan breaks up, shaking her head ruefully.</context>
      <utterance>I sure hope you're wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burke, not having intended humor, is also lighthearted, having somehow avoided a tight spot.</context>
      <utterance>I have to pick up Leslie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles broadly; hurriedly putting on something quick and loose to match her buzz. As she walks to him, the phone rings. She ignores it.</context>
      <utterance>I mistimed it.  I wanted you to catch me fully frontal.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you loved it. A lot? A little?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sits on the sofa--looking at him.</context>
      <utterance>Give me a second--all of a sudden, there's a lot to deal with.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's terrific.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you see why I think you're right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because you're nice and you know I need work.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know this is really happening, so I wish you wouldn't kid around about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cathy peeks down her bathrobe. Then broadly.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, but I think the audition rule is that I have to be serious unless the person in charge is wearing a bathrobe and her nipples are sticking out...  ...this much.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are some mixed signals coming out of here, aren't there?  Hi. Working... I can't write down a number now. Call me back.  The script?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's really good. I get a little nervous thinking about the opportunity.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to hear everything. You want to go page by page?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it's okay. I kind of work on these things in a private... it's just... it's a little better for me if I don't...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, let's do it. It won't kill me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An uncertain beat and then she leans over and kisses him. A sound escapes him. They get up and begin walking to the bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>Please. I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I swear to God, I don't know which thing I want more, the sex or the conversation afterwards.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean I haven't been to bed with anyone since Jeannie got here... I haven't talked to anyone the way I need to.  I haven't seen anything this beautiful. I haven't felt this good about life. I mean, I've been lonely, Cathy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She twists her body gracefully, sexily towards the phone.</context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you the truth, Matt. I've never felt more like turning my phone off.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't shut the phone off. I left this number with Jeannie's sitter.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand what you're worried about.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not worried. But if the phone was off, I would worry.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I get a lot of calls.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could put the machine on 'monitor,' but it's going to be... I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It will be okay. I think the most important thing is to stop talking about the phone. Turn it off, monitor, whatever.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She twists toward the phone again--not quite so beautifully.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look so serious.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am so serious.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>YOUNGER MALE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The love making continues as the calls continue.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Cathy... All my magazines came today... Read the new Vanity Fair, they take apart three people we hate... Spy is bad this month... Scorsese didn't get the Time cover, the plane crash did... ha, ha, ha... Why aren't you at the office? You know, I'm getting to the point where I prefer to reach people's machines... Bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE D PERSON VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cathy, in the throes of sexual union, feeling a bit divided by the offer on the phone... she shakes it off.</context>
      <utterance>Cathy? Are you there? Hello... Are you there?? I'm going to count to ten. One, two, three...  Did you go to the screening last night? What did you think? That makes two bombs in a row for her.  ...four, five, six... Pick up if you're there. I've got major gossip... major screwup. It could be good for us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this the kind of crap you listen to all day?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, we're making love here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sound of a hang up... the couple having more difficulty making love...</context>
      <utterance>If the TV show bombs, there's going to be a dance party on my grave. I don't give a crap. Nothing seems to have a point anymore. I'm really questioning everything... including action-adventure... Don't tell anyone I'm down. Even destroy the message tape. Don't tell anyone I said to destroy the message tape. Don't even give hints that there's something you can't tell them, but you wish you could... I'm losing it. I'm losing it. I'm losing it. Don't tell nobody. Don't tell nobody. Don't tell nobody.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JEANNIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Daddy...  You dialed bad... Where is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sound of a hangup... As Matt springs from the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Matt, Jeannie is very upset because you are not here when you said. And now the big hand is on the eight...</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there a name for what we just had?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is awkward, my driving you around and testing for you tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not really.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burke reluctantly considers, then:</context>
      <utterance>Well, I hope you understand I can't drive you to work tomorrow and then go in and test. It's just...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. I was going to come in late anyway. I'll get one of the kids to drive me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burke laughs--surprised at being genuinely amused.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks. And, look, if I get the lead in this movie, you'll have to go back to sitting up front with me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeannie's fine. There's a whole bunch of kids in the building. She's fascinated. And they're all ready for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many men are they testing today?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt is surprised... But he is a pro and so immediately makes use of this sudden blip in status.</context>
      <utterance>You're the only one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then tell them I need a little more time.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAKE-UP PERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's okay, we're done.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean for me. I want to focus a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then they're gone. With that bit of advice, Matt is totally fucked up. A beat after Cathy leaves:</context>
      <utterance>Sure.  Good luck, Matt.  The thing they're looking for most is sexy.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAIR PERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know who she was involved with for a minute or so?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAKE-UP PERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On their look...</context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get out of my way!</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't say it like that!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All this noticed by a casting person with a clipboard.</context>
      <utterance>Which way should I?  Get out of my way.  Get out of my way.  Get out of my way.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASTING PERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It felt great... Everybody...</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me tell him, let me tell him, let me tell him...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let him finish! God!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to tell him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeannie turns down her volume, but keeps repeating--incanting actually... "I can't wait to tell him... I can't wait to tell him... I can't wait to tell him..."</context>
      <utterance>If you wait one minute, I'll let you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyway, the girl I did it with, by the way, she's really good; the director, the crew... they all thought we nailed it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cathy nods and Jeannie begins to push Matt into Cathy's office for privacy.</context>
      <utterance>Now?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait till you hear this one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The words coming so fast that Jeannie lets loose with a bolt of SONG, as if taking a moment to catch her breath. Just a few sung lines proclaiming happiness.</context>
      <utterance>Some lady asked me to go in a room and, you know, make believe and say stuff like we were playing a game...</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the SUNG PHRASE.</context>
      <utterance>And everybody went 'yea' and they said they wanted me to be on television.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sung phrase again.</context>
      <utterance>And give me money and have a teacher there and a person to braid my hair and color my face and give me clothes...</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wait here, Jeannie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't!</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What in hell is wrong with you? You actually think...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm trying to hang in here but everything in me cuts off when somebody acts this way.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...that you can have my kid audition for a show without asking me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt takes this in. Just a millimeter underneath his fury is professional curiosity.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't... She went for water and by the time she got back, they had offered her the part. Blame Burke, he was there...</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the part, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The white kid in a multi-racial foster home with all these kids of varying ages. It's not a bad show. I sure can't wait to see the test.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How were they able to test her so fast?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. They offered it to her off the reading. I meant your test.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cathy has nothing to offer. Matt begins leading her back. We HOLD ON THEIR BACKS and see the chink in Matt's confidence, hear the tightness in his voice as he asks:</context>
      <utterance>Oh... A child actor. Just what any kid with problems needs to straighten out--a series of her own...</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll let me know as soon as they see my test?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hold hands.</context>
      <utterance>Right away... You've got my vote.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm doing it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes this shot hard, but tries to pretend otherwise, continuing to stare hard at her script to avoid him.</context>
      <utterance>Not if I don't let you. That's the law, the police law.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I have to learn to read to be on television?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going to have to learn to look at me and listen to me and the longer I have to wait THE ANGRIER</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so mad.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me too. Just listen.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't... why?!?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I know about this. I have worked with kid actors... They don't have that much fun. They're inside all day... they don't get to go to regular schools or play with their regular friends like Ricky and Essa.  And their parents? You think I'm going to be one of those parents, sitting in one of those rooms, where we all go crazy trying to jump start our egos with our kids' sweat, all the time smiling at each other like our lives are working while we root against everyone else's little girl?  No!! No way! I can't!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She throws the script down. Tears in her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. So, no, you're cuckoo anyway. I won't do it. And I don't care because I'm be stupid at it anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's so down, she complies--picking it up and walking it to the trash can. Matt stops her and takes the script.</context>
      <utterance>Pick it up, Jeannie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's work on it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She ignores him, continuing to watch the screen. He leans into her.</context>
      <utterance>So how do you think 'Ground Zero' will do tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you think my movie will do tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cathy turns in her chair and mouths "thank you" to Nan.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not going to talk to you during Matt's screentest.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How bad can it be? We've got to have at least a two million dollar Friday. There's nothing else out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm watching...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BURKE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The COLOR BAR GRAPH does a quick slide and disappears from the screen leaving the actors' faces green.</context>
      <utterance>Stop playing with that thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACTRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Deeds, tell me about the meeting.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>ACTRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about my crying. As a matter of fact, crying turns me on.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is laughter in the room. The actress smiles through her tears--pats Matt for being wonderful.</context>
      <utterance>Well, in that case, your dog died.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACTRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened at the meeting?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't remember. You're too pretty.  Oh, I told them I'd keep on being Chairman.  I'm Chairman, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACTRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Told them I'd keep on being Chairman if they hired everybody back.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACTRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did they say?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses him. We HEAR the director say, "Cut. Terrific, guys." The girl and Matt hug, no longer in character, as others come in to congratulate them.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, that I was crazy. You always wear your hair back like that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, come on... let's have our creative meeting right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE D PERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'd sure go to bed with her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very fuckable.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE CASTING PERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd sure fuck her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay... that's her... What about him?</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE D PERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think he's a very good to excellent actor--I do...  But there's something...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wouldn't want to fuck him?</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE D PERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, six years ago, maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think he's talented and attractive.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you'd want to fuck him?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He might be light in that area.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The man is talented. If you get one of those directors who like actors, I think...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A director can't make you hot if you're not hot. You'll end up with warm which is death.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We laughed.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me ask you something... Would you fuck him?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything doesn't boil down to...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burke rises and addresses his staff... the camera has his back in the foreground as it MOVES TOWARDS A RENDEZVOUS, Burke moving too as he continues...</context>
      <utterance>Let me stop you before you embarrass yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We all can do our little lectures on what things boil down to. Everybody else here was professional enough to come out and say... I'd fuck her... I wouldn't fuck him... and you're ducking it... I want you to forget the acting stuff and totally focus on the issue. And now Burke and CAMERA meet up--the effect being that he is talking directly to us as he continues.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We do have some kind of responsibility to the audience... You just saw his screentest... so, if this is the first time you saw the guy, do you come out thinking to yourself and your girl friends, 'I'd sure go to bed with him; oh God, would he be something.' Would you, Cathy?... I'm being real here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They file out. Cathy gets up several beats later than the others... and follows them out, avoiding Nan's look.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, so let's keep looking.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She listens, waiting for him to quiet Jeannie.</context>
      <utterance>Hello. Matt... Hi... Okay, sure...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Matt...  Matt... Matt... Maybe it would be easier if I just said 'hi' to her... Hi, Jeannie... Yes, it's exciting... No, no. He's right, honey, they get somebody to read it to you. Now, put your dad on--it's important. No, first put your dad on... DAMN IT!  ...Matt. Uh-huh, a few hours ago... They all... everyone liked your work, but I think they'll go for a name or something. She listens to him. He is hurt. Cathy, though, is also wrestling with her own internal struggles. She has betrayed him and is ashamed; in a strange way--terrified. She is, therefore, just a little irritable.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not a matter of doing it differently... they liked what you did, a lot... they laughed and... it's not you... it's them.  No, please. Don't thank me. If you feel like getting together later or anytime, call me, okay? You sound like you have your hands full right now... Goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanted to talk to her again...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt opens the door quickly.</context>
      <utterance>Dad? Daddy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks across the room, Jeannie tracking him.</context>
      <utterance>Everything's okay... I'm sorry I forgot to put you back on with Cathy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt sits down, still suffering a bit of dysfunction, unable to keep up appearances other than a few minor half-hearted tweaks at his daughter who stands solemn and silent at his side. She pets him some... this goes on for several beats as the STRAINS OF "YOU COULD BE WONDERFUL" accompany the moment. Then:</context>
      <utterance>You didn't cried because of that... I don't even want to talk to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With some effort, Matt lifts his head and nods permission.</context>
      <utterance>Dad. Can I say just one thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt nods, rises and leads her into the small kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>You've got to make me supper.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He braces himself... there is a tone, then:</context>
      <utterance>You have reached the Warner's Hotline. Estimated Box Office Grosses for Friday, December 3rd, Weekend Number 49, are as follows in millions of dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHONE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MUSIC IN... At first from the speaker phone... Burke moving in time to "THERE IS A LONELY..." And now singing... As the lyric concludes and the instrumental comes in.</context>
      <utterance>Due to the high volume of calls, we must ask you to wait till a line is clear...</utterance>
   <speaker>PHONE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Best Girl,' 1,820 theaters, six- point-four million, up 24 percent.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cappuccino movies.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHONE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...and now his film, "Ground Zero," is coming up to bat... as succor to the gods, he tries to make his dance gleeful in anticipation.</context>
      <utterance>Opening this weekend, 'Double Dare Two,' 1,870 theaters, fourteen-point- three million.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to pieces...  The picture was budgeted at 21 million and I spent 49 so they were a little mad at me to begin with. Now it doesn't open even with an Arby's Roast Beef tie-in... I mean, we only averaged 300 dollars a theater... they're going to think I'm Woody Allen.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think you have to worry about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now we HEAR Nan's voice on the speakerphone which Burke has been addressing all along.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks. But this is private. What about the exit survey? Did we do good with any group at all?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't hear you, but--hi, Matt-- that was funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She laughs delightedly. Burke leans across Matt's lap to get closer to the microphone.</context>
      <utterance>'I don't think you have to worry about that?'</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did we do well with any group at all?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sits stupified.</context>
      <utterance>Eleven-year-old boys in the South.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Burke? Burke? Matt, is he...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll see you later. Goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hits the "end" button. He slumps for a second, then:</context>
      <utterance>But, hon...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm all alone...  At least there's that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you going to need me? The kids are rehearsing and I'd like to take a look.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, sure. I have to stay inside during lunch hours now anyway--that's when everybody returns my calls because they're trying to miss me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that true?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Thanks for the support.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bet I know what it looks like to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Despite herself, she smiles at the reference, though her tone is a bit sarcastic.</context>
      <utterance>A giant "find Waldo."</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>PASSING VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five minutes, children, then we need you for work on the set.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Set?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That pretend living room, right over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Set. Bye...</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a second, Jeannie. Let Daddy give you a few tips here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt reacts.</context>
      <utterance>Is this the set?</utterance>
   <speaker>PASSING VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeannie is watching.</context>
      <utterance>Parents to Room Two, please.  Parents to Room Two, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>PASSING VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt looks him off fiercely. The Passing Voice addresses the friendlier parents.</context>
      <utterance>We have to clear the set.</utterance>
   <speaker>PASSING VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This way, parents.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm glad I found you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>OTHER AREA - BEHIND GRANDSTAND SEATS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As they walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You holding up? What did you do last night after I called?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think I did? I cried like a baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Okay. So you don't want to tell me. Be a tough guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel relieved just seeing you after all that stuff... whew... Okay.  Burke wants to...</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cathy is as simple and direct as she is embarrassed.</context>
      <utterance>You ever go out with him?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You slept with him?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you hate it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eventually.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good Lord.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her. She kisses back. Then there is an extraordinarily loud and piercing voice.</context>
      <utterance>This is the thing that makes me nervous about you... You keep on assuming I'm nicer than I am.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's such trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's very worried about being able to pretend cry when she has to and she doesn't get it about memorizing. That's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Director beckons Matt to lead her away. He does.</context>
      <utterance>That's all?!?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't going to be good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She seems stung by this, unusually vulnerable. He changes tactics, softening.</context>
      <utterance>Not with that attitude.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just that they... Well, did they tell you what an audience is?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know what an audience is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grasps at this unlikely straw.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Now, because there's an audience, they want you to know all the words you have to say really well. And since you can't read yet...  ...you're going to have to be patient and try hard. I can help you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you help me to cry?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeannie pauses half a beat, then:</context>
      <utterance>Yes.  I can. I can help make it okay. Trust me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I miss my mother bigger than you know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeannie grabs the phone in a flash.</context>
      <utterance>Not yet. Don't grab.  Thank you. We really appreciate this. Hi, Beth. I...</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad says he's going to make me to really cry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeannie shushes him, resisting with surprising will and strength when he tries to get the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Jeannie, your mom's not going to understand what you mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hangs up. Matt pissed.</context>
      <utterance>She understands!!!  He's being terrible right now.  I love, loved, the coloring book you sent me. Goodbye. Wait. I love you. Let me hang up first. Love you. Send me a letter. Bye. And a beaded T- shirt. Bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you let me be on your side for a second?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't even understand what you're saying now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know what trust means?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not very.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It means that even if something is hard to believe, you believe someone you trust because you know he wouldn't say it unless it were true.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand. So I don't trust anybody, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I think you get the concept.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't make sense. I don't understand you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeannie reacts broadly... indicating what a difficult man she's stuck with.</context>
      <utterance>I think you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just know that...</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okayyyy!</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes quickly to the phone and picks it up.</context>
      <utterance>You want to help me make a phone call?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seven... two...</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are we calling?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cathy. She's very nice. One... six...</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Very nice..." One...</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi...  What now?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT'S VOICE IN BACKGROUND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell her, 'How are you' and then let me...</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeannie... I can't talk now because...</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, my dad wants to...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell him I can't talk 'cause I'm on the phone with a director...</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wants to talk to you very much and...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She does.</context>
      <utterance>I can't. I have to hang up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to understand that sometimes people are too busy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So she's too busy for you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We look like jerks eating here this early. Everybody's going to think we couldn't get a reservation for the hot hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you do this to yourself? Why do you insist on eating dinner in a restaurant where you're bound to see all the people you're afraid of?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not afraid of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you call it when you think that what a group of people think of you can confirm or destroy any decent idea you have of yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Normal.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did little Jeannie do today?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't it something that they have you testing the TV show?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I asked was, how did Jeannie do?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody else. Jeannie. How did she do?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't talk to me like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to be treated as if I'm really saying words to you which you engage and respond to. I like Matt; I'd like to know how his daughter did. So before you take your dance of desperation across the restaurant and I end up feeling so sorry for you that I could die, I would like you to answer my question.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She did okay... and don't worry about Matt... If the pilot sells, his kid will be making five thousand a week. So what do you know about 'People Get Hurt?'</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm told that they're not going to release it...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew. I knew. What the hell are you smiling for?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forgive me. But telling you about this latest failure of yours--it pleases me. I have no idea why.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't be with someone who's not rooting for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I am. It's just that rooting for you is a good deal more complicated than you realize.  Don't go.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MUSIC IN as Burke leaves the table. This "Dance of Desperation" is classical. Burke himself lifting one of the women in greeting, then, as he puts her down.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. I'm not that mad. I gotta do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he continues to go from table to table.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry. I thought you were someone else.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he mumbles)</context>
      <utterance>Nan, you know Victor and his wife...  and Jay and his wife...</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all nod and ad-lib agreements with her premise to Burke's amazement.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. I'm sorry I can't talk now. I'm very upset about what's happening to Burke, so I just made up my mind I can't be witness to it anymore if I love him and I certainly shouldn't be here if I don't... so I was just in the process of leaving when he stopped me and you folks walked in... I'm sure you've had something like this happen to you some time... some horrible thing in your personal life happening in public.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUPLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burke accepts the compliments as if meant for him.</context>
      <utterance>Wasn't that spectacular? I've never seen anybody that secure...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Thank you. We're very close.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She begins to cry. Ordinarily this would be a scene which would be unendurable for Burke. However, the lesson of a moment ago is not lost on him. As people get out of cars and witness the sobbing Nan.</context>
      <utterance>You don't understand that I'm exhausted from hurting. I'm through with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The reaction to his openness is disdain and passing contempt. She drives off, leaving Burke hurt and alone. "Poor Bastards" up and out.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, we're working our shit out... I'm sure it happened to you... you know, private stuff in public.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt laughs. Jeannie looks at him shyly... he looks at her with encouragement. Suddenly she is in his arms, hugging him hard, an emotional dam seems to have broken.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know if I've been bad. I know somebody's been bad.  ...maybe it's you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt holds on--clearly, deeply moved. Then he exercises the effort to control his emotions and speaks, surprisingly, as a Black woman.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I love you so much, I love you so much... I love you so much.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope that makes you feel a whole lot better, Chile... 'Cause it sure goes a long way to cure what ails me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe I...</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...got in this much...</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...got in this much trouble. .</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Over a...</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Word?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. 'I can't believe I got in this much trouble over a word.' Now do you know what she means when she says that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to talk about it--just say her stuff so I know mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts to flail a bit.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's your choice... But I'm not helping unless you try to understand as well as memorize. It will be fun. Come on. I know it's hard...</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Okay...</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything to shut me up, huh? Okay, this little girl you're pretending to be... she can't be with her Mommy either, just like you, or her father... she has to stay in Rainbow House which is called that because...  Jeannie...  ...because everyone's a different color... so when this little girl calls the black lady who takes care of all the children this terrible word... it's like the worst thing anybody can do... Come here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to do the 'I love you' again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is unable to resist muttering one sarcastic shot.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I might have been working you too hard on that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Why don't you do that with poopie Cathy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, did the director tell you how he wanted you to do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said to smile all the time almost and to talk... uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Faster?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. We don't always get good directors, so it's important for us...</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me. You're not in the show.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeannie doesn't know quite how to take the name calling. MUSIC IN... we're heading for a rendezvous with a dance as it CONTINUES ACROSS THE CUT TO:</context>
      <utterance>I'm referring to the family of actors, you little shithead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is so good...</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a breakfast burrito. It's what actors eat when they're working.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, let's work a little more. The most important acting you do is when you listen. You're worried about being able to cry when you're supposed to, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. So much.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, there are really only two ways to do it. Think of something that makes you really sad... or forget you're you and really forget you're pretending...</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt reads from script.</context>
      <utterance>How do I do that one?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Don't test me, child! I could eat you for lunch when I was your age and I'm a hell of a lot bigger now!' Jeannie looks afraid.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it... You just looked at me and acted right without even thinking. And there are games you can play to help you with this. Get up...  Now, be my mirror... do exactly what I do... that's it... now, at a certain point, I'm going to become your mirror, but I'm not going to tell you when... you tell me...</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt nods.</context>
      <utterance>Now?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. We're going to make up words. The words aren't what matter now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm on a roof...</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a great dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This acting exercise of Chicago's Story Theater leads into the song, "BE MY MIRROR." As the song finishes, Matt and Jeannie are in the best spirits we've seen as an A.D. approaches.</context>
      <utterance>You're a...</utterance>
   <speaker>A.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They need you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes the A.D.'s hand as Matt calls.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're welcome. Don't mention it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a free man. Let's go to your house and break the answering machine.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Millie, having been at the screen test viewing, is taken aback, looking from one to the other. Cathy knows what she's thinking and is unnerved, feeling silently accused, as she leads Matt out.</context>
      <utterance>You know, I could get away now. But I've got a big meeting later. We'd better take two cars.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See you later. Thanks again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope it's you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY'S VOICE ON SPEAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt waves...</context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So this is how the big ones make out.</utterance>
   <speaker>FULL SHOT - THE TWO CARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Almost bumper to bumper... snuggling.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGLE - CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She takes a breath and then plunges.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>CATHY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up the phone. We intercut between the cars.</context>
      <utterance>Matt, will you take me off the speaker?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know whether I'm being a coward for telling you this way or brave for telling you period... Can you hear me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I better talk fast because this is where my phone always kicks out... When we did your screentest... Can you hear me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pauses, silence, then:</context>
      <utterance>Well, I sort of folded on you at the end.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Matt?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't like what I did?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did. Truly. But the discussion got sort of dumb. It was a question of sexiness.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what it came down to?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, sort of, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You folded on whether or not I'm sexy. You don't think I'm sexy... and you expressed that to...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'll tell you. I certainly must think so pretty much because I feel great about where we're going now...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you very mad at me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt manages to pull to the side... the other cars gobbling the places behind Cathy, who sees this... and now she watches Matt's car recede from her view.</context>
      <utterance>No. You were just... Aw, damn it, I am. Very. Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT'S POV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cathy going out of sight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FIRST VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He switches channels.</context>
      <utterance>...number seven at the box office this week-end is...</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE NUMBER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He switches channels.</context>
      <utterance>...the two words are Tom Cruise.</utterance>
   <speaker>THIRD VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns off the TV and crosses to the phone, allowing us to read the back of his bathrobe "ROCKY BALBOA."</context>
      <utterance>...becoming the first lawyer to be awarded his own star on Hollywood Boule...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Nan. I hope it's not too late to call.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like another chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You only think you feel that way because you're on the verge of failure and you're without a core...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See. Nobody else gets me.  You wanna have a little sex, honey?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know I've never hung up on anybody in my life... because what if the next thing they said solved everything... but I must end this conversation. Nan hangs up. Burke picks up a pocket electronic notepad from the bedstand and hits the scroll button.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSERT ELECTRONIC NOTEBOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Names and phone numbers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Matt, this is Burke. I'm sorry to bother you at home, but you know Nan... We were going out a little and I could use another guy's slant on what's just happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think I can get into this...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? Did I catch you at a bad time?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Worse. You caught me at a bad time you caused.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you mean about the screentest. The whole room thought you did good work.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, look, I'm not going to bother you about my thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Okay, good night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>A.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is appreciative laughter from everyone save Matt, who rises in disgust and crosses out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>...and when you're in the audience, make sure you laugh and applaud even when it's somebody else's kid...</utterance>
   <speaker>A.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt ignores him and exits.</context>
      <utterance>You're not allowed near the stage. We only have a few minutes...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns--sees her father and gives a small, cursory nod... He moves quickly, drawing even with her but still giving her a bit of space and a low-key pep talk.</context>
      <utterance>Jeannie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just remember. You're not even here tonight. There's only this other little girl that you're pretending to be who lives at Rainbow House.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt breaks up. Even Jeannie smiles briefly, then she takes him aside for privacy.</context>
      <utterance>...and who just vomited.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just found out that we bow before we even do anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And everybody claps.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I made up a great bow. You going to look?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't miss it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not going to be able to cry. It's too hard for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This does not satisfy her. She rolls her eyes as she is pulled away towards the front of the stage. Matt watches as the 10- year-old veteran actor leads his little daughter towards her debut.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, then they'll just give you more chances after everyone leaves.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and she beckons him towards her. With some hesitance, he joins her.</context>
      <utterance>Matt. Matt. Matt.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to miss her introduction.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll talk fast. It's amazing news. Oliver Stone's been looking for a comedy and...</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got to see my kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...he's doing my picture.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts off.</context>
      <utterance>Hey. Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt is terminally disappointed in her last cynical sentence.</context>
      <utterance>Part of this involves you. He remembers you from 'Platoon' and wants to use you in this one.  Got your attention, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the stage, we HEAR the VOICE of the WARM-UP MAN.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Cathy. Look, I'm going to watch this. Let me talk to you later or tomorrow. Thanks for your help. It's good news. Gotta go.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARM-UP MAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is applause. Matt's missed her intro.</context>
      <utterance>First, in her first appearance ever, Jeannie Hobbs...</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why couldn't you wait till later? Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess it's because I'm just incredibly insensitive to all human needs. I'd ask you to save me, but I'm so far gone, I wouldn't want you to waste your time.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reacts, but he walks off, not wanting to get into it. Cathy, however, has had a tricky nerve struck. She continues, biting off each word.</context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I don't have a kid or a mate or a talent.  I got this.  And shoot me if I think it's important.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I'm a superficial jerk.  You can't be right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you're the best of the bunch.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now she raises her eyes--big, blue and vulnerable. If this look were returned, "I love yous" could flow--they could sink to the floor in a joint epiphany; but there is no romance or kindling in Matt's eyes. He is in a hurry. Pridefully, Cathy turns and walks off in the opposite direction, her flight so instinctive, she forgets her book bag. We hold on this--her exit, then:</context>
      <utterance>Oh, great.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Matt doesn't hear him... a few feet away, Jeannie is making ready for her big moment. Three cameras swing in front of them, TV monitors showing a MASTER and CLOSE-UPS of the three characters in the scene: a short comic WHITE MAN, the Black Female Lead, and Jeannie, dressed as a poor child.</context>
      <utterance>What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait. This is it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The White Man jumps on the phrase.</context>
      <utterance>It's like everyone is pi... ticked off at me because I'm not colored.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHORT WHITE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The word is black.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK LEAD ACTRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A burst of laughter, whooping and applause from the audience. Burke brags in a whisper to Matt.</context>
      <utterance>The word is African American.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had them bring in two busloads of people from black churches.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGLE - STAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As they play out the scene.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK LEAD ACTRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you use it in a sentence.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at me, I...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BLACK LEAD ACTRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead. Use it in a sentence.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at me. I love an African American.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK LEAD ACTRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Black Lead Actress holds out her arms to Jeannie, who, tears streaming down her face, runs towards the arms...</context>
      <utterance>Look at me. I love a little redneck.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You little stinker!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You big stinker.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My little stinker.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The background to this intimacy is enormously alive. The Lead Actress and the Character Actor laughing out loud. In the b.g., we see the audience filling out preview cards as the FLOOR MANAGER leans in to say:</context>
      <utterance>My big stinker.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOOR MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay, Jeannie. Take a minute. We just need to get that hug at the end.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amazing, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOOR MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were great.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. That's nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt starts to walk her back to the set.</context>
      <utterance>I loved it, Daddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her answer surprises him.</context>
      <utterance>You want me to put you down?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. This is okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts her down. She turns from him to go back to work but, on impulse, he restrains her. He is kneeling down, holding her lightly by the arms, her back to him as he states an ultimate truth:</context>
      <utterance>Okay... Now, you're not finished until you hug the lady just like you did me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeannie, shocked by her father's unprecedented sentiment, turns to face him and clamp a hand over his mouth so he will add no more lush and primal affection. Having silenced him though, she finds that she has something of her own to say. She'd never tell it to her father, but she can't resist telling it to her acting coach.</context>
      <utterance>I'm very proud of you. I love you more than anybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I had to cry, I thought of you buried in the ground.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She does.</context>
      <utterance>Give me a kiss.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BLACK LEAD ACTRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have any idea how special you were?  That looks like a 'yes.' You've got to get dressed for the party.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's more?  What will I wear?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK LEAD ACTRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go to wardrobe; they'll give you anything you want.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It didn't sell.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This show didn't sell?!? How do you know so fast?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeannie exits the make-up room aglow. She is wearing an incredibly stylish outfit and her hair is in an expertly done intricate braid.</context>
      <utterance>It's the first time they had me do cards for a pilot and the demographics are all wrong for after nine o'clock. That's their only opening.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. I'm Nan. I'm a good friend of your Dad's.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Nan. I'm Jeannie. Did you see it?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, and you were wonderful.  89 percent likeability.  And knowing that you were that good means so much more than the show not going.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, no.  I couldn't help it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does she mean?  What do you mean?  What does she mean?  What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That they're not going to be doing any more of these shows right now-- but...</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, my God.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey...</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that means they're not going to have a party?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. They're still having the party.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>To which Matt answers:</context>
      <utterance>Oh... really?... good... can we stay late?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey, we're going to close the place.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I cast him so he has to dance with me, but I'm sure he'd prefer dancing with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on. You know how?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They begin to dance with the others. MUSIC SLOWS IN TEMPO as we indicate TIME PASSAGE and:</context>
      <utterance>Yesssssss.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not comfortable with television anyway... it's too small... I'm much better at something with size... I don't do itzy. Even this movie of Cathy's--it's small... medium small. But with Stone it takes on a certain volume where I start to feel comfortable.  I hate my life...  ...in a way. I had a drink in my office. I'm confused. You're not saying anything. Is it because you're not listening or because I haven't stopped talking?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This Oliver Stone thing... does he really want me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Oh, yeah. I forgot to say congratu...</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which part?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which one you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One of the two leads wouldn't be bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. It's the crippled factory owner.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets off the ledge and starts to move away... Burke moves quickly to cut him off.</context>
      <utterance>Best part in the movie.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a second.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to see my kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A second--look, they're taking the cast picture now anyway.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She doesn't look anything like the women I usually go with. And you know what they say, "beauty fades." What they don't say is that it fades very slowly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't think I can tell you what to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Only I can do that. I want you to tell me what to feel...  Look. I trust her. More important, everyone does. You have no idea how impressed people are with her. She's smart. She's interesting. You never know what she'll say next... Her work is amazing. I like talking to her. You have no idea what to expect next. I respect what she does more than any writer or director--sincerely-- much more unusual--much more important. So?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks away. Burke waves a grateful goodbye and looks around the room until he sees:</context>
      <utterance>Good luck.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dance with me.  On a business basis.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.  But I'll dance with you because I think it will reassure me that I should have nothing to do with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they dance.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you breathing so heavy?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nervous... Look, let's move our thing in a more regular direction.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Several more beats of dancing--as he awaits her answer.</context>
      <utterance>Let me think.  What if we go out this weekend...  ...with your kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...whose name is?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whose name is...  Leslie.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SONG BACK--"WOW"... sung as a chorus... a slower cadence for the romance as we... CHANGE MUSIC and they dance more closely. The song slows for time passage and MUSIC CHANGES to "BE MY MIRROR" as we...</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last ones here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes her hand and starts to lead her towards the stair shed--then:</context>
      <utterance>Well, I told you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks up, smiling pridefully, to see her father smiling back pridefully.</context>
      <utterance>I never got to see your bow.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She bows. It is a bow all her own.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, all right.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
