<movie id="291" title="I Still Know What You Did Last Summer">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julie swallows hard. This is difficult for her. JULIE (cont'd) I've never told anyone this. Not my mom, not the poice, not even my friends -- except for the ones who were there and they...well they're not around anymore. You see I...I...</context>
      <utterance>Bless me, Father, for I have sinned.  It's been a year since my last confession...</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She balks at the memory of it. The priest bows his head in the shadows of the other side. JULIE (cont'd) (emotional) You've got to understand...It was all an accident. A terrible accident. It's been a whole year. I've tried to get past this, but I just can't.</context>
      <utterance>I killed a man. Well, I thought I had...then...</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go on...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have these dreams...horrible dreams. And this man is always there with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The confession is cathartic for Julie. She looks relieved until,</context>
      <utterance>You see, he was a killer. He murdered Helen and Barry, and he would have killed me too, if I hadn't...gotten away with it.  I don't know, I guess I just need to deal with the fear, the guilt...to finally say his name. Ben Willis. His name was Ben Willis...</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julie stops. Looks through the screen. A chill shoots through her body.</context>
      <utterance>I know...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clouds of icy steam shoot through the partition. Julie moves closer to the screen, trying to get a better look.</context>
      <utterance>You know? But how could you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PROFESSOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice to see you find Political Science so stimulating -- The lecture hall erupts with laughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry -- Julie grabs her stuff and bolts.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Julie! Wait! You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julie realizes this is true.</context>
      <utterance>You don't seem fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will takes this seriously.</context>
      <utterance>I had another dream, Will.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The shower again?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I mean, I could feel his breath on me.</context>
      <utterance>It was in a church...it was so real.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought I was over the dreams for good. I really did. I hadn't had one for months.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It just takes time, Julie. It's gonna get better.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BLAM! BLAM! BLAM! EXPLOSIONS. Julie jumps out of her skin. It's just STUDENTS letting off FIRECRACKERS as they fly past on bicycles. Will and Julie are now thinking the same thing.</context>
      <utterance>It can't get worse. I mean, it's not like this was the first time I freaked out in class. I hardly ever get a full night's sleep, my grades suck, I'm this close from being thrown out of school.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was one year ago...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's...the anniversary. That's what's going on...Take it easy on yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm trying. I really am...Sometimes I don't even know why I came up here in the first place.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To get out of Southport?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles at her. She smiles back. They stop in front of her apartment building. JULIE (cont'd) Are you getting out of town on the fourth?</context>
      <utterance>Right. Now I remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah. I'll probably just be here studying for finals. The joys of summer school...  Are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She touches his face affectionately.</context>
      <utterance>Are you sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will stands there akwardly --</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the talk, Will. You're good to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will walks away. Julie watches him a beat, then turns down her walk --</context>
      <utterance>Um...Okay. Bye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Recovering, she hugs Ray, genuinely glad to see him. He's a bit cold.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, my god, Ray. You scared me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got in early. I was excited...  Who was that guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You'd like him.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, that's Will. He's a friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ray, we're just friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every guy in history who tried to pick up a girl did the good-friend thing first.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It should be obvious Ray feels insecure in the college environs, but they're miscommunicating.</context>
      <utterance>Why are you being like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at Ray, his compassionate demeanor. This is hard to say --</context>
      <utterance>Hey, I'm sorry. You're right. Are you ready to go? I've got the old truck. You know the drill...Crab boil at Ollie's. Croaker Queen Pageant...It's only small-town fun, but it's still nice. People really miss you. I miss you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ray, I can't...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray is cold. This is what he's expected all along.</context>
      <utterance>I just feel like some part of me hasn't healed up enough to go back. Like some critical piece is missing. Please understand...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand something.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And...there's a million things to do.</context>
      <utterance>It's not like that. It's not you. It's me. My head. I want to go back. I want to be with you. I want to be fine. I want everything to be like it used to be.  It just isn't. Ray is hurt and confused. JULIE  Hey, why don't you stay up here? They have fireworks over the river.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to work, Julie. My boat's in Southport, remember? But, I get it. You need your space from Craokerland. And maybe from me, too. Ray starts walking away. RAY  You know where to find me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray keeps on walking.</context>
      <utterance>Ray? Ray? At least come up for a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julie follows him out to the road. A group of LAUGHING STUDENTS block her way.</context>
      <utterance>It's okay. I'm just gonna go.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Ray is already gone. Julie stares after him a beat, then turns quickly to her door. She clearly feels uncomfortable, exposed on the walk alone. She nervously pulls her keys. A can of mace dangles from the keychain.</context>
      <utterance>Ray, I'm sorry. I didn't mean...  I'm just scared...that's all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you were out of town!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hug, jumping up and down with relief.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing in my closet?</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you were out of town!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing in my closet?</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julie turns on the light in the hallway. Karla has her shoes in her hand and black pants draped over her arm.</context>
      <utterance>i just wanted your black pants, but I'm not ready to die for them!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was heart attack time, Karla.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karla looks down and sees the knife. She picks it up with two fingers -- KARLA (cont'd) And we're going to put away the utensils and you're coming with me. Julie flops down on her bed.</context>
      <utterance>No. When I put these skinny pants on my body...Now, that's heart attack time.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not going anywhere. I'm fat, ugly, and depressed.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, right -- whatever.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I just really hurt Ray's feelings.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karla picks up the flashlight and goes into the closet.</context>
      <utterance>Listen to me, Julie. Ray's a great guy, nothing against old Ray, but he's so...Ray. I mean, he lives in Southport. Will's a nice guy, too, and he lives right down the street.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's nothing between Will and me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>She emerges with clothes for Julie. Holds up one outfit. KARLA (cont'd) What we gotta do is keep moving. No time to mope. I'm working at the club tonight. And you, dancing queen, are coming with me.</context>
      <utterance>Yet. Nothing yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karla holds up another dress for Julie -- strapless, sexy, the one.</context>
      <utterance>No I'm not.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karla is dancing around. Julie laughs at her friend and takes the dress when Karla hands it to her.</context>
      <utterance>Fine, then be fat, ugly, and depressed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what I want to do to you ...right now, don't you? There's gotta be somewhere we can be alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so. It's pretty crowded.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's looking for a dark corner or a storeroom or something.</context>
      <utterance>Just for a minute, baby. I got something I wanna tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you can say all you gotta say in a minute then I don't wanna hear it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll talk real slow. He's kissing her ear. She starts to giggle. The bartender sets down drinks on Karla's tray.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karla cuts away through the crowd, delivering drinks. Tyrell turns to Julie.</context>
      <utterance>Ask her to dance. Tyrell hesitates. KARLA  Go on.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the most beautiful woman in the bar tonight, Jules.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tyrell, you are an unstoppable force of nature.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karla passes by --</context>
      <utterance>That's right. It's how the species survives. You'll never convince me otherwise.  Wanna dance?</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No means yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tyrell, I appreciate it, but have you seen my people dance? We make the mouth face, we move the fingers --</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Worse comes to worse, you can stand there and watch me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, I'll take a break and we'll all dance.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Karla! Did you tell him I'd be here?</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nope. I told him that you absolutely, positively would not be here at this bar between ten o'clock and eleven o'clock tonight. And then he came anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This was not my idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will looks down at his feet. He and Julie stand there not quite knowing what to do.</context>
      <utterance>I said, this...Do you want a drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyrell and Karla go for it on the dance floor, leaving Will and Julie alone. They look at each other. They look at everyone dancing.</context>
      <utterance>Where I come from, you want to snatch the goodies, you got to at least talk to them first.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will is a few steps ahead as they move for the bar. Julie seems to be relaxing, having a good time. Then, she looks up into the balcony and sees, in a strobe light's FLASH --</context>
      <utterance>How about a drink?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The stranger turns around. It's only a club kid in a tacky vinyl raincoat and hat. She's shaken.</context>
      <utterance>Ben...</utterance>
   <speaker>SLICKER GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julie turns away and hurries down the hallway. Todd follows, but his figure quickly fades.</context>
      <utterance>Hye, baby. You following me up here?  Well, all right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That could break the machine.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Julie, people who end up making rules like that end up beating their kids with wire hangers. It's a fact. The phone RINGS. Karla looks at her watch. KARLA  It's Tyrell.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The number's unlisted...</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you relax? We've been dating three months. He ain't stalking your butt.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay. You're right.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A DJ for a local radio station BOOMS from the phone.</context>
      <utterance>I know it, and it feels good.  Hi, Ty.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Julie watches her friend get excited.</context>
      <utterance>This is Mark in the Morning for Magic 96.7 Radio Station! Who am I speaking with?</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark in the Morning! Magic 96.7! Oh my God! I'm Karla. Karla Wilson.  Jules, it's Mark in the Morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Karla, what're you doin' at home over the long fourth weekend?</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm in school and --</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd you like to win a Magic 96.7 Quicky Getaway?</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julie hits the SPEAKERPHONE BUTTON and Karla hangs up. The DJ's voice echos through the appartment.</context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Karla's smile abruptly fades.</context>
      <utterance>Good, then I hope you remember your geography, Karla, because all you have to do to win is tell me the capital of Brazil.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks to Julie, whose face is as blank as hers. KARLA (cont'd) You don't know?! You have to know. You know everything...</context>
      <utterance>Brazil? Um...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Karla, one easy question, one great getaway!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...South America...Carnival...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Karla, we need an answer. No looking it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still here...thinking...  You mean Brazil, the country?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Julie has an idea. She scramles for the kitchen. Grabs a BAG OF FRESH- GROUND COFFEE from the FREEZER. MARK (cont'd, V.O.) Three...Two... Julie tosses the bag across the room to Karla. Karla reads the label:</context>
      <utterance>Okay, Karla, five seconds.  Five...Four...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rio de Janeiro!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, no...Did you say Rio?</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BELLS and WHISTLES and triumphant MUSIC.</context>
      <utterance>No. Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Karla and Julie jump up and down ecstatically.</context>
      <utterance>You just won Magic 96.7's Quickie Getaway...a trip for four to Tower Bay Island in the fabulous Bahamas.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Waaaaahhhhhhhhhh!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll call you back with all the details...So what's your favorite radio station?</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA AND JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julie hangs up and joins Karla dancing on the couch.</context>
      <utterance>Magic 96.7!</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julie thinks, she seems torn.</context>
      <utterance>I won. I won...I won, I won, I won.  Now, let's see...There's Tyrell, that's one. And, there's my parents ...And I got some cousins.  Okay, Julie, you can come, but Mark said four tickets. That means you gotta get yourself a date.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. Ray is happy to hear her voice, but cautious.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm sorry.</context>
      <utterance>Hey. I'm really glad you called...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you don't have to be sorry. I'm the one --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I was just...</context>
      <utterance>No, I shouldn't have left so fast...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dave holds up two wriggling snappers. He dances them toward each other in a puppetlike mating ritual, making KISSING SOUNDS and narrating --</context>
      <utterance>It's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray waves him away, concentrating on his call.</context>
      <utterance>Julie, I love you. I know I'm only a humble fish, but if you really look at it, you're a fish, too.  Oh, Ray, you're right...Do me like a snapper.  Hey, something smells like fish...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ray, Karla won a trip to the Bahamas! An island called Tower Bay. And she wants us to come with her.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dave's interest is piqued.</context>
      <utterance>What? The Bahamas? You're kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'd have a long weekend just to sit in the sun, drink fruity drinks, and swim, and...  You know...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dave is watching Ray closely. Ray's expression hardens.</context>
      <utterance>This weekend?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll go away with you're college friends, but you won't go away with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karla is watching Julie.</context>
      <utterance>Idiot. Idiot. Idiot.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karla is watching Julie.</context>
      <utterance>It's not you, it's Southport. And it's the Bahamas! And it's free!</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta sell his butt on the Bahamas?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray thinks. Dave looks at him like he's crazy.</context>
      <utterance>Ray, come on. I want us to be together.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Julie, we're working a big run up here. It's been crazy. We probably have to go out again tonight. I don't think I can do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dave moves one of the fish like it's been shot through the heart.</context>
      <utterance>Will you try...for me, please?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, I'll try. But, listen...  If I don't make it up, then you go ahead and have a great time.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hangs up and Karla sits next to her.</context>
      <utterance>Ray...please try. I really miss you.  Okay. Bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That boy has got fish on the brain.  Hey, cheer up, Charlie.  We're going to the Bahamas. Bahama Mama, yeah...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray realizes how right he is.</context>
      <utterance>Man, what is your problem? We haven't caught anything for days. Pull the big ugly stick out of your butt. She asked you to go to the Bahamas! Man, you gotta go. We'll both drive up. I got friends I can see up there.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stupid. Stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray looks at Dave a contemplative beat, then walks over to his truck. He leans in the passenger side and pulls out the engagement ring box. Dave walks over.</context>
      <utterance>Stupid. What were you thinkng?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up the box and slowly opens it. Dave is stunned.</context>
      <utterance>You wanna see what I've been thinking?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeez, Ray, fourth and forty, throw the bomb.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should go up there. I should call her back, tell her I'm coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray is excited by the plan and Dave's right there with him.</context>
      <utterance>No way, man. Surprise her. She'll be psyched.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He adjusts the dial again, tuning in a country song, "MAMAS, DON'T LET YOUR BABIES GROW UP TO BE COWBOYS," by Waylon Jennings and Willie Nelson. Dave starts singing along, extra LOUD and out of tune. DAVE (cont'd) (singing) "...Mamas, don't let your babies grow up to be cowboys, don't let 'em pick guitars and drive them old trucks. Let 'em be doctors and lawyers and such." Ray looks at his goofy friend singing and starts to get a little happy himself... Then, Ray sees something in the road ahead. He turns down the radio. They both stare --</context>
      <utterance>Man, I love AM radio. You got right-wing conspiracy, tips for pregnant womem, Single-A baseball games, and real country music... None of that new crap...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY'S POV: A CAR TURNED SIDEWAYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray slows and creeps past the car. The driver's door is open. It appears EMPTY.</context>
      <utterance>its HAZARDS blinking.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, man. Maybe we should keep going, find a phone --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray has seen this before --</context>
      <utterance>The guy looks dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He throws open his door.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe not.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>12C	EXT. MEDIAN - NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ray nears the body. He kneels down.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray reaches toward the body...</context>
      <utterance>Hey, can you hear me?</utterance>
   <speaker>12D	INT. RAY'S PICKUP - NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something FLASHES IN THE SIDE-VIEW MIRROR.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julie turns.</context>
      <utterance>Girl, it's gettin' down to the wire.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not coming. I thought he was just...</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Four.</context>
      <utterance>Julie, you left four messages...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, he said he'd try.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Try is nothing!</context>
      <utterance>He said he'd try. Try is like maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He does work hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Work hard, huh? He's breaking your heart just because he can.  And I don't want to have to say I told you so...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A Jeep Cherokee stops, and an ebullient Tyrell steps out wearing shorts and a Hawaiian shirt.</context>
      <utterance>Then, don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The passenger door opens and Will Benson steps hesitantly around the Jeep.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, baby, we gonna get tropical or we gonna get tropical?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh!</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will reads Julie's expression.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, sorry...  He's my friend, too. And that ticket is not going to waste.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Julie, is everything cool? Karla said...</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julie takes a last look up the street. She stands.</context>
      <utterance>I said we start having fun. And that means now.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there a problem here?</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where there's a Will, there's a way. Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will is relieved.</context>
      <utterance>You know what? This rocks. We're going to the Bahamas!</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She bops over to Tyrell.</context>
      <utterance>We goin' Bahamas, I'm Ty's Bahama Mama. We goin' Bahamas...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just take deep breaths and think of something happy from childhood.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if I don't have anything happy from childhood...Sorry, I can't relax going five hundred miles an hour, or four thousand, four hundred feet a minute...  Which is over seven hundred feet a second. Imagine hitting something at seven hundred feet a second.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Deep breaths --</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fumes build up in the fuel tanks. You can by surface-to-air missiles over the internet. Planes use O-rings...which freeze in tap water. Planes fall from the sky for practically no reason at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got a better chance of getting hit by lightning.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyrell shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Right. Planes get hit by lightning. They get hit by meteors. They hit other planes.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something is gonna hit your butt if you don't quit complaining.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will doesn't move, frozen with fear of flying, but more closely bonded with the concerned Julie.</context>
      <utterance>Honey, some folks just can't fly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the King of the World.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They switch places. They look at each other and crack up laughing. Karla takes in the surroundings, the salt spray, the day --</context>
      <utterance>No, I'm the King of the World.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remind me to study real hard so someday this is normal and all that back there is somethin' I do for a weekend once every ten years.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They throws their arms around each other and stare into the horizon.</context>
      <utterance>I will, and you remind me of the same thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyrell is trying to keep from puking --</context>
      <utterance>You just gotta breathe.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't talk right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PAULSEN, the BOAT CAPTAIN, overhears as he passes --</context>
      <utterance>See, it's not a macho thing. It's about equilibrium in your inner ear. You could've used a patch, but it's too late now. Get used to it.  Some folks just can't sail.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julie and Karla have rejoined the men.</context>
      <utterance>That's too bad, too, because it's the only way on or off the island.  Unless you have an accident. And then they call the Coast Guard.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's pretty remote here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep. That's what the tourists pay for -- sun, sea, and solitude.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we there yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We move off the boat and REVEAL the island. The intrepid vacationers excitedly take in the island.</context>
      <utterance>Few more minutes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A dockhand, DERRICK, glides past him toward the ladies.</context>
      <utterance>I feel like I'm still on that thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That way for a complimentary Planter's Punch to get you readjusted.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Derrick reaches for Julie's hand, clearly checking her out in the process.</context>
      <utterance>I can get used to this.</utterance>
   <speaker>DERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julie smiles politely. Will gently nudges her on. They walk away.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome, Fair Princess, to Tower Bay.  I'm Derrick. At your service for the duration of your stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm at your service, Princess.</utterance>
   <speaker>DERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Season's over old man. So I gotta work fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs a SIGN at the end of the gangplank. It reads: LAST DEPARTING</context>
      <utterance>If Marine Radio's right about the weather, you're already out of time.</utterance>
   <speaker>FERRY -- LINE FORMS HERE.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our guys are already at the end of the dock.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Check it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOW BIKINI GIRLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>catch the eyes of Tyrell and Will.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karla THWACKS him on the back of the head, but they're all having fun. The path widens. The trees part. It's even nicer up close. They walk across a tiled plaza. Behind them, THREE YOUNG GUYS carry their GIRLFRIENDS piggyback, racing each other toward the departure dock. Our two arriving couples move on toward the entrace, passing a FENCED TENNIS COURT on the left. A GLASS-PANED ORCHID HOUSE straight ahead. And, on the right, A LUSH POOL with a built-in JACUZZI in the shallow end. An outdoor THATCHED ROOF BAR stands nearby -- and just beyonk it, a small POOL</context>
      <utterance>Yes, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOUSE.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A guy's unintelligible RASTA VOICE calls out --</utterance>
   <speaker>RASTA VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They turn to see TITUS, white guy, dreads, full-Rasta demeanor. He's a phony, but sincere about it. Titus approaches Tyrell --</context>
      <utterance>Anybudorsomethin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>TITUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My brother, can I interest you in the islands finest ganja?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Tyrell, we found you brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>TITUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who be wantin' the kind, the uber- sticky, the Bwana, The depth-charge, the Up-All-Night-Laughing-With-Your- Friends? Who wants it? 'Cause Titus got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>TITUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will and Tyrell walk on. Undetered, Titus goes up to Karla and Julie. TITUS (cont'd) How 'bout you, ladies? Lovely ladies. Titus moves his hips. TITUS (cont'd) (lascivious) Something I can do for you? Karla looks him up and down, wrinkles her nose --</context>
      <utterance>Come on, man. Everybody wants something.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take a bath, maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>TITUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's cold, but if that's how you want it. The group moves on. Titus watches them go -- TITUS   Anybudorsomethin' you come and see me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello? Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is everyone? I'll ask -- Julie turns to consult the maid.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can I do for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will saunters away to look at the books in the lobby.</context>
      <utterance>Checking in...Karla Wilson.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He scans a sheet as Tyrell stares at the pit bull.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, yes. Roll out the red carpet. Our contest winners are here at last.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not really. I've found peices of guys like you in his stool. Tyrell is put off by this aggressive comment.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your problem, buddy?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have a problem in the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It sure is a beautiful old hotel.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Built in 1948 for a member of the Rockefeller clan. The tile work was imported from Spain. A lot of history in these walls...Judy Garland stayed here...Hemmingway fished for marlin right off that dock --</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, we get it...It's old.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Creepy thing to say. Slides a registration form. BROOKS (cont'd) Wilson comma Karla... (sees something on the form) Oh --</context>
      <utterance>It'll outlive you, I'm sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brooks covers --</context>
      <utterance>Oh, what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're in 201 and 202.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honeymoon suites. I take it you kids haven't exchanged vows, yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We haven't exchanged anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Julie, we're talkin' suites!  That'll be just fine with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And, while you're here, our marginally trained, off-season staff of five will attend to your every need.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait...Did you say off-season?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>July fourth weekend. Storm season starts today. The clouds roll in like clockwork.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Storm season?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Brooks turns away through the office door. They walk toward their rooms. Will catches up with them.</context>
      <utterance>It's our version of winter.  201 and 202. There's Scrabble and Parcheesi in the lobby. Enjoy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>24	INT. HOTEL HALLWAY - DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They walk down the hallway. Karla seems annoyed.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't nothin' free in this world. Everybody says it, and it's true.  I wanted you all to have a good trip.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We will, baby...All this means is we got the whole island to ourselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And it's been blue skies all day. It might be perfect all weekend.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It beets being on the mainland.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oooh, the mainland --</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A BRASS LUGGAGE CART has appeared behind them. And ESTES, 60s, the weary Haitian porter, steps from behind it.</context>
      <utterance>Somebody's gone tropical on us, baby. Tropical! The mood is improving. A SQUEEKING NOISE interupts.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>201 and 202...Who put you in...?  Don't use these much --</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sees their happy, expectant faces and changes the subject.</context>
      <utterance>Why's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No real reason.  Pretty fancy rooms for kids your age.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We won a competition.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah? What you have to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guess the capital of Brazil --</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rio, baby!</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat as Julie and Karla exchange a look. Then, Karla tosses one of the keys to Julie.</context>
      <utterance>Ahh, good for you, girl.  ...And, where would you like me to put the bags?</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Their stuff in there...  ...and ours in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Karla! You promised.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I also promised Tyrell.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyrell makes fake goo-goo eyes at Will. Estes looks away. TYRELL (cont'd) Sweetie, you brought your nightie, didn't you?</context>
      <utterance>Promised me what, baby?  I made all my promises to William.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Tyrell grabs Karla and drags her into the room. We here GIGGLES.</context>
      <utterance>Forward! A girl needs time to make up his mind.  Julie, look, if it's cool, I'll sleep on the couch and they can have their own room to practice for that real honeymoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take those.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Estes grabs the bags and takes them into the room. Julie and Will are left staring at each other.</context>
      <utterance>No, I've been doing this since before you were a dream in your father's eye.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure it's okay with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. It's fine. As long as you don't snore.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She laughs and they go into the room.</context>
      <utterance>You can toss a shoe at me if it gets out of hand.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>25A	INT. HOSPITAL ROOM - NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We see a COP next to the doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's beaten up pretty bad --</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the cop stares at him deadpan, the doctor realizes how rediculous this must sound.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, but he seemed certain his friend was killed out on the highway by somebody named Ben Willis.  He said he has a hook on his hand. He said he was driving a BMW.</utterance>
   <speaker>25B	INT. HOSPITAL ROOM - NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>CLOSE UP: Ray's eyes pop open. He's listening.</utterance>
   <speaker>26	INT. HOSPITAL ROOM - NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The cop explains things to the doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk back down the ICU.</context>
      <utterance>There's no body. And there was no other vehical involved.  He fell asleep at the wheel...and ran his old truck into a guardrail. He got thrown way the hell down into a ditch. He's damn lucky.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He suffered a severe head trauma --</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The doctor and cop approach the nurse's station. The NURSE is reading a magazine. She folds it away. Suddenly, the monitoring equpment goes OFF with a series of LOUD</context>
      <utterance>Probably once he rests up, it'll all come back to him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys lost?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me this ain't the bar scene.</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wanna drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We didn't get all dressed up for nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Planter's Punch, Singapore Sling, or how about a Mai-Tai?</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They nod.</context>
      <utterance>How about some ID? They freeze. NANCY  Kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The guy at the desk said the place would be quiet, not dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't anyone tell you this is --</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The last day of the season. Yeah, we heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So why are you still here?</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyrell sizes her up quickly.</context>
      <utterance>That's none of your business.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter, boy trouble?</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He leave you?</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will and Tyrell exchange a danger-Will-Robinson glance. NANCY (cont'd) What you want is a Dark and Stormy: Vernon's rum, ginger beer, and a touch of Tabasco. Sailors drink it for luck in the hurricane season, trust me.</context>
      <utterance>No. I shot him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I bad? I mean, he's really great, and he's cute --</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's cute...And he's got a crush on you...  But...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karla looks at her. She's sincere, but firm.</context>
      <utterance>I miss Ray...I tried to call him.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joining the men, but continuing her thought -- KARLA (cont'd) For the next foury-eight hours... (joking) Your smile is a frown...turned upside down. She illustrates with her own big smile.</context>
      <utterance>Ray made up his own mind...so, you're free to make up yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretty cool bar.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nancy reaches out a hand and they touch just the tips of their fingers.</context>
      <utterance>They all start to look the same once you've worked in one.  Am I right, sister?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Julie. This is Karla.</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nancy continues making their cocktails.</context>
      <utterance>Nancy.  Welcome to Tower Bay's most happenin' hotspot.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all pick up their drinks.</context>
      <utterance>Four Dark and Stormies...</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To a great weekend --</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, a great weekend. Forget the weather!</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA &amp; JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They drink and toast again.</context>
      <utterance>I'll drink to that!</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nancy looks straight at Will --</context>
      <utterance>So what do you do around here for fun?</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She flips a switch that lights the Karaoke stage.</context>
      <utterance>Make fun of tourists mainly.  Or let them make fun of themselves...</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Karaoke -- perfect.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't even think about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's already heading for the stage.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, I won't.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go baby! Go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, this ain't for me, baby, this is for somebody who really needs it.  Ah-hah! One single with extra cheese!</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone thinks their a singer.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not me...no way...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, it'll be fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But there will be no mercy.</context>
      <utterance>Ladies and gentlemen, please put your hands together for my friend, my very best friend, Julie James.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA, TYRELL, &amp; WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reluctantly she goes to the song book. She sees something particularily awful.</context>
      <utterance>Ju-lie! Ju-lie! Ju-lie!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyrell nods and punches a few buttons. Julie takes the stage as sappy strings begin to swell. She looks at the MONITOR, then melodramatically at the crowd, and begins to sing -- no, BELT -- Gloria Gaynor's "I WILL SURVIVE." JULIE (cont'd) (singing) First I was afraid...I was petrified... (continues singing under) Will stands, clapping. Tyrell pounds his chest. Karla flips up her LIGHTER, swaying like a hard-core fan. And Julie continues, crooning out the chorus as the beat kicks in and the gang begins to dance. JULIE (cont'd) (singing) I will survive...I will survive...</context>
      <utterance>You asked for it.  Song number thirty-nine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CLOSE - JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>trembling, shaking, a mess. Will jumps onstage.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Julie? What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's...him.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, Julie?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julie loos at the screen -- the normal lyrics are still scrolling. She suddenly feels their eyes upon her. They're looking at her like she's having a nervous breakdown. JULIE (cont'd) Nothing. Nothing, I'm sorry... Stung, she rushes off the stage.</context>
      <utterance>He did something to the screen...it, it, said...</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But it's to late. She's bolted from the bar.</context>
      <utterance>Julie...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Will! I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grabs a TOWEL off the bathroom door, trying to help him clean up the mess.</context>
      <utterance>It's my fault. I shouldn't have...I didn't think...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, no. This was really sweet...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I scared you -- I crossed the line --</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- it's not that. It's...I'm just a little on edge. I'm really sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, you don't have to appologize to me. I'm the one. I understand.  I'm going to take a walk and dry off.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up a rose. Most of its petals on the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Are you sure? I really appreciate it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands the rose to her. There's a moment between them. He reluctantly heads for the door.</context>
      <utterance>I just really like you and I want you to feel good about everything...You know? I want you to be happy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>28A	EXT. HOTEL HALLWAY - NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will looks down at his wet pants.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Passing Karla and Tyrell's room on his way down the hall, Will spots the DO NOT DISTURB SIGN. He hears an INCREDIBLE POUNDING from inside. He shakes his head and mopes down the hall.</context>
      <utterance>Dork.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tha's it.  I've decided.  I'm changing my major to finance.  And going to Wall Street.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She falls back against the plush comforter, looking up at herself in a long MIRROR HANGING RIGHT OVER THE BED. Tyrell loves this and quickly moves beside her in the bed. She lets him get real close, then she jumps up -- KARLA (cont'd) Jacuzzi. Tyrell reaches for her, but she bounces off the bed.</context>
      <utterance>'Cause that's the only way I'm ever gonna be able to afford a big bed like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karla pulls her suit out of a bag and models it seductively and flirtatiously for Tyrell.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, baby, let's stay right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyrell gets off the bed --</context>
      <utterance>I spent a hundred bucks on it...even if it's just so you can pull it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like the sound of this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>TITUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>standing there smoking a spliff.</utterance>
   <speaker>DERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get lost, you scared me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TITUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fish are all over the water...Come on, let us take a boat out.</utterance>
   <speaker>DERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Titus, you're so stoned, you'd end up in Spain.</utterance>
   <speaker>TITUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Derrick throws the hose in its place.</context>
      <utterance>That's why you'll come with Titus, mon.</utterance>
   <speaker>DERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a storm comin', Titus. No boats are going out.</utterance>
   <speaker>TITUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Derrick is now ignoring Titus.</context>
      <utterance>Storm is what makes it interesting. Thass why all the fish are up. Less hook us a couple big ones.</utterance>
   <speaker>DERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got work to do. Take the bake elsewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>TITUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Titus glides away into the dark. Derrick watches him go. There's another SPLASH in the water near the dock. Derrick walks to where the splash was. He kneels down by the edge -- watching BUBBLES RISE from the dark water below.</context>
      <utterance>Up-tighteous and self-righteous.</utterance>
   <speaker>DERRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, little sea bass. You're lucky I'm busy or I'd hook you myself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure you didn't pick up my hair tie?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, I just didn't wanna get my hair wet.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She splashes him.</context>
      <utterance>Baby, I finally got you alone in this Jacuzzi and I don't wanna be discussin' hair care.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyrell moves in for the kill. He won't take no for an answer.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you get feisty...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes in for a serious kiss. Things start to heat up --</context>
      <utterance>Too late for that. We're miles from anywhere, baby. No one's gonna hear you scream.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I used to be a lifeguard...I'd hate to have to blow my whistle.</utterance>
   <speaker>TITUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karla SCREAMS. And not just because it was a surprise. Titus looks even uglier when he's wet. Titus opens his mouth, reveals a smoking PHILLY BLUNT on the end of his tounge.</context>
      <utterance>surface in the pool next to them.</utterance>
   <speaker>TITUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Titus eyes Karla in the Jacuzzi. Tyrell moves protectively in front of her.</context>
      <utterance>No water sports after midnight. Hotel policy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the policy on burnin' herb?</utterance>
   <speaker>TITUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Titus blows a cloud of smoke on them both, rolls the joint back into his mouth, and swims off. Tyrell is angry, but Karla pulls him back. A dejected Will appears in his bathing suit, a towel over his arm. Tyrell sees him coming.</context>
      <utterance>We got one for that, too. It's don't try until you buy.  You don't buy any, you don't get any.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's ten people on this whole island and they're all gonna end up in this Jacuzzi with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's the water?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crowded.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will slips into the water ignoring Tyrell's look.</context>
      <utterance>Ty!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahh, that feels great.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's Julie?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alone. In the room.  Got any advise?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karla shoots Tyrell a look.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Find another Jacuzzi.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your not out yet, slugger. You gotta just get back up there and keep swingin'.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will cathes her in his arms and she sobs uncontrollably.</context>
      <utterance>It's happening again! There's a body!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Where?</context>
      <utterance>What? What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They can see she's not fooling around.</context>
      <utterance>It's in my room!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="30">
   <speaker>BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julie steps in -- stares into the empty closet. She can't believe her eyes. She searches their faces, looking for someone to believe her.</context>
      <utterance>I don't find this at all funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was a body! I swear it!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Julie, you said you were tired. Waybe you were dreaming.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wasn't dreaming.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julie grabs Brooks by his robe.</context>
      <utterance>I knew you people were goining to be trouble. I knew from the first time I laid eyes on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to me. He's here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She doesn't know where to start. Nancy pokes her head around the door.</context>
      <utterance>Who? Who is here?</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Julie thinks there's a dead guy in the closet.</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The rest of us see bathrobes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am not crazy, Tyrell. He was right there.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will wanders over to the closet and checks it out.</context>
      <utterance>Fine. Show me the body.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think about this, Julie. What did you actually see?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The dockhand guy. Hanging by his neck from up there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the morning we'll talk to Derrick, the "dockhand guy," and put the whole thing to rest.  Now, let's slow down on the Dark and Stormies and get some sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't look at me --</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want off this island.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not possible, I'm afraid. The last ferry left hours ago. And we got a storm coming. There won't be another one for days.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a storm coming?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Tis the season, like I told you. It's a big one. Julie goes for the phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I'll call the mainland for a charter.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She picks up the phone, listens, then dangles it from her hand.</context>
      <utterance>Phones went down a few minutes ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An exasperated Brooks heads for the door.</context>
      <utterance>It's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Duh. The next couple of days is gonna be rough, but we'll make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about a radio?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. Emergencies only.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell would you call this?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Brooks is gone. Outside the window, it starts to rain. There's a CLAP of thunder.</context>
      <utterance>I'd call this four spoiled city kids who wouldn't know a hurricane if it blew up their butts.  All we can do now is batten down and ride it out. If things get really bad, there's a storm shelter.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>looks out the window with glazed-over eyes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeez, that's a full carat --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, there's some flaws in her...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mac looks around his shop at the usual jumble of crap: vacuum cleaners, golf clubs, guitar amps...</context>
      <utterance>How much?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't really have the market for something like this...  I can go two...two-fifty.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make it three hundred. And throw that in, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>REVEAL - .38 REVOLVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>encased in a glass cabinet.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell, that's worth three, easy. And you got your waiting period.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mac barely hasitates, he knows he's getting a steal --</context>
      <utterance>I'm not waiting...So give me the gun and keep the ring.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine, buddy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karla kisses Tyrell on the cheek.</context>
      <utterance>This ain't the romantic weekend I had in mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You get any sleep at all?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyrell glares at Julie by the window. Sees the incredible rain.</context>
      <utterance>Some.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, look. Another day in paradise with Julie-your-tour-director...Miss Psychotic Episode.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey --</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julie ignores him, staring out the window.</context>
      <utterance>See any dead bodies out there? Any fresh kill? How 'bout Freddy, Jason?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angry at her boyfriend, Karla gets out of bed and joins Julie.</context>
      <utterance>Leave her alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just saying what all of you are thinking. It's bad enough gettin' rained out without having to hold her hand the whole time.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karla pulls Julie close in a show of support for her friend whose mind everyone believes has been inventing dead bodies.</context>
      <utterance>You don't have to be a jerk.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay...He doesn't believe me. That's his right. I'm starting to think I'm crazy, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julie doesn't look to enthusiastic.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, slow down, turn off the little motor up in there...What do you say we go to the gym and work off a little stress?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice move.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julie smiles at her friend bravado. She steps over to a stairmaster and starts her workout.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be givin' your fisherman some of that and see how he likes it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is everybody?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk down the steps to the lobby.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>43	INT. HOTEL LOBBY - DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They cross the lobby.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyrell's already out the front entrance.</context>
      <utterance>Hello?  There's nobody here, Tyrell.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're around...They just don't care about us 'cause we're the contest winners.  Let's go find Stoner Boy...Make his lazy butt hook us up with fishing poles or Ping-Pong paddles or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, the greenhouse effect has caused the gulf stream to shift and almost every meteorological expert expects a dramatic increase in tropical depression --</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyrell keeps walking. Will looks around at the wind-and-water-swept vista. Not much of a day for activities.</context>
      <utterance>Hey -- shut up, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyrell moves across the grounds. He looks back. Will is stopped in his tracks, looking up at --</context>
      <utterance>I don't like to fish.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will trots after him, but he takes a glance back at the window...Estes is gone.</context>
      <utterance>You coming?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karla leads Julie over to the tanning beds.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Vampira. I got just the thing for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cancer in a box.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, this is the safe sun.  It's better than a day at the beach. Julie is reluctant. KARLA  Come on, a little photosynthesis and you'll feel like a new --</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karla opens the canopy of the tanning bed.</context>
      <utterance>Houseplant.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julie peels off her sweats. Lies down in her underwear. Straps on a small pair of GOGGLES. Karla lowers the canopy over Julie.</context>
      <utterance>Exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Karla!</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULTRA-VIOLET TUBES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>come to life -- Julie is bathed in purple light.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take this.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyrell breaks another bottle in half.</context>
      <utterance>And do what with it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They move toward the nearby POOL HOUSE.</context>
      <utterance>Julienne of pool boy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>54	EXT. HOTEL POOL HOUSE - DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The two of them collapse, COUGHING and CHOKING.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will splashes a puddle of rainwater on his face --</context>
      <utterance>What the -- ?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyrell rolls over on his back next to Will, practically coughing up a lung.</context>
      <utterance>That's chlorine and muriatic acid. Put the two together and you get cyanide.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, they both hear KARLA SCREAMING. They sprint for the main building.</context>
      <utterance>Cyanide? Like poison gas?  You mean, somebody really killed him...Omigod. Think...Think...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will struggles to open the bed, but the chain holds strong. Tyrell grabs a nearby dumbbell.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, God, get me out. Get me out.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hang on...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not crazy...I'm not crazy. He's here...  We've got to get to the radio and call for help.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They head for the manager's office.</context>
      <utterance>I think we can classify this as an emergency situation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody...is a sick, fingerpainting psycho.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE POWER CUTS OUT and the hotel plunges into darkness. Julie SCREAMS and runs from the hotel.</context>
      <utterance>We gotta get out of here. Now.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Julie!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyrell picks up the end of a cut mooring line --</context>
      <utterance>There were boats here? Refresh my memory, there were boats...</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were cut loose.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at Julie. Their escape is cut off by water. They're scared.</context>
      <utterance>Julie? Wanna tell us what is going on here?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're all going to die. He's going to kill us one by one.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben Willis.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, stop it! He's dead. You killed him. Now, get over it. We gotta think here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her voice is low and urgent, an impromptu confessional. JULIE (cont'd) Two summers ago. We lied to the authorities. We hit Ben Willis with our car. Ray, me, Barry, and Helen ...We threw the body in the water to cover it up --</context>
      <utterance>They never found the body.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Julie...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyrell begins backing away from Julie. He picks up a piece of driftwood from the dock. JULIE (cont'd) I thought Ray and I killed him on the boat, but we didn't and now he's back to finish up the job. Tyrell holds up the log as a weapon. He's angry and afraid --</context>
      <utterance>Only he wasn't dead. He killed Barry and Helen last July Fourth.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're on an island, miles from anywhere. I don't give a crap about you're fisherman. There's dead bodies pilling up everywhere and there's one guy missing -- Will moves closer to Tyrell --</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The porter...what's his name? Old Asbestos --</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyrell turns and heads down the dock. Will goes with him. Karla takes a few hesitant steps after them, then turns back toward Julie, who hasn't moved.</context>
      <utterance>Estes! That's exactly who it is. That old guy knows something. We can sit here and wait for him to pick us off or we can go find him first.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julie sees her friend caught in the middle, sees her suffering. She reluctantly starts for Karla --</context>
      <utterance>Julie, we have to do something.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OLD LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray slumps back, waiting for the pills to work.</context>
      <utterance>People live healthy in Miami.  It's the future down there every day of the week...The future.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll keep that in mind.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo, Freak Boy -- The cluttered room is empty.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyrell and Will begin roughly searching through Estes's possessions.</context>
      <utterance>He's not here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the corner there is a curtain used as a partition. Julie pulls the curtain back and discovers</context>
      <utterance>We're gonna find some weird crap in here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>THE LITTLE STRAW MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>impaled on a fishhook.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Voodoo.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julie looks closer. She sees her toothbrush, a hair tie, assorted other knickknacks belonging to her friends.</context>
      <utterance>I told you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karla looks in. Tyrell snatches the straw man up.</context>
      <utterance>Missing a hair tie?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THUNDER rumbles across the sky like the judgement of God.</context>
      <utterance>We found our guy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will and Tyrell eye the stairs leading down to the lobby.</context>
      <utterance>We gotta find flashlights, torches, guns if they got 'em, anything that'll help.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will and Tyrell exchange a glance, an "are you man enough?" kind of glance.</context>
      <utterance>Wait. Maybe he's down there collecting the body parts.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>65	INT. HOTEL LOBBY - NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The men head into the kitchen and bar area.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll only be a second, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karla is terrified and waits by the stairs, but something catches Julie's eye. She walks across the lobby.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, wait right here, it's the safest place.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julie keeps walking. She sees historical pictures of the hotel: work crews during construction; the first limbo contest; fishermen standing next to sailfish and marlin. Near the pictures, Julie sees the globe. It's spinning slowly. Julie hesitates, then walks toward the globe. It stops spinning. She looks down at it.</context>
      <utterance>Julie, where are you going?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>WILL/ESTES/TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let go. I got him. That's me. It's him. We got you...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyrell holds up battered Estes --</context>
      <utterance>Leave him alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's youre killer --</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No --</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We found your voodoo crap --</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They shake Estes, finally giving him a chance to speak. ESTES (cont'd) I found the bodies this morning...I tried to use the radio, but he already destroyed it.</context>
      <utterance>No --</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let him go. I believe him.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Julie. You saw his room.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't hurt anyone...I stole those things to help you. To protect you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's telling the truth. He could've easily killed me. He didn't.  Look, we didn't even answer the radio question right...This whole thing was a setup.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rio isn't the capital of Brazil. It was the wrong answer. Sorry, we lose.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got all these theories but where is he? Where? Where's your fisherman killer?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You never do...The guy at the nightclub, the body in your room last night. Little notes that only mean something to you. How do we even know you're not the one behind this -- Estes steps forward --</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do we know you're not?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at Estes...Is he telling the truth?</context>
      <utterance>I know who you're talking about. He used to work here at the hotel.  And I've seen him around again. Out in the woods by the orchard.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stare a beat --</context>
      <utterance>I can't remeber his name, but I don't forget a face.  I can show you...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do we know you're not setting us up?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look to the office, the gym...The sense of death surrounding them.</context>
      <utterance>Where else you gonna go, son?</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know I don't want to stay in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll be better off in the open. If we stick together, maybe we can kill this creep for good.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They begin moving for the door.</context>
      <utterance>Show us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PAULSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paulsen slowly gets up. He cracks the door open. Ray stands silhouetted against the rain.</context>
      <utterance>What the...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paulsen senses something isn't right.</context>
      <utterance>I need to get to Tower Bay Island.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray pushes his way in --</context>
      <utterance>We're closed.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to get there, now. Paulsen looks at him standing there drenched.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray pulls out the gun and points it at Paulsen --</context>
      <utterance>Did you happen to notice what's going on outside?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not looking for a weather report, I'm looking for a boat. So which one's yours?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ESTES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Estes looks at them in the dark, slowing for just a second. ESTES (cont'd) One day his wife went missing. Maid found blood all over the honeymoon suite -- Room 201. There are strange NOISES out in the woods. ESTES (cont'd) Eventually, they found her body. Pieces. A leg in the swamp. An arm washed up on Three Mile Beach. (beat) And the head they found much later. A huge branch is blown from a tree and comes crashing down through the underbrush, scaring them. Estes calmly steps around it. ESTES (cont'd) Careful --</context>
      <utterance>He worked here for many years. He had a nice family. A pretty wife and two little ones. A boy and a girl. They'd be about your age, now. They continue along the path.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did he do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The winding path leads to a small orchard. They hang on his every word. ESTES (cont'd) We're here. In the center of the orchard is a cemetery. They move off the path into the safety of the woods. There seems to be activity around the place. It's silent and eerie. Julie stares, fascinated. She is slowly drawn toward the house. Karla grabs for her arm.</context>
      <utterance>People say she was running around on him. People say he caught her in bed with other men. People say a lot of things.  He disappeared, taking the two small ones with him. At least they were never found.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be careful, Julie.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leads, they follow, circling the house. Julie rounds a corner of the shack and stops. She sees --</context>
      <utterance>I've got to see.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>JULIE JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>born September 6, 1979 died July 4, 1998 "A Lying Whore" "A Lying Whore" is scratched with a knife.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will goes to comfort Julie --</context>
      <utterance>...Today's July fourth.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks defiantly down the path.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not dying on this island, Will.  Do you hear me? Julie shouts into the darkness. JULIE  You want me, Ben Willis? Come and get me. I'm right here. She kicks over her headstone -- JULIE  My grave stays empty!</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Julie, the boats are gone, the phones are down. There's no way off this place.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then, we fight -- Will looks around. Estes is gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd Estes go?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is up with that weirdo?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll go find him.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? He can't help us.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's probably the only one who can help us.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll come with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you crazy? We're not staying here on our own.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will disappears into the darkness.</context>
      <utterance>It's okay. He couldn't have gone far. I'll catch up with you later.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hide in a tree?</context>
      <utterance>Maybe we should just wait here?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not hiding up no tree.  I'm with her. Let's arm ourselves to the teeth and kick this psycho's butt.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up a huge butcher's knife and cuts the air with it. He then roughly empties other drawers looking for more weapons. Karla looks to Julie, something on her mind. Julie catches the look.</context>
      <utterance>What I need is a gun. Not a steak knife. Karla grabs a paring knife -- TYRELL  You gonna clean vegetables? You gonna stir-fry? You need something that'll get his attention.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm your best friend...You could have told me the truth about what happened. I would've understood.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Karla, I just wanted the whole thing to be over. I didn't want to involve anybody else.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julie steps over to Karla.</context>
      <utterance>It's too late for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyrell picks up on the mood swing. He moves closer to them. He's sympathetic.</context>
      <utterance>I'm so sorry. I brought this on everyone. It's my fault.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget that. You didn't do nothing. This fisherman's a piece of scum.  I should've been listening to you... I'm sorry. Julie smiles for a second. TYRELL  Now, let's take a look at the pantry.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think that's a good place to hide?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, but I'm starving.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Estes doesn't answer right away -- he keeps his back to Will. WILL (cont'd) You abandoning us? How come you didn't tell us you had a boat? Estes picks up the boat's oar. He speaks low, almost inaudibly.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Estes.  Estes? Where'd you go?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This has to end. Now.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Estes swings the oar, cracking Will's head hard.</context>
      <utterance>What -- ?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>72	INT. HOTEL KITCHEN - CONTINUOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tyrell steps inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts looking for something to eat -- CLANK. There's a soft CLATTERING from somewhere in the room. Everyone freezes, staring into the darkness. Tyrell puts a finger to his lips, then creeps down an aisle, listening. There's nothing but SILENCE. He moves toward the first aisle...He jumps out. The aisle is empty.</context>
      <utterance>Steel door...Food...Perfect.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE AND KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyrell ducks around to the second aisle. He slices the air, ready to pounce. This aisle is empty.</context>
      <utterance>move down an aisle behind him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE AND KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyrell moves stealthily toward the third aisle...This is it. He lunges forward into the row...Empty, also. There's a small SOUND...A MOUSE scampers off under the shelves. Tyrell turns and smiles at Karla and Julie --</context>
      <utterance>nervously move another aisle down.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just a --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A DARK FIGURE jumps down from the shelves. Tyrell puts his arms up --</context>
      <utterance>Ty!</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't kill me --</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nancy, the bartender steps out of the shadows brandishing her rolling pin.</context>
      <utterance>Wait, it's Nancy --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, but you could've been the one doing all of this --</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And so could you -- crazy fool.</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You stumbled into my hiding place.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Must have missed the sign.</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, but this island didn't have a murder rate until you people showed up.  I've never seen a dead body before.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get used to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's doing this?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julie helps Nancy reach a pull cord in the ceiling.</context>
      <utterance>Give me a boost up --</utterance>
   <speaker>A WOODEN LADDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pulls down. Nancy quickly climbs up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN WILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>enters the hallway and continues toward them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no way to lock it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From below comes LAUGHTER. There's a tug on the hatch, cracking it open. The girls pull it back shut, but it's hard to get a grip. There's more tugging, the hatch bending down; they can see Ben. Then, the rope SNAPS. The hatch slams shut.</context>
      <utterance>What do we do?</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly the STEEL TIP of the HOOK pokes through the crack...It wriggles around...Turning...And begins to pull the hatch down. They try to hold it...But it's no use. They let go and jump away. The attic is lit by a cathedral window. It's crosshatched with wooden beams and pink insulation.</context>
      <utterance>There's no way to grip this thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THUNK! Karla's foot goes through a gap between two beams.</context>
      <utterance>Watch your step...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd be amazed by what you'd see. My wife with every man on the island, for example.  And you, sexy...I loved watching you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben suddenly whirls and lunges at Karla. He grabs her, but they both lose their balance, teetering for a moment on one of the beams, before falling -- They CRASH through the mirror --</context>
      <utterance>You sick freak.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, god, no -- She's almost to the support when</utterance>
   <speaker>THE ROOF EXPLODES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>taking Karla down into the orchid house.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nancy sees a KEY RING by the door.</context>
      <utterance>It's locked!</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nancy tries the first of many keys. Something catches Julie's eye. She moves in for a closer look. Her eyes go wide --</context>
      <utterance>It's gotta be one of these.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karla spins. Sees him. Her terrified scream blends with the cranes, now SHRIEKING VIOLENTLY.</context>
      <utterance>He's inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please! Hurry!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nancy fumbles for the right key but the lock is old.</context>
      <utterance>Hurry!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nancy...</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The key is stuck.</context>
      <utterance>It's jammed!</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's running out of time. Julie sees a FIRE AXE encased in the glass safety box.</context>
      <utterance>Come on!!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julie smashes the glass with her elbow. Grabs the axe.</context>
      <utterance>No way!!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julie hammers the door with the axe. Wood splinters. Glass cracks. Ben is almost on top of Karla now. Julie swings. The axe breaks the glass, pulls the frame out. Julie drops the axe. They grab Karla. Pull her through. Ben swings. The hook rips Karla's shoe, but Julie and Nancy pull her through. Julie and Ben are face to face. Julie has the axe in her hands. She stares him down.</context>
      <utterance>Move!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, gimme a shot -- Ben rips off his hook, eyeing Julie.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They flee. Ben tries the door, realizes it had locked behind him. He can't fit through the circular window. He throws his shoulder against the door. And again. And again. The door frame starts to give --</context>
      <utterance>Julie, come on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julie gets in, pulling Karla in behind her. They pull the door closed behind them.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, you can make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a light somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>96	INT. STORM SHELTER - NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The darkness is complete. We hear MOVEMENT.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Julie?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm right here. Grab my hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This place has emergency power. Just ease you way down the stairs and I'll find the light.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. I'm at the bottom. Karla, just get my hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm holding your hand!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you're not.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nancy pulls the chain on an overhead bulb. The lights go on, illuminating</context>
      <utterance>...Nancy?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are ecstatic to see him. They bound up the concrete stairs --</context>
      <utterance>It's you guys, thank god. Is everyone okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Help's here. Help's here.</utterance>
   <speaker>97	EXT. HOTEL WALKWAY - NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will is already on the move toward the hotel.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on. We're gonna be okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you get help? Will shakes his head. He's walking woozily. JULIE  What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Estes came after me with a gaffing hook.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's in it with Willis?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julie points out that his chest and stomach are covered in blood, too.</context>
      <utterance>I guess so.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will looks down, clutches himself, and keeps moving.</context>
      <utterance>Your stomach, you're hurt --</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I was coming back I saw your slicker friend looking for you guys down by the water.  Let's hurry and get inside...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, my god, you're bleeding to death. She looks back towards Nancy -- JULIE  We need a first-aid kit.</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karla starts, then hesitates. Will moans, looks at her. NANCY (cont'd) I'll come with you.</context>
      <utterance>I saw one in the lobby.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karla and Nancy rush from the bar. Julie looks tenderly at Will. He looks back at her. She pulls some hair off his forehead. He smiles weakly.</context>
      <utterance>You'll be okay. It's over.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will, just hold on. We'll get you fixed up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will takes her head in his hands, looks her in the eye.</context>
      <utterance>You've got blood everywhere, but I can't find the wound.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His voice switches to that of a familiar radio disk jockey. WILL (cont'd) (as Mark in the Morning)</context>
      <utterance>That's because it's not my blood. The slow change in Julie as she realizes... She starts to run. Will roughly grabs her. WILL  It's time you woke up, Julie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ESTES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Estes's expression changes to surprise, and</context>
      <utterance>Will...He's in on it. He's --</utterance>
   <speaker>A SPEAR TIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nancy screams and looks over Estes's shoulder to see</context>
      <utterance>appears in the front of his chest.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN WILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Estes topples over on top of Nancy, pinning her underneath his dying, convulsing body. Nancy struggles to get loose.</context>
      <utterance>standing there holding a spear gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karla rushes to Nancy. She tugs on her arm, trying to pull her free. The fisherman strides toward them. He raises his hook. He swings at Karla's head.</context>
      <utterance>Help me.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE HOOK CATCHES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>on a beam. Karla struggle with Nancy.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben tries to free his hook hand. Karla looks up at him. He calmly puts his foot onto Estes's back and steps down with all of his weight, driving</context>
      <utterance>Come on, come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE SPEAR TIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karla, blind with rage, attacks the fisherman. He kicks out with a boot and sends Karla fying onto</context>
      <utterance>deep into Nancy who expires with a sigh. KARLA  Damn you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julie's trying to get to the knife she's stashed in her back pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Look at the bright side, Jules. We finally get to spend some quality time together.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you doing this to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm having trouble with my boyfriend.</context>
      <utterance>Me, me, me. It's always about you. I'm having bad dreams. I can't sleep. I'm not doing well in school.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I trusted you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They come into the orchard. They are covered in mud. Julie stumbles again. Goes to her knees. Works the knife free and slashes up at Will. She slices him across the face. He steps back, feels the blood. WILL (cont'd) What'd you have to do that for? There is a creepy pause. Will stares at his own blood. She catches her breath... Then suddenly, Will knocks the knife from her hand. He lifts her by the hair. Enraged, he puches her in the face. She goes down.</context>
      <utterance>We had a connection, didn't we? I can tell you one thing, though. Ray didn't trust me. He was right. He's dead, but he was right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shoves her. She falls backward into the arms of Ben Willis. WILL (cont'd) Hi, Dad. Julie WAILS, struggling wildly in Ben's grasp.</context>
      <utterance>Why? Come on, Julie. Think. You'll get it. Will Benson -- Ben's son.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben holds her back to look at her. He throws back the hood of his slicker. We see his face clearly for the first time.</context>
      <utterance>That's my boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben pulls off his hook and strokes Julie's cheek with his stump.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, no --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben and Will spin to see</context>
      <utterance>Shush, now. No more screaming...No more running. Time to die. RAY  Let go of her! Now!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta be kiddin' me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you gonna do, boy? Call us names?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray raises the .38 caliber handgun. He COCKS the hammer. Ben doesn't let go of Julie. Lightning fast, he slaps his hook back on and gets the point to Julie's neck.</context>
      <utterance>Let her go. Now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray hesitates, his finger on the trigger. He does look scared. Ben takes a step toward Ray. Then another, pushing Julie in front of him. Will moves closer, too.</context>
      <utterance>Think about it, boy. You're no killer.  That's my job.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray's finger squeezing down the trigger.</context>
      <utterance>Stop right there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, Will dives for Ray. Ray gets a shot off, tagging Ben in the shoulder. The gun goes flying. Julie spins and hits Ben in the face. He knocks her into her own grave...Mud begins to slide in on her. She tries to scramble out. Will and Ray wrestle, punching each other repeatedly in the face. Will has Ray down and his hands around his kneck. He looks him in the eye.</context>
      <utterance>You don't have it in you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will gets the better of Ray. He's stronger. He yanks him up -- choking him. Ray is begging to check out. WILL (cont'd) Think of all the things I'm gonna do to her. (beat) Dad, finish him. Ben charges toward Ray's back. He pulls back the hook for a roundhouse slashing -- At the last second, Ray dips, elbows Will.</context>
      <utterance>We haven't missed you down here, Ray boy. I got to know Julie real well.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE HOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Father and son make final eye contact, the son's eyes go blank. Ben stares in shock as Will expires, falling back into the mud. Ben SCREAMS in rage. Ray is tired. THWACK. Ben begins beating Ray. He puches him. He straight-arms him with the hook. He knocks him again and again and Ray is beaten, giving up... Ben has Ray against a tombstone. The hook slowly inches toward his eye.</context>
      <utterance>goes straight into Will's chest. The fisherman has hooked his own son.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The hook is touching the eyelid --</context>
      <utterance>Gonna blind you first.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>stands behind him holding the gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BLAM. BLAM. BLAM. She empties the gun into Ben, who flies backward into Julie's grave. As he tumbles, Ben releases the dirt stacked beside the grave...</context>
      <utterance>Just...Die.</utterance>
   <speaker>A MUDDY LANDSLIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben's face is covering over. His mouth starting to fill with dirt --</context>
      <utterance>slowly covers Ben up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His face is completely covered. His mouth still moving. BEN (cont'd) I'll always be with you. The dirt covers him. It continues to fill, until just the</context>
      <utterance>You can't kill me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, god, it's you --</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're okay. Thank god.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They nod. They go to her -- jubilant group hug time. They compose themselves. KARLA (cont'd) You know, it's true what they say about package vacations...You get what you pay for. (beat) Now, how about we get off this piece of crap island. The first rays of the morning sun appear. Ray looks adoringly at Julie as the beautific light catches her face. Ray kisses her. She kisses him back. They are silhouetted against a beautiful orange sunrise.</context>
      <utterance>Is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three of them throw their arms around each other's shoulders and they start walking for the beach as...</context>
      <utterance>We don't have to tell anyone it rained the whole time. It can just be our little secret.</utterance>
   <speaker>A COAST GUARD HELICOPTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>rises into view.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ray...what are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh...it's not working right. You're home early.  Did I scare you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never do that again.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sees the love in his eyes. She hugs him.</context>
      <utterance>Hey -- I didn't know you were here. It's okay.  We got the refrigerator in. Come see.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love it here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's gonna be great.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Checking the locks again?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julie smile and walks to the bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>You know me to well.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NOTHING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She looks around the room.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles, relaxes. She looks in the mirror leaning against the wall. Something has caught her eye. She freezes. She turns slowly back to the reflection in the mirror. She sees the glint of steel --</context>
      <utterance>What is my problem? She sits down on the bed. We see her bare feet from under the bed.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
