<movie id="300" title="Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JEFF BOAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Story by</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE LUCAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>and</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RIDERS climb down from their mounts... and only now do we realize that this is a TROOP OF BOY SCOUTS, all of them about thirteen years of age. The "Commanding Officer" is only their SCOUTMASTER, Mr. Havelock. One of the Scouts, a pudgy kid named HERMAN, steps away from his horse, bends over and pukes. The other Scouts rag on him.</context>
      <utterance>Dis-mount!</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST SCOUT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A BLOND SCOUT, however, befriends Herman. He has a thatch of straw-colored hair and the no-nonsense expression common to kids whose curiosity and appetite for knowledge exceed what they teach in school. Additionally, he has adorned his uniform with an authentic HOPI INDIAN WOVEN BELT.</context>
      <utterance>Herman's horsesick!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOUTMASTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two Boy Scouts climb up the rocky base of the cliff.</context>
      <utterance>Chaps, don't anybody wander off. Some of the passageways in here can run for miles.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LAUGHTER is HEARD; the Blond Scout pulls Herman forward toward its source. The VOICES GROW LOUDER now as the boys get closer to their source. The light of kerosene lanterns dances on the tunnel walls ahead. The boys approach cautiously, careful to stay hidden.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think this is such a good idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>HERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is what they see: FOUR MEN digging with shovels and pick-axes. They have broken into one of the pueblo's SECRET CHAMBERS... called "Kivas." The men are ROUGH RIDER (his name describes his dress), ROSCOE (a Bowery Boy bully of 14) and HALFBREED (with straight black hair that cascades over his shoulders). And the fourth man wears a LEATHER WAIST JACKET and BROWN FELT FEDORA HAT. He has his back turned to us, but we would be willing to bet anything that this is INDLANA JONES. However, when the man turns, and his face is illuminated by the lantern's glow, we are shocked to discover that it is someone else. We'll call him FEDORA.</context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TITLES END.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now we realize that the Blond Scout is actually young INDIANA JONES.</context>
      <utterance>The TWO BOYS are mesmerized by what they see.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEDORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alfred, did you get anything yet?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two of the men stand and look at ROSCOE who steps forward holding a box in his hands.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing. Dig in.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whoops from the other men.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, I've got something!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got something, Garth!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ROSCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FEDORA puts the box on the rock next to the lantern. HALFBREED pushes ROSCOE as he jumps with excitement. ROUGH RIDER steps forward to look at the box as Fedora opens it.</context>
      <utterance>I got something... I got something right here. More whoops from the other men.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, look at thatl  We're richl We're rich!</utterance>
   <speaker>HALFBREED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FEDORA takes a BEJEWELED CROSS from the box and holds it aloft. Fedora's comrades practically salivate at the sight of it.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up. Shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSCOE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>INDY takes off his hat and looks down at the o.s. action.</context>
      <utterance>Well, we're rich, ain't we?l</utterance>
   <speaker>HERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana? Indiana?</context>
      <utterance>Indy? Indy? What are they doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FEDORA blows dust from the Cross, turning it in his hand, silently appraising its beauty... and its value. He seems aloof from the others; somehow superior to them.</context>
      <utterance>Shhhl</utterance>
   <speaker>HALFBREED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY stays hidden, but is astounded by what he sees.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, we got to find more stuff to bring back.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the Cross of Coronadol Cortes gave it to him in 15201</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HERMAN doesn't seem to be listening. Instead, he watches in wide-eyed horror as a SNAKE SLITHERS ACROSS HIS LAP.</context>
      <utterance>Run back and find the others. Tell Mister Havelock that there are men looting in the caves.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY matter-of-factly picks up the snake and tosses it aside. HERMAN gasps.</context>
      <utterance>Have him bring the sheriff.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY grabs HERMAN's scout scarf and pulls him closer.</context>
      <utterance>It's only a snake.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you hear what I said?</utterance>
   <speaker>HERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Run back. Mister Havelock. The Sheriff. What, what are you gonna do?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY releases the scarf, gives HERMAN a pat and Herman dashes off. Indy sees the Cross on the rock next to the lantern. As the Robbers continue to search for additional valuables, Indy is able to work his way unseen to within arm's reach of the Cross... FEDORA looks over at the men digging in a hole b.g.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know... I'll think of something.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEDORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY picks up the Cross.</context>
      <utterance>Dig with your hands.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FEDORA</speaker>
      <mode>O . S . </mode>
      <context>As FEDORA stands watching the other men digging, INDY puts the Cross in his pants and begins to pull himself up a rope hanging nearby. As he climbs, Indy's feet break a wooden beam, attracting the men's attention.</context>
      <utterance>Not with your mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got our thing!</utterance>
   <speaker>HALFBREED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get 'im!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hears RUNNING FOOTSTEPS BEHIND HIM and dashes off. ROUGH RIDER, HALFBREED, and ROSCOE are quick to appear and run after him.</context>
      <utterance>Mister Havelock! Anybody Everybody's lost but me!</utterance>
   <speaker>FEDORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There he isl</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY jumps back in horror... only to land with a SQUISH into the SNAKE VAT.</context>
      <utterance>Oh...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hundreds of slippery, squirming snakes. INDY sinks into them. They cover him. Engulf him. Almost smother him. INDY jumps out of the side of the vat, freeing himself. INDY locates a clean-out door at the bottom of the car and uses it to escape. HALFBREED, meanwhile, tries to open the closed window of the car. He groans. ROUGH RIDER moves to assist him.</context>
      <utterance>Oh... Oh...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROUGH RIDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here, let me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FEDORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As INDY edges away from FEDORA, a portion of the STOCKCAR'S ROOF COLLAPSES and Indy FALLS THROUGH into the car below.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, kid. There's no way out of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY's eyes take a moment to adjust to the dark. A bit of sunlight leaks in through the cracks between the boards. Then INDY sees it. At the far end of the boxcar. Rising slowly to its feet... an AFRICAN LION. The Lion ROARS. The boxcar walls shake. Indy gasps. Dust swirls up into the shafts of sunlight. And INDY has one more surprise in store: The Cross of Cortes has been dislodged from his belt during the fall... INDY glances around, sees a coiled LION TAMER'S WHIP hanging on a nail. He carefully takes it down by the handle. The Lion sees this and GROWLS SOFTLY. INDY swallows hard and gives the whip a try. It unravels awkwardly, its TIP flying back and HITTING INDY IN THE FACE... CUTTING his chin. The Lion GROWLS LOUDER. Indy quickly gathers up the whip, wets his lips, and tries again. This time—success! The WHIP CRACKS SHARPLY. The Lion BELLOWS and SWATS the air... and steps back. INDY looks amazed and delighted. He CRACKS the whip again. The Lion backs away even more. Indy inches forward—bends down (never taking his eyes off the Lion)—picks up the Cross—and steps back again, sweat pouring down his face. But now... how to get out? He looks up at the opening through which he fell and sees FEDORA LOOKING DOWN AT HIM. Fedora extends his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Ohhh!</utterance>
   <speaker>FEDORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Toss up the whip.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FEDORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got heart, kid.  But that belongs to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It belongs to Coronado.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEDORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coronado is dead. And so are all his grandchildren.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This should be in a museum.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ROSCOE makes a grab for the Cross—but INDY doesn't let go. A tug-of-war ensues until a SNAKE WIGGLES OUT FROM INDY'S SHIRTSLEEVE and WRAPS AROUND Roscoe's hand. ROSCOE SCREAMS BLOODY MURDER—releases his grip on the Cross and tries to shake off the snake. This is all the opportunity Indy needs. He LEAPS ONTO</context>
      <utterance>Now give me thatl</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances back at the men and quickly opens the door to the caboose, stepping inside. FEDORA puts out his arm, gesturing for the others not to follow INDY.</context>
      <utterance>Magic?</utterance>
   <speaker>FEDORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold it. Make sure he doesn't double back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FEDORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FEDORA smiles confidently and advances toward the box. The box unexpectedly collapses; all four sides flop away... revealing NOTHING. INDY has completely vanished. FEDORA is mystified, frustrated and angered. Then he feels a breeze at his back. He turns and discovers that the caboose door is open. He rushes out onto the balcony and sees: INDY RUNNING along the tracks, turning up a street of modest clapboard houses.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, kid. out of the box. Now.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEDORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's important!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then wait—count to twenty.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Dad. You listen to me—</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No question who is the boss here. INDY gulps, his look says "What am I going to do with this guy?" And obeys— starts counting, VERY, VERY FAINTLY.</context>
      <utterance>Junior!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now we see what HENRY is concentrating on. We see his hand sketching; then, he holds up one finger.</context>
      <utterance>One, two, three, four...</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY's reaction:</context>
      <utterance>In Greek.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An ancient car is heard arriving. Perhaps INDY glimpses it going past the window. Anyway, it stops outside the house. Two men sit in the front seat. HERMAN sits in the rear, BLOWING A TRUMPET. INDY's reaction: Trouble! HENRY is just finishing the sketch.</context>
      <utterance>One... two... three... four...</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>illuminate me...</context>
      <utterance>May he who illuminated this...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>HERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HERMAN means the SHERIFF, who now enters the house.</context>
      <utterance>I brought the Sheriff.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just the man I want to see! Now, there were five or six of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, son.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... they came after... me...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You still got it?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY shows the CROSS, more or less handing it to the SHERIFF to make his point. The Sheriff takes it casually.</context>
      <utterance>Well, yes, sir. It's right here!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FEDORA enters the house, followed by ROSCOE, ROUGH RIDER and HALFBREED. He politely removes his hat and holds it in his hand. He nods at INDY in a friendly manner.</context>
      <utterance>I'm glad to see that... because the rightful owner of this Cross won't press charges, if you give it back.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SHERIFF hands the Cross to FEDORA. ROSCOE reaches in and takes it from Fedora, then runs out the door.</context>
      <utterance>He's got witnesses, five or six of them. The SHERIFF and FEDORA are in Cahoots</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yahoo!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FEDORA remains behind for a moment. He turns and speaks to INDY in an ironic man-to-man way.</context>
      <utterance>Good day.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEDORA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then, FEDORA takes off his hat and takes a step towards INDY. He holds the hat by the crown, and puts it on Indy's head, a show of respect and admiration for the boy. The hat blocks Indy's face.</context>
      <utterance>You lost today, kid, but that doesn't mean you have to like it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PANAMA HAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Small world, Doctor Jones.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE MAN IN THE PANAMA HAT (years older now) removes the CROSS OF CORONADO from Indy's belt.</context>
      <utterance>Too small for two of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>PANAMA HAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the second time I've had to reclaim my property from you—</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That belongs in a museum—</utterance>
   <speaker>PANAMA HAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So do you.  Throw him over the side.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BARCELONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A SHREDDED PANAMA HAT floats past.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O .</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Archaeology is...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARCUS BRODY approaches Indy's classroom. He peers through the window in the door to see INDY completing his lecture.</context>
      <utterance>So forget any ideas you've got about lost cities, exotic travel, and digging up the world. Eve do not follow maps to buried treasure and "X" never, ever, marks the spot.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reading.</context>
      <utterance>Seventy percent of all archaeology is done in the library. Research.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The BELL RINGS. INDY stands at his desk as students begin to disperse. A pretty coed puts a note on the desk.</context>
      <utterance>We cannot afford to take mythology at face value.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BRODY approaches as the last of the students leaves the lecture hall.</context>
      <utterance>Next week: "Egyptology." Starting with the excavation of Naukratis by Blinders Petrie in 1885. I will be in my office if anybody's got any problems for the next hour and a half.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marcus!  I did it!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY removes the cloth-wrapped Cross from his desk. He places it on the desk and takes off his glasses as BRODY examines the Cross.</context>
      <utterance>You've got itl</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know how long I've been looking for that?!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All your life.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All my life!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY gathers up his books and makes his way toward the door.</context>
      <utterance>Well done, Indy. Very well done, indeed This will find a place of honor in our Spanish collection.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns back toward BRODY, now holding the Cross.</context>
      <utterance>We can discuss my honorarium over dinner and champagne tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your treat.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. My treat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY shoulders his way to the desk of his secretary, an overwhelmed Teaching Assistant named IRENE.</context>
      <utterance>Shush! Shush! Shushl</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Here are your phone messages.</context>
      <utterance>Doctor Jones! I'm so glad you're back! Your mail is on your desk.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE STUDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doctor Jones—</context>
      <utterance>Doctor Jones, you promised...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY takes the term papers then turns to enter his PRIVATE OFFICE. Students once again CLAMOR for his attention: "Doctor Jones!" "Wait, Doctor Jonesl" "My grade!" "Sign my registration card!" INDY silences the mob with a raised hand.</context>
      <utterance>This is your appointment schedule. And these term papers still haven't been graded.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Students descend upon poor IRENE, each claiming to be first. INDY slips into his -</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Irene, put everyone's name on a list, in the order they arrived, and I'll see each and every one of them in turn.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>THREE MEN step out of the sedan. Everything about them bespeaks "G-MAN." The First Man steps behind Indy.</context>
      <utterance>Doctor Jonesl</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doctor Jones?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shakes hands with INDY.</context>
      <utterance>I trust your trip down was comfortable, Doctor Jones. My men didn't alarm you, I hope.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name is Donovan. Walter Donovan.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know who you are Mr. Donovan. Your contributions to the museum over the years have been extremely generous. Some of the pieces in your collection here are very impressive.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, like yourself, Doctor Jones, I have a passion for antiquities.  Have a look over here. This might interest you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's sandstone. Christian symbol. Early Latin text. Mid- Twelfth Century, I should think.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was our assessment as well.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did this come from?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Translating the inscription is no easy matter, even for someone as knowledgeable as INDY.</context>
      <utterance>My engineers unearthed it in the mountain region north of Ankara while excavating for copper.  Can you translate the inscription?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donovan pours champagne into several fluted glasses as Indy reads.</context>
      <utterance>"... who drinks the water I shall give him, says the Lord, will have a spring inside him welling up for eternal life. Let them bring me to your holy mountain in the place where you dwell.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly INDY stops and looks up at DONOVAN with a startled expression.</context>
      <utterance>Across the desert and through the mountain to the Canyon of the Crescent Moon, to the Temple where the cup that—"</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Where the cup that holds the blood of Jesus Christ resides forever. "</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY rubs his chin with a dubious expression as he takes the glass of champagne DONOVAN now offers him.</context>
      <utterance>The Holy Grail, Doctor Jones. The chalice used by Christ during the Last Supper. The cup that caught His blood at the Crucifixion and was entrusted to Joseph of Arimathaea.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Arthur Legend. I've heard this bedtime story before.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eternal life, Doctor Jones! The gift of youth to whoever drinks from the Grail.  Oh, now that's a bedtime story I'd like to wake up to!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An old man's dream.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY stiffens slightly at the mention of his father, nods.</context>
      <utterance>Every man's dream.  Including your father's, I believe.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door opens and MRS. DONOVAN steps into the room. She's a matronly woman in an expensive evening gown.</context>
      <utterance>Grail lore is his hobby. He's a teacher of Medieval Literature. The one the students hope they don't get.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Walter, you're neglecting our guests.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans over and kisses her cheek. MRS. DONOVAN sighs to herself and returns to the party. INDY, meanwhile, has turned his attention back to the Grail Tablet, obviously hooked by its archaeological promise. He moistens his finger with champagne and rubs it over the tablet. DONOVAN steps up next to Indy.</context>
      <utterance>Be along in a moment, dear.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hard to resist, isn't it? The Holy Grail's final resting place described in detail!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What good is it? This Grail Tablet speaks of deserts and mountains and canyons. Pretty vague. Where do you start looking? Maybe if the Tablet were intact, you'd have something to go on. But the entire top portion is missing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY has to shake his head at DONOVAN's apparent lack of judgment.</context>
      <utterance>Just the same, an attempt to recover the Grail is currently underway.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me tell you another "bedtime story, " Doctor Jones. After the Grail was entrusted to Joseph of Arimathaea, it disappeared and was lost for a thousand years before it was found again by three Knights of the First Crusade. Three brothers, to be exact.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've heard this one as well. Two of these brothers walked out of the desert one hundred and fifty years after having found the Grail and began the long journey back to France. But only one of them made it. And before dying of extreme old age, he supposedly imparted his tale to a—to a Franciscan friar, I think.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DONOVAN produces an ANCIENT LEATHER-BOUND VOLUME with very brittle pages. INDY views the manuscript with considerable interest.</context>
      <utterance>Not "supposedly," Doctor Jones.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the manuscript in which the friar chronicled the Knight's story... it doesn't reveal on location of the Grail, I'm afraid... but the Knight promised that two "markers" that had been left behind would.  This Tablet is one of those "markers." It proves the Knight's story is true. But as you pointed out—it's incomplete.  Now, the second "marker" is entombed with the Knight's dead brother. Our project leader believes that tomb to be located within the city of Venice, Italy.  As you can now see, Doctor Jones, we're about to complete a great quest that began almost two thousand years ago. We're only one step away.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's usually when the ground falls out from underneath your feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could be more right than you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've hit a snag. our project leader has vanished. Along with all his research. Uh, we received a cable from his colleague, Doctor Schneider, who has no idea of his whereabouts or what's become of him.  I want you to pick up the trail where he left off. Find the man and you will find the Grail.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got the wrong Jones, Mister Donovan. Why don't you try my father?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We already have. Your father is the man who's disappeared.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They climb the porch and notice that the front door is ajar. They exchange a quick look of concern as they enter.</context>
      <utterance>Your father and I have been friends since time began. I've watched you grow up, Indy. And I've watched the two of you grow apart.  I've never seen you this concerned about him before.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pushes open the door. He enters the house and calls out.</context>
      <utterance>Dad?  He's an academic A bookworm. He's not a field mans</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad? Dad?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk into the room.</context>
      <utterance>Dear God.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What has the old fool got himself into now?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BRODY picks up some mail from Henry's cluttered desk.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. But whatever it is, he's in over his head!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY turns and sees the pile of torn papers and envelopes. Then something hits him.</context>
      <utterance>It's today's mail. And it's been opened.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He immediately empties his pockets of his own mail taken earlier in the day from his college office and finds the envelope with the Venice postmark.</context>
      <utterance>Mail! That's it, Marcus!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Venice, Italy!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY uncovers a small book. It looks like a JOURNAL or DIARY. Indy flips through it: Page after page of handwritten notes and drawings. BRODY glances at it with great curiosity.</context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Why would he have sent this to me?</context>
      <utterance>It's Dad's Grail Diary. Every clue he ever followed. Every discovery he made. A complete record of his search for the Holy Grail. This is his whole life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. But someone must want it pretty badly.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As INDY asks the question, he turns to a PAINTING on the wall: A depiction of Christ on the Cross, his blood being captured in a golden chalice. A SECOND PAINTING on the wall shows Eleventh Century Crusaders plummeting to their deaths over a high cliff. One Crusader, however, floats safely in midair because he holds the Grail in his hands.</context>
      <utterance>Do you believe, Marcus?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you believe the Grail actually exists?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BRODY sees that INDY is unsatisfied by this response.</context>
      <utterance>The search for the Cup of Christ is the search for the divine in all of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But if you want facts, Indy, I have none to give you. At my age, I'm prepared to take a few things on faith.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call Donovan, Marcus. Tell him I'll take that ticket to Venice now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll tell him we'll take two.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me, what's going to happen when we get to Venice?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. Doctor Schneider will be there to meet you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Schneider?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I maintain an apartment in Venice, at your disposal.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BRODY and DONOVAN shake hands. INDY steps from the back seat of the limo. He turns back to Donovan and shakes his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, well. That's good. Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doctor Jones. Good luck. Be very careful. Don't trust anvbody.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, Venice...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Uh, how will we recognize this Doctor Schneider when we see him?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Maybe he'll know us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doctor Jones?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him with an appraising expression that is brazenly flirtatious.</context>
      <utterance>I knew it was you—</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY is instantly attracted to her.</context>
      <utterance>—you have your father's eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And my mother's ears. But the rest belongs to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY grins, enjoying the repartee. The WOMAN turns to BRODY, who tips his hat.</context>
      <utterance>Looks like the best parts have already been spoken for.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marcus Brody?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Woman, DR. ELSA SCHNEIDER, extends her hand to BRODY.</context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY's grin fades. BRODY registers a look of surprise.</context>
      <utterance>Doctor Elsa Schneider.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh... how do you do?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The last time I saw your father we were in the library. He was very close to tracking down the Knight's Tomb. I've never seen him so excited. He was as giddy as a schoolboy.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY can't take his eyes off ELSA. Perhaps he's feeling a bit like a schoolboy himself right now. As they cross over a bridge to the opposite side of the canal, Indy steals a flower from a street vendor. He holds it out to Elsa.</context>
      <utterance>Who? Attila the Professor? He was never giddy, even when he was a schoolboy!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fraulein—will you permit me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I usually don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I usually don't either.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY gives her the flower.</context>
      <utterance>In that case, I permit you.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It would make me very happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I'm already sad—by tomorrow it will have faded.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow I'll steal you another.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate to interrupt you—but the reason we're here—</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands a slip of paper to INDY.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. I have something to show you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY extends the scrap of paper to BRODY.</context>
      <utterance>I left your father working in the library. He sent me to the map section to fetch an ancient plan of the city. When I got back to his table—he'd gone—with all his papers—except for that scrap which I found near his chair.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roman numerals.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They have arrived at the front steps of the library.</context>
      <utterance>Here is the library.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That doesn't look much like a library.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ELSA leads the way inside.</context>
      <utterance>It looks like a converted church.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She indicates FOUR HUGE MARBLE COLUMNS that go from floor to ceiling.</context>
      <utterance>In this case it's the literal truth. We're on holy ground. These columns over here...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... were brought back as spoils of war after the sacking of Byzantium during the Crusades.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The minute ELSA is out of earshot.</context>
      <utterance>Now please excuse me. The library's closing in a few moments. I'll arrange for us to stay a little longer.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marcus—I've seen this window before.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY whips out the Grail Diary and opens it to the sketch he noticed in the airplane.</context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BRODY glances at the Diary, then at the window—noticing that the Roman numerals in question have been worked into the window's design.</context>
      <utterance>Right here. In Dad's Diary. You see?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Indy. The Roman numerals!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad was onto something here!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY and BRODY now see ELSA approaching. Indy quickly tucks the Diary back into his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Well, now we know the source of the numbers, but we still don't know what they mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My dad sent me this Diary for a reason. Until we find out why, I suggest we keep it to ourselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY doesn't reply. He's looking in five directions at once. His eyes moving across the walls and ceilings—charged with the thrill of discovery.</context>
      <utterance>Find something?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, yes. Three, seven and tent That window seems to be the source of the Roman numerals.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God, I must be blind</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad wasn't looking for a book about the Knight's Tomb... he was looking for the Tomb itself ELSA wears a blank expression.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY's eyes travel up one of the four huge marble columns.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you get it? The Tomb is somewhere in the library! You said yourself it used to be a church! Look.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY looks again to the stained-glass window. He points.</context>
      <utterance>Three.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY has discovered that each Column is numbered with a Roman Numeral. Indy hurries away toward Column VII. All BRODY and ELSA can do now is try to keep up with him.</context>
      <utterance>Three!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points again to the stained-glass window.</context>
      <utterance>Seven.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks down to the scrap of paper in his hands.</context>
      <utterance>Seven... Ten.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY walks past aisles of book-lined shelves. He stops, turns, then looks down.</context>
      <utterance>And ten. Now where's the ten? Look around for the ten.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bingo.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't disappoint, Doctor Jones. You're a great deal like your father.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Except he's lost, and I'm not.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY is impressed with Elsa's spirit, and cooperates agreeably—holding her by the hands and lowering her into the hole. When her feet finally touch ground below, Indy releases his grip on her and slips the Grail Diary to BRODY.</context>
      <utterance>Lower me down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY and ELSA glance around. This is really a horrid place. Dark and dank. foul smelling. Elsa turns. She removes a cigarette lighter with a unique ivory four-leaf clover design. INDY and ELSA inspect markings carved onto the walls.</context>
      <utterance>Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pagan symbols. Fourth or Fifth Century.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Six hundred years before the Crusades.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY takes the lighter from her and lights their way down a dark passageway.</context>
      <utterance>The Christians would have dug their own passages and burial chambers centuries later.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. If there's a Knight of the First Crusade entombed down here, that's where we'll find him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY only has to give it a quick glance to know.</context>
      <utterance>What's this one?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Ark of the Covenant.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY holds the lighter up and he and ELSA enter another dark passageway.</context>
      <utterance>Pretty sure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY reaches up and tears a piece of cloth from one of the skeletons, which breaks apart and falls into the oil-slick water. INDY uses the scrap of cloth and a bone to fashion a crude torch, which he then dips into the oily water.</context>
      <utterance>Petroleum. I could sink a well down here and retire.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me the lighter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ELSA gasps as the rats scamper between her legs. INDY moves forward through the rat-infested water as ELSA follows, still gasping in horror. Suddenly he slips into a hole. Recovering his balance, he reaches out to Elsa.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, rats...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gasps once again, terrified. INDY lifts her and carries ELSA as he moves forward.</context>
      <utterance>Come onl</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARGE BURIAL CHAMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The chamber is flooded with black, briny water.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It must be one of these...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One coffin is elevated above the others.</context>
      <utterance>Look at the artistry of these carvings and the scrollwork.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Together they begin to push on the lid—STRAINING and GROANING until it slides away and BANGS against the stone platform.</context>
      <utterance>It's this one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY unfolds a piece of paper and holds it over the shield.</context>
      <utterance>This is itl we found it! Look— the engraving on the Shield. It's the same as on the Grail Tablets The Shield is the Second Marker!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The missing portion of the rubbing is completed by the shield.</context>
      <utterance>It's a rubbing Dad made of the Grail Tablet.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Just like your father—giddy as a schoolboy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't it be wonderful if he were here now to see this?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He never would have made it past the rats! He hates rats! He's scared to death of them!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE - A HAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PULL BACK TO REVEAL KAZIM dropping the lighted match into the oil-slick water.</context>
      <utterance>as it lights a match.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY braces his back against the altar and TOPPLES THE COFFIN with his feet. It CRASHES against the stone platform and SPLASHES into the water.</context>
      <utterance>Get back! Back against the wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They jump into the water beside the bobbing, overturned coffin.</context>
      <utterance>Quick! Under it!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ELSA hesitates. INDY literally DUNKS her and pushes her underneath.</context>
      <utterance>Air pocket!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY disappears under the water and swims out from under the coffin.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNDER THE WATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>INDY swims, looking for an escape route.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ELSA can barely hear INDY over the noise of the motor.</context>
      <utterance>Are you crazy?! You don't go between them!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY finally delivers the punch that sends the Turkish Agent flying overboard. Turning, Indy sees that ELSA has committed the speedboat to a course BETWEEN the two Freighters, now being pushed even closer together by a Tugboat.</context>
      <utterance>Go between them? Are you crazy?!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said go around!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said go between them!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's purely academic at this point since the hulls of the the two Freighters loom up on either side of them like cavern walls.</context>
      <utterance>I said don't go between them!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY kicks KAZIM in the face, knocking him into the water, then pulls him back into the boat, now being SUCKED THROUGH THE CHURNING WATER toward the Steamer's giant propeller blades.</context>
      <utterance>No!!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you trying to kill us?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because you're looking for the Holy Grail.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father was looking for the Holy Grail. Did you kill him too?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is he? Talk—or you're dead. Damn it, tell me! Tell me!</utterance>
   <speaker>KAZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you don't let go, Doctor Jones, we'll both die.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then we'll die.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>By now half the boat has been chopped up into matchwood and the blades are getting closer.</context>
      <utterance>My soul is prepared. How's yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is your last chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The wind of the blades is on their necks. INDY grabs KAZIM just in time and jumps... into the motorboat, driven by ELSA, which gets alongside in the nick of time.</context>
      <utterance>No, Doctor Jones. It's yours!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right! Where's my father</utterance>
   <speaker>KAZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you let me go, I will tell you where he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name is Kazim.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And why were you trying to kill me?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KAZIM pulls back his shirt to reveal a birthmark... or is it a tattoo? Whatever it is, it's a cruciform sword; a Christian cross which tapers down, like the blades of a broadsword.</context>
      <utterance>The secret of the Grail has been safe for a thousand years. And for all that time the Brotherhood of the Cruciform Sword has been prepared to do anything to keep it safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boat is close to the edge of the canal. INDY gives ELSA a nod, telling her to bring the boat in. KAZIM steps ashore.</context>
      <utterance>Let me get off at this jetty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KAZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ask yourself, why do you seek the Cup of Christ? Is it for His glory, or for yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't come for the Cup of Christ. I came to find my father.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KAZIM walks away.</context>
      <utterance>In that case, God be with you in your quest. Your father is being held in the Castle of Brunwald on the Austrian-German border.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's the head?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY, wearing a bathrobe, leans over to study the impression.</context>
      <utterance>It's better, now I've seen this. It's the name of a city. "Alexandretta?" Hmmm...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BRODY lowers the ice pack from his head and looks at INDY.</context>
      <utterance>The Knights of the First Crusade laid siege to the city of Alexandretta for over a year. The entire city was destroyed.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The present city of Iskenderun is built on its ruins. Marcus— you remember what the Grail Tablet said. "Across the desert and through the mountain to the Canyon of the Crescent Moon."  But where exactly?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BRODY picks up the Grail Diary.</context>
      <utterance>Your father would know. Your father did know. Look. He made a map.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A map with no names.</context>
      <utterance>He must have pieced it together from clues scattered through the whole history of the Grail Quest.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, he knew there was a city with an oasis due east. Here. He knew the course turned south through the desert to a river, and the river led into the mountains. Here. Straight to the canyon. He knew everything except where to begin, the name of the city.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alexandretta. Now we know.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Now we know.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY closes the Grail Diary and puts it into the pocket of his robe.</context>
      <utterance>Marcus, get hold of Sallah. Tell him to meet you in Iskenderun.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about you?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going after Dad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens the bathroom door, peering inside.</context>
      <utterance>Elsa?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elsa?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My room!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mine, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks to INDY, who pulls the Grail Diary from his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>What were they looking for?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Grail Diary.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks hurt and beautiful. She comes closer to him.</context>
      <utterance>You had it? You didn't trust me!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's awfully hard to resist.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't know you.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least I let you tag along.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes. Give them a flower and they'll follow you anywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Knock it off. You're not mad.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You like the way I do things.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stomps her foot angrily. INDY flinches. She starts to walk away but Indy grabs her.</context>
      <utterance>It's lucky I don't do things the same way. You'd still be standing at the Venice pier.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, what do you think is going on here? Since I've met you, I've nearly been incinerated, drowned, shot at, and chopped into fish bait. We're caught in the middle of something sinister here. My guess is Dad found out more than he was looking for. And until I'm sure, I'm going to continue to do things the way I think they should be done.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONTINUED:</speaker>
      <mode>2</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He pulls her to him and kisses her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now ELSA reaches for INDY and kisses him.</context>
      <utterance>How dare you kiss me!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he embraces her, and ELSA begins to nibble at his ear.</context>
      <utterance>Leave me alone. I don't like fast women.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY smiles slyly as they fall to the bed.</context>
      <utterance>And I hate arrogant men.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you know about this place?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know the Brunwalds are famous art collectors.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you going to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances up to the beret ELSA is wearing. She reaches up and adjusts it.</context>
      <utterance>Don't know. Think of something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BUTLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY, followed by ELSA, steps inside, shaking the water from his overcoat. He adopts a Scottish accent.</context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As INDY says this he pushes his way past the startled BUTLER, pulling a handkerchief from the man's pocket. ELSA follows, taking off her coat. INDY</context>
      <utterance>And not before time! Did you intend to leave us standing on the doorstep all day? We're drenched!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY dabs at his nose with the handkerchief as ELSA looks on in amused amazement.</context>
      <utterance>Now look! I've gone and caught a sniffle.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you expected?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't take that tone with me, my good man. Now buttle off and tell Baron Brunwald that Lord Clarence MacDonald and his lovely assistant are here to view the tapestries.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BUTLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tapestries?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dear me, the man is dense. This is a castle, isn't it? There are tapestries?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a castle. And we have many tapestries. But if you're a Scottish lord, then I am Mickey Mouse.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simultaneously knocking the BUTLER cold with one slug on the jaw. The Butler falls against a wall tapestry, sliding down to the floor, out cold.</context>
      <utterance>How dare he?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY and ELSA continue down the hallway. Indy carries a gun in his hand and his whip hangs from his belt. He steps to a closed door and listens.</context>
      <utterance>Nazis. I hate these guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This one. I think he's in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY points out an ELECTRICAL WIRE.</context>
      <utterance>How do you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He studies the situation for a moment, then decides to enter one of the other doors. He knocks at the door—there is no response. He looks back at ELSA and enters.</context>
      <utterance>Because it's wired.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY reassures her.</context>
      <utterance>Indy? Indy?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans out the window and wraps his bullwhip around some wires that protrude from the castle wall above the next window. He gives the whip a forceful tug to make certain it will hold his weight.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry... this is kid's play. I'll be right back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY gets to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>Junior?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sirl</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is you Junior!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't call me that, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>NAZI VOICES ARE HEARD approaching. INDY and HENRY press themselves against the wall, Henry still holding the broken vase in his hand. INDY steps to the window and looks down. HENRY moves to a lamp, holding the vase under the light for a closer look.</context>
      <utterance>I came to get you! What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HENRY is all about the broken vase which he still holds in his hand. Father and son get onto crossed lines for a couple of moments.</context>
      <utterance>Late Fourteenth Century, Ming Dynasty.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, it breaks the heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the head.  You hit me, Dad!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll never forgive myself—</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry—I'm fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank God!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HENRY throws the vase against the wall where it SHATTERS.</context>
      <utterance>... it's fake. See, you can tell by the cross section.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! Dad, get your stuff. We've got to get out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I am sorry about your head, though. But I thought you were one of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, they come in through the doors.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good point. INDY steps to the door and stands, listening.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HENRY slides his umbrella through the straps of his bag.</context>
      <utterance>But better safe than sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Humpf—so I was wrong this time. But by God, I wasn't wrong when I mailed you my Diary. You obviously got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got it and I used it. We found the entrance to the catacombs.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Through the library?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew it. And the tomb of Sir Richard?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONTINUED:</speaker>
      <mode>3</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>INDY nods.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Found it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was actually there? You saw him?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what was left of him.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And his shield... the inscription on Sir Richard's shield...?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's a great moment in HENRY's life. He turns aside, lost to himself for a moment, then turns to INDY with joy.</context>
      <utterance>Alexandretta.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY winces, and would interrupt but suddenly it's not the moment.</context>
      <utterance>Alexandretta... of course... on the pilgrim trail from the Eastern Empire. Oh, Junior...</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... you did it.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Dad. You did. Forty years.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If only I could have been with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There were rats, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rats?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. big ones. What do the Nazis want with you Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They want my diary.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY's interest is a moment which becomes important later but for now it passes.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY's hand moves unconsciously to his pocket. His eyes turn inward.</context>
      <utterance>I knew I had to get that book as far away from me as I possibly could.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then... BAMI The door is kicked open and three NAZIS enter. One is an S.S. OFFICER. The other two are SOLDIERS with machine guns. HENRY and INDY raise their hands.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. . .</utterance>
   <speaker>S.S. OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doctor Jones!!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY &amp; INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes!!</utterance>
   <speaker>S.S. OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will take the book now.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY/HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What book?</utterance>
   <speaker>S.S. OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HENRY laughs genuinely, believing himself to be laughing at the expense of the</context>
      <utterance>You have the Diary in your pocket.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At which point an awful thought strikes HENRY.</context>
      <utterance>You doltl Do you think that my son would be that stupid that he would bring my Diary all the way back here?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't, did you?  You didn't bring it, did you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did!!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, can we discuss this later?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should have mailed it to the Marx Brothers.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you take it easy....!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take it easy?! Why do you think I sent it home in the first place?  So it wouldn't fall into their hands!!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I came here to save you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY's eyes blazes His nostrils flares He's so pissed off, he literally RIPS A MACHINE GUN from the hands of one of the startled soldiers... and for a moment we think he's going to use it on his dad.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah? And who's gonna come to save you, Junior??</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and sprays the room with machine gun fire, cutting all three NAZIS to ribbons and blowing them backwards across the room.</context>
      <utterance>I told you--</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HENRY looks shocked and horrified.</context>
      <utterance>--don't call me Junior!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy grabs him and pushes him ahead.</context>
      <utterance>Look what you did!!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe what you just....</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>VOGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's far enough Put down the gun, Doctor Jones. Put down the gun or the Fraulein dies.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But she's one of them!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Indy, please!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's a Nazi!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY is thrown. He doesn't know what to do. He looks at ELSA, then back to his father. Everyone is yelling at once:</context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trust me!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Indy, no!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will kill her!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah? Go ahead!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! Don't Shoot!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. He won't.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Indy, please! Do what he says!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And don't listen to her!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VOGEL jams the barrel of the luger painfully into ELSA's neck. Elsa SCREAMS.</context>
      <utterance>Enough! She diesl</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then Indy gives in. He drops the machine gun to the table and it slides across, SHATTERING GLASS. HENRY GROANS audibly. VOGEL releases his grip on ELSA and shoves her toward INDY. She is propelled directly into his arms. He holds her tightly. She buries her face in his chest.</context>
      <utterance>Wait! Waitl</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY comforts her.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her hand slips into his coat pocket and removes the Grail Diary.</context>
      <utterance>No, don't be.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She steps back next to VOGEL. INDY is stunned. HENRY gives him his most withering look of reprimand.</context>
      <utterance>But you should have listened to your father.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She ransacked her own room and I fell for it. How did you know she was a Nazi?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Umh?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you she was a Nazi?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY nods, and then the statement catches up with him. He looks at HENRY with surprise.</context>
      <utterance>She talks in her sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't trust her. Why did you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN CHAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The MAN IN THE CHAIR gets to his feet and turns, revealing himself to be... WALTER DONOVAN. INDY and HENRY react with stunned expressions.</context>
      <utterance>Because he didn't take my advice.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Donovan</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DONOVAN smiles benignly and flips through the Grail Diary.</context>
      <utterance>Didn't I warn you not to trust anybody, Doctor Jones?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I misjudged you Walter—I knew you'd sell your mother for an Etruscan vase. But I didn't know you'd sell your country and your soul to the slime of humanity.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ELSA rushes to DONOVAN's side. she takes the Grail Diary from him. Elsa takes a look for herself—then glances up at Indy.</context>
      <utterance>Doctor Schneider There're pages torn out of thisl</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This book contained a map—a map with no names—precise directions from the unknown city to the secret Canyon of the Crescent Moon.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So it did.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HENRY gives INDY a look of surprise. Indy smirks.</context>
      <utterance>Where are these missing pages? This maps we must have these pages backs</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HENRY now wears a pained expression.</context>
      <utterance>You're wasting your breath. He won't tell us. And he doesn't have to... it's perfectly obvious where the pages are...  ... he's given them to Marcus Brody.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marcus?! You didn't drag poor Marcus along, did you? He's not up to the challenge.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We'll find him.</context>
      <utterance>He sticks out like a sore thumb.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HENRY looks amazed and impressed.</context>
      <utterance>The hell you will. He's got a two-day head-start on you, which is more than he needs.  Brody's got friends in every town and village from here to the Sudan. He speaks a dozen languages, knows every local custom. He'll blend in. Disappear. You'll never see him again. With any luck, he's got the Grail already.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A Man in the crowd holds out a cup of water to BRODY.</context>
      <utterance>Does anyone here speak English? Or even ancient Greek?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BRODY continues through the crowd past various STREET VENDORS. A Woman holds a chicken out to him.</context>
      <utterance>No water, no thank you. No, fish make love in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Woman walks away, leaving BRODY alone in the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you so much. No, I don't like that. No, I really don't want... No, no, thank you very much. No, thank you, madam. I'm a vegetarian.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SALLAH shoulders his way through the mob toward BRODY.</context>
      <utterance>Does anyone understand a word I'm saying here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mister Brodyl They meet and hug, then begin to walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Sallahl What a relief!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marcus Brody, sir. And where is Indy?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, he's in Austria. A slight detour.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A Woman runs in and tugs on BRODY's coat. He waves her away.</context>
      <utterance>You are on your own?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, but don't panic. Everything's under control. Have you. . .have you arranged our supplies?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes, of course. But where are we going?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BRODY searches in his coat pocket for the map as a SINISTER MAN approaches.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, this map will show you. It was drawn by, uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>SINISTER MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BRODY puts the map back in his pocket. The SINISTER MAN clicks his heels and bows quickly.</context>
      <utterance>Mister Brody?</utterance>
   <speaker>SINISTER MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BRODY takes off his hat.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome to Iskenderun. The Director of the Museum of Antiquities has sent a car for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, what?... your servant, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I am his.</utterance>
   <speaker>SINISTER MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man turns and joins a SECOND MAN. BRODY and SALLAH follow them.</context>
      <utterance>Follow me, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My reputation precedes me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SECOND MAN overhears SALLAH. He and his companion turn quickly.</context>
      <utterance>There is no museum in Iskenderun.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Papers please.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Papers?  Of course.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BRODY does not run. SALLAH pats his clothing, searching for his papers.</context>
      <utterance>Run.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SALLAH laughs and pulls out a newspaper.</context>
      <utterance>Papers, sir. Got it here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BRODY looks confused. SALLAH shows the newspaper to the SECOND MAN.</context>
      <utterance>Just finished reading it myself.  Run!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Egyptian Mail. Morning edition.  Run!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SALLAH puts the newspaper in front of the SECOND MAN's face, then punches him through the newspaper.</context>
      <utterance>Did you say...? Uh, uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SECOND MAN falls, knocking over a vendor's stand. SALLAH and BRODY begin to run. SALLAH knocks the FIRST MAN into another vendor's stand. The STAND COLLAPSES on impact. SALLAH grabs BRODY and pulls him through the crowded streets.</context>
      <utterance>Run!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SALLAH points to a DARKENED DOORWAY, hung with a curtain, at the top of a ramp. BRODY runs up the ramp, throws back the curtain and disappears into the darkness.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay, quick, quick, quickl Hide in that doorl Hide in that door!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Intolerable.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doctor Schneider. Message from Berlin. You must return immediately: a rally at the Institute of Aryan Culture.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your presence on the platform is requested... at the highest level.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Herr Oberst.  I will meet you at Iskenderun.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands her the Grail Diary.</context>
      <utterance>Take this Diary to the Reich Museum in Berlin. It will show them our progress, ahead of schedule. Without a map, I'm afraid it's no better than a souvenir.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me kill them now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. If we fail to recover the pages from Brody, we'll need them alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DONOVAN leads VOGEL out. The NAZI GUARDS follow. Once they are gone, ELSA turns to INDY.</context>
      <utterance>Always do what the doctor orders.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY shakes his head "no."</context>
      <utterance>Don't look at me like that—we both wanted the Grail, I would have done anything to get it. You would have done the same.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She runs her hand down the side of his face. INDY pulls away. INDY and HENRY are still tied back-to-back of course. ELSA bends to speak quietly into INDY's ear... which is near enough to Henry's ear.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry you think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't forget... how wonderful it was.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles and kisses INDY passionately. HENRY glances back and looks rather disappointed. VOGEL appears to remind ELSA of her appointment.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you. It was rather wonderful.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doctor Schneider! Your car is waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ELSA exits. VOGEL stays behind for another moment.</context>
      <utterance>That's how Austrians say goodbye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>VOGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VOGEL punches INDY in the jaw. A hard and vicious jab that snaps Indy's head around.</context>
      <utterance>And this is how we say goodbye in Germany, Doctor Jones.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VOGEL exits. INDY shakes his head clear.</context>
      <utterance>Ohh. . .</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ooooh... I like the Austrian way better.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So did I.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's try and get these ropes loose. We've got to get to Marcus before the Nazis do!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That he would blend in. Disappear!</context>
      <utterance>You said he had two days' start.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy and Henry are pulling at the ropes with great urgency.</context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding?—I made that up! You know Marcus—he got lost once in his own museum!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HENRY is able to wiggle his hand towards Indy's coat pocket. INDY squirms his body around towards Henry's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Can you try and reach into my left jacket pocket?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What am I looking for?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My lucky charm.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Feels like a cigarette lighter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HENRY's fingers open the lighter and ignite the flame.</context>
      <utterance>Try and burn through the ropes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HENRY yelps as the cigarette lighter burns his hand. He drops the lighter to the floor. Henry kicks at the lighter, trying to reach it, but cannot. The rug starts to burn. INDY doesn't know it yet.</context>
      <utterance>Very good.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ought to tell you something.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't get sentimental now Dad— save it 'til we get out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The floor's on fire! See?!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What???</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the chair.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They begin to rock their chair legs, inching their way off the burning carpet.</context>
      <utterance>All right, movel Move! Rock your Chair. Do what I do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DONOVAN puts on his glasses to read the message.</context>
      <utterance>Etwas wichtig, mein Herr.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A RADIO OPERATOR steps forward with yet another written message for</context>
      <utterance>Well, we have Marcus Brody. But more important, we have the map.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RADIO OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aus Berlin, mein Herr.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The car drives off.</context>
      <utterance>"By the personal command of the Fuhrer. Secrecy essential to success. Eliminate the American conspirators."  Germany has declared war on the Jones boys.  Los fahren.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finally they turn their heads in the same direction.</context>
      <utterance>Dad!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Head for the fireplace!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BANGING, ROCKING and HOPPING their chairs, they work their way INTO THE FIREPLACE—the only safe place from the now ROARING FIRE.</context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy struggles to free his hands. His foot kicks out and accidentally hits a metal grill that operates a Secret Door.</context>
      <utterance>I think I can get these ropes off.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The fireplace floor rotates like a Lazy Susan and Indy and his father find themselves in the:</context>
      <utterance>Whoopsl</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY glances over his shoulder at HENRY.</context>
      <utterance>Our situation has not improved.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY's foot hits the grill again... and the fireplace rotates to:</context>
      <utterance>Listen Dad... I'm almost free.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now the RADIOMEN turn to see HENRY and INDY.</context>
      <utterance>Alarm!</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TWO NAZIS draw their revolvers and FIRE SEVERAL SHOTS at INDY and HENRY</context>
      <utterance>Schnel!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is intolerable!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY finally breaks free. And he immediately begins to untie his father.</context>
      <utterance>I'm out, Dad!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well done, boy!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HENRY looks horrified by what he's been forced to do as INDY searches frantically for an exit.</context>
      <utterance>Dead end.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY begins to run his hands over the walls—frantic.</context>
      <utterance>There's got to be a... a secret door around. A passageway or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HENRY sits on a chair which tips back, hitting the wall behind it. The floor at INDY's feet suddenly begins DROPPING AWAYI INDY grabs a railing to keep from falling, but loses his grip and plunges through the opening which has formed a SPIRAL STAIRCASE. He rolls down the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>I find that if I just sit down and think...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HENRY follows INDY down the staircase.</context>
      <utterance>... the solution presents itself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HENRY tosses his case at INDY who catches it and angrily throws it back to his father.</context>
      <utterance>Would you say this has been just another typical day for you? Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY moves back to the dock and pushes the boat away. HENRY looks confused.</context>
      <utterance>Ooofl No! It's been better than most.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Dad. Come onl</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the boat? We're not going on the boat?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ha!</utterance>
   <speaker>FOUR NAZI SOLDIERS ON MOTORCYCLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY turns the motorbike down a smaller, dusty tree-lined road. HENRY gasps as he is jostled about in the sidecar. One of the NAZI SOLDIERS gives chase along a higher road running in the same direction.</context>
      <utterance>They chase down the road after INDY and HENRY.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The motorbike skids to a stop.</context>
      <utterance>Stop! Stop!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going the wrong Way! We have to get to Berlin!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brody's this way.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My Diary's in Berlin.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcus has the map.</context>
      <utterance>You don't need the Diary, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is more in the Diary than just the map.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right Dad—tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, he who finds the Grail must face the final challenge.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What final challenge?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three devices of such lethal cunning.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Booby traps?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes. But I found the clues that will safely take us through, in the Chronicles of St. Anselm.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what are they? Can't you remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wrote them down in my Diary so that I wouldn't have to remember</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Half the German Army's on our tail and you want me to go to Berlin? Into the lion's den?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes! The only thing that matters is the Grail.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Marcus?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marcus would agree with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HENRY slaps him across the face. INDY is rocked to his foundations, not by any means entirely by the blow itself.</context>
      <utterance>Two selfless martyrs. Jesus Christl</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Do you understand me?</context>
      <utterance>That's for blasphemy. The quest for the Grail is not archaeology. It's a race against evil. If it is captured by the Nazis, the armies of darkness will march all over the face of the earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is an obsession Dad. I never understood it. Never. Neither did Mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yes, she did. Only too well. Unfortunately she kept her illness from me until all I could do was mourn her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Still startled, her reaction makes it clear that Indy is even now a lover in her thoughts.</context>
      <utterance>Fraulein Doctor. Where is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you get here?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY pushes ELSA against a column and begins to search her clothing for the Diary. He pulls the book from Elsa's pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Where is it? I want it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whv?</context>
      <utterance>You came back for the book?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She understands him. It's as though he slapped her.</context>
      <utterance>My father didn't want it incinerated.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that what you think of me? I believe in the Grail, not the Swastika.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yet you stood up to be counted with the enemy of everything the Grail stands for—who gives a damn what you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now it's as though she'd slapped him back. His hands fly to her neck.</context>
      <utterance>You do.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All I have to do is squeeze.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's a standoff emotionally. He knows he'd never do it. she knows it too. And the same goes for screaming. INDY releases her and backs away. she looks at him with a lover's pain. He moves over to HENRY.</context>
      <utterance>All I have to do is scream.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They move off and almost run headlong into HITLER and his entire entourage coming down from the Podium. 50 kids push their autograph books for Hitler's signature. HITLER pauses to sign them. Hitler looks Indy's way. They make eye contact. It only lasts a moment but the moment is electric. HITLER breaks the spell by taking the Grail Diary from him, opens it to the first page and signs his autograph. He hands it back and moves on.</context>
      <utterance>I've got it. Let's get the hell out of here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you get?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. The first available flight out of Germany.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY and HENRY show their papers to the Boarding Guards, then join the line of passengers, which has already begun to move toward a:</context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HENRY looks over his newspaper at INDY.</context>
      <utterance>Well, we made it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When we're airborne, with Germany behind us, then I'll share that sentiment.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But INDY looks out the window and is suddenly concerned when he sees:</context>
      <utterance>Relax.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGEL AND A GESTAPO AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>rushing across the tarmac toward the Zeppelin.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nicht zumachen! Wir steigen ein!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VOGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Passengers at the table shake their heads in the negative. VOGEL shows the picture to other Passengers.</context>
      <utterance>Haben sie disen Mann gesehen?</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE PASSENGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nein.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fahrscheine, bitte.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE PASSENGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VOGEL turns to see:</context>
      <utterance>Nein.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MALE PASSENGER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ich habe ihn night gesehen.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Passengers do not react to the request, made in English.</context>
      <utterance>Tickets please.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fahrscheine meine Dame. Bitte.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VOGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now INDY, still playing the role of Steward, asks VOGEL for his ticket.</context>
      <utterance>Guten Tag, Herr Jones.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fahrscheine meine Herr.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Weg.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HENRY looks confused.</context>
      <utterance>Tickets please.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VOGEL glances up and recognizes INDY—who quickly punches Vogel in the face, knocking him toward the window. In another quick move, Indy TOSSES HIM OUT THE WINDOW onto the tarmac below. Shocked Passengers blink in bewilderment.</context>
      <utterance>Was?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone else with a ticket quickly produces it and waves it in Indy's face.</context>
      <utterance>No ticket.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not all we shared. It's disgraceful. You're old enough to be her fa---er, her grandfather!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm as human as the next man.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was the next man.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HENRY opens his Diary and begins to thumb through it.</context>
      <utterance>Ships that pass in the night...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you remember the last time we had a quiet drink? I had a milk shake.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmmm... What did we talk about?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We didn't talk. We never talked.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And do I detect a rebuke?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A regret. It was just the two of us, Dad. It was a lonely way to grow up. For you, too. If you had been an ordinary, average father like the other guys' dads, you'd have understood that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, I was a wonderful father.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HENRY looks up from his Diary.</context>
      <utterance>When?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did I ever tell you to eat up? Go to bed? Wash your ears? Do your homework? No. I respected your privacy and I taught you self- reliance.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you taught me was that I was less important to you than people who had been dead for five hundred years in another country. And I learned it so well that we've hardly spoken for twenty years.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You left just when you were becoming interesting.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, how can you --?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He closes the Diary and leans back in his seat.</context>
      <utterance>Very well. I'm here now.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY stutters uncomfortably as HENRY stares at him, waiting for a response.</context>
      <utterance>What do you want to talk about? Hmmm?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... I can't think of anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what are you complaining about?  Look, we have work to do. When we get to Alexandretta we will face three challenges.  "First, the breath of God. Only the penitent man will pass. Second, the Word of God, only in the footsteps of God will he proceed. Third, the Path of God, only in the leap from the lion's head will he prove his worth. "</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. We'll find out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know you could fly a plane.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fly--yes. Land--no.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HENRY turns and grips the MOUNTED MACHINE GUN with a perplexed expression.</context>
      <utterance>Dad, you're gonna have to use the machine gun. Get it ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HENRY pulls out his watch.</context>
      <utterance>Eleven o'clock!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad—eleven o'clock!!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY uses his arm to demonstrate that he's referring to a direction and not a time.</context>
      <utterance>What happens at eleven o'clock?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HENRY does—and the EXPLODING GUN nearly shakes him out of his seat. Indy's slow speed and small size works to his advantage. The speeding Messerschmidts continually overshoot him, WHIZZING past in a blur—making wide turns miles away in the sky. HENRY has one of the Messerschmidts in his sight. He pulls back on the trigger</context>
      <utterance>Twelve—eleven—ten. Eleven o'clock. Fire!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, are we hit?!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More or less.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY looks back at the missing tail section, then at his father. The plane begins to go down. INDY struggles to control its descent.</context>
      <utterance>Son, I'm sorry. They got us.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HENRY slumps down fearfully in his seat.</context>
      <utterance>Hang on, Dads We're going in!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice landing.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, INDY's attention is directed to:</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWO SCREAMING MESSERSCHMIDTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As BULLETS EXPLODE around them, INDY and HENRY jump over a stone barricade. Henry, frightened, grabs at Indy.</context>
      <utterance>coming in low. Guns BLAZING.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those people are trying to kill us!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, Dadl</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a new experience for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It happens to me all the time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is intolerable!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This could be close.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DONOVAN and the SULTAN walk together through an archway.</context>
      <utterance>These pages are taken from Professor Jones' diary, Your Highness. And they include a map that pinpoints the exact location of the Grail.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As you can see, the Grail is all but in our hands.  However, Your Highness, we would not think of crossing your soil without your permission, nor of removing the Grail from your borders without suitable compensation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SULTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What have you brought?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TWO NAZI SOLDIERS bring forward a HUGE STEAMER TRUNK. They open the lid and begin to empty it of its contents: Gold and silver objects of every description.</context>
      <utterance>Bring den Schatzl</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SULTAN gets up from his chair and walks toward the trunk. He goes right past it and begins to inspect the Nazi staff car parked nearby.</context>
      <utterance>Precious valuables, Your Highness, "donated" by some of the finest families in all of Germany.</utterance>
   <speaker>SULTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SULTAN points to the engine under the hood.</context>
      <utterance>Rolls-Royce Phantom Two. 4.3 litre, 30 horsepower, six cylinder engine, with Stromberg Downdraft carburetor.</utterance>
   <speaker>SULTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can go from zero to 100 kilometres an hour in 12.5 seconds. And I even like the color.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The keys are in the ignition, Your Highness.</utterance>
   <speaker>SULTAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shall have camels, horses, an armed escort, provisions, desert vehicles—and tanksl</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somebody else is also taking note...and we see that it is KAZIM, the spy at the court. ELSA is revealed coming down the stairs toward DONOVAN and VOGEL.</context>
      <utterance>You're welcome.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have no time to lose. Indiana Jones and his father have escaped.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SALLAH waves his arms and shouts to a CAMEL HERDER.</context>
      <utterance>We go this way.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get that camel out of the way!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to Marcus, Sallah?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HENRY removes his hat and hits INDY with it.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, they set out across the desert this afternoon. I believe they took Mister Brody with them.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now they have the map! And in this sort of race, there's no silver medal for finishing second.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Care to wet your whistle, Marcus?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VOGEL snatches the canteen away from BRODY before he can drink.</context>
      <utterance>I'd rather spit in your face. But as I haven't got any spit...</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We must be within three or four miles. Otherwise we are off the map.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Marcus, we are on the brink of the recovery of the greatest artifact in the history of mankind.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HENRY and SALLAH are at INDY's side as he views Donovan's party in the distance. Parked nearby is a CAR containing all of their supplies.</context>
      <utterance>You're meddling with powers you cannot possibly comprehend.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then Donovan notices a reflection from the hills. What he sees is:</context>
      <utterance>Ah, I see Brody. He seems okay. They've got a tank. Six-pound gun.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Get down!</context>
      <utterance>What do you think you're doing?!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment the tank FIRES A SHELL in their direction. It WHISTLES overhead and BLOWS UP THE PARKED CAR. INDY, HENRY and SALLAH cover their heads as automobile fragments rain down upon them.</context>
      <utterance>Dad, we're well out of range.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That car belonged to my brother- in-law.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on--come on!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe it wasn't even Jones.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. It's him all right. He's here somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KAZIM peers over a rock, pointing his rifle at the group below.</context>
      <utterance>Put Brody in the tank.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Jones, all right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, who are all these people?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CUT BACK to the action. The BRETHREN are firing at the DONOVAN party and are being fired on by the Donovan party. TWO NAZI SOLDIERS throw HAND GRENADES into the cliffs. They EXPLODE, killing one of Kazim's Brethren. The battle continues—a fierce exchange of GUNSHOTS, GRENADES and MACHINE GUN FIRE with losses on both sides.</context>
      <utterance>Who cares? As long as they're keeping Donovan busy. Dad, you stay here while Sallah and I organize some transportation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going after those horses.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take the camels.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't need camels.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, Indy—</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No camels!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KAZIM dies.</context>
      <utterance>A messenger from God. For the unrighteous, the Cup of Life holds everlasting damnation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marcus!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arghhh! Oh!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now BRODY tugs his ears, flaps his arms and touches his head.</context>
      <utterance>"Genius of the Restoration—"</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"—aid our own resuscitation!" They exchange a handshake.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Henryl What are you doing here?!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As HENRY starts to climb out of the tank, TWO NAZI SOLDIERS DROP DOWN from above, their Lugers drawn. They are followed by VOGEL.</context>
      <utterance>It's a rescue, old boys Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The NAZI SOLDIERS point their guns at HENRY and BRODY.</context>
      <utterance>Search him.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VOGEL removes a glove and slaps HENRY with it.</context>
      <utterance>What is in this book? That miserable little Diary of yours!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slaps HENRY again.</context>
      <utterance>Here's the map. The book is useless, and yet you come all the way back to Berlin to get it. Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another slap.</context>
      <utterance>What are you hiding?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VOGEL reaches out to slap HENRY yet again, but Henry grabs his arm, stopping him.</context>
      <utterance>What does the Diary tell you that it doesn't tell us?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DONOVAN appears at the turret cover.</context>
      <utterance>It tells me that goose-stepping morons like yourself should try reading books instead of burning them.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Colonel? Jones is getting away.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think not, Herr Donovan.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not that Jones—the other Jones!</utterance>
   <speaker>NAZI SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Herr Colonel!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sallah, I said no camels! That's five camels. Can't you Count?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Compensation for my brother-in- law's car. Indy, your father and Brody—</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's my father?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY and SALLAH charge forward leading their horses and camels. Then VOGEL commands the Tank Driver to give chase.</context>
      <utterance>They have them. In the belly of that steel beast.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fire!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NAZI SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points his gun at HENRY and BRODY.</context>
      <utterance>Keine Bewegung.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAZI SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The smaller gun, blocked by the rocks, BACKFIRES, blowing the breech out into the face of the gunner, killing him and filling the tank with smoke. BRODY, HENRY, VOGEL and the driver begin to choke.</context>
      <utterance>Keine Bewegung.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad! Dad! Dad!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLOSE UP - VOGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hate-staring at INDY</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE UP - INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, from nowhere a German soldier flies INTO FRAME, tackling Indy.</context>
      <utterance>Hate-staring back at VOGEL.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drops the gun down into the tank.</context>
      <utterance>Dad!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VOGEL pulls INDY from the tank entrance, yanking on the chain wrapped around his neck.</context>
      <utterance>Dad! Dadl Get it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Henry, the pen—</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But don't you see? The pen is mightier than the sword.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look what you didl</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's war.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You call this archaeology?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY pulls HENRY and BRODY from the tank. VOGEL pulls himself back atop the tank armed again with the shovel which he swings at Indy, who ducks and grabs Vogel's arm.</context>
      <utterance>Get out of there, Dad!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As INDY winds up to punch VOGEL he catches BRODY in the face on the backswing, then completes the movement and knocks Vogel down.</context>
      <utterance>How does one get off this thing?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before INDY can answer, VOGEL is up and swinging with the shovel. Indy ducks but the shovel catches HENRY sending him over the side and onto the moving tread. INDY grabs his whip, knocking VOGEL aside. As HENRY speeds toward the front of the tank to certain doom, INDY, with lightning speed, whips out his bullwhip, wrapping the end of the whip around Henry's right ankle.</context>
      <utterance>Where's Marcus?!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HENRY is bouncing across the treads like a rag-doll. INDY struggles to hold onto the end of the bullwhip.</context>
      <utterance>Dad!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SALLAH draws his horse next to the treads. He tips his fez to HENEY.</context>
      <utterance>Hang on, Dad!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VOGEL now punches INDY in the back and grabs him around the neck. Still, INDY refuses to let go of the whip.</context>
      <utterance>Father of Indy—give me your hand!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sallah! Get Dadl SALLAH reaches out to HENRY.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SALLAH manages to hold onto HENRY as he brings his horse to a stop just at the cliff's edge. INDY finally frees himself of VOGEL's grasp, twisting his arm painfully away from Indy's neck, then landing a hard blow to Vogel's head.</context>
      <utterance>Give me your hand!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We HEAR the TANK EXPLODING.</context>
      <utterance>Junior?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Indy?!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then... looking dazed and bewildered, INDY STAGGERS UP BEHIND THEM. He joins the others at the edge of the cliff, looking down at the wreckage below with a bewildered expression. Finally, Henry becomes aware of his presence. HENRY says nothing. He just looks at Indy, overcome with emotion. Finally, he throws his arms around him.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, God. I've lost him. And I never told him anything. I just wasn't ready, Marcus. Five minutes would have been enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a moment, Indy's head clears. And he becomes aware of his father's embrace. Something he hasn't felt in a long time—if ever. And it touches him. He hugs his father back.</context>
      <utterance>I thought I'd lost you, boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BRODY and SALLAH are moved by this sudden reconciliation.</context>
      <utterance>I thought you had too, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HENRY pats INDY on the back and Indy collapses, sitting hard on the rocky cliff edge.</context>
      <utterance>Well—well done! Come on!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>INDY, HENRY, BRODY AND SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>react to the sight.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA AND DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She looks at him, horrified.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TWO NAZI SOLDIERS force another Turk forward. Suddenly... The SOUND OF RIFLE BOLTS being cocked. Everyone turns to discover INDY and his party surrounded by NAZI SOLDIERS. Indy's group are relieved of their guns.</context>
      <utterance>Helmut, another volunteer!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never expected to see you again.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm like a bad penny. I always turn up.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Step back now, Doctor Schneider. Give Doctor Jones some room. He's going to recover the Grail for us.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Impossible? What do you say, Jones? Ready to go down in history?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As what? A Nazi stooge like you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nazis?!—Is that the limit of your vision?! The Nazis want to write themselves into the Grail legend and take on the world. Well, they're welcome. But I want the Grail itself. The cup that gives everlasting life. Hitler can have the world, but he can't take it with him. I'm going to be drinking my own health when he's gone the way of the Dodo.  The Grail is mine, and you're going to get it for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shooting me won't get you anywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then DONOVAN shifts his aim, just a bit, and SHOOTS HENRY. The bullet enters his side below the ribs.</context>
      <utterance>You know something, Doctor Jones?... you're absolutely right.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad?!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Junior. . .</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!!</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HENRY collapses. Blood flowing from the wound. BRODY and SALLAH rush to his assistance.</context>
      <utterance>Get back!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="143" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>You can't save him when you're dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY takes in the situation. The two decapitated men lie a few yards in front of him. He walks to the entranceway, flanked by two stone lions. We get silent reaction shots—ELSA—SALLAH—BRODY—DONOVAN—registering their different emotions INDY proceeds forward. His hands open the Grail Diary.</context>
      <utterance>The healing power of the Grail is the only thing that can save your father now. It's time to ask yourself what you believe.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"The Breath of God... Only the penitent man will pass. Only the penitent man will pass. . . " INDY takes a few steps forward.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY stops. He is about to reach the spot where two men have just died. HENRY looks at INDY. Indy looks at Henry.</context>
      <utterance>"The penitent man will pass. The penitent man..."</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Only the penitent man will pass."</context>
      <utterance>"Only the penitent man will pass.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The penitent man will pass. The penitent... the penitent. The penitent man...</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY takes a step forward through the cobwebs.</context>
      <utterance>The penitent man. The penitent...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="144" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The penitent man is humble before God.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Penitent. Penitent...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cobwebs begin to move....</context>
      <utterance>The penitent man is humble...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear the awful rush of air—WHOOSH! Because INDY is in the act of kneeling, only his hat is knocked off and his hair flies in his face. Instinctively he ROLLS FORWARD on the ground out of harm's way and looks up. From his new position he is able to see what is causing all the trouble: A RAZOR</context>
      <utterance>He kneels before God.  Kneel!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="145" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BRODY and SALLAH smile, relieved.</context>
      <utterance>We're through!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HENRY shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>He's all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="146" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY pulls away some cobwebs to reveal a cobblestone path. Each cobble is engraved with a letter.</context>
      <utterance>"The second challenge is the Word of God. Only in the footsteps of God will he proceed."  The Word of God... The Word of...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Proceed in the footsteps of the Word."</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>lifts his head painfully.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Word of God...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Henry. Try not to talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Name of God...</utterance>
   <speaker>BACK TO INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>as he studies the cobblestones before him.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Name of God... Jehovahl</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="147" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>reacts.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh dear!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="148" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY looks around and then he notices that inscribed into the rock above his head is the head of a lion.</context>
      <utterance>"The path of flood. Only in the leap from the lion's head will he prove his worth."</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY looks down into the Diary and tortures over what it is asking him to do.</context>
      <utterance>Impossiblel Nobody can jump this!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>rushes forward and calls to INDY.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Come quickly!</context>
      <utterance>Indy... Indy, you must hurry!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="149" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's... a leap of faith. Oh, God.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>calls to his son.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see him do it. We see him leap into space. We see that he is in midair. We see that he is not going to make it. His hands claw for the opposite wall but he is going to fall 100 feet to his death. And then—he doesn't! He appears to be held up by thin air as he lands on his hands and knees. INDY looks around and down and now he figures it out. Ingeniously, the First Crusaders have painted a pathway to align with the rocks 100 feet below. It is a perfect forced perspective image of the rocks below with lines from a hundred feet continuing six feet below his sight line where his feet are stepping. It's painted to blend in with the rocks below. Highly evolved camouflage... in perfect alignment with everything we see below. When INDY leans out to the left or right... that's when he sees the perfect alignment shift that betrays the trick. Indy throws some dirt on the bridge and he crosses it like the first Crusader from the painting over Henry's desk. Indy crawls through a small opening in the side of the cliff and enters a Temple. A vast array of chalices is displayed on the altar of this small Temple. Perhaps a hundred or more. Many sizes, many shapes, some gold, some silver, but they all glitter and shine. INDY is mesmerized by their number and their beauty. And then he realizes that a man is praying at the altarl He has his back turned to INDY... but he is dressed as what he is! A GRAIL</context>
      <utterance>You must believe, boy. you must... believe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="150" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew you'd come, but my strength has left me.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The last of three brothers who swore an oath to find the Grail and to guard it.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was seven hundred years ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The GRAIL KNIGHT reaches forward and fingers Indy's clothing.</context>
      <utterance>A long time to wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're strangely dressed...for a knight.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not exactly...a knight. What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was chosen because I was the bravest and the most worthy. The honor was mine until another came to challenge me to single combat. I pass it to you who vanquished me. The GRAIL KNIGHT holds his sword out to INDY.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment DONOVAN and ELSA appear. Donovan turns to face the display of cups.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, I don't have time to explain, but—</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which one is it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="151" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must choose.  But choose wisely. For as the True Grail will bring you life— the False Grail will take it from you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not a historian. I have no idea what it looks like. Which one is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me choose.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ELSA and INDY exchange looks. He thinks he is seeing her in her true colors. ELSA chooses a cup—a solid gold, emerald encrusted goblet. DONOVAN instantly takes it from her.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DONOVAN rushes to the well and fills the goblet with water.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes. It's more beautiful than I'd ever imagined. This certainly is the cup of the King of Kings.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then, DONOVAN'S entire body starts to convulse. His face contorts in agony. He grabs his stomach and turns toward ELSA.</context>
      <utterance>Eternal life! DONOVAN drinks from the goblet.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to age—fast! His hair grows long and gray and brittle. His face sinks. Fingernails curl back on themselves. Milky cataracts coat his eyes. ELSA gasps and screams.</context>
      <utterance>What . . . is . . . happening. . . to . . . me. . .?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His skin turns brown and leathery and stretches across his bones until it splits. His skeletal hands reach for ELSA's throat, choking her.</context>
      <utterance>What. . . is . . . happening. . . ?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="152" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY studies the array of chalices.</context>
      <utterance>He chose...poorly.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY picks up another cup—a simple earthenware jug.</context>
      <utterance>It would not be made out of gold.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He and ELSA exchange a look.</context>
      <utterance>That's the cup of a carpenter.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY goes to the well and fills the earthenware jug with water, then pauses. INDY brings the jug to his lips and takes several large swallows. A strange sensation overcomes him, a feeling of peace and contentment...and we see his wounds begin to heal.</context>
      <utterance>There's only one way to find out.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CUT TO BRODY AND SALLAH who attend to Henry awaiting Indy's return. INDY and ELSA come forward with the Grail. The TWO NAZI SOLDIERS are over-awed by the possessors of the Grail. They put down their guns and kneel. INDY kneels by HENRY's side and tilts his head forward and holds the Grail to his lips. HENRY is too weak to even open his eyes. HENRY swallows some of the water. Much of it runs down the corners of his mouth. Finally INDY pours the water over the wound and everyone watches in astonishment as the wound and the blood stain disappear before their eyes. The color returns to Henry's face. HENRY's eyes open. The first thing he sees is the Grail and they light up. Then they shift to INDY's face—and they light up even more...</context>
      <utterance>You have chosen wisely. But the Grail cannot pass beyond the Great Seal. That is the boundary and the price of immortality.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAZI SOLDIERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>run forward. SALLAH points a rifle at them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The NAZI SOLDIERS drop their weapons at their feet and raise their arms in surrender.</context>
      <utterance>Drop your guns. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, come on. Get to your feet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="153" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ELSA steps onto the edge of the Great Seal.</context>
      <utterance>We have got it. Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elsa! Elsa, don't movel</utterance>
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's ours, Indy. Yours and mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A RUMBLING SOUND IS HEARD and the ground roars and shifts. Dirt falls from the ceiling of the cavern. ELSA falls on the Great Seal. The Grail bounces away from her grasp. She reaches for it and the ground beneath her begins to SPLIT OPEN. ELSA slips into the crevasse. She screams. ELSA is hanging perilously in the abyss, with the Grail almost within her reach. As her hands lose their grip, INDY just manages to one of them, he himself sliding forward across the slanted floor.</context>
      <utterance>Elsa, don't cross the Seal. The Knight warned us not to take the Grail from here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With her free hand, ELSA is trying to get the Grail. INDY can't save her unless she gives him her free hand. She has to choose.</context>
      <utterance>Junior! Junior!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elsa. Elsa don't. Elsa. Elsa. Give me your other hand, honey. I can't hold you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="154" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ELSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her hand begins to slip from Indy's grasp.</context>
      <utterance>I can reach it. I can reach it...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ELSA just manages to touch the Grail. In doing so, she has tipped the balance too far—INDY slides down another yard, Elsa loses her grip and falls screaming to her death.</context>
      <utterance>Elsa! Give me your hand. Give me your other hand!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now the ledge INDY lies upon begins to break apart. HENRY grabs one of his hands as Indy struggles to reach the Grail with the other.</context>
      <utterance>Elsa!!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I can't hold on!!</context>
      <utterance>Junior, give me your other hand!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY looks down into the black bottomless pit beneath him from which nothing can ever be retrieved.</context>
      <utterance>I can get it—I can almost reach it, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY snaps his look up to his father. His father has never called him this before.</context>
      <utterance>Indiana. Indiana!!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INDY abandons the Grail and grabs onto HENRY with both hands. HENRY pulls him up to safety.</context>
      <utterance>... let it go...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="155" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elsa never really believed in the Grail. She thought she'd found a prize.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did vou find, Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HENRY and INDY mount their horses. Henry turns back to his son.</context>
      <utterance>Me?... Illumination.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you find, Junior?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Junior?! Dad...</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please...What does it always mean, this...this "Junior?"</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's his name. Henry Jones, Junior.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like Indiana.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We named the dog Indiana.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May we go home now, please?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="156" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The dog!?  You are named after the dog...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A moment passes as they all ready their mounts and SALLAH continues to laugh at INDY.</context>
      <utterance>I've got a lot of fond memories of that dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Indy! Henryl Follow met I know the way!  Haaa!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got lost in his own museum, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After you, Junior.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir!  Haaa!</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
