<movie id="301" title="Indiana Jones and the Raiders of the Lost Ark">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Barranca looks evilly at Indy's hand upon him. Indy releases him and smiles in a friendly way.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Satipo watches this confrontation with some concern.</context>
      <utterance>We don't need them.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARRANCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do not carry supplies.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns back to the trail. Satipo gets the two remaining Indians moving behind Indy. Satipo and Barranca then have a fast, silent communication: Barranca indicates his desire to slit Indy's throat; Satipo gives him a look that says "Be patient, you idiot".</context>
      <utterance>We'll leave them. Once we've got it, we'll be able to reach the plane by dusk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SATIPO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Hovitos are near. The poison is still fresh... three days. They're following us, I tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two Indiana jabber in Quechua, near hysteria. Barranca is sweating profusely, eyes darting. He yells at the Indians in Quechua to "shut up". In the undergrowth, there is slithering movement. Indian 1 draws aside a branch and is faced with a horrific stone sculpture of a Chachapoyan demon. The Indian is so frightened no sound comes out when he screams. He turns and runs silently away. Indian 2 calls to his friend. Getting no response, he steps in that direction. A huge macaw, flushed from the undergrowth, screams and flies away. Indian 2 does exactly the same thing, never to be seen again. Indy, Satipo and Barranca, just clearing the trees, look back in that direction. They all turn to face the Temple. It is dark and awesome. Vegetation curls from every crevice, over each elaborate frieze. The entrance - round, open and black - has been designed to look like open jaws.</context>
      <utterance>If they knew we were here, they would have killed us already.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So this is where Forrestal cashed in.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATIPO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A friend of yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Competitor. He was good, very good.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy fixes them with an expectant stare. Satipo produces a similar, but folded, piece of parchment. He lays it - the other half of the floorplan - next to Indy's. They all regard it for a moment, then Indy stands and walks toward the Temple. Barranca's eyes are shining as they dart between the floorplan and Satipo.</context>
      <utterance>No one ever had what we have... partners.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATIPO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy looks him over, then nods. He frees the whip from Barranca's body and picks up the man. His eyes sweep the surrounding woods.</context>
      <utterance>I knew nothing! He was crazy! Please!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SATIPO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy picks up a stick and throws it through the shaft of light. Giant spikes spring together from the sides of the chamber with a ferocious CLANG! And impaled on the spikes are the remains of a white man, half-fleshed, half skeleton, in explorer-type grab. Indy reaches out and takes hold of the man's carcass. As the spikes slowly retract, Indy pulls it free and seats the remains gently on the floor.</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong? Are you lost?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forrestal.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATIPO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can go no further.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy steps sideways into the chamber. His back pressed against the very points of the retracted spikes, he moves along the edge of the light beam, and steps clear on the other side. Satipo grimaces and begins sweating his way through.</context>
      <utterance>Now, Satipo, we don't want to be discouraged by every little thing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lowers the torch to the floor of the landing. The landing is carpeted with human skeletons, one on top of another, all squashed flat as cardboard. Satipo gasps. Indy looks up at the ceiling of the landing, then steps onto skeletons, which make a cracking noise under his feet.</context>
      <utterance>Let me see that.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try not to touch the vines.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SATIPO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy stands still looking at the hall.</context>
      <utterance>Seor, I think we are very close.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATIPO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let us hurry. There is nothing to fear here.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They begin walking down the hall side by side. Satipo has inched a little ahead. Suddenly his lead foot comes down and through the floor! As Satipo begins to pitch forward, Indy grabs him by the belt and pulls him back. They both look down at the "floor". Indy swings his whip across the floor. Fifteen feet of it cuts open beneath the lash, falling away to reveal black pit as wide as the hall. The illusory floor was made of dust- covered cobwebs. Satipo picks up a stone and drops it down the pit. No sound. The two men exchange glances. Indy looks up at the high roof of the hall. He swings the whip up around a support beam, tests its strength with a pull and swings over the pit on the whip. From the other side he swings the whip back to Satipo, who throws Indy the torch. Satipo swings across. When they are both standing on solid floor there is a moment of quiet in which they hear, from far, far below - SPLASH! Indy wedges the whip handle into the wall and leaves it strung to the beam for quick retreat.</context>
      <utterance>That's what scares me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SATIPO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy kneels and uses the unlit end of the torch to reach out and tap a white tile. It is solid. He taps a black tile. There is a whizzing sound and a tiny dark sticks in the torch. Satipo points to the wall nearby: there is a recessed hole there.</context>
      <utterance>There's plenty of light, amigo.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATIPO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy nods, stands and looks around the sanctuary. The entire room is honey-comed with the same kind of hole. Satipo sees it too and is properly impressed.</context>
      <utterance>From that hole!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wait here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATIPO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Torch in hand, Indy begins his careful walk across the sanctuary. Stepping only on the white tiles, he almost appears to be doing a martial arts kata. Before each big move he waves the torch in front of him head to toe, looking at the flame. Halfway out, he sees something on the floor and kneels to look at it. A dead bird lies on one of the white tiles. Its body is riddled with little deadly darts. This has great significance to Indy and he stands with even greater caution. He waves the torch ahead of him and at waist height an air current whips at the flame. Indy ducks under it and leaves a burn mark on the white tile beneath it. Satipo watches, wide-eyed and mystified. Indy reaches the altar. The tiny idol looks both fierce and beautiful. It rests on a pedestal of polished stone. Indy looks the whole set-up over very carefully. From his jacket he takes a small, canvas drawstring bad. He begins filling it with dirt from around the case of the altar. When he has created a weight that he thinks approximates the weight of the idol, he bounces it a couple times in his palm concentrating. It's clear he wants to replace the idol with the bag as smoothly as possible. His hand seems ready to do that once, when he stops, takes a breath and loosens his shoulder muscles. Now he sets himself again. And makes the switch! The idol is now in his hand, the bag on the pedestal. For a long moment it sits there, then the polished stone beneath the bag drops five inches. This sets off an AURAL CHAIN REACTION of steadily increasing volume as some huge mysterious mechanism rumbles into action deep in the temple. Indy spins and starts his kata back across the sanctuary at four times the speed. Satipo's eyes widen in terror. He turns and runs.</context>
      <utterance>If you insist, seor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SATIPO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy hesitates, eyeing the rumbling walls.</context>
      <utterance>No time to argue. Throw me the idol, I throw you the whip.</utterance>
   <speaker>SATIPO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy concurs with that assessment. He tosses the idol across the pit to Satipo. Satipo stuffs it in the front pocket of his jacket, gives Indy a look, then drops the whip on the floor and runs.</context>
      <utterance>You have no choice! Hurry!</utterance>
   <speaker>SATIPO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy grimaces. He had a feeling this might happen. He looks around.</context>
      <utterance>Adios, amigo!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BELLOQ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Belloq extends his hand. Indy looks at it, then produces the idol and hands it to Belloq. Belloq extends his other hand, smiling. Indy hands over his gun. Belloq sticks it in his jacket.</context>
      <utterance>Dr. Jones, you choose the wrong friends. This time it will cost you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLOQ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you thought I'd given up.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too bad they don't know you like I do, Belloq.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLOQ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kill him!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't mind him. That's Reggie. Wouldn't hurt a soul.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't stand snakes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The world's full of them, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate them.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on now, Sport, show a little of the old backbone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think the idol will ever show up?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy snaps the book closed and puts it on the shelf. He takes his glasses off and focuses on Brody. At the windowed door to his office, two pretty Coeds pause for a moment, look in at their sexy Archeology professor, giggle and disappear.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Just because Belloq had it doesn't mean he kept it.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A young male graduate student, Indy's TEACHING ASSISTANT, taps on the door and then pushes his way in with an armload of reference books. Indy helps him find a spot for them.</context>
      <utterance>Getting it away from those Indians would be a neat trick  I hope they got him.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEACHING ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I couldn't get the McNabe, Professor. Someone's got it checked out 'til next month when classes start.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all right, Phil. Thanks a lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEACHING ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will there be anything else?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Teaching Assistant leaves. Brody is scowling as he examines the last of the artifacts.</context>
      <utterance>No. I'll see you Thursday.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, if you don't like them, I can always return them.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, they're beautiful. The Museum will buy them as usual. No questions asked.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I brought along some people today.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of people?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Government.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Government?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, it's not about your business.  They're from the Army.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've already served.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Army Intelligence. They're looking for Abner.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="37">
   <speaker>MUSGROVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you did study under Professor Ravenwood at the University of Chicago?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We haven't spoken in ten years. I'm afraid we had a bit of a falling out.</utterance>
   <speaker>EATON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know nothing of his whereabouts?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Musgrove and Eaton exchange a look; they're disappointed.</context>
      <utterance>Just rumors. Somewhere in Asia, last I heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSGROVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... you must understand, Dr. Jones, this is all strictly confidential.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSGROVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Musgrove takes a sheet from his briefcase.</context>
      <utterance>Yesterday, one of our European sections intercepted a Nazi communiqu from Cairo to Berlin. We don't quite know what to make of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSGROVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here it is - "Tanis development proceeding. Acquire headpiece, Staff of Ra, General Tengtu Hok, Shanghai. Locate Abner Ravenwood, U.S." Brody is excited. He looks at Indy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy contemplates this big news; he's impressed.</context>
      <utterance>Tanis. They must have discovered the lost ruins.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tanis. Ain't that somethin'!</utterance>
   <speaker>EATON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frankly, we're a little suspicious... An American being mentioned so prominently in a secret Nazi cable.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, Ravenwood's no Nazi.</utterance>
   <speaker>EATON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what do they want him for?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're looking for the headpiece to the Staff of Ra.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSGROVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it says here that's in China.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only half of it. Ravenwood had the other half.</utterance>
   <speaker>EATON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What would the Nazis want with this - this Staff of Ra?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can tell you that. Over the last two years the Nazis have had teams of archeologists running around the world looking for all kinds of religious artifacts.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSGROVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. Hitler's a nut on the subject. Crazy. He's obsessed with the occult.</utterance>
   <speaker>EATON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this Staff of Ra, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now it's the Army men who are impressed.</context>
      <utterance>It all has to do with the Ark of the Covenant.  The chest the Hebrews used to carry around the Ten Commandments.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy moves to the blackboard and makes a quick sketch to give a rough idea of the system as he describes it. (and we get a glimpse of what an interesting and enthusiastic teacher he must be).</context>
      <utterance>An Egyptian pharaoh stole the Ark from Jerusalem and took it back to the city of Tanis. A short time later, Tanis was consumed by the desert in a sandstorm that lasted a year. But before that, the Pharaoh had had the Ark hidden away in a secret chamber called the Well of the Souls. Which is where the Staff of Ra comes in.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now this was rather clever. The Staff was really just a big stick - oh, I don't know, say like this -  no one really knows for sure. Any way, it was capped by an elaborate headpiece with a carving of the sun at the top. What you had to do was take the Staff to a special map room in Tanis - it had the whole city laid out in miniature on the floor. When you placed the Staff in a certain spot in this room, at a certain time of day, the sun would shine through a hole here in the headpiece and then send a beam of light down here - to the map - giving you the location of the Well of the Souls...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSGROVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...where the Ark of the Covenant was kept.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which is probably what the Nazis are after.</utterance>
   <speaker>EATON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this Ark look like?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy pulls a big format book from the stack on his lectern and flips through the pages until he finds a large color print. The other men gather to look.</context>
      <utterance>Look like? Why, it's right here...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE PRINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It shows a Biblical battle. The Israelite Army is vanquishing an opposition force. At the forefront of the Israelite ranks, two men carry the Ark of the Covenant, a beautiful gold chest, crowned by two sculptured gold angels. The men do not touch the Ark itself; rather they carry it by use of two long wooden poles which pass through rings in the corners of the Ark. The painting is very dramatic, full of smoke, tumult and sinewy dying men. But the most astounding thing in the picture is the brilliant jet of white light and flame issuing from the wings of the angels. It pierces deep into the ranks of the retreating enemy, wreaking devastation and terror.</context>
      <utterance>Fills the screen.</utterance>
   <speaker>EATON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good God!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. That's what the Hebrews thought.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSGROVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that supposed to be coming out of there?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who knows... lightning... fire... the power of God.</utterance>
   <speaker>EATON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm beginning to understand Hitler's interest in this thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eaton and Musgrove exchange worried looks.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yes. The Bible tells of it leveling mountains and wasting entire regions. Moses promised that when the Ark was with you, "your enemies will be scattered and your foes fell before you".  An army which carries the Ark before it is invincible.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, there's one other thing that Hitler undoubtably believes about the Ark...  It's said that the Lost Ark will be recovered at the time of the coming of the True Messiah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSGROVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Jones, you've been very helpful. I hope we can call on you again if we have questions.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody and Indy exchange a look as they all shake and Brody starts to leave with the Army men.</context>
      <utterance>Most certainly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got to talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't really a good time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Indy, it's important.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. Come on in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They want you to go for it. And they'll pay.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good work, Marcus. I had a feeling this would happen. And, of course, the Museum gets the Ark when we're done.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy's manner is vigorous, aggressive.</context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, here's the way it's gonna be. First, I'll high-tail it to Shanghai and get the piece from General Hok. Then I think I know where I can find Ravenwood. If only I can get -</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>General Hok's a tough customer. They don't call him the Wild Boar for nothing. And he's tied in with the Japanese.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll worry about that when the time comes. My only hope is to find the Well of the Souls before the Nazis do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KEHOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buzz Kehoe, Army Intelligence. You've met Bang Chow.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the hurry?</utterance>
   <speaker>KEHOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some German agents got here two hours ago. Luckily, Bang was able to have them detained at Customs. We'll have to hurry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KEHOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus! Are you all right!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kehoe guns it, throwing Indy back against the cushions.</context>
      <utterance>Great. Got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEHOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What now?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got to get to Nepal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="68">
   <speaker>SHERPA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gmoiska! Shurga rintoik!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLIMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The bar has quieted ominously and so we hear with startling clarity when - a door behind the bar slams open with a huge BANG! and some Presence, too small to be seen as it moves through the forest of towering patrons, makes a beeline for the troubled corner of the bar. A path clears for it. The Sherpa and the Climber are about to kill each other when the Presence arrives directly between them: she is MARION RAVENWOOD, twenty-five years old, beautiful, if a bit hard- looking. At this moment, however, that look does not hurt. She is not intimidated by the combatants; she jabs accusatory fingers into their chests. She is angry as hell. The patrons shrink under her gaze.</context>
      <utterance>Aye! That'll be your last word.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The place clears quickly. Stragglers and grumblers are given special attention by Marion and Mahdlo, who has come from behind the bar carrying a big axe handle. Mahdlo herds the crows out the front door as Marion turns and walks behind the bar. A scowl on her lovely face, she has just begun clearing the bar of glasses when she notices one remaining Patron huddled over a glass at the far end of the bar. Grimacing in exasperation, she heads that way like a locomotive.</context>
      <utterance>That does it! I've been patient with you no-goods long enough. I'm not open at 2 o'clock for myself, you know. It's all for you. And how do you repay me: Trouble and noise and blood on my floor! I won't have it. Everybody out! Out! Out! We're closed. Closed! Do your killing outside! And don't leave any bodies on the porch!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is almost on him when Indy looks up smiling. Marion stops, stares, shocked.</context>
      <utterance>Hey you, deaf one! I said out of my place. I don't mean next Easter, I mean now -</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hits him with a solid right to the jaw, knocking him off the barstool on the floor. He rubs his jaw and smiles up at her.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Marion.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice to see you, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get up and get out.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take it easy. I'm looking for your father.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mahdlo is hesitant, but lays the axe handle on the bar and goes out. Indy has been barely aware of him. Now he settles again on the barstool. Marion has a vindictive look. She'll let him stay, but she wants to inflict as much pain as possible.</context>
      <utterance>Go home, Mahdlo. I'll see you tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Avalanche. Up there. He was digging. What else? He spent his whole life digging. Dragging me all over this rotten earth. For what?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you find him?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly the hardness cracks. She is on the verge of tears and does not want him to see them. She turns away and takes a whiskey bottle from the shelf, then turns back to pout herself a drink.</context>
      <utterance>Hell no. He's buried where he was working. Probably preserved real good, too. In the snow.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not a bad way to go. Doing what he loved.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks around the saloon.</context>
      <utterance>Don't give me that stuff! What do you know?  I'm the one that was left in a bad way. He didn't have a penny. Guess how I lived, Mister Jones. I worked here. And I wasn't the bartender.  Finally the guy that owned the joint went crazy. Snow crazy. They took his away screaming. As they dragged him out, he said the place was all mine for life.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you imagine a more evil curse?  So far, it's working.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not leave? Go back to the States.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll go back. I'll get there. Not that there's a soul there who knows my name or cares. But I'll go. And when I do, they'll know me. 'Cause I'm going to go back in style. With money. A goddamn lady!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you gonna get it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy looks at her, thinking. Under his gaze, she blushes, for reasons only she understands. She looks into her glass and, for a moment, she softens.</context>
      <utterance>If I knew that, you think I'd still be running this dive?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy takes a long time to answer.</context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you something Indy. I've learned to hate you in the last ten years. But somehow, no matter how much I hated you, I always knew that someday you'd come through that door. I never doubted that. Something made is inevitable.  Why are you here... now... tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion's eyes go icy. She swings at him again with her right, but this time he catches her at the wrist. Then he stops her left, which she has brought up to slap him.</context>
      <utterance>I need one of the pieces your father collected.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You son-of-a-bitch! You know what you did to me, to my life? This is your handiwork.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never meant to hurt you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was a child!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You knew what you were doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was in love.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess that depends on your definition.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy releases her arms.</context>
      <utterance>It was wrong. You knew it.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I did what I did. I don't expect you to be happy about it. But maybe we can do each other some good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why start now?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This stops her.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up and listen for a second. I want that piece your father had. I've got money.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enough to get you back to the States. Where are his things?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gone. I sold it all. It was all junk. The junk he wasted his life on.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion nods.</context>
      <utterance>Everything?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy feels tired, defeated. Marion is pleased.</context>
      <utterance>That's too bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy has to smile at her glee.</context>
      <utterance>You look disappointed. I like that. How's it feel?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you drinking?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seltzer.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pours herself another as Indy watches, amused.</context>
      <utterance>Real man's drink. Me, I like scotch. And I like bourbon. And vodka and gin. I'm not much for brandy. I'm off that.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a tough broad now, aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's no act, pal. This ain't Schenectady.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion looks at him thoughtfully, takes a drink.</context>
      <utterance>I can only say I'm sorry so many times.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really have money? You don't look rich.  I may be able to locate some of his things. I know who's got them. What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion thinks, nods slowly.</context>
      <utterance>A bronze piece, about this size. In the shape of the sun. Probably broken off at the bottom. Has a little hole in it, off-center. Does that sound familiar?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know where it is?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe. How much?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three thousand. American.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That'll get me back, but not in style. This doodad must be pretty important.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A huge smile lights up Marion's face.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew it would happen eventually. I knew it. Something had to go my way.  I've got to think this out. I'm used to bargaining with yaks.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, five thousand. That's all I can give you now. I can get you more when you land in the States.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You word, huh?  Just like you said you'd be back last time? That was your word too.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion sneers and they smile together.</context>
      <utterance>I'm back, aren't I?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can trust me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come back tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy nods, gets up to go.</context>
      <utterance>Because I said so, that's why. It's about time I called the shots in this relationship.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy thinks about this a moment, then reaches inside his shirt and pulls cash from a money belt. He lays five grand on the bar.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute. Leave the five thousand here.  You want trust, give some. I want to smell your money.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I trust you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're an idiot.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy starts for the door. Marion takes another think. She is getting high.</context>
      <utterance>I've heard that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold it. Come here.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bossy, aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy looks into her eyes, then leans over the bar and kisses her deeply. When the kiss ends, their faces are very close. Marion is flushed. She liked it and would like more. She raises her glass between them to discipline herself.</context>
      <utterance>That's right. Give me a kiss.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy smiles and walks to the front door. Then, without looking back -</context>
      <utterance>Get out of my place.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's gone. Marion stares after him, thinking. She takes a drink. Then slowly, her hand comes up to loosen the scarf that is draped around her throat. It falls away, revealing her graceful neck above the dipping top of her blouse. Hanging there on a gold chain against her white skin is a sun-shaped golden medallion. The bottom looks broken off. Marion lifts the medallion so she can see it in her hand, then looks thoughtfully after Indy.</context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>BELZIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good evening, Fraulein.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The bar's closed.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELZIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Mongolian and the Nepalese poke around, checking to make sure there's no one else there. Down at the end of the bar, the medallion lies partially hidden by surrounding glasses and bottles. The Second Nazi stops very near it, but turns his back to it to face Belzig and Marion.</context>
      <utterance>We are not thirsty.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELZIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>The same thing your friend Dr. Jones wanted. Surely he told you there would be other interested parties.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELZIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, the man is nefarious. I hope for your sake he has not yet acquired it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, are you willing to offer more?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELZIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Almost certainly. Do you still have it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Belzig's smile fades at this news. He's not a patient sort. Marion is chilled by the look. She turns and moves to the shelf of bottles behind her, reaching high for one, very near the large stuffed raven. He hand lingers there a moment and we see - From an angle behind the stuffed raven, that the left wing spread hides a Baretta automatic pistol. Marion's hand is very near it, but withdraws with only a whiskey bottle as the Mongolian walks toward her behind the bar. Marion opens the bottle before Belzig, who watches her intently.</context>
      <utterance>No. But I know where it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Second Nazi lights up at this suggestion. Belzig gives him a withering look.</context>
      <utterance>How 'bout a drink for you and your men?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELZIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We will stick to the business at hand, Fraulein.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELZIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid an auction is not possible.  Your fire is dying here, Fraulein.  Why don't you tell us where the piece is right now?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Belzig, still looking in the fire, sneers and shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, Herr Mac, I don't know who you're used to dealing with, but no one tells me what to do in my place.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELZIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He motions with his hand. The Mongolian moves up behind Marion and lifts her roughly over the top of the bar, knocking over bottles and spilling liquor. He deposits her on the other side, where the Nepalese and the Second Nazi flank her and hold her cruelly, arms behind her back. Marion raises a ruckus. Belzig turns from the fireplace. In his hand is the poker, its end glowing orange. He advances on Marion. Marion stops yelling, her eyes widen in terror.</context>
      <utterance>Americans! You're all alike. Fraulein Ravenwood. I'll show you want I'm used to.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait! I can be reasonable -</utterance>
   <speaker>BELZIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The glowing poker point moves inexorably across the room toward Marion's face.</context>
      <utterance>That time is passed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't need that. I'll tell you everything!</utterance>
   <speaker>BELZIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Belzig has no intention of stopping now. The glowing tip is approaching Marion's face. The Nepalese watches with savage glee. The tip of the poker is five inches from Marion's nose when there is a loud CRACK! and the fall of Indy's bullwhip wraps around the middle of the poker and tears it out of Belzig's hands. The poker sails high across the room, free of the whip, and lands in the heavy curtains that cover one window. The curtains immediately burst into flame. The four Bad Men look in surprise toward the front entrance. Indy is poised there, the whip in his right hand, a .45 automatic raised toward them in his left.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I know you will.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now everything begins to happen very fast - The Mongolian had just come around the bar at the end opposite the medallion. He dives back to crouch behind the end of the bar, raising his submachine gun. Belzig and the Second German dive behind tables near the bar. The Nepalese is slower to leave Marion, he draws a Luger. Indy's .45 barks and the Nepalese dies spinning against the bar. Indy fires in the direction of the Mongolian. Marion swings up over the top of her bar. Belzig fires at her, but his bullets smash bottles behind the bar and thud into the raven. Marion flattens out on the floor behind the bar as bullets hit above her. She reaches up, snatches the axe handle from where Mahdlo left it, and begins crawling down the length of the bar toward - The Mongolian, who sticks his submachine gun out and fires blindly in Indy's direction. Indy is in a crouch behind a table, trying to get a shot at someone. He doesn't notice in the din and confusion when the door bursts open. An incredible, fearsome GIANT SHERPA, almost seven feet tall, soars in and tackles Indy from behind. The whip flies from Indy's hand as he and the Giant Sherpa roll across the floor, upsetting furniture. The Mongolian, seeing this, stands up confidently. Marion rises behind him and bashes him over the head with the axe handle. He goes down and out. Fire has completely engulfed the curtains and is working across the ceiling on decorative yak skin bunting. A burning fragment drops to the top of the bar, which immediately lights up, fueled by the spilled alcohol. Full whiskey bottles explode like Molotov cocktails. Rolling on the floor, Indy and the Giant Sherpa are fighting for control of Indy's .45. Belzig sees this and shouts to the Second Nazi, who is rising from cover with submachine gun in hand.</context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELZIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shoot them both!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND NAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's our man!</utterance>
   <speaker>BELZIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both the Giant Sherpa and Indy hear this. The Giant Sherpa exchanges an alarmed look with Indy and together they swing the .45 around toward the surprised Second Nazi. Two blasts blow him away. That done, Indy brings a brass spittoon down on the Giant Sherpa's wrist and the .45 slides away. Indy jumps up and kicks the Giant Sherpa, who barely seems to feel it. He grabs Indy and flips him effortlessly onto a table. Belzig now has a clear shot at Indy. He raises his luger. Marion, at the end of the bar, finally gets the hand of the Mongolian's submachine gun. It roars to life in the general direction of the ceiling. Belzig runs for cover as Marion gets control of the gun and levels it. Belzig dives around the end of the bar opposite Marion. When he has set himself, he peeks up over the edge of the scorched bar. The alcohol fire has moved down the bar and now, much to Belzig's surprise, he finds himself staring at the fire-blackened sun-shaped medallion! His eyes widen. He cannot believe his good fortune. Without hesitation he picks up the metal medallion, palming it. Immediately there is a sickening searing sound and Belzig's expression changes from joy to agony. He screams in pain and tries to shake the red-hot medallion from his skin. Marion opens up and the bar starts to splinter in front of Belzig. The medallion comes free of Belzig's hand and rolls across the floor. Belzig has had enough. In excruciating pain, he turns, sees a window, runs and dives through the glass. An exhausted Indy uses his whole body to upend the Giant Sherpa, who lands hard on his back. They are surrounded by flames.</context>
      <utterance>Do as I say!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the end of the bar, the Mongolian has come back to life. He shakes out his head, then reaches inside his coat and pulls out a Mauser pistol. Indy smashes a chair over the head of the Giant Sherpa and the huge creature goes down. The Mongolian points his Mauser through the smoke and flame at Indy. Suddenly, the Mongolian is shot dead. Marion stands beneath her stuffed raven with the Baretta. Indy moves quickly through the flames, his eyes scanning the floor. He picks up his bullwhip and his crumpled felt hat. He peers through the smoke till he spots Marion moving among the burning furniture.</context>
      <utterance>Unbelievable!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's get out of here!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not without that piece you want!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion nods, kicks aside a burning chair. Another burning beam falls from the roof. Indy pulls Marion close to him protectively.</context>
      <utterance>It's here?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He begins dragging her out.</context>
      <utterance>Forget it! I want you out of here. Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She breaks away from him, darts back and picks the hot medallion up in the loose cloth of her blouse.</context>
      <utterance>There!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You burned down my place!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I owe you plenty!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You owe me plenty!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're something!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am something. And I'll tell you exactly what - She holds up the medallion possessively.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm your partner!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FAYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The gaggle of grinning off-spring parts to reveal in their midst - a MONKEY. It is munching some flat Arab bread.</context>
      <utterance>Silence!  Why do you forget yourselves?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All the children chatter their innocence at once. The Monkey chatters too; it's an entertainer. The Monkey jumps from the children's table to the adults' and struts slowly up toward Marion, who thinks it's the cutest thing she ever saw. When it reaches her, it takes off its turban and does a deep, grand bow to her. She is delighted and takes the Monkey into her arms. The Monkey kisses her cheek. The children laugh.</context>
      <utterance>What is this? Who brought this animal in?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, thank you. I like you too.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then it shall be welcome in our house.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, no! You don't have to have it around if you don't want it -</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All of Allah's creatures are welcome here. You please us by letting us please you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew the Germans would hire you, Sallah. They couldn't have an excavation in the desert without the best digger in Egypt.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All Arabs look alike to them, Indy.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me about the map room at Tanis.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We found it three days ago. I broke through myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those Nazis are moving awfully fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy reacts.</context>
      <utterance>The Frenchman is helping them.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Belloq. So he got away from the Indians. This is going to be more interesting that I thought.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid this has put the Germans close to finding the Well of the Souls.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even Belloq won't be able to find it without that. Can you make anything of those markings? They're nothing I'm familiar with.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I know someone who might. You can go to see him tomorrow.  Indy... something bothers me.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sallah finds it hard to say. When he finally speaks, his words are accompanied by a strange, eerie, foreboding rush of wind through the courtyard. Just a coincidence we might suppose.</context>
      <utterance>What is it, my friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The wind dies down. Indy shakes off a chill and stares thoughtfully at his friend.</context>
      <utterance>It is the Ark. If it is there, at Tanis... It is not something man was meant to disturb... Death has always surrounded it. It is not of this earth.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you really need that monkey?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm surprised at you, Indy. Talking that way about our baby. He's got your looks, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Indy and Marion turn a corner, the Monkey seems to notice something and immediately jumps from Marion's shoulder and hurries off at a frantic pace down the street.</context>
      <utterance>And your brains.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Hey!... where're you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'll be OK. Come on. Come on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy catches a dagger-wielding Bad Arab around the legs with the whip and flips him. Marion is reluctant to leave Indy.</context>
      <utterance>Run! Get out of here!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion goes. She runs off between two buildings. A Bad Arab takes off after her. Monkey Man, now standing at the edge of the square, points at Marion. The Monkey jumps off his shoulder and follows Marion.</context>
      <utterance>Go, dammit! Go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>ARAB BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The gentleman in the corner sent it. He would like you to join him.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Belloq.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLOQ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good evening, Dr. Jones.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ought to kill you right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLOQ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy knows its true; that's what's tearing him up.</context>
      <utterance>It was not I who brought the girl into this dirty business.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLOQ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy sits, glancing at the German Henchmen, who settle nearby, just out of earshot.</context>
      <utterance>Sit down, please, before you fall down. We can behave as civilized people. I'm afraid it will be your last opportunity.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not a very private place for a murder.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLOQ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These Arabs will not interfere in the white man's business. They do not care if we kill each other off.  Terribly difficult finding a decent vintage here. You were quite vigorous in Shanghai. Unfortunately, our friend the Wild Boar had taken the precaution of making several copies of the piece. Indy registers this as he takes a drink. Belloq watches him with disdainful amusement.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLOQ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How odd that is should end this way for us, after so many... stimulating encounters. I almost regret it. Where shall I find a new adversary so close to my own level?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try the local sewer.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLOQ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you despise me. We always hate in others that which we most fear in ourselves. And you and I are very much alike.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you're getting nasty.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLOQ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a certain amount of truth to this; the recognition of it flickers across Indy's bleary eyes. Belloq sees it there.</context>
      <utterance>We have always done the same kind of work. Our methods have not differed as much as you pretend. I am a shadowy reflection of you. But it would have taken only a nudge to make you the same as me, to push you out of the light.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLOQ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Belloq leans forward, eyes shining, voice suddenly different.</context>
      <utterance>You know it to be true! How nice. And how ironic the timing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLOQ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you realize what the Ark is?  It's a transmitter. A radio for talking to God! And now it is within my grasp.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Belloq glances into the gloom at the German Henchmen.</context>
      <utterance>What about your boss, der Fuhrer? I thought he was waiting to take possession.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLOQ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When the time is right. When I am finished with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope your friends are patient. Dangerous work, Belloq.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLOQ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Very. You may consider yourself fortunate that your involvement concludes here.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me, did you get away with the idol?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLOQ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy takes a drink.</context>
      <utterance>I was lucky to get away with my life. The Hovitos proved quite narrow-minded about the whole matter.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, if it's God you want to talk to, maybe I can arrange it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE SON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uncle Indy, we have been looking for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE DAUGHTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly the Arab patrons of the bar take an intense interest in the situation, shifting their weapons.</context>
      <utterance>Come home now, Uncle. Hurry!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy stands up. The German Henchmen and poised. Belloq eyes the Arab patrons and signals for the Henchmen to relax.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Yes, I'll come now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLOQ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The children usher Indy out.</context>
      <utterance>Next time, Indiana Jones, it will take more than children to save you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought we would find you there.  Better than the United States Marines, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks you.  Marion's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy looks back there, nods.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I know. I am sorry.  More reason than ever to beat the bastards.  Life goes on, Indy.  There is the proof.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have much to tell you, Indy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And they made the calculation in the map room?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This morning. Belloq and the boss German, Shliemann. When they came out of the map room, we were given a new spot in which to dig... out away from the camp.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men go and huddle over the old man. The Monkey peeks up over the edge of the table at the array of food. He picks up a date and disappears below the table. Amir points to some markings on the lower part of the headpiece.</context>
      <utterance>Come. Look.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a warning... not to disturb the Ark of the Covenant.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Monkey's paw comes up over the edge of the table and grabs another date.</context>
      <utterance>Just want I need.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How 'bout the height of the staff? Did Belloq get it off of there?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy, nervous, goes back to the food tray, picks up another date. When he turns back to the men, the Monkey's paw grabs another date. We see the headpiece in closeup on the table. Amir's crooked fingers trace a line of markings along the bottom section to the break in the piece.</context>
      <utterance>Yes... it is here.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It says it is... ten jamirs high...</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About seventy-five inches.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amir's finger moves across the break as the markings continue on the sun medallion.</context>
      <utterance>Wait! I am not finished...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sallah nods.</context>
      <utterance>You said their top section was blank. Are you absolutely sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sallah and Indy begin to laugh. Amir gives them a glance and returns to his wine. Sallah leans over and kisses the old man.</context>
      <utterance>Belloq's staff is seven and a half inches short. They're digging in the wrong spot!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bad dates.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There! That is the map room!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What time does the sun hit the map?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just after eight.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sallah points out into the desert a short way beyond the main area of activity. The desert turns to sand dunes out there, the surface undulating into the distance. Several trucks and men are out there and a bulldozer is lumbering noisily toward it.</context>
      <utterance>We haven't got much time. Where are the Germans digging for the Well of the Souls?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JEEP GERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Sallah jumps about three feet. The JEEP GERMAN is standing in an open space ten yards away looking at Sallah.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! You, the skinny one!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP GERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sallah gestures his innocence.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, you. What are you doing there?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP GERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Jeep German starts back toward his major concern: his jeep is stuck in some sand beyond the next tent. Some Arab Workers are trying in vain to budge it. Now another German has backed his truck up to it. Sallah can think of nothing to do expect obey. With a worried glance at the map room, be begins untying the rope from the oil drum.</context>
      <utterance>Well bring that rope over here, you cur.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HUNGRY GERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>He points to the kettle. Sallah looks frantically from the rope, back to the skylight of the map room, to the kettle of food.</context>
      <utterance>Bring us some of that!</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNGRY GERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sallah picks up some serving pieces and gets to work.</context>
      <utterance>Now, idiot!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More waiting. Nothing. Indy looks around for some alternative means of escape. The room doesn't offer any. He looks up at the skylight again.</context>
      <utterance>Sallah.  Sallah!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long pause. Then something comes down. A makeshift rope. Really just a bunch of clothing tied together - tunics, robes, pants. But what we see first and most prominently, the first section of Indy's escape rope, is a bright Nazi flag. Indy beams and climbs.</context>
      <utterance>Sallah!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HUNGRY GERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Sallah glances at Indy, Then hurries back in that direction. The Hungry German focuses on Indy.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, you! More water over here!</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNGRY GERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy bows in wild subservience and hurries off in the opposite direction.</context>
      <utterance>Why aren't you at the digs? Come here!</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNGRY GERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, dummkopf, I said come!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I though you were dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were throwing me around like a rag doll.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They must have switched baskets. Thank god for that! Bless those bastards. Have they hurt you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy pulls out a knife and then stops suddenly, thinking.</context>
      <utterance>No. Not since I got here. They just asked about you - what you knew. The Frenchman's got the hot's for me. I've been playing that along. Oh, Indy, get me out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to leave you here for a little while. I know where the Ark is. If I take you out of here they'll start combing the place for us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cut me loose!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep your voice down.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy pops the gag back in her mouth. Her eyes widen in fury and she grunts obscenities at him.</context>
      <utterance>I said get me out of -</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her forehead, jumps up and hurries out of the tent.</context>
      <utterance>Look, you don't know how glad I am to see you. And I don't like doing this. But the whole thing will be shot if you don't just sit here quietly. They haven't hurt you in the last twenty-four hours, they aren't going to start now. I'll be back to get you in no time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BELLOQ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I cautioned you about being premature with that communiqu to Berlin. Archeology is not an exact science. If does not adhere to time schedules.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHLIEMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Fuhrer is not a patient man. He demands constant reports and he expects progress. You led me to believe -</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLOQ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing. I have made no promises. I said only that it looked very favorable. Perhaps the Ark will still be found in an adjoining chamber. Based on the information in our possession, my calculations were correct. Perhaps some bit of evidence still eludes us. Perhaps</utterance>
   <speaker>GOBLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Belloq shoots him an angry look.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps the girl can help us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHLIEMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My feeling exactly. She was in possession of the original piece for years. She may know much.  If properly motivated...</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLOQ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tell you, she knows nothing useful.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHLIEMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shliemann signals Gobler, who steps outside the tent a moment, calls someone and then reappears. Belloq looks warily at the entrance. After a moment Belzig enters, reeking villainy. When his eyes find Shliemann, his superior, he snaps a crisp "Heil, Hitler!" at him, holding his palm rigid a long time, exposing a burned scar in the prefect shape of the sun medallion.</context>
      <utterance>I'm surprised to find you squeamish. That is not your reputation. But it needn't concern you. I have the perfect man for this kind of work.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a moment of this, he stops. He gathers his energy and resolve and gets back to the task.</context>
      <utterance>Why snakes? Why did it have to be snakes? Anything else.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Where Indy's torch had landed is a circle of snake-free floor. The snakes hate the flame; they stay away.</context>
      <utterance>Asps. Very dangerous.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lots of torches. And oil. I want a landing strip down there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BELLOQ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Believe me, you made a mistake. If you would just give me something to placate them. Some bit of information.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He wants to believe her.</context>
      <utterance>I swear to you, I know nothing more. I have no loyalty to Jones. He's brought me only trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLOQ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion's frightened look shifts suddenly to the entrance of the tent. There are new arrivals there - Shliemann, Gobler and Belzig. Belzig carries a black leather case. He steps forward and smiles at Marion.</context>
      <utterance>I cannot control them.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELZIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We meet again, Fraulein.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The wooden crate stands open next to the stone chest. Now Indy extracts the wooden poles from its rings and begins fitting them through the rings in the Ark. This takes some maneuvering by the two men, but soon they are able to lift the Ark clear of the stone chest and into the wooden crate. They extract the poles, fasten the top of the crate and stick the poles through the rings of the wooden crate. They start back toward the space under the hole. The fire strips have begun to dwindle, as have some of the torches. The snakes move slowly in toward the clear spaces. Indy and Sallah eye them nervously as they hurry along with their heavy load. Under the hole, they hurriedly attach ropes to the wooden crate and it is pulled up. Indy's concentration is on the tide of snakes.</context>
      <utterance>Don't touch it! Never touch it!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sallah takes the next rope and climbs quickly out of the Well. Indy has picked up a torch and now throws it at a pool of snakes who are too close for his comfort. He turns and takes hold of the exit rope. He gives it a first tug and it falls down into the Well, landing partly beyond the ring of fire where is instantly disappears in a tangle of angry, hissing asps. Indy looks up at the hole.</context>
      <utterance>Hurry up! Why did it have to be snakes?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smiling down at him from the perimeter of the entry are Belloq, Shliemann and Gobler.</context>
      <utterance>What the -</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLOQ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Belloq and the Germans laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Why, Dr. Jones, whatever are you doing in such a nasty place?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you fellows come down here? I'll show you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLOQ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No thank you, my friend.  I think we are all very comfortable up here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>SHLIEMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Belzig and the Nazi move Marion to the hole and, to Belloq's surprise, push her in. Marion falls thirty feet screaming. Indy drops his torch, braces, and catches her! Her weight knocks him to the ground, almost into the snakes. She looks around at the snakes, clinging to him more desperately as he struggles to his feet trying to unload her.</context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid we must be going now, Dr. Jones. Our prize is awaited in Berlin. But I do not wish to leave you down in that awful place...  ...all alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't put me down! Up at the hole, there's plenty of dissension.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLOQ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The girl was mine!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHLIEMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shliemann glances meaningfully around at the other Nazis.</context>
      <utterance>She is of no use to us. Only our mission for the Fuhrer matters.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHLIEMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Belloq feels how much he is the outsider, his own vulnerability. He backs down with the wisdom of survival. He turns to look down at Indy and Marion. His manner is gallant.</context>
      <utterance>I wonder sometimes, Monsieur, if you have that clearly in mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLOQ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Belloq and the others step back from the hole and unseen Nazis slam the heavy stone door into place. Marion screams. Her scream is accompanied by - A huge WHOOSH! as air is sucked out and the chamber is sealed. Half of the torches still burning go out with the sound. The remaining torches continue to extinguish at punctuating intervals throughout the following action and the snakes immediately flood into the newly-darkened spaces. Indy puts Marion down and snatches up two burning torches. He hands one to Marion.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, mademoiselle.  Indiana Jones... adieu!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy holds his torch out like a lantern and begins a slow O- turn, his eyes peering into the gloom, examining every inch of wall and ceiling.</context>
      <utterance>Don't panic. There's plenty of time for that later. Wave that at anything that slithers.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reminded of the encroaching snakes, Marion waves her torch at the nearest edge of their circle. She looks faint. Indy continues his slow turn.</context>
      <utterance>Just watch the floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever you're doing, do it faster.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His head whips around, looking at the pillars around the room. He sees what he wants. He grabs one of the oil canisters, looks back to the spot on the wall he's chosen and splashes oil on the floor in that direction, then lights it. A path opens toward that wall.</context>
      <utterance>There!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion is frozen in her spot. Indy drags her after him. He splashes oil the rest of the way to the wall. It lights and Indy pulls Marion over to the wall. He pours the remaining oil in a circle around them, creating a safe zone there.</context>
      <utterance>Come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay here!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion looks at the wall, which looks like all the rest to her. She thinks he's crazy.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be back in a minute. We're going through this wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just keep your eyes open and get ready to run. No matter what happens to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Snakes are moving in force up the pillar toward Indy's dwindling torch. Indy grasps the pillar for dear life, grimaces with exertion and pushes against the wall with all he's got. The pillar begins to break loose of the ceiling, then stops. Indy's eyes are on the torch. It is just a spot of flame now. Snakes are sliding up toward his hands. Indy again pushes against the wall and the torch falls out of his mouth. The pillar goes! In the dim light, we see it fall like a tree directly at Marion. Indy rides it down. The top hits the wall three feet from a cringing Marion and smashes through to a black chamber beyond. Indy flies off into the darkness. Gone. Marion clutches her torch at the black hole.</context>
      <utterance>Where are you?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a moment that seems an eternity, then Indy appears like an apparition out of the void.</context>
      <utterance>Indy! Where are you?! Please Lord!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs her and helps her over the remains of the wall into -</context>
      <utterance>Come on!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The snakes... are they here?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess not. I think I'd be dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know where you're going?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank god. Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They round a corner and flush a covey of bats. Marion screams.</context>
      <utterance>Out.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion gives him a look. They round a corner and begin a walk through a maze of chambers that present for their inspection: moldering mummies and stacked sarcophagi; a room decorated with a thousand human skulls; a wall crawling with huge scarabaeid beetles. Marion is quite naturally a nervous wreck; she jumps when Indy grabs her suddenly and points.</context>
      <utterance>Don't do that. It scares me.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GOBLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the distance, the Flying Wing lands and rolls toward the men. Gobler spins and heads back toward the main camp, which is hidden from view by a rise. Indy and Marion watch him go.</context>
      <utterance>Get is gassed immediately! It has an important cargo to take out!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>already going to be on that plane. The Flying Wing rolls up into the space near the fuel trucks. The German Mechanic puts blue blocks in front of the tires as the engines continue to roar. Indy and Marion run in a crouch to a hiding spot closer to the plane, near the supply tent. Suddenly, a Second German Mechanic appears behind them. He is as surprised as they are, but recovers quickly and swings a big monkey wrench at Indy. Indy grabs the swinging arm and the two men tumble out into the open, wrestling. Marion remains hidden, moving fast among the crates. The first German Mechanic, who is just pulling the fuel hose from the tank truck to the plane, sees the combatants and runs to help his countryman. He is almost upon them when Indy puts the Second German away with a devastating left - right - left combination. He turns to find the first German Mechanic flying at him. The roll toward the rear of the Flying Wing and its lethally spinning reversed propellers. In the cockpit of the Flying Wing, the Pilot has been fiddling with his gauges just prior to shutting off his engines. Now he notices the fight going on outside. The fistfight between Indy and the German Mechanic has taken on a new stomach-tightening dimension. The men are fighting and flailing in and out between the spinning props at the back of the plane's wings. Each man comes within inches of becoming instant mincemeat. The Pilot slides away the top of his cockpit and stands up. He pulls a Luger from his side and points it, waiting for a clear shot at Indy. The German Mechanic kicks Indy away from him and the Pilot aims his pistol. Suddenly, Marion appears behind the Pilot, standing on the opposite wing, and bashes him over the head with one of the blue blocks that was holding the tires. The Pilot drops down into the cockpit, his body falling on the throttle. The engines roar louder, revving up. The plane begins to roll, rotating around its one still- blocked set of tires. Marion grabs onto the cockpit to keep from slipping into the props. She bends into the cockpit, trying to pull the Pilot's body off the throttle. No luck. She grimaces and climbs inside. Her shoulder bumps the top of the cockpit; it slides tightly shut above her. Under the moving wing, Indy delivers a knockout rightcross to the German Mechanic which sends him staggering back toward a roaring propeller. Indy's grimace registers the man's demise and a fine mist of blood wafts toward him. Indy spins toward the sound of crumpling metal and sees - The other prop of the Flying Wing slice into a tank truck. The airplane fuel inside floods out onto the pavement, surrounding the plane. Indy backpedals away from the plane, his eyes searching the scene for Marion. Suddenly, he is shocked to see her in the cockpit. He runs toward her, skidding through the gasoline.</context>
      <utterance>When the Ark gets loaded, we're</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion is struggling with the top of the cockpit. She can't budge it. She's trapped.</context>
      <utterance>Get out! Get out!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SHLIEMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sabotage!</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLOQ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We must get the Ark away from this place immediately!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHLIEMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gobler snaps his heels, turns to go.</context>
      <utterance>Have it put on the truck. We'll fly out of Cairo.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHLIEMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I want plenty of protection. Gobler nods and runs off. Shliemann heads back toward camp. Belloq hesitates a long moment, studying the burning wreckage with an odd, suspicious look. Finally, he turns and leaves, passing a nearby stack of barrels. When he has passed, Sallah appears from among the barrels. He searches the crowd for his people and starts a broken field run along some tents to avoid a group of Germans and is running flat-out when someone sticks out a leg and sends him flipping. Sallah, dust all over his face, looks angrily toward the concealed culprit. At once, a flashing white grin splits his darkened face. Indy and Marion, splotched with soot and oil, are hiding in the flap of a tent. Sallah runs into their arms and the three embrace warmly. When they break -</context>
      <utterance>And Gobler -</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy smoke, my friends! I am so pleased you are not dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Us too.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Ark! They're taking it on a truck to Cairo.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sallah gestures to follow and all three run off stealthily through the mostly deserted camp.</context>
      <utterance>Where is it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You two get back to Cairo quick and get us transportation to England - a plane, a ship, anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about you?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sallah nods. Marion looks at him like he's nuts. Indy jumps up, looks around desperately.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to get that truck. I'll meet you at Omar's. Be ready for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you going to get that truck?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs away between two tents.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I'm making this up as I go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a feeling I'm not the first woman to travel with these pirates. There's a whole wardrobe in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy sits on the cot, takes off his boots. He leans back against the wall and rubs his eyes. Marion sits on the bed, leans back against the wall with him and looks down at her white nightgown. She chuckles.</context>
      <utterance>It's lovely.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel like a virgin bride in this.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what you look like.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are some things you can recapture in this life, but that isn't one of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What would you like to recapture?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He watches her closely as she drains her glass and puts it down.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing. That is the way it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns so their lips are very close.</context>
      <utterance>Did I ever say I was sorry I burned down your tavern?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Then again, I burned up that plane.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You saved my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you saved mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seems things have worked out kind of even.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the way I like them.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion thinks about this a long time.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe we should consider all past accounts closed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks into his eyes. A smile jumps from her lips to his. He kisses her and they sink slowly to the cot.</context>
      <utterance>What else?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The engines have shut down.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to find out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATANGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Katanga turns quickly, pointing with a sweeping hand. Indy looks. Arrayed in a rough semicircle around the ship are ten German Wolf Submarines. All of their deck guns are manned and trained on the Bantu Wind. Worse, at least five heavily- armed boarding parties in rafts are closing quickly on the ship.</context>
      <utterance>You have most important friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATANGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I sent my man for you. You and the girl must disappear. We have a place in the hold. Go, my friend!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SHLIEMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take it aboard the Wurrfler!</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLOQ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Ark is taken away.</context>
      <utterance>And be very careful!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHLIEMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Jones?</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not a trace yet, sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>KATANGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jones is dead. Belloq and Shliemann regard him suspiciously.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATANGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We killed him. He was of no use to us. The girl, however, has certain value where we are headed. She will bring a very good price. If that cargo you have taken was your goal, then go in peace with it. But leave us the girl. It will reduce our loss on this trip.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHLIEMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Belloq steps forward and puts a proprietary hand on Marion's arm, fixing Shliemann with a steady look.</context>
      <utterance>Savage. You are not in a position to ask for anything. We will take what we wish and then decide whether or not to blow your ship from the water.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLOQ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shliemann considers.</context>
      <utterance>That girl goes with me. It will be part of my compensation. I'm sure the Fuhrer would approve.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLOQ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This appeals to Shliemann's nature. He signals his agreement with a gesture. Belloq ushers Marion away with her two keepers.</context>
      <utterance>If she fails to please me, you can do with her as you wish.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>THE WURRFLER'S CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shliemann nods and continues to stare at the Bantu Wind, as does the Captain. The Pirate crew is all lined across the bow. Towering above the others, standing on the rail, proud and defiant, is Katanga. Shliemann looks at the Wurrfler's Captain a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Colonel Shliemann, all torpedoes are loaded.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHLIEMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think, Captain?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WURRFLER'S CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shliemann mulls this, then turns to the hatch.</context>
      <utterance>I think not, Colonel. Nothing is to be gained. We are not at war.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHLIEMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shliemann disappears down the hatch. The Captain is very pleased. A Radioman speaks into his headset, then follows the other Aides down the hatch. In the distance the other subs begin to move away from the ship. The Captain, alone on the bridge, looks once more at Katanga. On the Bantu Wind, Katanga executes what might be taken for a salute. The Wurrfler's Captain smiles, salutes crisply, then goes below, pulling the hatch closed. Immediately, the Wurrfler begins to move. And as it does, we see the rail at the aft of the main deck. From nowhere, a wet sleeve appears and a hand grabs the rail! Indy pulls his dripping body onto the sub's main deck. He has lost his felt hat once and for all. Other than that, his outfit is the same as always, just wetter. Suddenly, water is washing over his feet; the Wurrfler is beginning to submerge. Indy runs through quickly deepening water toward the haven of the conning tower. Halfway there, he slips and goes down. Only by grabbing the base of the aftmast light does he keep from being swept away. He struggles to his feet and sloshes through knee-deep water to the base of the conning tower. Indy climbs the ladder to the bridge of the conning tower and looks down. The water is rising toward his fast. Indy climbs the ladder to the top of the turret and braces himself between the two uprights there - the 7 foot radio mast and the 20 foot periscope. Still the ocean comes up to meet him. Soon the top of the turret is under water and the radio mast is disappearing. Indy shifts his grip to the periscope, working his way up it and hanging on for dear life as the ocean whips at his body. The periscope is quickly going under. Indy hangs on to the top three feet, all that remains above. The forward movement of the sub continues, but, to Indy's slowly dawning delight, the dive stops. No more of the periscope goes under. Indy smiles; it's a pretty good smile, too, given the circumstances. Indy pulls out his bullwhip and begins tying himself to the periscope.</context>
      <utterance>...yet. Let the vermin live. We must be on our way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TALL CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The tents have been arranged in accordance with your radioed instructions, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLOQ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shliemann looks a little unhappy about this exchange, but says nothing. The group moves swiftly toward the end of a mine train arrangement. The train, consisting of small, separate, electric-powered cars, sits on a track which disappears into a tunnel cut in the rock. On the turret of the Wurrfler, the Wurrfler's Captain lights a cigarette as he watches the mine train disappear, then returns his attention to the activity on the dock. He leans idly against the periscope, his head two feet below Indy's dangling whip. Something catches his eye, he yells an order and climbs down from the turret to deal with the matter. We hold on the whip for a long moment, until its owner's hand appears and quickly reclaims it.</context>
      <utterance>Good. We must take the Ark there now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHLIEMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am uncomfortable with the thought of this -  Jewish ritual. Are you sure it's necessary?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLOQ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me ask you this - Would you be more comfortable opening the Ark in Berlin - for the Fuhrer - and finding out only then if the sacred pieces of the Covenant are inside? Knowing, only then, whether you have accomplished your mission and obtained the one, true Ark? Shliemann doesn't like any of his alternatives. He looks at Belloq with some suspicion as the train comes into bright light.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shliemann makes it clear to the other Nazis that Indy is to be obeyed.</context>
      <utterance>Hold it.  One move from anybody and I blow that box back to Moses.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLOQ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jones, your persistence surprises even me. You are going to give mercenaries a bad name.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about you? Talked to God yet?  Where's the girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHLIEMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doctor Jones, surely you don't think you can escape from this base.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That depends on how reasonable we're all willing to be. All I want is the girl. We'll keep possession of the Ark only till we've got safe transport to England. Then it's all yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHLIEMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we refuse?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Tall Captain flies out of the silk and takes Indy down by the neck. The bazooka clatters across the cement floor as two other Nazis help subdue Indy. The three Nazis take Indy's pistol from his holster and raise him roughly in their grasp.</context>
      <utterance>Then the Ark and some of us are going up in a big bang. I don't think Hitler would like that a bit. Now I don't want to talk about this anymore. Show me that girl in five seconds or -</utterance>
   <speaker>SHLIEMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jones, this is the second time I have seen you looking very foolish.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shliemann draws his Luger.</context>
      <utterance>It's a bad habit. I'm trying to break it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHLIEMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shliemann raises the pistol.</context>
      <utterance>I'll help you. This time I'll kill you myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLOQ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shliemann eyes Belloq, then the Ark. He lowers the pistol, motions for the Nazis to take Indy out ahead of him. They stop a moment only when Belloq speaks.</context>
      <utterance>No! Not in the presence of the Ark! Take him outside.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLOQ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Indiana Jones, I salute you. I am even a little sorry you will miss this moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shliemann motions them out and follows. Belloq turns back to the Ark, raising the ivory rod.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks. If you talk to Him, tell Him I'm on my way up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The far side of the Tabernacle burns completely away, revealing Marion, tied spread-eagle between two upright posts. Her nightgown is now in tatters, black with soot. She is gagged, but her eyes are screaming, focused on the flaming river of black oil which is about to engulf her feet. Indy rushes toward her, unaware of a uniformed Nazi who has appeared from the flames. Marion looks up to see Indy and the Nazi leveling his submachine gun at Indy. She motions desperately with her eyes. Indy dives and rolls through the flames just as the Nazi opens fire. From the floor, Indy blasts the Nazi. The river of burning oil is only a foot from Marion. Indy jumps up and runs toward the bound Marion, his bayonet aimed directly at her. Her wide eyes flash between the flames and the shining blade. Expertly, Indy slashes down both sides at Marion, cutting all four bindings. Marion falls backwards, away from the flames, but before she hits the ground, Indy is there, catching her in his arms. They embrace. They kiss. They break.</context>
      <utterance>Marion! Marion, can you hear me? Suddenly, Indy looks as -</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Indy! Thank god you're here.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy rises, pulling her up with him. The Tabernacle is burning away so fast that soon Indy and Marion will be completely exposed. Indy rushes over and grabs the submachine gun and a Luger from the dead Nazi.</context>
      <utterance>Glad I could make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's get out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy stops, startled by her spunky attitude. He's considering their changes.</context>
      <utterance>What about the Ark?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you game?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell yes! We've made it this far.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They approach the altar through the dying flames, Indy slinging the submachine gun over his back. The long carrying poles are still in place.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Let's do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion nods. Each taking an end with the poles, they lift the Ark from the altar and lower it to the floor. Marion grunts under the weight. Indy registers this, hands her the submachine gun. He pulls out his whip, motions her back, and sweeps the whip tightly around the body of the Ark. The whip wraps snugly around the plaiting and Indy ties it off. The Ark is now harnessed to the whip handle. Indy gives it an experimental pull and the Ark slides across the smooth cement. Indy indicates the direction of the second train tunnel.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever you do, don't touch it. Let's put it on the floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll go down that side. Shoot anyone who looks at us crosseyed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SHLIEMANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A dozen Nazis spin and look at the mine car. Marion is just leveling the submachine gun. Indy pushes forward the throttle and the mine car moves toward the tunnel, picking up speed. As the Nazis raise their guns to fire, Marion and Indy both open up, peppering the area with lead. As the mine car is about to disappear into the tunnel -</context>
      <utterance>Stop them! Kill them!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the car disappears, bullets pock the entrance of the tunnel. Shliemann runs up with three Nazis. They jump into the next mine car and take off, disappearing into the tunnel. Over at the burning stack of goods, some terrified fire- fighters scurry away as the burning pile of general goods falls over onto the stack of cartridge boxes. The wooden boxes immediately start burning. Many of the Nazis just want to get out of there, but a couple of disciplined OFFICERS are trying to salvage the situation. They point to the far side of the court, the walls are lines with oil and gas drums.</context>
      <utterance>Get down!</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We must cover the drums! Protect them from the bullets!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>MUSGROVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've done your country a great service.</utterance>
   <speaker>EATON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And we trust you found the settlement satisfactory?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quite.</utterance>
   <speaker>EATON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good, good.  Then I guess that about does it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eaton's glance flicks over to the mysterious Bureaucrat, then back to Brody.</context>
      <utterance>When can we have the Ark?</utterance>
   <speaker>EATON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought we answered that. It's someplace very safe -</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a powerful force. Research should be done -</utterance>
   <speaker>EATON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, it will be, Dr. Jones, I assure you. We have top men working on it right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>EATON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy exchanges a look with Brody.</context>
      <utterance>Top men.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We may be able to help.</utterance>
   <speaker>EATON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We appreciate that. And we won't hesitate to call on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSGROVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy looks them over coldly. He gets up, sullen.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you all. Thank you again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy stops, looking across the river, his mind occupied.</context>
      <utterance>Well they aren't going to tell you, so why don't you just forget it. I'd think you'd had enough of that damn Ark. Just put your mind on something else.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion makes a face, then puts her arms around his neck and plants a humdinger of a kiss on his mouth. It goes on a while. Finally they break.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They move down the steps, smiling.</context>
      <utterance>It's not the Ark... but it'll have to do.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
