<movie id="299" title="Indiana Jones IV">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MACGOWAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need your assistance!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Mac... It's the first bite I've had all week...</utterance>
   <speaker>MACGOWAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana STRUGGLES a bit longer with the line. But his conscience prevails and Indy DROPS the fishing pole. With a GRUMBLE, he ROWS back to shore.</context>
      <utterance>Please... It's very importantl...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you value our friendship, Mac?</utterance>
   <speaker>MACGOWAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More than me' nightly pint.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then this better not be some wild goose chase...</utterance>
   <speaker>MACGOWAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a sudden SCREAM! One of the villagers STUMBLES UPON something. Everyone GATHERS around the villager. A CORPSE lies before them. The body has a somewhat rubbery appearance, as if all of its bones had been BROKEN. The man's pale, greenish face is FROZEN in a hideous grimace. Indiana and MacGowan STARE in shock. The villagers WHISPER among themselves.</context>
      <utterance>T'ain't wild geese we're after, Doctor Jones. You got me' word on that...  ...and a MacGowan's word is truer than an angel's kiss!</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scotty Ferguson.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's the eighth.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just like the others...all his bones busted...crushed...</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever's killin' people around here ain't human.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woman SHOOTS FORWARD. The police and the townspeople are right BEHIND her. A curious Indiana FOLLOWS. The woman stops in a CLEARING. She is POINTING ahead. The villagers SURROUND her. They STARE ahead, in the direction where the woman points. Nearly a mile in the distance, WE SEE</context>
      <utterance>It's there! Again!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MACGOWAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That light...only burns after a murder's been committed.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The villagers STEP BACK. Eyes wide with FEAR. Murmers of 'Ain't goin' in there', 'Nor I', 'Got me a wife and kids', are heard from the TERRIFIED villagers. Indiana TURNS to MacGowan. Even the usually sturdy Inspector is TREMBLING. But MacGowan turns to his men, FORCING himself to be strong.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACGOWAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As each man is called, the color LEAVES his face. The chosen policemen RELUCTANTLY join the Inspector and Indiana, as they begin walking TOWARD the castle. The remaining villagers and policemen STAY BEHIND. WAITING. The elderly woman KISSES the crucifix that hangs from her neck. She STARES at the departing men.</context>
      <utterance>Well... Ahmmmm...that is what we're here for...eh, men?...ah...  Hennesey... Galbraith... Bottomley... You're comin' with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDERLY WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May God help them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HENNESEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hearing this, the other Policemen exchange TERRIFIED glances. Indiana shines his flashlight to a TWISTING, STONE STAIRCASE. The staircase spirals upward along a far wall, leading to the SECOND FLOOR. A FAINT GLIMMER of light emanates from the top of the stairs. Indiana moves FORWARD. The Policemen FOLLOW. Indiana ASCENDS the stairs. SLOWLY. SILENTLY. Toward the LIGHT. MacGowan and the others are directly BEHIND Indy. As he makes his way to the top, Indiana examines the bizarre OIL PAINTINGS that line the wall. There are various PORTRAITS and LANDSCAPES, depicting everything from MILITARY BATTLES to SUNDAY PICNICS. But the unsettling quality of the pictures, is that they each feature the same white haired, ELDERLY MAN. Indy COMMENTS to Mac.</context>
      <utterance>It's deathly cold in 'ere. How could a human bein' survive?...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This guy's got one hell of an ego.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACGOWAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy arrives at the TOP OF THE STAIRS. His hand rests on a SCULPTURE that is part of the bannister. The sculpture is a bust of BARON SEAGROVE. Indiana makes his way to the first doorway, where the LIGHT emanates. The door is WIDE OPEN. A THICK COBWEB covers the entrance. Indy WIPES away the web, and ENTERS the room. The Policemen DRAW their pistols. They FOLLOW.</context>
      <utterance>Baron Seamus Seagrove III. Some say 'e walks the moors every midnight... others claim e's been dead for years...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MACGOWAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for catchin' me.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They CONTINUE down the stairs, arrivifig at the bottom. It is a large, MUSTY STONE BASEMENT. The slimy walls are covered with a GREEN MOSS. There are several DOORS along the basement wall. The sound of the ringing bell is much LOUDER down here. Indiana moves to the FIRST DOOR. He REACHES for the handle. The Policemen DRAW their pistols. Indy OPENS the door. A LARGE OBJECT SHOOTS OUT FROM INSIDE! Rolling TOWARD the men! The policemen FIRE their guns. SEVERAL SHOTS ring out. The object comes to a STOP. A DEEP RED LIQUID pours out onto the floor. Indy DIPS his finger into the liquid. He TASTES.</context>
      <utterance>I'd rather be catchin' trout.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Policemen STARE. WIDE EYED. Indy SMILES.</context>
      <utterance>Interesting blood type...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy's flashlight beam shines ahead, ILLUMINATING the 'mysterious object', a WINE BARREL. And inside the room, is a deserted WINE CELLAR. Suddenly, a LOUD CREAK echoes through the basement. Galbraith</context>
      <utterance>Cabernet sauvignon. 1897.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy and Bottomley TURN to the crypt door. It begins to CLOSE! The two men DASH FORWARD. The door CONTINUES to close. Indy and Bottomley are only INCHES away...when the door SLAMS SHUT! They PUSH and KICK at the door. NO GOOD. It WON'T BUDGE. A PANICKED Bottomley calls for help.</context>
      <utterance>Let's get outta' here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOTTOMLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Using his flashlight, Indy SCANS the door, looking for a CRACK, another way OUT. Indy NUDGES Bottomley.</context>
      <utterance>Inspector MacGowan! Galbraith! Open the door!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bottomley HURRIES to the candle. He REACHES OUT. There is a LOUD WHOOSH! The candle flame GOES OUT! Followed by TOTAL DARKNESS! Indy TURNS from the door.</context>
      <utterance>I need more light.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>NO answer. Indy SHINES his flashlight toward the area. The candle is GONE. There is NO SIGN of Bottomley. Indiana takes a STEP FORWARD.</context>
      <utterance>Bottomley?...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AGAIN, no answer. Indy SWEEPS the flashlight beam across the room. It PASSES one of the coffins...then SHOOTS BACK! Indy is met with a</context>
      <utterance>Bottomley?...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MACGOWAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doctor Jones! Try to push!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana suddenly FALLS! The floor has DISAPPEARED FROM BENEATH HIM! Indy manages to GRAB HOLD of a stone coffin. His fingers tightly GRIP the coffin's edge. Indiana LOOKS DOWN. Beneath him, is a SEVERAL</context>
      <utterance>Can't! There's some kinda' hot ice coverin' the...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baron Seagrove DOES NOT look up from his plate. Indy moves CLOSER. He speaks LOUDER.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, sir...? Hello...?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Canyou hear me?...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Baron still IGNORES Indiana.</context>
      <utterance>Chow time's over, mister. You better start talkin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A SUIT OF ARMOR, located a few feet behind Indy, suddenly TWITCHES. Its arm LOWERS. Its head slowly TURNS. Indiana still walks TOWARD the Baron, who is only concerned with spreading butter on his bread. Indy SHOUTS.</context>
      <utterance>There's a lot of strange things happening around here...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a LOUD CREAK OF METAL. A huge, sharp BATTLE AXE SHOOTS INTO FRAME! SWINGING toward Indy's head! Indiana SPINS. The axe is only INCHES from his face. Indy LEAPS BACK. WHOOSH! The axe SLICES through the air. JUST MISSING Indy. The shaken Indiana is SHOCKED to see A GLISTENING, BLACK SUIT OF ARMOR! The black knight is nearly SEVEN FEET TALL! It has COME TO LIFE and is walking TOWARD Indy. The black knight is WILDLY swinging the battle axe. Indiana continues to STEP BACK... BACK... Unbeknownst to Indy, his steps are leading him toward ANOTHER SUIT OF ARMOR! Also over seven feet tall, this armor is made of a SILVERY, WHITE METAL! As Indy moves CLOSER, the WHITE KNIGHT OPENS ITS ARMS! When Indy is within reach, the white knight LOCKS its powerful arms around Indy's chest! Indiana TRIES to break free. NO GOOD. The white knight's grip is TOO TIGHT. Indy is TRAPPED! The black knight still COMES TOWARD Indiana. Its frenzied axe SWINGS back and forth. Indy still STRUGGLES with the white knight's bone crunching grip. The black knight is only a FEW FEET from Indy. Its deadly axe blade INCHES from Indy's face. Indiana MOVES FAST. He JERKS his body forward. This FLIPS the white knight off its feet! OVER Indy's head. The white knight FLIES INTO the black knight. CRASH! This sends both knights FALLING to the floor. Indiana SHOOTS to his feet. The two knights LEAP to their feet. They CHASE Indy. The black knight armed with his AXE, the white knight armed with a long, sharp SWORD! Baron Seagrove SPOONS another helping of boiled potatoes onto his plate. Indy snatches a SHIELD and SWORD from a nearby wall display. Ready to FIGHT. The knights are UPON HIM. Indiana battles BOTH knights. He DEFENDS the bludgeoning battle axe with his shield, and SWORDFIGHTS the other knight! THRASH! CLANG! The sound of HEAVY METAL fills the room! Indy's sword STRIKES the white knight's thick chest. The sword SNAPS IN TWO. In the confusion, Indy's shield is KNOCKED from his hand by the powerful battle axe. Indy is DEFENSLESS. The two metal giants RAISE their weapons. HIGH. AIMING for Indy's head. The two knights SWING! Indy DIVES to the floor! The knights CAN'T STOP their weapons in time... CRUNCH! They deliver a HARD BLOW to each other! The woozy knights WOBBLE and SPIN. In a momentary DAZE. Indiana JUMPS to his feet. The BLACK KNIGHT hisses. FURIOUS. He DASHES after Indiana. The WHITE KNIGHT is still REELING from the blow. Seeing the black knight in HOT PURSUIT, Indy searches for a WEAPON. He spots the curtain's long, thick ROPE. LYING on the floor. The black knight is nearly UPON Indy. AXE RAISED! Indiana GRABS the rope. He SPINS. FACING the knight. Indy SNAPS HIS WRIST! A LOUD CRACK! The rope SHOOTS FORWARD! Not unlike Indiana's familiar WHIP! The rope WRAPS itself around the black knight's neck. Indy JERKS the whip forward. HARD. This sends the knight FLYING THROUGH THE AIR! The knight crashes into the stone FOONTAIN! Several of the fountain's sculptures SHATTER into pieces. The dazed, dented black knight ATTEMPTS to stand...but LOSES his footing. The knight FALLS backward. Into the fountain's WIDE DRAIN OPENING! Its HEAVY ARMOR causes the knight to SINK. DISAPPEARING into the hole. Into the POOL OF WATER. Indy CATCHES HIS BREATH. The white knight's SWORD SWINGS INTO FRAME! SLICING through Indiana's jacket! Indy JUMPS BACK. The vicious white knight COMES toward him. Indiana TURNS to run. Finding himself at the BANQUET TABLE. Face to face with the ROASTED PIG. A few feet away, Baron Seagrove CONTINUES to dine. The white knight raises his sword ABOVE Indy. WHOOSH! The sword begins to swing DOWN! Indiana DUCKS and DODGES the deadly blows. Instead of carving Indiana, the knight's sword manages to SLICE perfect sections of the roasted pig. The satisfied Baron HELPS HIMSELF to a freshly carved slice of pork. Indiana LEAPS onto the table top. Trying to ESCAPE the living suit of armor. But the white knight CLIMBS up onto the table. FOLLOWING Indy. The sword slashing knight PURSUES Indy along the table top. Indy GLANCES upward. To the heavy CHANDELIER. Indy SMILES. A PLAN. He continues to STEP BACKWARD. Leading the knight DIRECTLY BELOW the chandelier. At the precise moment, Indy picks up a STERLING SILVER PLATE from the table top. Indy WHISKS the plate in the air. Toward the ROPE that holds the chandelier. The spinning plate SEVERS the rope. The chandelier FLIES DOWNWARDl! CRASHING ON TOP of the white knight! The knight lies BENEATH the chandelier. MOTIONLESS. The sword DROPS from its lifeless hand. Onto the TABLE TOP. Indy takes the knight's SWORD. Eyes on FIRE, sword OUTSTRETCHED, Indiana WALKS across the table top. HEADED for Baron Seagrove. The Baron prepares to take ANOTHER BITE of his food. THE SWORD SHOOTS INTO FRAME! The tip of the blade RESTS upon Baron Seagrove's rubbery throat. Indiana SNARLS.</context>
      <utterance>...and I want some answers! Do you hear me?  I want some answers! Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baron Seagrove finally LOOKS at Indiana. The Baron LOWERS his fork. His face twists into an EERIE GRIN. He begins LAUGHING. It's the SAME MANIACAL LAUGH we heard earlier. Indy responds by BLOWING OUT the flame of the mysterious candle. The room's door BURSTS OPEN! INSPECTOR MACGOWAN and GALBRAITH dash inside. They HURRY to Baron Seagrove. Their PISTOLS aimed at him. Galbraith HANDCUFFS the Baron. MacGowan looks at the BRUISED, BLOODIED and TATTERED Indiana Jones.</context>
      <utterance>Haven't you had enough?</utterance>
   <speaker>MACGOWAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you can get back to your fishing, Doctor Jones.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No chance, Mac. My plane leaves in the morning. Vacation's over. Gotta' get back to school.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACGOWAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Tis a shame to go home empty handed...  Tell ya' what, my friend... I fancy me'self quite the fisherman... Tomorrow, I'll go out and catch you a real beauty, eh?...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Send it to me airmail.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACGOWAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doctor Jones! A MacGowan's word is truer than...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They EXIT the room.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, yeah...an angel's kiss. I know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BARON SEAGROVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A CHILL rushes through Indiana. The Baron turns, CONTINUING to the Police wagon. One of the villagers SHOUTS.</context>
      <utterance>No...jail...can...hold...me.</utterance>
   <speaker>VILLAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd CHEERS. Indiana gives a HUMBLE NOD and WAVE. MacGowan SHAKES Indy's hand. Indy glances to the POLICE VEHICLE.</context>
      <utterance>'E's done it! Indiana Jones has captured the killer!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MACGOWAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy POINTS back to the police vehicle. But it has already DEPARTED. It drives over a far hill, DISAPPEARING INTO THE NIGHT. Indy SIGHS, turning back to MacGowan.</context>
      <utterance>What is it, man? You look as if you've seen a screamin' banshee!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah... It was nothing, Mac. Nothing at all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>TEDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Professor...</context>
      <utterance>Doctor Jones... I took your class instead of all the others!... I coulda' had Professor Needles... Professor Eisenschmidt...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You promised. You said you'd have 'em graded by yesterday.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My paper finished yet? Name's "Virgil Vektor". That's VIRGIL.  Capital V... I... R...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My parents paid good money to send me here. You know how much they shelled out for your class?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He doesn't care about us. He only wants fame and fortune. We're just a buncha' peons to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana continues to grade the papers, trying to IGNORE the verbal assault. BETSY TUFFET pushes her way to the front. Betsy is Indy's STUDENT ASSISTANT. She is 21 YEARS OLD, with thick, luxurious black hair, bright brown eyes and a small framed, athletic body. Betsy is a TOUGH. BRASH. A BROOKLYN kid. She moves CLOSE to Indy, her hair brushing his cheek. Indiana is very TENSE, continuously working on the term papers.</context>
      <utterance>VEKTOR. Capital V... E... K...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Ind --  Doctor Jones.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not now, Betsy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>LOOK at all of those papers!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, I...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want me to come by later? Help you grade?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Help me grade. Yeah. Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She EXITS. Indy SIGHS. Again, the obnoxious student SHOUTS.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Ind --  Doctor Jones!</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didja' get the name? VIRGIL! Capital</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PRIESTLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Moby Dick.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?...</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIESTLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana GLANCES to the photo. It is a picture of Prof. Priestly dressed in fisherman's outfit, standing on a pier, holding a GIANT FISH. Indy STEAMS. Priestly gives him a MANLY SLAP to the back.</context>
      <utterance>That's what I named 'im. Captain said it was the biggest fish he ever saw.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIESTLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Didja' catch the big one?...</context>
      <utterance>What about you, Jonesey? You were over in Scotty-land for two weeks...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy is suddenly INTERRUPTED by a HARD SLAP to his face. He LOOKS UP. A beautiful, blonde student, REBECCA, stands over his desk. She</context>
      <utterance>Look, Priestly... I'm real busy...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana RUBS his jaw. STARTLED. Rebecca CONTINUES.</context>
      <utterance>Two-timing bastard!</utterance>
   <speaker>REBECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Priestly HIDES his chuckle. Rebecca THROWS a shirt that obviously belongs to Indiana on the desk and STORMS out of the room. Indy shakes his head and CONTINUES working. The students are still HARASSING him. A LOUD VOICE ECHOES through the room.</context>
      <utterance>How could you?!?... My own Mother?!?... In my own bed?!?...  I've had it with you! It's over!</utterance>
   <speaker>POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>A burly POSTMAN stands in the doorway, holding a thick, enormous BROWN ENVELOPE. Indy MOTIONS to the postman. The Postman tries to MAKE his way through the crowd. Indiana goes back to his grading, but is suddenly INTERRUPTED BY A LOUD TAPPING NOISE. He LOOKS UP. DEAN CLAUDE COVENTRY, a stately, elderly gentleman, RAPS a steel ruler on Indiana's desk. The Dean is UPSET. Very SERIOUS.</context>
      <utterance>Special Delivery! Dr. Indiana Jones!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN COVENTRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman INTERRUPTS, dropping the heavy envelope onto Indy's desk. The Postman SHOVES a yellow paper in front of Indy.</context>
      <utterance>Doctor Jones, I've had complaints from several of the students --</utterance>
   <speaker>POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy SIGNS. Dean Coventry continues LECTURING.</context>
      <utterance>Sign here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN COVENTRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They feel that you are ignoring them, that you are distracted...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me?... Distracted?...</utterance>
   <speaker>POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy GRABS the paper. He's signed a "B+" on the LINE where his name is supposed to appear. Indy CROSSES out the grade and signs his name. Professor Coventry still LECTURES Indiana.</context>
      <utterance>What's this? "B+"? That's how you sign your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN COVENTRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment, Indy OPENS the envelope! A LARGE AMOUNT OF WATER POURS OUT! SATURATING the papers on the desk! This is followed by an ENORMOUS DEAD TROUT! It FLOPS onto Indy's desk. The students exchange STARTLED and NAUSEOUS glances. Indiana removes a water logged NOTE from the envelope. It reads, "A MACGOWAN'S WORD IS TRUER THAN AN ANGEL'S KISS". Indiana uses a TISSUE to WIPE some of the water from his desk. Dean Coventry SHAKES A FINGER at Indy.</context>
      <utterance>Marshall University is not the place for sloppy behavior...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN COVENTRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE PHONE RINGS! INTERRUPTING the Dean! Indiana quickly ANSWERS the phone. A FUMING Dean Coventry impatiently waits to finish his threat. Indiana SPEAKS into the receiver.</context>
      <utterance>I have one final warning for you, Doctor Jones --</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... Oh, Hello, Marcus... Look, can you hold on?...  You were saying, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN COVENTRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Either you begin concentrating on your --</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Marcus... I'm still here... Just hold on!  I'm very sorry, sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN COVENTRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- concentrating on your teaching duties or --</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana HANGS UP. He gives an EMBARASSED look to the furious, red faced Dean.</context>
      <utterance>Damn it, Marcus! I'm standing here with Dean... What?.. Just how important?...  It is, huh?... Okay. Five minutes. Yeah. I'll be right over. But this better be important, Marcus!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEAN COVENTRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Dean STORMS OUT of the room. Indiana GATHERS the wet papers. He begins to EXIT the room, EXPLAINING to the students as he makes his way through the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>You are on probation, Jones! Ten days! If there is no improvement, you will be dismissed!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana continues making APOLOGIES and EXCUSES. The obnoxious student again SHOUTS at him.</context>
      <utterance>I promise...by tomorrow...I'll have all of these graded...and DRIED!</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>VIRGIL VEKTOR! Capital V... I...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This better be important, Marcus... or the museum will soon be displaying my bones. My teaching career is in danger of extinction.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will not be disappointed, Indiana.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>CAMERA PULLS BACK. We are inside of the museum BOARD ROOM. Marcus holds the tattered painting before Indiana, who sits at a desk, still feverishly GRADING the wet term papers. After he finishes each paper, Indy PINS it to a nearby bulletin board for drying. He GLANCES to the painting of Sun Wu Kung.</context>
      <utterance>...Look familiar?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Sun wu Kung, The Stone Monkey King". Big deal. That was ten years ago, Marcus.  Geez! This Heller kid's got the worst grammar.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten years or fifty years. It will always be in your blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't believe this... He spells "repeat" with two "E's".</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think back, Indiana. Remember your desire? Your passion?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kid gets an "A" on content...a "D" on form.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana finally LOOKS UP from the papers. He glances at Marcus, then LOOKS at the painting. CAMERA DOLLIES INTO Indiana's face. He becomes very SERIOUS. SOMBER. His eyes are EMPTY. Memories of FAILURE fill his head.</context>
      <utterance>Damn it, man! You can't bury those feelings forever!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two years. Nearly two years of my life...looking for the remains of that Monkey...a piece of his legendary Golden Hooped Rod...or some sign of the Lost City.  Nine men perished on the journey. Rest of us nearly died from starvation or one of the many horrible deseases we discovered...  We still came back empty handed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One mustn't give up so easily, Indiana.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give up?!?... Marcus, we spent thirteen months in China!...another seven in India!...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But none in Africa.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was no proof...archeological or anthropological...to indicate that Sun Wu-Kung ever visited Africa...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcus TURNS OFF the room lights.</context>
      <utterance>Until now.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcus STARTS the projector. A BLACK AND WHITE image flickers on the far wall. We see a PYGMY, standing in what appears to be a grassy area. The pygmy's name is TYKI. He is ADORABLE. A little Over FOUR FEET TALL, his body is TAUT, MUSCULAR. His long black hair is SHAGGY, his eyes are WIDE and BRIGHT. Almost CHILDLIKE. His face is CUTE. IMPISH. Covered with a very INQUISITIVE expression. Tyki's energy is BOUNDLESS. He cannot stop MOVING. Standing BESIDE Tyki, is DR. CLARE CLARKE. 32 years old. A tall, strikingly BEAUTIFUL woman. She is COMMUNICATING with Tyki in sign language.</context>
      <utterance>Hey... My papers...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The woman is Dr. Clare Clarke. The famous zoologist. She works in Africa, studying animals in their natural habitat.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very interesting, Marcus. Now if you'll turn the lights back on --</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three weeks ago, Dr. Clarke discovered that cute little fellow... "Tyki"...a pygmy of an unusual race...unrelated to any known African tribe...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marcus. The lights.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana PAUSES. He STANDS, walking closer to the flickering image. Suddenly INTERESTED.</context>
      <utterance>Dr. Clarke believes that Tyki comes from the Lost Civilization of Sun Wu-Kung.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?... But how did Miss --</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Doctor".</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Doctor" Clake. How did she arrive at such a preposterous hypothesis?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The pygmy speaks in a language that has no African origins...but bears a strong resemblance to Chinese.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Means nothing. The rivers of Africa have been plagued by various Oriental Pirates and Scavengers since the 16th Century.  Not much evidence, Marcus.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's more. The pygmy was found wearing an ornamental peach stone around his neck...believed to come from Sun Wu-Kung's legendary Garden Of Immortal Peaches.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana WALKS back to his papers. Marcus PAUSES.</context>
      <utterance>Marcus, there are countless undiscovered African tribes...all with various obscure beliefs and practices...  One tribe may wear peach stones... another may wear banana peels...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is one final bit of evidence...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enlighten me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana ADJUSTS his spectacles. He STARES at the black and white image. The cute pygmy appears to be in his MID-TWENTIES. He walks to the CAMERA, STARING into the lens. Tyki examines the camera with</context>
      <utterance>The pygmy is over 200 years old.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Clarke has done a considerable amount of testing on the pygmy's clothing...his sandals...everything was over 200 years old.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does all of this have to do with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Clarke wants to mount an expedition to find the Lost City of Sun Wu-Kung. She is quite familiar with your reputation...she'd like you to come along.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There will be money involved... The museum is willing to fund the expedition...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana TURNS and begins to WALK out of the room. Marcus CALLS him.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Marcus. I've burned this bridge.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy TURNS. He WAVES the papers at Marcus.</context>
      <utterance>Indiana...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marcus. Please. I've got to finish these...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana STARES at the painting of Sun Wu Kung.</context>
      <utterance>You've got to finish something much more important. You crossed the threshold over a decade ago...and it's been tearing at your insides ever since.  My friend, if there is even one iota of truth in Dr. Clarke's findings... then you can lift the veil of mystery that has surrounded this Chinese legend for Centuries. You may uncover the secrets to a Lost Civilization...and possibly, to man's never ending search for immortality.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana has NO ANSWER for Marcus. Indy PICKS up the painting. A THRILLING expression slowly covers Indiana's face. His eyes GLIMMER. Filled with a long, lost EXCITEMENT. The SOUND TRACK MUSIC SOARS!</context>
      <utterance>Indiana... Can you afford to pass up the single most important adventure of your life?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't do this to me!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Betsy. Relax. You're gettin' 'em all wet again.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just can't go away...I mean... Africa is so far away, and...well...  I love you, Indy.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thought we agreed this was s'posed to be casual...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You call what happened last night "casual".</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My dear...a momentary lapse into passion does not a love affair make.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy SHOOTS to her feet, walking OFF SCREEN.</context>
      <utterance>Momentary lapse! So that's all I am to you!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana SIGHS. His eye CATCHES one of the termpapers. He begins to READ, making a few CORRECTIONS. We see Betsy's HAND removes Indiana's WHIP from the bed. Indiana continues to CORRECT the papers. Suddenly, there is a CREAKING NOISE. Indy TURNS. His face goes WHITE. He runs OFF SCREEN. One end of Indiana's WHIP is attached to an OVERHEAD LAMP. CAMERA PANS DOWN the whip. The other end has been formed into a NOOSE around Betsy's neck. Sbe stands on a wooden CHAIR. She KICKS AWAY the chair. Suddenly GAGGING. Indiana GRABS Betsy in midair. He TAKES the noose from her neck and PLACES Betsy on the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Betsy... Wait...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatsa' matter with you!... Tryin' to ruin my whip!...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana TOSSES the whip into his suitcase. He pulls up the chair and forces Betsy to be SEATED. He pours her a tall glass of BOURBON.</context>
      <utterance>If I can't have you... I don't want to live.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana WALKS to his suitcase, continuing to pack. His BACK is to Betsy. She raises the GLASS to her lips. She PAUSES, reading a MESSAGE on the Bourbon bottle. It reads: DANGER! CONTENTS FLAMMABLE! Betsy BEAMS. An IDEA. She LIFTS the bottle over her head and begins to DOUSE her body with the liquid. Indiana is BUSY folding his clothing. Suddenly, we hear the FLICK OF A MATCHSTICK! Indy TURNS. He sees the bourbon covered Betsy preparing to LIGHT HER BODY ON FIRE! Indy DASHES forward. He BLOWS OUT the match, moments before it SPARKS Betsy's clothing. Indy SHAKES Betsy by the shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>Drink this. You'll feel better.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Betsy... Get a hold of yourself. You're young. There are a lot of other guys...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana TURNS and finishes his packing. Betsy SIGHS. She notices an enormous, STONE AFRICAN URN. The 150 POUND antique sits atop a section of BOOKSHELVES. Meanwhile, Indiana makes certain that his gun is PACKED. He places the familiar HAT on his head and begins to CLOSE the suitcase. CLOSE UP: THE AFRICAN URN. It is WOBBLING. SHAKING. Moving CLOSER and CLOSER to the edge of the bookshelves. CAMERA PANS TO THE FLOOR. Betsy LIES here. Directly BELOW the trembling urn. Betsy SHAKES the bookshelves, causing the urn to TILT and SHIVER. The urn is nearly HALFWAY OFF of the edge. If it falls...the urn will CRUSH Betsy's head. Indiana STRUGGLES with closing his tightly packed suitcase. The urn FALLS! HEADED STRAIGHT for Betsy! Indiana SUDDENLY GRABS the urn. In MIDAIR. Inches before it STRIKES Betsy. Indiana RESTS the urn on the floor. He HELPS Betsy to her feet. Betsy WRAPS her arms tightly around Indiana.</context>
      <utterance>That's true...  But that's no reason to stop living! Besides, I'm too old for you. By the time you're seventy five, I'll be...  Yeccchhh! I'll be disgusting.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana PICKS UP his suitcase and tries to WALK to the door. But Betsy's arms are still TIGHTLY WRAPPED around him. Finally, Indy STOPS. His eyes BURN through Betsy.</context>
      <utterance>Don't leave me, Indy!</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never underestimate the determination of a Brooklyn girl, Doctor Jones. Never.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy RESTS Scraggy back onto the ramp. Scraggy MOVES to assist Indiana with his luggage. Before picking it up, Scraggy RAISES his arms over the baggage. Again, he BLESSES the suitcases. Scraggy then PICKS UP the bags. Indy CHUCKLES.</context>
      <utterance>Indy! At last we are reunited!  Oh, Keechingo, God Of Friendship...I thank you for granting my wish!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see you haven't changed, Scraggy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mahootmek, God Of Goodness, say... "Before body make contact with foreign object...one must cast out bad spirits, or -- "</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>" -- or bad spirits will enter your body!"</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes! You have excellent memory, Indy.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should! Last time we saw each other...you made me wear the same clothes for 3 weeks straight.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never separate body from clothes, or bad spirits will hide in pockets!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In other words... If people never changed clothes...there would be no evil in the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I missed all a' your crazy philosophies, Scraggy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy and Scraggy CONTINUE to walk down the ramp, moving OFF SCREEN. CAMERA PANS TO A FEW FEET BEHIND THEM. CAMERA STOPS, as the SCREEN IS FILLED WITH A LARGE, BLAZING RED SWASTIKA! CAMERA PANS UPWARD. We see that this is the SLEEVE OF A GERMAN SOLDIER. CAMERA STOPS on the face of</context>
      <utterance>They not so crazy, Indy.  These days... There is much evil in the air. I feel it. Everywhere.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Jones! Forgive me.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No sweat.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thought I was being attacked by a degenerate sailor.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Just a degenerate archeologist.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your appearance is deceiving.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They exchange a handshake and a SMILE. Immediately ATTRACTED to each other.</context>
      <utterance>Likewise.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Indiana TURNS. A ship PORTER walks through the crowd, pushing a LARGE BARREL on a dolly. Indy WAVES to the Porter. The Porter STOPS in front of him.</context>
      <utterance>Indiana Jones! Calling passenger Indiana Jones!</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You left this aboard ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Porter POINTS to a section of the barrel that reads: DELIVER TO:</context>
      <utterance>There must be some mistake... I didn't --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="38">
   <speaker>PORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's you, ain't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Porter DROPS the barrel in front of Indiana and hurriedly WALKS back to the ship. SGT. GUTTERBUHG continues to SPY on Indiana. The Nazi HIDES a few feet away. In a DARK alleyway. A puzzled Indiana begins to OPEN the barrel. Scraggy SHOUTS a warning.</context>
      <utterance>Well, yeah...but...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana IGNORES Scraggy and begins to PRY OPEN the barrel.</context>
      <utterance>Indy! Remember Mahootmek, God Of Goodness! "Before body make contact with foreign object -- "</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana still IGNORES Scraggy. He STRUGGLES with the barrel top, FLIRTING with Clare.</context>
      <utterance>"...you must cast out bad spirits!"</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I call you "Clare"?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Clare... We've obviously got a lot of notes to compare... Let's get started tonight...over dinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like that very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment, the barrel lid FLIES OFF! The inside if FILLED with old, brown BANANA PEELS. Suddenly, BETSY'S HEAD POKES THROUGH the peels! Indiana is SHOCKED. Scraggy SIGHS.</context>
      <utterance>Friend of mine owns a Cafe... He'll get us a nice quiet table. No disturbances. Just the two of us --</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A dirty, unkempt Betsy LEAPS OUT OF THE BARREL! She THROWS her arms around Indy.</context>
      <utterance>I warn you, Indy! You must always cast out bad spirits!</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My precious!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your daughter?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My assistant.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His girlfriend.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A child!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's nothing. Really.  What the hell are you doing here'?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Proving my love for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How terribly sordid.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Puppy love. Schoolgirl crush. She'll get over it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never. This proves that nothing can come between us. Not an ocean. Not two separate Continents.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think I'm going to be ill.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How...I mean... How could you stay alive?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey... I'm from Brooklyn.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we'ye been sailing for three weeks!</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ate my way to the bottom.</context>
      <utterance>Stowed away in the banana barrel.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charming.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Indy... Who's the babe?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your intellectual and emotional superior.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...well you're gettin' on my nerves, Miss... Miss...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Doctor" Clare Clarke.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Betsy Tuffet...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As in curds and whey?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, sister... You better stay away from Indy...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana SHOOTS Clare an angry glance. Indy removes a wad of BILLS from his pocket. He GIVES them to Betsy.</context>
      <utterance>My dear, he has no interest in me. I've already celebrated my tenth Birthday.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Betsy... Why don't you get back on the boat... This time, as a passenger.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scraggy points toward the OCEAN LINER. The boat is SEVERAL FEET from shore. It SAILS back out to sea. Indiana STEAMS.</context>
      <utterance>Too late, Indy.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When's the next one out?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana GRUMBLES. An amused Dr. Clarke gets back into the car. Indy SHOVES Betsy inside. He is FURIOUS. Before Indiana gets into the car, GUTTERBUHG steps out from the alleyway. He TOSSES the tiny mechanical COCKROACH at Indiana. The roach ATTACHES itself to Indy's TROUSER LEG. The tiny transmittor is very LIGHT. Indiana can feel NOTHING. He gets INTO the car. Scraggy BLESSES the Taxi and gets into the driver's seat. Gutterbuhg WATCHES as the battered Model-T DRIVES OFF. The NAZI turns, walking in an opposite direction. The CAMERA FOLLOWS Gutterbuhg, as he enters a SEEDY WATERFRONT HOTEL.</context>
      <utterance>Two weeks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MEPHISTO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gutterbuhg gives a TIMID NOD. With trembling fingers, he reaches over and TURNS UP THE VOLUME of the radio transmission. The voices of Indiana, Betsy, Clare and Scraggy echo through a TINNY SPEAKER. Mephisto manages a pleased GRUNT.</context>
      <utterance>Were you successful?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEPHISTO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gutterbuhg NUDGES the officer before him. The officer hurriedly begins to SCRAWL a manuscript of the radio transmission. Mephisto NODS.</context>
      <utterance>Keep a record of everything that is said.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEPHISTO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ever since our battle for the Lost Ark... The feuhrer has been very interested in the adventures of Indiana Jones. Very interested.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyki EXTENDS his right hand. He SHAKES Indiana's hand. Indiana is CHARMED by the civilized display of friendship. Indy SMILES at Clare.</context>
      <utterance>Tyki... This is Doctor Jones...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a real gentleman.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clare pauses, noticing that Betsy is MISSING. Clare suddenly breaks into a LAUGH! She points OFF SCREEN. Everyone TURNS.</context>
      <utterance>Just basic manners. What it takes most men a lifetime to learn... Tyki's accomplished in two weeks.  This is our guide, Scraggy Brier... and Miss Bets--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyki has gone back to his ARTWORK. A FASCINATED Indiana looks over the pygmy's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>It appears that Bonzo is attracted to Miss Tuffet's Derfume... Eau De Banana Peel.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did you find him?...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana STARES at the pygmy. A skeptical look COVERS his face.</context>
      <utterance>About ten miles from here. We were on a photographic expedition...in the thick of the jungle... I heard sounds. Whimpering. Moaning. I took a few steps, and found Tyki. He was lying in a shallow swamp...semi conscious...a high fever...nearly dead from exhaustion. He had obviously been travelling on foot for many days, over countless miles... So I brought him back to the compound...nursed him back to health...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clare, I hate to quibble with your anthropological abilities...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quibble.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clare OPENS a door at the rear of the cage. It LEADS into another room, directly behind the CAGE. Clare and Indiana ENTER. Scraggy STAYS behind. He EXCHANGES a friendly smile with Tyki. Meanwhile, in the BACKGROUND, we see BETSY and the CHIMPANZEE. They ROLL BY on the ground. Still WRESTLING.</context>
      <utterance>...but if this little fellow is over 200 years old... I mean... What accounts for his youthful appearance?...his vitality?...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Jones, you are obviously familiar with the legend of Sun Wu- King's Garden of Immortal Peaches?...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The vicious Gutterbuhg SMILES. CAMERA PANS to his notebook. Gutterbuhg underlines the words "FOREVER YOUNG".</context>
      <utterance>A bite from the fruit of that peach tree would give a person eternal life...make them forever young...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The fruit fly LANDS on Indiana's neck. Indy SMACKS the fly! KILLING it! A SHOCKED Clare RUNS to Indiana. She GRABS his hand and GENTLY removes what remains of the fruit fly. She GLARES at Indiana. FURIOUS.</context>
      <utterance>There's nothing unusual about this ...nothing to indicate that it's from Sun Wu Kung's garden...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This fruit fly had a normal life- span of TWENTY FOUR HOURS.  As an experiment...the fly was put in this room...alone...with only the peach stone to sustain its existence. The fly stayed alive for</utterance>
   <speaker>THREE WEEKS.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She FLICKS the'fly against the wall. Indy gives an EMBARASSED SHRUG.</context>
      <utterance>Until now.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana and Clare are suddenly INTERRUPTED by the sound of Scraggy and Tyki's LAUGHTER. This is followed by the two of them having a DISCUSSION! In Tyki's FOREIGN TONGUE! Clare and Indy exchange a SHOCKED GLANCE and DASH out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He understands him?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scraggy NODS and ASKS Tyki. Tyki ANSWERS and POINTS to the painting of the clouds. Scraggy TRANSLATES.</context>
      <utterance>Scraggy knows hundreds of languages... He's the best guide in Africa.  Ask Tyki where he came from.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He say... "I come from 'Land Of City On Clouds'".</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyki OFFERS some more information to Scraggy. Scraggy TRANSLATES.</context>
      <utterance>He say if he could... He would go back!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana's eyes WIDEN. STARTLED. AMAZED. Clare LOOKS at Indy. PUZZLED.</context>
      <utterance>He say "Pai Cho" may help you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Pai Cho"?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scraggy ASKS Tyki. The pygmy NODS and REMOVES his belt. We see that the thick belt actually unravels into a CLOTH SCROLL. Tyki KISSES the scroll and GIVES it to Scraggy. Scraggy nervously OPENS the scroll. It is filled with countless ANCIENT CHINESE WRITINGS and PROVERBS. Indiana STARES over Scraggy's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>The Sacres Proverbs and Writings of Sun Wu Kung.  His disciples always carry the Pai Cho with them...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scraggy NODS. Indiana's eyes ANXIOUSLY scan the document. He is BREATHLESS. EXCITED. The SOUND TRACK MUSIC SOARS. Suddenly, BETSY AND THE CHIMPANZEE FALL INTO FRAME! ON TOP OF THE SCROLL! Bonzo STRADDLES Betsy, trying to move his lips TOWARD hers! She is SCREAMING!</context>
      <utterance>Can you translate it?...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bonzo moves its lips to Betsy and gives her a BIG KISS! SMACK! Betsy GRIMACES. Finally, Clare begins to make BIZARRE MONKEY HAND MOTIONS and SOUNDS. Bonzo TURNS. He UNDERSTANDS Clare. She continues to COMMUNICATE with the chimp, until Bonzo turns and RUNS out of the cage! Indiana and Scraggy exchange an IMPRESSED GLANCE. Betsy WIPES the kiss from her lips.</context>
      <utterance>Get...him...off...of...me...!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Sun Wu Kung run like fire, He journey to Many Monkey Land, To build his final empire."</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's Sun Wu-Kung?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Many Monkey Land... That's a definite reference to Africa.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Africa?... He journeyed to Africa?...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That confirms our suspicions that he may have formed his Civilization here...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What civilization?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Betsy. Keep your trap shut. This doesn't concern you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine. Terrific. Who cares about this stuff anyway! We're in a nightclub. We should be havin' fun.  C'mon, Indy. Let's dance.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Later.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a buncha' stiffs!  Bet you can't dance.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quite the contrary...I spent several months studying dance.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah? Whattayou' know?... The Bunny Hop?... The Jitterbug?...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Bondogea. The Kyebe Kyebe. The Dungumaro.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>African Tribal dances.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never heard of 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Insulted, Betsy GOBBLES down her glass of wine and TURNS back to Indiana, who is still deeply CONCENTRATING on the scrolls.</context>
      <utterance>Of course not. They're beyond the spectrum of your microscopic world.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DASHIELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone NODS, expressing their thanks. Dashiell LEANS close to Indiana and WHISPERS.</context>
      <utterance>Enjoying your dinners?...</utterance>
   <speaker>DASHIELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana's eyes DART around the room. He sees the VARIOUS NAZIS. WATCHING him. Indy gives a CONFIDENT SMILE. A WORRIED Dashiell continues WHISPERING to Indiana.</context>
      <utterance>Watch yourself, sport. Most of the talk here tonight is about you. And it isn't good.</utterance>
   <speaker>DASHIELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you've done to the Nazis. But they are certainly no friends of yours.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"With his Golden Hooped Rod, And its powerful lightning rays, Sun Wu Kung build Water Curtain Cave, Where he live for 500 days."</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Golden Hooped Rod?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A heavenly staff with many different powers...most notably, it had the ability to transform itself into hundreds of objects...  It remains the most priceless treasure of Sun Wu Kung's empire.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what is the...the Water Curtain Cave?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clare again REACHES for her coffee. The cup and saucer are still TREMBLING. Clare PEEKS under the table, and again SEES Betsy's foot RUBBING Indiana's leg. Clare gives a revolted GRUMBLE. Indiana EXCITEDLY explains Scraggy's translation.</context>
      <utterance>Sun Wu Kung's legendary hideout...an enormous secret cave, hidden behind a running waterfall.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This proves that the Water Curtain Cave exists in Africa...  Does it mention anything about Sun Wu Kung's travels?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only place called..."Twisted Snake Water".</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Zarnbesi River! It has a reputation for its deadly water snakes...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It would have been Sun Wu Kung's logical path.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clare SMILES.</context>
      <utterance>It will also be our logical path.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana finally REMOVES the mechanical bug. He LIFTS it above the table. EXAMINING it. Clare is about to ASK a question. Indy INDICATES for her to "Shhhh". He COVERS the bug and WHISPERS to the others.</context>
      <utterance>Please try to control that monstrous libido of yours!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana, Clare and Scraggy HURRY from the table. A TIPSY Betsy Follows. Indiana passes the JAZZ BAND. He nonchalantly DROPS the mechanical bug into the trumpet player's HORN! The trumpet player hits a PIERCING HIGH NOTE!</context>
      <utterance>We have to get back to the compound. Tyki may be in danger.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scraggy NODS. The end of the dock is only a FEW FEET ahead. Getting CLOSER... CLOSER... Clare COVERS her eyes. Between hiccups, Betsy laughingly SINGS. Indy LOOKS to the speedboat... BACK to the approaching dock edge... He PAUSES... WAITING for the right moment... He SCREAMS!</context>
      <utterance>When I tell you... Hit the brakes!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scraggy's foot SLAMS ON THE BRAKES! The sudden jolt sends Indy FLYING</context>
      <utterance>Now, Scraggy!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A WORRIED Scraggy sees Indiana, FIGHTING with the Nazis.</context>
      <utterance>About time we had some fun!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Nazi speedboat is HEADED TOWARD THE SIDE OF AN ENORMOUS OCEAN LINER! Gutterbuhg RADIOS for help. Indiana and Klaus continue to FIGHT. ROLLING along the deck. Exchanging PUNCHES. A bound Tyki watches with WIDE EYES. HELPLESS. The speedboat makes a sudden SHARP TURN. AVOIDING A COLLISION with the Ocean liner. Indiana and Klaus TUMBLE OFF, THE BOAT! INTO THE WATER!</context>
      <utterance>Bad spirits have Indy! He in trouble! Big trouble! Scraggy RUNS OFF SCREEN.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GUTTERBUHG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a LOUD GUNSHOT! Gutterbuhg's mechanical arm is HIT BY A BULLET! Pieces of SPRING, METAL and SPROCKETS fly from the wound. Gutterbuhg TURNS. FURIOUS. DASHIELL, the nightclub owner, is a few feet away. He is driving a sleek SPEEDBOAT, its side adorned with the AMERICAN FLAG. Dashiell points a PISTOL at Gutterbuhg, ready to take ANOTHER SHOT... With a ROAR, The Nazi speedboat DRIVES AWAY! Toward a CLUSTER OF DOCKS! Indiana CLIMBS into Dashiell's speedboat.</context>
      <utterance>Goodnight, Doctor Jones.</utterance>
   <speaker>DASHIELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dashiell HITS the gas. TEARING after the Nazis. A FRENZIED, HIGH SPEED CHASE BEGINS! Through the DARKNESS. Beneath the ROWS OF DOCKS. The speedboats face countless OBSTACLES. They SWERVE around a virtual forest of wooden poles, which FLY BY AT BREAKNECK SPEED! The men DUCK and DODGE dangling FISH HOOKS and NETS. Many paths are BLOCKED by the wooden RAFTS and ROWBOATS. (NOTE: Because of the darkness, these obstacles APPEAR only when they are a FEW FEET AHEAD of the speedboats. This makes the chase completely SURPRISING and SCARY, causing a FUNHOUSE effect.) Throughout the chase, Indiana and the Nazis continue to exchange GUNFIRE. A frustrated Gutterbuhg CAN'T SHOOT. His mechanical-machine gun arm rendered USELESS by Dashiell's bullet. He continues to RADIO Nazi headquarters for help. Dashiell CATCHES UP with the Nazis. The two speedboats travel SIDE BY SIDE. Their edges SCRAPE together. SPARKS fly. The recovered Helmut AIMS his luger at Indiana... But Indy LEAPS toward the Nazi. The two FALL. ROLLING. TUMBLING. STRUGGLING for the gun. They fight BETWEEN the two speedboats. The crack below them slightly OPENING and CLOSING. Up ahead, an ENORMOUS STONE POLE appears. To AVOID a collision, the speedboats MUST SEPARATE. Dashiell SCREAMS.</context>
      <utterance>Scraggy said you might be needing some help, sport.</utterance>
   <speaker>DASHIELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy FREES himself from Helmut and ROLLS back onto Dashiell's boat. Helmut LOOKS UP. He sees the stone pole AHEAD. COMING AT HIM. Helmut tries to MOVE...TOO LATE. The two boats SEPARATE. Helmut SMACKS into the pole! CRUSHED! Dashiell TURNS AWAY from the wheel, looking at Indiana.</context>
      <utterance>Indy! Rollout!</utterance>
   <speaker>DASHIELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana begins to answer...then sees SOMETHING. AHEAD. He SCREAMS.</context>
      <utterance>You okay, sport?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dashiell TURNS BACK. The speedboat is HEADED STRAIGHT FOR A SOLID WOODEN WALL! A sign on the wall reads: FUTTERMAN'S FISHING WAREHOUSE. The Nazi speedboat has already made a SHARP TURN, AVOIDING the warehouse. There's NO TIME for Dashiell to TURN. Indy HITS the deck. The speedboat ARCHES upward, at an ANGLE... CRASH! The speedboat BLASTS into the warehouse. Splintered wood SPLATTERS through the air.</context>
      <utterance>Dash!...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An ANNOYED Indy pushes Betsy away. In a drunken stupor, Betsy moves to the next person, CLARE. Thinking she's still with Indiana, Betsy puts her arms AROUND Clare. A WORRIED Clare is TOO CONCERNED with the departing Nazi speedboat. Clare TURNS to Inqy.</context>
      <utterance>What a romantic night!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will they hurt Tyki?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eyes CLOSED, resting her head on Clare's shoulder, Betsy SIGHS.</context>
      <utterance>They know he's important to us.  They'll use him to bargain for this.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clare PUSHES Betsy away. Betsy SPINS and WRAPS HER ARMS around Scraggy. Clare watches the Nazi Speedboat DISAPPEAR into the night.</context>
      <utterance>Indy, you smell so good! So masculine!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will they be following us?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy, still thinking she's SNUGGLING with Indiana, rubs her face against Scraggy's bristly beard.</context>
      <utterance>Every step of the way.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scraggy PUSHES Betsy away. She SPINS, this time putting her arms around a hanging FISHERMAN'S NET. Filled with FISH. Meanwhile, Scraggy LOOKS at Indiana and Clare.</context>
      <utterance>Mmmm, Indy. I love it when you don't shave. It's so sexy!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pandoola, God of Purity, say... "Always stay ten paces ahead of bad spirit".</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana turns and WALKS AWAY. Clare and Scraggy hurriedly FOLLOW. There's NO TIME to lose. The drunken Betsy continues to embrace the net of DEAD FISH. Betsy TURNS. Eyes CLOSED. She SMILES.</context>
      <utterance>Exactly. We can't let the Nazis get to the City first. If they do, they'll wipe out one of the greatest archeological finds in History!</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy KISSES the LIPS OF A DEAD FISH! She SMILES. IMPRESSED.</context>
      <utterance>How 'bout a little goodnight kiss?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy OPENS her eyes. FACE TO FACE with the dead fish. Betsy SCREAMS and RUNS toward the departing Indiana, Clare and Scraggy!</context>
      <utterance>Mmmmm, Indy...you really know the way to a girl's heart!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is that awful aroma?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy points OFF SCREEN. Scraggy, fully clothed, STANDS here. He rubs a large, FRESH ONION over his FACE, ARMS and LEGS. SQUEEZING the onion JUICE over his body. Indiana EXPLAINS to a befuddled Clare.</context>
      <utterance>Scraggy's takin' a shower.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He believes that onions keep bad spirits from entering his body.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In all my years of anthropology... I've never run across anyone or anything quite like Scraggy.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a rare breed.  You're looking very lovely.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're looking very lecherous.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just tryin' to be friendly.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Save it for the schoolgirls.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There was never any romance.</context>
      <utterance>Look, Clare... Betsy's just an anxious archeology student...she admires my work...  Who can blame her?...  But it's just some kinda' hero worship thing...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy SIGHS. Clare DISGUSTINGLY shakes her head. She continues to scrawl more into her notebook. Indiana gives her a STARTLED look.</context>
      <utterance>I dreamed about our first night together!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're writin' this down?...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm keeping an accurate record of our journey.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that got to do with my personal life?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana SHAKES his head. STARING into the distance. He SIGHS.</context>
      <utterance>Evidence. I plan on testifying at your child molestation trial.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holding her head in PAIN, Betsy turns to Clare.</context>
      <utterance>Why do I do this to myself?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, lady...you're s'posed to be a Doctor...you got any cures for a hangover?...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy's face becomes PALE. Indy INTERRUPTS.</context>
      <utterance>The best I've heard was used by a New Zealand Tribe...  One part crushed owl skull...two parts rhino saliva...one part zebra dandruff.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy turns a light shade of GREEN. Scraggy ARGUES.</context>
      <utterance>No, No... Get a cup of donkey sweat ...two spoons of skunk hair...and one pint of shredded lizard tongue.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I always use family cure! Two spoons chopped leeches... Half cup horse mucous...two quarts crocodile urine!</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy runs OFF SCREEN. The others exchange a SHRUG. Scraggy LOOKS at the river ahead.</context>
      <utterance>Ex...cuse...me...!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How far we travel, Indy?...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Almost 20 miles.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any sign of the Nazis?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA PANS from the hopeful faces of Indiana, Scraggy and Clare, to the CABIN behind them. Here, a CREW MEMBER HIDES in the shadows. His face HIDDEN. He HOLDS a small radio receiver. He WHISPERS into the receiver. Speaking in perfect GERMAN.</context>
      <utterance>Long as we keep up this pace... they'll have trouble tracking us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's so hot... Stuffy... Do we have to stay on this stupid boat all night?...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to keep moving.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we at least jump in the water?... Go for a swim?...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's an old legend about the Zambesi... In ancient times, criminals were given their choice of execution...or swimming across the Zambesi. Most chose execution.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An angry Betsy TOSSES her tin can overboard. She STANDS. FURIOUS with Indiana.</context>
      <utterance>Clare's right. We'll be safer on the boat.  Now quit moanin' and eat your food.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clare RAISES an eyebrow. IMPRESSED. Indiana says NOTHING. He can't ARGUE. Scraggy INTERJECTS.</context>
      <utterance>You are so rude! I travel thousands of miles just to be with you...and everybody treats me like dirt!  Nobody even talks to me without making some condescending remark they think I'm too stupid to understand!  So maybe I don't know a lot about weird tribal dances... I'm still pretty good with anthropology and archeology... Maybe I could even help you out...if somebody gave me a chance...clued me in to what it is we're doin' here...  'Cause whether you like it or not, Indiana Jones... I'm part of this expedition, too!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crew members NOD. STARING at Indiana. Indiana turns to Clare. She</context>
      <utterance>My friends also curious about where we journey to, Indy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana SIGHS. The crew member's GUITAR PLAYING COMBINES with the SOUND TRACK, backing up Indiana's story with an EERIE TUNE.</context>
      <utterance>Tell us all a bedtime story, Doctor Jones.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Long ago...a place known as the Flower Fruit Mountain, in the Chinese province of Ao-Lai...was struck by lightning. A Stone Monkey, "Sun Wu-Kung", was born.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Talk?... Like human?...</context>
      <utterance>This monkey?... He could walk?...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crew members, Scraggy, Betsy and Clare, listen with FASCINATION.</context>
      <utterance>More than human. He was blessed with countless heavenly powers... But it wasn't enough. Sun Wu-Kung wanted to learn the secret of Eternal Life... of Immortality...  Equipped with his Golden Hooped Rod to protect him, Sun Wu Kung travelled the world for many years ...learning the secret philosophies and teachings of Eternal Youth. Eventually, he was granted entrance to heaven...where the Jade Emperor gave Sun Wu Kung the title of "Great Sage of the Heavens"...and permitted him to oversee the Garden of Immortal Peaches.  After several years, the stone monkey returned to somewhere on earth. Here, he ruled an empire...a Civilization of Monkeys and humans who had life spans of many hundred years...  The exact whereabouts of that Lost City has been a mystery for hundreds of years...until Doctor Clarke discovered the pygmy.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's uncertain just how much of this legend is based in reality... Nevertheless, we're hoping to find some sign of the Lost Civilization.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Sun Wu Kung?...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, they are INTERRUPTED BY A DISTANT SOUND. A LOW, RUMBLING SOUND. BIZARRE. UNEARTHLY. UNLIKE anything we've heard before. Indiana TURNS to Scraggy.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever he was...a stone idol...an actual monkey...a human being...is unknown. But he is one of the most influentual religious figures in History, and his remains are most likely somewhere in the Lost City.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sound familiar?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is far, far away...many miles...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?... Some kinda' weird animal?...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No animal sounds like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could be "Banseebaba".</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Banseebaba?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Banseebaba is giant demon from hell. He is 50 feet tall. Breathes fire. Make sound like human never hear before. He is made up of all evil in the world!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sound suddenly STOPS. Everyone exchanges a FRIGHTENED, TERRIFIED GLANCE. Indiana STANDS.</context>
      <utterance>Cheery thought.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever the hell it is... It went to sleep for the night. Which is what we should do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Couldn't sleep. The heat. I'm in the mood for passion.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana LEADS Betsy to the open door. He begins to PUSH her back outside. Betsy STOPS him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm in the mood for isolation.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not leaving. Not till I get a kiss.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Betsy...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana has NO CHOICE. He SIGHS.</context>
      <utterance>One kiss. Or I'll scream. I swear. I'll wake the whole boat.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They KISS. Betsy WRAPS her arms around Indiana, turning it into a</context>
      <utterance>OKay. Just one.  Keep your mouth closed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that you're writing?...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"The Erotic Adventures Of Indiana Jones, Professor Of Perversity".</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA PANS TO THE FRONT DECK. STOPPING on the DRIVER. He STARES ahead. STEERING the ship. SUDDENLY, A FIGURE APPEARS. BEHIND the driver. The figure GRABS the driver. AROUND THE NECK. Before the driver can SCREAM...the figure SLICES HIS THROAT. Scraggy WITNESSES this. Through an OPEN PORTHOLE. His face covered with SHOCK. FEAR.</context>
      <utterance>Very funny.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana LEANS down. He RINSES his face in a large BUCKET OF WATER. A DAGGER FLIES INTO FRAME! JUST MISSING Indiana. It STICKS into the wall. A FEW FEET ABOVE Indy's head. Clare WITNESSES this. SHOCKED. UNAWARE of the danger, Indiana RAISES his head out of the bucket. He still tries to REASON with Clare.</context>
      <utterance>You are blowing this Betsy thing all out of proportion...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clare is trying to INTERRUPT Indy, trying to POINT OUT the dagger. But before she can say a word, Indiana again LEANS into the water bucket. ANOTHER DAGGER SHOOTS INTO FRAME! INTO the wall. This time only INCHES above Indy's head. Indiana again RAISES his head.</context>
      <utterance>It's not as if I have this sleazy reputation...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clare LEAPS FORWARD. She pushes Indy OUT OF THE WAY, moments before another DAGGER FLIES INTO FRAME! STICKING into the wall! Indy and Clare TURN. THREE PIRATES stand here. DIRTY. TOOTHLESS. UGLY. SWORDS EXTENDED, they MOVE toward Indiana and Clare. Indy's eyes DART to the water bucket table. His WHIP and PISTOL rest here. OUT OF REACH. Indy and Clare are TRAPPED. The Pirates move CLOSER... Suddenly, A LOUD SCREAM. The Pirates LOOK UP. SCRAGGY swings from a ROPE above. TOWARD the Pirates. Before the Pirates can react, Scraggy CRASHES into them. They TUMBLE to the deck. Scraggy SHOOTS to his feet. He tosses a spare SWORD to Indy. Scraggy and Indy begin to SWORDFIGBT the Pirates. Clare TURNS. DASHING around the corner. To SAFETY. A SUDDEN STOP. Her face is buried in the hairy, bare chest of KEZURE, an enormous, bear- like PIRATE KING. Kezure HASN'T BATHED in years. He is dressed in SEVERAL LAYERS of tattered, colorful clothing, GOLDEN JEWELRY, and ANIMAL SKINS. His STRINGY hair is long, tied in a PONYTAIL behind his head. A thick, long MOUSTACHE wraps around a large mouth, filled with crooked, GOLDEN TEETH. Clare SHRIEKS. Kezure GRABS her around the waist. He TOSSES Clare over his shoulder. The river boat is overcome with a mixture of ORIENTAL and BLACK Pirates. SOUND TRACK MUSIC SOARS! There is a HEATED BATTLE between the crew members and the Pirates. Fists FLYING. Swords CLASHING. Using her Brooklyn street smarts, Betsy FIGHTS like a pro. With a swift PUNCH and KICK, Betsy DEFEATS one Pirate. She takes his SWORD. ANOTHER Pirate comes for Betsy. She EDGES him on.</context>
      <utterance>I am a respected...honored... admired...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Pirate ATTACKS. He and Betsy begin a HEATED SWORDFIGHT. Indiana and Scraggy CONTINUE TO BATTLE the onslaught of sword slinging Pirates. Suddenly, Indy is interrupted by Clare's LOUD SCREAM! He</context>
      <utterance>C'mon... You ain't so tough. You wouldn't last ten minutes in Brooklyn.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kezure STOPS. He TURNS. Indy WALKS toward Kezure, stopping less than TEN FEET from the Pirate King and Clare. Indy's eyes BURN through Kezure.</context>
      <utterance>Wait...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kezure LAUGHS. Indiana LIGHTS the dynamite fuses. Kezure STOPS laughing...WORRIED for a moment... Then, the Pirate King breaks into a wide, DEFIANT SMILE.</context>
      <utterance>Free the girl...  ...and my friends...  ...or I blow your hideout here out of the water!</utterance>
   <speaker>KEZURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A STANDOFF. Indy DIDN'T EXPECT this. He is suddenly FRIGHTENED. PUZZLED. Betsy, Scraggy and Clare STARE at Indy. Waiting for his NEXT MOVE...as the dynamite fuse SLOWLY BURNS. Getting CLOSER...CLOSER...to the TNT. Kezure seems CALM. Perfectly WILLING TO DIE. Indy gets ANOTHER IDEA. He BLURTS it out to Kezure.</context>
      <utterance>Good. We will all die.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can take you to the Lost City of Sun Wu Kung!</utterance>
   <speaker>KEZURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hah! Better men than you have tried to find the Lost City... They have all failed.  You are a fool.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>as the TNT fuse burns</utterance>
   <speaker>LOWER...LOWER...)</speaker>
      <mode> LOWER...LOWER...)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... You're the fool. You and your friends are hiding out in Sun Wu Kung's Water Curtain Cave...and you don't even know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEZURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scraggy and Betsy exchange a SHOCKED glance. Clare is also SURPRISED by the news. The TNT fuse nears the end...ready to BLOW AT ANY SECOND... Indiana removes the ANCIENT SCROLL from his pocket. He EXTENDS the scroll to Kezure.</context>
      <utterance>Huh?...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kezure GRABS the scroll. Attempting to READ it. Indy INTERRUPTS.</context>
      <utterance>The Sacred Pai-Cho Scroll.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kezure EXAMINES the scroll. PUZZLED by the writing. Indiana and Scraggy exchange a HOPEFUL glanpe. Kezure PAUSES. THINKING. He MUMBLES to himself.</context>
      <utterance>Don't bother. Only WE can translate it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEZURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kezure PUSHES Clare away. TOWARD Indiana. Clare EMBRACES Indy, as he BLOWS OUT the dynamite fuse. Kezure GROWLS at Indy.</context>
      <utterance>The Lost City... Said to have streets paved in gold...treasures far greater than any mortal man could imagine...</utterance>
   <speaker>KEZURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your pathetic lives will be spared. For now.  But everything we find in the Lost City...belongs to ME.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fat chance, Sinbad. It's 50-50. Or you've got no deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEZURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is my way. Or you've got no head.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Read that last proverb again...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"High tide drowns curiosity, Low tide quenches thirst".</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meanwhile, Betsy and Clare work in ANOTHER SECTION of the cave. Clare is doing some ARCHEOLOGICAL WORK, studying the various artifacts and utensils. Betsy ASSISTS her. They are surrounded by LEERING, HUNGRY EYED PIRATES. The drunken Pirates DON'T take their eyes off of the girls. Betsy NOTICES. She POINTS it out to Clare.</context>
      <utterance>There's something here...something that could help us...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at 'em. It's like they've never seen a woman before.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To them... We're the ultimate women.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meanwhile, Indiana, Scraggy and Kezure WALK through the cavern. Indy is LOOKING around. CURIOUS, he turns to Kezure.</context>
      <utterance>Kinda' flattering, isn't it?... Being the girl of 200 guy's dreams? Clare and Betsy exchange a CHUCKLE.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kezure leads Indiana and Scraggy into a DARK CORNER of the cavern. A large, smooth WALL stretches to the ceiling. The wall is filled with intricate CRACKS. At the base of the wall, water slowly POURS into the cavern. Kezure POINTS to the water.</context>
      <utterance>Is there an area... A place where the tide changes?...</utterance>
   <speaker>KEZURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In a few hours...the water will be lower...much lower...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kezure NODS. Indiana's eyes LIGHT. A REALIZATION. He excitedly TURNS to Kezure.</context>
      <utterance>And the remainder of this wall will be visible?....</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kezure NODS. Indiana EXCHANGES an anxious, hopeful glance with Scraggy.</context>
      <utterance>We're gonna need light. A lot of light. On this wall.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>KEZURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kezure GOBBLES down the whiskey. Indiana RELUCTANTLY drinks. Kezure pours TWO more glasses. LAUGHING.</context>
      <utterance>To my good fortune.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEZURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know... We are very much alike, Doctor jones.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I doubt that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEZURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We both share a remarkable talent for killing.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never gotten used to killing, pal. I do it for survival.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEZURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana DOWNS his whiskey. A LAUGHING Kezure does the same. Indiana NOTICES something. ON the wall. He JUMPS to his feet. CAMERA PANS TO THE WALL. The tide is VERY LOW. The entire wall is now VISIBLE. What were once simple CRACKS, have become the specific LINES OF A MAP. A group of ARROWS leads to an "X" at the BOTTOM CORNER OF THE MAP. A FASCINATED Kezure and Indiana STUDY the wall.</context>
      <utterance>I do it for pleasure.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is incredible...this map was obviously used by Sun Wu Kung's disciples...if they were ever lost...</utterance>
   <speaker>KEZURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These drawings...they are of the surrounding jungle...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is that?...</utterance>
   <speaker>KEZURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is located at the most South Eastern part of the jungle...near the mountains... There is a village there. The Mongooboo Tribe.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know them?</utterance>
   <speaker>KEZURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very well. I traded with the chief for many years.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That sound. Again.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEZURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scraggy NODS. He DRIVES toward the village. Suddenly, AN ARROW SHOOTS THROUGH THE WINDOW! JUST MISSING everyone. It SHATTERS the passenger window. A TRIBE OF NATIVE WARRIORS appear on the terrain. There are HUNDREDS. SCREAMING in high pitched squeals. Their bodies ADORNED with red and white PAINT. The angry warriors RUN TOWARD the taxi. FIRING ARROWS! On the Taxi roof, the men DIVE for cover. Arrows WHIZ by their heads. Inside, everyone ROLLS UP the windows. The taxi is attacked with a SHOWER OF ARROWS. Scraggy FLOORS the gas. The taxi keeps MOVING AHEAD. SPEEDING toward the jungle. Indiana GLARES at Kezure.</context>
      <utterance>The village is there. Beyond the thick of jungle.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The WARRIORS continue to CHASE the Taxi. Getting CLOSER. Firing more ARROWS. The taxi SPINS to a stop. Directly in front of a LARGE OPENING that leads into the jungle. Everyone POURS OUT of the Taxi. ARROWS fly by their heads. They DASH through the opening. Into the JUNGLE. The Warriors STOP. OUTSIDE of the opening. They DON'T ENTER. TURNING to each other, they begin to LAUGH. VICTORIOUS.</context>
      <utterance>Thought you said they knew you?... Kezure gives a PUZZLED SHRUG.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of the Pirates CONTINUES TO MOVE FORWARD. His foot TRIPS A THIN STRING that stretches across the path. WHOOSH! A BOOBY TRAPPED PALM TREE SWINGS FORWARD! It SLAMS into the Pirate! Like a giant BASEBALL BAT! It sends the Pirate FLYING UPWARD. HIGH INTO THE AIR! His body is THROWN several feet into the jungle. Indiana exchanges a CAUTIOUS look with the others.</context>
      <utterance>Wait... Listen... They're not following us...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana LEADS everyone. They CREEP through the path. Indy PAUSES. CAMERA PANS TO HIS WAIST. A SECTION OF VINE stretches across the path. ANOTHER booby trap. Indiana CRAWLS BENEATH THE VINE. He MOTIONS for the others to follow. One by one, they CAREFULLY CRAWL beneath the vine. The guitar player is LAST. He begins to CRAWL through. He NEARLY makes it, when...the top of his guitar HITS THE VINE! The vine SNAPS. There is a CREAKING SOUND.</context>
      <utterance>Be careful where you step... We've got to move slowly...very slowly...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The lions STOP. Inches from Clare. They SURROUND her. Ready to ATTACK. Indiana WATCHES. PUZZLED. Clare begins to make bizarre PURRING and COOING SOUNDS. The lions PAUSE. They RECOGNIZE the sounds. Clare CONTINUES. The lions begin to WARM UP to her. Clare KNEELS. She PETS the beasts. The lions SNUGGLE up to Clare. LICKING her face. Indiana and the others COME CLOSER. PUZZLED. Clare EXPLAINS.</context>
      <utterance>Clare! What are you...?!?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I imitated the sound of a Lion Mother calling her babies. Betsy is IMPRESSED. Indiana SMILES. RELIEVED.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy TURNS...FACE TO FACE with a grotesque SHRUNKEN HEAD! He STEPS BACK. The shrunken head is worn around the neck of a tall, muscular TRIBAL CHIEF. Leader of the WARRIORS. Countless NATIVES stand behind the chief. A look of ANGER...HATE...covers the Chief's face. Indiana gives a HOPEFUL glance to Kezure.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon. Let's get outta' --</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this the Tribal Chief you told me about?... Your friend?...</utterance>
   <speaker>KEZURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana ROLLS his eyes. The warriors SURROUND everyone. ARROWS aimed. Ready to KILL. The Warriors lead everyone OUT of the path.</context>
      <utterance>No. That is him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KEZURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a different tribe. New. They have taken over the village.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kezure SHRUGS. Indiana TURNS to Scraggy.</context>
      <utterance>What happened to the other tribe?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You recognize their language?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy SMILES. Scraggy TURNS and again SHOUTS to the chief. The chief OBEYS Scraggy's every word. He LEADS Indy and Scraggy to another area of the village. Scraggy TRANSLATES for Indiana.</context>
      <utterance>I tell him we divine messengers of Sun Wu-Kung. If he interfere with our mission... Jade Emperor come down from heavens and destroy his village.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The chief leads Indy and Scraggy into a LARGE GRASS HUT.</context>
      <utterance>I tell him we lose path to city... I ask if he have something to help us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Indy. I'm frightened.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana attempts to PUSH Betsy out of the hammock. She RESISTS. They begin to WRESTLE. STRUGGLE. The hammock becomes TANGLED around their bodies. Clare WALKS BY the hut. She LOOKS inside. To her, it appears that Indy and Betsy are in the middle of a PASSIONATE love scene. She emits a SHOCKED GASP. Indiana SEES Clare. He CALLS OUT.</context>
      <utterance>I'm claustrophobic.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the startled Clare HURRIES AWAY. Indiana manages to ESCAPE Betsy and the tangled hammock. He LANDS on the floor. BREATHLESS.</context>
      <utterance>Clare!... Wait!...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Tribal Chief STEPS FORWARD. He says ONE WORD in his language. Scraggy TRANSLATES for the others.</context>
      <utterance>An earthquake?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wildebeest.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to get out... Or we'll be crushed to death.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scraggy puts his EAR to the trembling ground. He LISTENS.</context>
      <utterance>Scraggy... How close?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy dashes to the Model-T SUPPLY RACK. He tosses SHOVELS to each of the group. He LOOKS around.</context>
      <utterance>Two miles.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scraggy asks a PASSING VILLAGER. The villager SHOUTS some gibberish and continues running. Scraggy POINTS OFF SCREEN. Toward a COMMUNAL</context>
      <utterance>Where's the softest ground?...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, the same LOW, RUMBLING SOUND from earlier, ECHOES through the area. But this time it is LOUD. Nearly DEAFENING. Scraggy LOOKS at Indy.</context>
      <utterance>That's odd... Wildebeests will not stampede unless provoked...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment, directly behind Scraggy and Indy, the jungle ERUPTS! The trees SEPARATE. CRASHING to the ground. Making way for some GIANT BEHEMOTH. Scraggy and the others LEAP IN ONE DIRECTION. Indiana LEAPS</context>
      <utterance>This time, it is very close, Indy. Very close!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scraggy begins to CLIMB OUT of the tree. A GUN suddenly MOVES INTO FRAME. POINTED at Scraggy's head. Scraggy TURNS. One of his CREW MEMBERS holds the gun.</context>
      <utterance>Indy in trouble! We must help!</utterance>
   <speaker>CREW MEMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scraggy and the others FREEZE. Clare makes a REALIZATION. She GLARES at the Crew Member.</context>
      <utterance>Don't move.  All of you. Stay where you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana continues to FIGHT the Nazis, along the SECOND LEVEL of the frenzied tank. Indy has DEFEATED most of the soldiers. Only TWO NAZIS remain. They OVERCOME Indy. They push him DOWNWARD. Toward the tank's FIRST LEVEL. Toward the rows of FIRING MACHINE GUNS. Indiana STRUGGLES to break free. But the powerful Nazis push him CLOSER...CLOSER...to the machine guns. In the TREE, the crew member keeps his pistol AIMED at Scraggy's head. CAMERA PANS UPWARD. Kezure is PERCHED on the top branch. ABOVE Scraggy. At the right moment, Kezure LEAPS DOWN. ON TOP of the treacherous crew member. Kezure KNOCKS the gun from the crew member's hand. BLAM! The gun GOES OFF. A stray bullet STRIKES the tree trunk. Kezure PUNCHES the crew member, who LOSES HIS BALANCE and FALLS from the tree. Going OVER THE EDGE of the ravine. His body DROPS hundreds of feet. CRASHING to the rocks below. Kezure SMILES. VICTORIOUS. But the tree suddenly CREAKS. GROANS. A CRACK has formed around the trunk, where the bullet STRUCK. The tree begins to TILT. Slowly TEETERING over the ravine's edge. Everyone PANICS. Betsy SHOUTS.</context>
      <utterance>It was you. You're the reason the Nazis found us. The crew member gives an evil SMILE.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone FREEZES. Scared to DEATH. They TIGHTLY GRIP their branches. The tree SWAYS. SLOWLY. Indiana still FIGHTS the two Nazis. STRUGGLING to keep his body from the tank's deadly machine guns. Indy FLIPS one of the Nazis over his head. The Nazi falls DIRECTLY IN FRONT of an entire row of machine guns. His body does a GROTESQUE DANCE OF DEATH. RIDDLED with bullets. Indiana and the other Nazi exchange PUNCHES. Their bodies TUMBLE over the rear of the tank. They fall onto a SMALL LEDGE. Above the enormous, rotating TANK TREADS. Indy and the Nazi battle to push the other OFF THE LEDGE. Indiana PREVAILS. He pushes the Nazi ON TOP of the giant treads. The Nazi tries to CLIMB BACK...but his body is</context>
      <utterance>Nobody move. Or we'll go over.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gutterbuhg GROWLS. He SPEAKS German into the microphone. The voice of LIEUT. MEPHISTO answers. Echoing over the SPEAKERS. Indy GRABS the microphone. INTERRUPTING.</context>
      <utterance>Call your mommy.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Jones. I've got your tank.  It's all over, pal. You lose.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scraggy ASKS Tyki. The pygmy ANSWERS, pointing OFF SCREEN. Scraggy TRANSLATES for Indiana.</context>
      <utterance>We've got to move. Fast.  Ask him if he knows the way to the City from here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy TURNs to the direction where Scraggy points. Several miles away, we see COUNTLESS ROWS OF MOUNTAINS. Thick layers of CLOUDS surround the mountains. Indiana SIGHS.</context>
      <utterance>He do not know exact place... But it is somewhere over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy has an IDEA. She removes the STONE MIRROR from Indiana's pocket.</context>
      <utterance>A lotta' good that does us... It could take us months...years...to search everyone of those.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy GIVES the mirror to Tyki. His eyes WIDEN. In AWE. Tyki RECOGNIZES the mirror. He excitedly EXPLAINS to Scraggy, who TRANSLATES for Indiana.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe he knows what to do with this...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is "Magical Mirror of Sun Wu Kung"...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scraggy ASKS Tyki. The energetic pygmy PLACES the mirror against an upright stone. Tyki ADJUSTS the mirror, until it FACES the distant mountains. Tyki emits a high pitched GIGGLE. POINTING to the mirror. Everyone GATHERS around the mirror. The SOUND TRACK MUSIC SOARS. The mirror reflects the CLOUDS above the mountains. But above one SPECIFIC MOUNTAIN, we see the image of a CITY REFLECTED ON THE CLOUDS! Indiana TURNS away from the mirror, looking at the SPECIFIC MOONTAIN. But the city is ONLY REFLECTED IN THE MAGICAL MIRROR! Clare SMILES at Indy, quoting Tyki from earlier.</context>
      <utterance>But whattayou do with it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana NODS. HOPEFUL. ANXIOUS. He looks back to the magical</context>
      <utterance>"I come from Land Of City On Clouds".</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been talking to Dr. Clarke about our problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Problem?... Hey... What're you two doin' talkin' behind my back?...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Betsy needed help. I obliged.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since when did you become the female Sigmund Freud?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy ROLLS HIS EYES. Meanwhile, Kezure has TAKEN all of Scraggy's tokens. He's obviously WON the game. A carefree Scraggy THROWS up his hands.</context>
      <utterance>Since I received a Masters Degree in Psychology.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We play again?</utterance>
   <speaker>KEZURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The game is not yet over, my friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh?</utterance>
   <speaker>KEZURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have lost. You must pay.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have money...</utterance>
   <speaker>KEZURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scraggy GULPS. Kezure PAUSES. RUBBING his jaw. THINKING. Meanwhile, Betsy EXPLAINS to Indians.</context>
      <utterance>No. No. money.  Rules of the game declare that I may choose a souvenir.  A part of your body. Any part I wish.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Clarke says that you're not really in love with me. You're just trying to prove that you can still attract younger women. You're terrified of getting old.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I told her. I told her that you really did love me.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well...that's...ah...well...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean... She was right?...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy TURNS, seeing Clare GLARING at him. Indy SIGHS. PAUSES. He gives Betsy a TENDER, HONEST look.</context>
      <utterance>No... I mean Yes... I mean...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Betsy. I don't love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy begins CRYING. Into Clare's ARMS. Indiana SHAKES his head. Clare COMFORTS Betsy.</context>
      <utterance>That's the first time you ever said it!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana SIGHS. He TURNS. FACE to FACE with a GRINNING and NODDING Gutterbuhg. Kezure has made his DECISION. Scraggy WAITS. TERRIFIED. Kezure RAISES his knife. TOWARD Scraggy's face.</context>
      <utterance>There. There. He's a very disturbed man.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEZURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scraggy COVERS his face. Kezure ATTACKS him. Trying to CUT OUT Scraggy's eyes. A FIGHT begins. The crew members VS. the Pirates. Indiana TURNS, away from the controls. He BREAKS UP the fight.</context>
      <utterance>Your eyes. They are a striking deep blue.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEZURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You owe me, old man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gutterbuhg SMILES. He REFUSES to answer. Indy has NO TIME for games. He LOOKS at Kezure.</context>
      <utterance>How do I work the big gun?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kezure SMILES and removes his LONG KNIFE. He moves it Gutterbuhg's NECK. The snivelling Nazi CRIES OUT.</context>
      <utterance>Want your souvenir?  Start with his good arm.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUTTERBUHG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy NODS to Kezure. The Pirate King moves his KNIFE. Gutterbuhg hurriedly POINTS to two switches on the control panel.</context>
      <utterance>W-W-Wait!... Please!...</utterance>
   <speaker>GUTTERBUHG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy NODS. He TURNS to the switches.</context>
      <utterance>There. That is what you want.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana and the others SMILE. Betsy WHIPSERS to Indy.</context>
      <utterance>He thank us...for returning his son.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy motions for Betsy to "Shhh". Bohbala continues to SPEAK. Scraggy</context>
      <utterance>If the little guy's pushin' 200 years?... How old's his Father?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana exchanges a HOPEFUL glance with Clare. As Bohbala CONTINUES to speak, CAMERA PANS TO GUTTERBUHG. The Nazi has successfully UNTIED his bindings. FREE. While the others listen to Bohbala, Gutterbuhg REMOVES ONE SPARE BULLET FROM HIS MOUTH. He slyly INSERTS the bullet into his mechanical arm. Indiana is TOO CONCERNED with Bohbala to notice Gutterbuhg.</context>
      <utterance>His name "Bohbala". He is Ruler of City, faithful servant of his Lord and Master... Sun Wu-Kung.  He welcome us to stay. As long as we wish.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIOLENCE.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Indiana CLUTCHES Gutterbuhg by the throat.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana pulls back his fist to PUNCH the Nazi. But Indy is STOPPED by the PALACE GUARDS. They move their SWORDS to his throat. Indy is suddenly PUZZLED. The VILLAGERS FALL TO THEIR KNEES. BOWING to Gutterbuhg. A distraught Tyki hurriedly EXPLAINS to Scraggy, who translates for Indy.</context>
      <utterance>Bastard...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gutterbuhg's eyes fill with a sadistic THRILL. He RAISES his MECHANICAL ARM. In a "Heil Hitler" POSE. The entire City IMITATES the Nazi. RAISING their right arms. CHEERING. HAILING their new leader. Indiana is HORRIFIED by the scene. Tyki is UPSET. SCREAMING. He knows that Gutterbuhg is truly EVIL! But NONE of the villagers listen. Indiana LOOKS to his SHOCKED friends.</context>
      <utterance>It is written... If ruler is defeated by greater power...he who possess that power...  ...shall become ruler!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is turning into one helluva nightmare.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUTTERBUBG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy GLARES at Gutterbuhg. Clare and Betsy exchange a FRIGHTENED glance.</context>
      <utterance>One you will never awaken from, Doctor Jones.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GUTTERBUHG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy's eyes BURN. Gutterbuhg GULPS down a glass of wine. Liquid SPITTLES from the sides of his mouth. He LOOKS at Indy.</context>
      <utterance>Your friend makes a wonderful interpreter.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUTTERBUHG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"The Nazi Party will exist for one thousand years...and I wish to be alive for every year!"  That is a favorite philosophy of our feuher.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your feuher's philosphies belong on a bathroom wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUTTERBUHG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a very serious matter, Doctor Jones. It could save your life.  I understand that somewhere in this City...there is a Garden of... Immortal Peaches?...  I want information about this Garden... And I would greatly appreciate it, if you would share everything you know, with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gutterbuhg NODS. He TAKES another bite of food, shooting a GLOWERING look to Indiana.</context>
      <utterance>I don't share anything with Nazis.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUTTERBUHG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gutterbuhg goes back to his FOOD. Scraggy exchanges a WORRIED GLANCE with Indiana.</context>
      <utterance>Very well. My friends will be here soon. They will rest...enjoy the pleasures of my newfound kingdom...  Then we shall exterminate these worthless people! Destroy their City! And we will carry away all of its riches...in pieces.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GUTTERBUHG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy LOOKS at Scraggy, who is very FRIGHTENED.</context>
      <utterance>Doctor Jones... Those beasts are anxious to run wild. Free.  How long will you be able to ride... before they TEAR YOU IN TWO?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUTTERBUHG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gutterbuhg TURNS to the guards. Ready to give them the ORDER...to OPEN THE CAGE and SET THE BUFFALO FREE! Indy suddenly SCREAMS.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Doctor Jones.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Upon hearing the words, Gutterbuhg STANDS. Like a ROBOT. He RAISES his mechanical arm in a "Heil Hitler" POSE.</context>
      <utterance>Heil Hitler!</utterance>
   <speaker>GUTTERBUHG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The FINGERS of Gutterbuhg's mechanical arm get CAUGHT IN THE METAL GRATING ABOVE HIS HEAD! Gutterbuhg TRIES TO REMOVE his fingers. NO GOOD. STUCK. Gutterbuhg PULLS. HARD. His mechanical arm is RIPPED FROM ITS SOCKET! It DANGLES from the grating. The crowd WATCHES. PUZZLED. SHOCKED. Scraggy THINKS FAST. He LEAPS to his feet and GRABS the arm. He TEARS IT OUT of the grating. Scraggy HOLDS the arm above his head. Now it is HE who possesses the POWER! The crowd CHEERS Scraggy! Their NEW RULER! Gutterbuhg STEPS BACK. Suddenly FRIGHTENED. Scraggy ORDERS the guards to FREE Indiana. The guards hurriedly UNTIE Indy from the buffalo. Gutterbuhg TURNS. RUNNING out of the Coliseum. Scraggy SCREAMS to the people, motioning for them to FOLLOW Gutterbuhg. Several people LEAP from their seats. CHASING the Nazi.</context>
      <utterance>Heil Hitler!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They want you to give speech.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!?...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Before battle... General always give speech to inspire troops.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But ALL EYES are on Indiana. DEPENDING on him. Indy SIGHS. Trying to THINK of something to say. He MUMBLES to Scraggy.</context>
      <utterance>General?... Who the hell do they think I am... Custer?...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scraggy SHRUGS. Indy CLEARS his throat. He LOOKS at everyone.</context>
      <utterance>Geez... The only speeches I remember are from college...when I played ball...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy's eyes LIGHT. A moment of INSPIRATION. The background MUSIC SLOWLY BEGINS TO RISE. Indy's voice becomes LOUDER. TOUGHER.</context>
      <utterance>Men...and, ah...women... I...ah... We're about to face one of our toughest opponents... They've got size...hardware...and well, quite frankly...we're the underdogs...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But...well, if it wasn't for the little guy...where would this country be?...  I mean...I knew this little guy once ...a scrawny runt, with thick black glasses and about 300 different kinds of allergies... But this little kid had a dream... He wanted to be on the football team.  Well, all the big guys made his life miserable...always shoving his head in the drinking fountain...putting mustard in his pants...throwing me ...'er, HIM!...throwing HIM in the shower with all his clothes on...  But that little guy didn't quit. Be worked hard. Never gave up. And in two years...he was the Quarterback. Star of the team. And you know why?...  'Cause that little kid had somethin' that those big guys never heard of... He had HEART! And nothin' can stop that! Nothin'!  Now let's go out there and show 'em</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy NODS. The Nazis MOVE CLOSER. Clare looks to the SKY. She begins to make BIZARRE...HIGH PITCHED...NOISES. A CONFUSED Betsy makes the same noises. The Nazis LOOK at each other and CHUCKLE. The women CONTINUE to make the sounds. Suddenly, the exact sound seems to ECHO FROM THE SKY. It becomes LOUDER... LOUDER... But it belongs to A HUNDRED VOICES. The Nazis PAUSE. Looking UPWARD. PUZZLED. There is a SPLATTERING OF BIRDS. They ATTACK from above. The birds' screeching is IDENTICAL to Clare and Betsy's calls. The angry birds ATTACK THE NAZIS. PECKING. SCRATCHING. BITING. Clare and Betsy CONTINUE to make the sounds, which causes the birds to IGNORE THEM. The Nazis SCREAM. DROPPING their weapons. FALLING to their knees. Each soldier is COVERED with birds. They are being TORN TO SHREDS. Clare and Betsy TURN and RUN. ESCAPING into the jungle. The Nazis' screaming ECHOES behind them. As they run, Clare EXPLAINS to Betsy.</context>
      <utterance>Do exactly what I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I made the sound of a baby Swandola bird, crying for help... The Mother birds immediately reply to the cries ...angrily protecting their children, and murdering the baby's attackers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyki WHISPERS to Scraggy, who explains to Betsy.</context>
      <utterance>But... It's... It's the middle of the night...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clare NODS. Kezure is MESMERIZED by the peach trees. His mouth HANGS OPEN. He TURNS to Scraggy.</context>
      <utterance>Sun always shine in the Garden of Immortal Peaches.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEZURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scraggy NODS. Tyki LEADS the procession to a clearing in the garden. Many freshly dug GRAVES are here. All of the bodies are carried to SEPARATE GRAVES, including Indiana And Bohbala. A few feet ahead of the graves, rests the LARGEST PEACH TREE in the forest. It is much WIDER and TALLER than the others. There is a small, glass encased TOMB built into the tree. Inside of the tomb, is a TINY SKELETON. No more than FOUR FEET TALL. The skeleton is adorned with a LION SKINNED ROBE and golden CROWN. In its hand, the skeleton clutches the famous GOLDEN HOOPED ROD, a glorious, elaborate STAFF. An ancient inscription is ETCHED IN STONE over the tomb. Pointing to the inscription, Clare TURNS to Scraggy.</context>
      <utterance>These are the peaches that make one ...forever young?...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does it say?...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pygmies begin to LOWER the dead bodies, including Indiana and Bohbala, into the ground. Tyki reads from ANCIENT SCRIPTURE. Scraggy SOBS on the shoulder of Kezure, who continues to stare in ASTONISHMENT at the peach trees. Suddenly, there is a RUMBLING SOUND. Followed by a slight, TREMOR. The trees begin to SWAY, as a HOWLING WIND rushes through them. The tomb of Sun Wu Kung GLOWS with a BRIGHT LIGHT. The glass surrounding the tomb suddenly SHATTERS. The skeleton's head TURNS. Its body RATTLES. Beginning to MOVE. The skeleton STEPS OUT OF THE TOMB. Everyone STARES in awe. TERRIFIED. The skeleton takes a FEW STEPS forward, STOPS, and RAISES its arms. HIGH in the air. The skeleton OPENS its mouth. Emitting a HIGH PITCHED ...UNEARTHLY...SCREECH! An ectoplasmic GREEN SMOKE seeps from the skeleton's fingers, slowly TRAVELING over the heads of the humans. The ectoplasm separates into several INDIVIDUAL LINES, that touch down upon EACH OF THE GORILLAS. The ectoplasm ENCIRCLES each the Gorilla's bodies. The Gorillas begin to RISE from the ground. HIGH in the air. The ectoplasm appears to be CARRYING them toward Sun Wu Kung. As the Gorillas TRAVEL through the air, their bodies begin to SHRINK. Growing</context>
      <utterance>Damn you, Jones! Why couldn't you be here to share this with me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>SUN WU KUNG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy WHISPERS to Clare.</context>
      <utterance>We cannot bury these men!... This is a garden of life... Not of death!...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why's he speakin' in English?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy NODS. Sun Wu Kung CONTINUES his heartfelt scream into the heavens.</context>
      <utterance>He is a heavenly being. According to legend, when a heavenly being speaks, men of all countries can understand him. We hear him in English...the pygmies hear him in their language.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUN WU KUNG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A few MOMENTS pass. Then...a thick, white cloud ECLIPSES the sun. A small hole in the cloud, allows one RAY OF SUNLIGHT to shine through. The ray shines down upon ONE PARTICULAR PEACH TREE. Sun Wu Kung TURNS to that peach tree. He raises the GOLDEN HOOPED ROD toward the tree. He begins to SING an unusual hymn. Suddenly, several peaches magically FLY from the trees. They congregate ABOVE the golden hooped rod. The peaches SPIN in midair. With quick movements of the rod, Sun Wu Kung SENDS several peaches flying OFF SCREEN. CAMERA FOLLOWS the magical peaches as they SEPARATE and FLY INTO EACH GRAVE. Toward the BODIES OF THE DEAD PYGMIES. Each body is HIT with an individual peach. When the peaches MAKE CONTACT with the dead bodies, there is a small, colorful EXPLOSION. A small FIREWORKS display. The bodies erupt with a BRIGHT GOLDEN GLOW. A few moments PASS. One of the bodies STIRS. MOVES. The body SITS UP. Gets to its FEET. ANOTHER BODY does the same. So does ANOTHER. And ANOTHER. Soon, the various pygmies CLIMB out of the graves. Their wounds have DISAPPEARED. Their life has been RESTORED. Sun Wu Kung flings the remaining TWO PEACHES into the GRAVES of Indiana and Bohbala. There is a small EXPLOSION...followed by the WARM GLOW of their bodies. The wound in Indy's chest VANISHES. His eyes POP OPEN. To the delight of his friends, Indy STANDS. ALIVE. He is PUZZLLED by the surrounding grave. Clare, Scraggy and Betsy HELP Indiana OUT of the grave. They SHOWER him with EMBRACES and KISSES. But Indy remains CONFUSED. PUZZLED.</context>
      <utterance>Return their souls!... I demand it!... Return their souls!</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sun Wu Kung, looking very PLEASED with himself, stands BEHIND Indiana. Clare SMILES at Indy.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell's goin' on?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clare POINTS to behind Indy, who TURNS and sees the smiling SUN WU KUNG. Indy is at first SHOCKED... His face breaks into a CHILDLIKE SMILE...filled with DELIGHT. He then manages to UTTER...</context>
      <utterance>I think there is someone you should meet...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sun Wu Kung STEPS FORWARD. He nods and ANSWERS.</context>
      <utterance>You... You're... Sun Wu Kung?...</utterance>
   <speaker>SUN WU KUNG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are... Indiana Jones?...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?... You know me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUN WU KUNG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have watched you for many, many years...from the heavens. I was fascinated by your bravery...your passion...in searching for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I... Thanks I'm very honored.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUN WU KUNG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sun Wu Kung gives Indiana the GOLDEN HOOPED ROD. Indiana takes the PRICELESS ARTIFACT. He STARES at the beautiful rod. He is very MOVED. SPEECHLESS. Sun Wu Kung EXPLAINS. RAISES an eyebrow.</context>
      <utterance>The honor is mine, Doctor Jones. You and your friends have saved my city from ruin.  I would like to return the favor.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUN WU KUNG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy manages a NOD. Sun Wu Kung SIGHS.</context>
      <utterance>The Golden Hooped Rod will be a faithful friend. It is capable of one hundred transformations...and will always remain by your side.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUN WU KUNG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meanwhile, Kezure uses the oppurtunity to SNEAK AWAY. He DISAPPEARS into a cluster of PEACH TREES. He CLIMBS the smallest tree. The GREEDY Pirate King begins to PICK several peaches. HIDING them in his pockets. Sun Wu Kung LOOKS OVER the healthy, restored community of pygmies. The Monkey King SMILES.</context>
      <utterance>I will explore the heavens for another. Surely, my search will be shorter and less hazardous than yours! Indiana SMILES.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUN WU KUNG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sun Wu Kung again RAISES his arms. Green ECOTPLASM again emanates from his fingers. The individual strands of HAIR fly from his body. In a reversal of what we saw only moments ago, the strands of hair FLY through the air. They grow LARGER...LARGER...until they resume the shape of the GORILLAS. Sun Wu Kung has RETURNED to his skeletal form. He TURNS and WALKS back to his resting place. The pieces of broken glass RE-ASSEMBLE. SEALING the tomb. Kezure, his pockets STUFFED with peaches, hurriedly REJOINS the others. Tyki EMBRACES Bohbala, glad to have his Father ALIVE. Bohbala, resuming his position as Ruler, LEADS HIS PEOPLE out of the garden. Indiana, CLUTCHING his golden hooped prize, EXITS with the others.</context>
      <utterance>With my city alive again...I will be able to return to the heavens.  Goodbye...my dear friends.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KEZURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eh?...</context>
      <utterance>She is a wonderful treasure...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We had a deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEZURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have no deals with dead men.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kezure LAUGHS. He has REMOVED a peach from his pocket. He SHINES the peach on his cloak, and gives a SHRUG to Indiana.</context>
      <utterance>Son of a bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEZURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy is DISGUSTED. Kezure TAKES A LARGE BITE from the peach. As he chews and swallows, Kezure NODS to his men, motioning toward Indy and the others.</context>
      <utterance>I am an old Pirate, Doctor Jones. Do you suddenly expect me to treat you with kindness and fairness?... It is not my way of life!</utterance>
   <speaker>KEZURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men MOVE to kill Scraggy, Betsy, Clare and the crew members. Suddenly, Kezure emits a LOUD SCREAM. He GRABS his stomach in pain. He FALLS to his knees. The HALF EATEN PEACH rolls from his hand. Onto the</context>
      <utterance>Kill them...  But save their hair. I will make a coat out of it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought the peaches promised immortality...eternal youth?...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indiana DROPS the peach to the ground. He grabs his WHIP, REVOLVER and GOLDEN HOOPED ROD. Scraggy and his crew members RETRIEVE their weapons. Everyone TURNS, CONTINUING down the mountain path. LEAVING Kezure's clothes and the several peaches behind.</context>
      <utterance>The garden of immortal peaches promises life only to those who are pure in heart.  Kezure was evil. His heart was filled with greed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, a HORN interrupts. Indy turns to the DIRECTION OF THE SOUND. It is SCRAGGY. He is wearing DRIVING GOGGLES. He rides a battered, bruised MOTORCYCLE, attached to a ricketty SIDECAR. The word "TAXI" is painted on the sidecar's exterior. Scraggy PULLS UP beside Indiana. Scraggy JUMPS OFF the motorcycle. Excitedly, he RUNS toward Indy.</context>
      <utterance>Where's Betsy?... The boat leaves in five minutes...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scraggy FUMBLES through his pockets. He removes a small bottle of PURPLE LIQUID. He HOLDS it out to Indy.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Indy! Indy! I want to give you something for your journey!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRAGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy DECLINES. He flashes a FLASK OF WHISKEY from inside of his coat pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Take one drink before bed. It keep out all bad spirits.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But this'll keep out all the bad spirits. Scraggy SHRUGS. They are suddenly INTERRUPTED.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Scraggy...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Indiana TURNS. BETSY and CLARE walk toward him. Indy LOOKS at Betsy.</context>
      <utterance>Indy!...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where're your bags?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not leaving.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?... But, you... You have to finish school.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy shoots a JEALOUS GLANCE to Clare, then back to Betsy.</context>
      <utterance>I'm staying on as Clare's assistant.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you're MY assistant.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not any more. I'm having my credits transfered.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clare is a brilliant teacher.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So am I.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, but I don't offer a course in seduction.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You stay out of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Indy... I thought you wanted me out of your life...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was before I realized how gifted...how talented you are... I mean... I could really use you...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Especially aboard ship for three weeks. It gets terribly lonely.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I warned you...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Indy, I've learned a lot from you. But it's time I started concentrating on a career in anthropology...instead of romance.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've certainly developed a mature attitude.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks to you.  You know... I always thought of you as my knight in shining armor...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But now, I'll think of you as the Father I never had.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clare WALKS up to him. She EXTENDS her hand.</context>
      <utterance>Terrific.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doctor Jones...although your libido is questionable, your bravery and intelligence are exceptional.  It has been an honor working with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indy LEANS toward Clare, as if he is going to KISS HER. He RAISES an eyebrow. SPEAKING in his smoothest...most suave...</context>
      <utterance>Why... Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, Clare...there's something...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...something I've been wanting to do...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ocean liner's horn SOUNDS! It begins to DRIFT away from the dock. Indiana TURNS and RUNS up the stairs, leading to the boat. The boat is a FEW FEET from the dock. Indy LEAPS onto the boat. He MAKES IT. JUST</context>
      <utterance>Sorry. Guess I left her cage open... she followed us.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
