<movie id="303" title="Inglourious Basterds">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The French Farmer sinks his axe in the stump, looks over his shoulder, and see's the Germans approaching. The FARMERS WIFE, CHARLOTTE comes to the doorway of their home, followed by her TWO OTHER TEENAGE DAUGHTERS, and see the Germans approaching. The Farmer yells to his family in FRENCH, SUBTITLED IN ENGLISH;</context>
      <utterance>Pappa.</utterance>
   <speaker>FARMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go back inside and shut the door.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ready Pappa.</utterance>
   <speaker>FARMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julie walks inside the farm house and closes the door behind her. As her father stands up from his stump, and moves over to the window sill with the water basin... .The SOUND of the ENGINES of the two motorcycles and car get LOUDER. The Farmer SPLASHES water from the basin on his face and down his front. He takes a towel off a nail, and wipes the excess water from his face and chest, as he watches the two motorcycles, the one automobile, and the four representatives of the National Socialist Party come to a halt on his property. We don't move into them, but keep observing them from a distance, like the Farmer. The TWO NAZI MOTORCYCLIST are off their bikes, and standing at attention next to them. The NAZI DRIVER has walked around the automobile, and opened the door for his superior. The NAZI OFFICER says to The Driver in UNSUBTITLED GERMAN;</context>
      <utterance>Thank you darling, now go inside and take care of your mother. Don't run.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAZI OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the property of Perrier LaPadite?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NAZI DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Nazi officer climbs out of the back the vehicle, carrying in his left hand n d</context>
      <utterance>Yes heer Colonel.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Herman, until I summon you, I am to be left alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAZI DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The S.S. COLONEL yells to The Farmer in FRENCH, SUBTITLED IN ENGLISH;</context>
      <utterance>As you wish Heer Col.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAZI OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this the property of Perrier LaPadite?</utterance>
   <speaker>FARMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The S.S. Colonel crosses the distance between them with long strides, and says in French with a smile on his face;</context>
      <utterance>I am Perrier LaPadite.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAZI OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLONEL.HANS LANDA offers the French Farmer PERRIER LAPADITE his hand. The Frenchman takes the German hand in his and shakes it.</context>
      <utterance>It is a pleasure to meet you Monsieur LaPadite, I am Colonel Hans Landa of the S.S.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How may I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was hoping you could invite me inside your home and we may have a discussion.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The S.S. COL clicks his heels together, and takes the hand of the French Farmers Wife...</context>
      <utterance>Colonel Landa, this is my family.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her hand, then continues without letting go of his hostess hand...</context>
      <utterance>Col Hans Landa of the S.S. madame, at your service.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>please excuse my rude intrusion on your routine.</utterance>
   <speaker>FARMERS WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>While still holding the French Woman's hand, and looking into her eyes, The S.S. Colonel says;</context>
      <utterance>Don't be ridiculous, heer Col.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes leave the mother, and move to the three daughters.</context>
      <utterance>Monsieur LaPadite, the rumors I have heard in the village about your family are all true. Your wife is a beautiful woman.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Farmer offers The S.S. Colonel a seat at the families wooden dinner table. The Nazi officer excepts the French Farmers offer, and lowers himself into the chair. Placing his grey S.S. cap on the table, and keeping his black attache case on the floor by his feet. The Farmer (perfect host) turns to his Wife and says;</context>
      <utterance>Merci. Please have a seat.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charlotte, would you be so good as to get The Colonel some wine?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Merci be coupe Monsieur LaPadite, but no wine. This being a dairy farm one would be safe in assuming you have milk?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLOTTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oui.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then milk is what I prefer.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLOTTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The mother of three, takes a craft of milk out of the ice box, and pours a tall glass of the fresh white liquid for The Colonel. The S.S. Colonel takes a long drink from the glass, then puts it down LOUDLY on the wooden table.</context>
      <utterance>Very Well.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monsieur, to both your family, and your cows, I say; Bravo.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Merci.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, join me at your table.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The French Farmer sit's at his wooden dinner table across from The Nazi. The Women remain standing. Col Landa leans forward, and says to the Farmer in a low tone of</context>
      <utterance>Very well.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monsieur LaPadite, what we have to discuss,' would be better discussed in private. You'll notice, I left my men outdoors- if it wouldn't offend them, could you ask your lovely ladies to step outside.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monsieur LaPadite, I regret to inform you I've exhausted the extent of my French. To continue to speak it so inadequately, would only serve to embarrass me. However, I've been lead to believe you speak English quite well?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oui.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it just so happens, I do as well. This being your house, I ask your permission to switch to English, for the remainder of the conversation?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They now speak ENGLISH;</context>
      <utterance>By all means.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Farmer answers;</context>
      <utterance>Monsieur LaPadite, while I'm very familiar with you, and your family. I have no way of knowing if you are familiar with who I am. Are you aware of my existence?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is good. Are you aware of the job I've been ordered to carry out in France?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Colonel drinks more milk.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please tell me what you've heard?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The S.S.Colonel smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I've heard, the fuhrer has put you in charge of rounding up the Jews left in France who are ether hiding, or passing for Gentile.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Fuhrer couldn't of said it better himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But the meaning of your visit, pleasant though it is, is mysterious to me. The Germans looked through my house nine months ago for hiding Jews, and found nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taking his black leather attache case, and placing it on the table, he takes out a folder from inside. He also extracts a expensive black fountain pen from his uniform front pocket. Opening the folder, and referring to it;</context>
      <utterance>I'm aware of that, I read the report on this area. But like any enterprise, when under new management, there's always a slight duplication of efforts. Most of it being a complete waste of time, but needs to be done nevertheless. I just have A few questions Monsieur LaPadite, if you can assist me with answers, my department can close the file on your family.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now before the occupation there were four Jewish families in this area, all dairy farmers like yourself. The Loveitts, The Doleracs, The Rollins, and The Dreyfus's, is that correct?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looking up from his papers.</context>
      <utterance>To my knowledge those were the Jewish families among the dairy farmers. - Heer Colonel, would it disturb you if I smoked my pipe?</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Farmer gets up from the table, goes to his shelf over the fireplace, and removes from it a WOODEN BOX that contains all the fixins to his pipe. He sits back down at the table with his Nazi guest. As The Farmer loads the bowel of his pipe with tobacco, sets a match to it, and begins slowly puffing, making it red hot, the S.S. Colonel studies the papers in front of him.</context>
      <utterance>Please, Monsieur LaPadite, it is your house, make yourself comfortable.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now according to these papers, all the Jewish families in this area have been accounted for - except, The Dreyfusis. Somewhere in the last year it would appear they have vanished. Which leads me to the conclusion that they've ether made good their escape, or someone is very successfully hiding them.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode>(looking up from his papers, across the table at The FARMER)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What have you heard about The Dreyfusis Monsieur LaPadite?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only rumors -</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Farmerlooks at Landa.</context>
      <utterance>- I love rumors! Facts can be so misleading, where rumors, true or false are often reveling. So Monsieur LaPadite, what rumors have you heard regarding The Dreyfusis?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Farmer puffs thoughtfully on his pipe.</context>
      <utterance>Speak freely Monsieur LaPadite, I want to hear what the rumors are, not who told them to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Again, this is just a rumor - but we heard the Dreyfusis had made there way into Spain.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So the rumors you've heard have been of escape?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the Farmer answers this question, the CAMERA LOWERS behind his chair, to the floor, past the floor, to a small area underneath the floorboards revealing;</context>
      <utterance>Were the LaPadites and the Dreyfusis friendly?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The S.S. Colonel takes in this answer, seems to except it, then moves to the next question.</context>
      <utterance>We were families in the same community, in the same bussiness. I wouldn't say we were friends, but members of the same community, we had common interest.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Having never met the Dreyfusis, would you confirm for me the exact members of the household and their names?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>her brother, Bob ...</context>
      <utterance>There were five of them. The father, Jacob... .wife, Miram...</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- How old is Bob?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirty - thirty one?</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Continue.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the children... Amos... and Shoshanna.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ages of the children?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amos - six - I believe. And Shosanna, was fifteen or sixteen, I'm not really sure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Be begins gathering up his papers, and putting them back into his ttache case. the Farmer, cool as a cucumber, puffs on his pipe.</context>
      <utterance>Well I guess that should do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>However, before I go, could I have another glass of your delicious milk?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Farmer stands up, goes over to the ice box, and takes out the aft of milk. As he walks over and fills the Nazi Colonel's glass, German Officer talks.</context>
      <utterance>But of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monsieur LaPadite, are you aware of the nickname the people of France have given me?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have no interest in such things.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you are aware of what they call me?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm aware.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you aware of?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That they call you, "The Jew Hunter".</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As "The Jew Hunter" enjoys his fresh milk, he continues to theorize with the french farmer.</context>
      <utterance>Precisely! Now I understand your trepidation in repeating it. Before he was assassinated, Heydrich apparently hated the moniker the good people of Prague bestowed on him. Actually why he would hate the name, "The Hangman", is baffling to me It would appear he did everything in his power to earn it. But I, on the other hand, love my unofficial title, precisely because I've earned it.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The feature that makes me such a effective hunter of the Jews, is, as opposed to most German soldiers, I can think like a jew. where they can only think like a German, or more precisely, a German soldier. Now if one were to determine what attribute the German people share with a beast, it would be the cunning and predatory instinct of a hawk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode>CON'T</mode>
      <context>smell - physical strength - penis size. But, if one were to determine what attributes the jews share with a beast, it would be that of the rat. Now the Fuhrer and Gobbles propaganda have said pretty much the same thing. Where our conclusions differ, is I don't consider the comparison a insult. Consider for a moment, the world a rat lives in. It's a hostile world indeed. If a rat were to scamper through your front door right now, would you greet it with hostility?</context>
      <utterance>Negro's - gorilla's - brain - lips -</utterance>
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose I would.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Has a rat ever done anything to you to create this animosity you feel toward them?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rat's spread disease, they bite people -</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- Unless some fool is stupid enough to try and handle a live one, rats don't make it a practise of biting human beings. Rats were the cause of the bubonic plague, but that was some time ago. In all your born days, has a rat ever caused you to be sick a day in your life? I purpose to you, any disease a rat could spread, a squirrel could equally carry. Yet I assume you don't share the same animosity with squirrels that you do with rats, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yet, they are both rodent's, are they not? And except for the fact that one has a big bushy tail, while the other has a long repugnt tail of rodent skin, they even rather look alike, don't they?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is a interesting thought, beer Colonel.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>However, interesting as the thought may be, it makes not one bit of difference to how you feel. If a rat were to scamper through your door, this very minute, would you offer it a saucer of your delicious milk?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably not.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(let's the</context>
      <utterance>I didn't think so. You don't like them. You don't really know why you don't like them. All you know is, you find them repulsive.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, Cononel, make yourself at home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Colonel lets the last statement stand.</context>
      <utterance>The other mistake the German soldier make is their severe handling of the citizens who give shelter and aid to the Jews. These citizens are not enemies of the state. They are simply confused people, trying to make some sense out of the madness war creates. These citizens do not need punishing. They simply need to be reminded of their duty in war time. Let's use you as a example Monsieur LaPadite. In this war, you have found yourself in the middle of a conflict that has nothing to do with yourself, your lovely ladies, or your cows - yet, here you are. So Monsieur LaPadite, let me purpose a question. In this time of war, what is your number one duty? Is it to fight the Germans in the name of France to your last breath? Or, is it to harass the occupying army to the best of your ability? Or, is it to protect the poor unfortunate victims of warfare who can not protect themselfs? Or, is your number one duty in this time of bloodshed, to protect those very beautiful women who constitute your family?</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was a question Monsieur LaPadite. In this time of war, What do you consider your number one duty?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To protect my family.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, my job dictates, that I must have my men enter your home, and conduct a thorough search, before I can officially cross your families name off my list.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode>CON'T</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if there are any irregularities to be found, rest assured, they will be. That is unless, you have something to tell me that will make the conducting of a search unnecessary.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are sheltering enemies of the state, are you not?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your sheltering them underneath your floorboards aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Farmer points out the area's on the floor with the Dreyfusis are underneath.</context>
      <utterance>Point out to me the area's where their hiding.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since I haven't heard any disturbance, I assume that while their listening, they don't speak english?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes .</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to switch back to french now, and I want you to follow my masquerade - is that clear?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Nazi Officer opens the front door, and silently motions for his son to approach the house.</context>
      <utterance>Monsieur LaPadite, I thank you for milk, and your hospitably. I do believe our business here is done.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yet the LaPadite women watch the Nazi soldiers, machine guns at ready, approach the house. The Soldiers enter the doorway, Col Landa, silently points out area of the floor the Jews are hiding under.</context>
      <utterance>Mademoiselle LaPadite, I thank you for your time, we shant be bothering your family any longer.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>otions to the Soldiers with his index finger. wy TEAR UP the wood floor with MACHINE GUN FIRE. The little farm house is filled with SMOKE, DUST, SPLINTERS, SCREAMS, 0ULLET CASINGS, and even alittle BLOOD. With a hand motion from the Colonel, the Soldiers cut off their gunfire. The Colonel keeps his finger in the air to indicate silence.</context>
      <utterance>So, Monsieur and Madame LaPadite I bid you adieu.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LTHY BAREFEET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>same as a animal being chased by a predator FLIGHT - PANIC - FEAR</context>
      <utterance>LAPPING against wet grass. Qt! SHOSANNMA' S FACE</utterance>
   <speaker>SNOSANNA'S POV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>the safety of tree's, getting closer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CU COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>SLOW ZOOM into his eyes as he aims.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFILE CU SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sod dash for life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Au revoir, Shosanna! Till we meet again!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>T h e S.S. Colonel closes the window.</context>
      <utterance>Maces it to the woods, and is gone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Herman, I sense` a question on your lips? Out with it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did yoy allow a enemy of the state to escape?</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I don't think the state is in too much danger, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose not.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The S.S. Colonel chuckles at his little funny.</context>
      <utterance>I'm glad you see it my way. Besides, not putting a bullet in the back of a fifteen year old girl, and allowing her to escape, our not nessessarlly the same thing. She's a young girl, no food, no shelter, no shoes, who's just witnessed the massacre of her entire family. She may not survive the night. And after word spreads about what happened today, it's highly unlikely she will find any willing farmers to extend her aid. If I had to guess her fate, I'd say she'll probably be turned in by some neighbour. Or, she'll be spotted by some German soldier. Or, we'll find her body in the woods, dead from starvation or exposure. Or, perhaps-she'll survive. She will elude capture. She will escape to America. She will move to New York city. Where she will be elected, President of the United States.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode>CON'T</mode>
      <context>He stops pacing, and looks at everybody.</context>
      <utterance>We will be cruel to the Germans, and through our cruelty, they will know who we are. They will find the evidence of our cruelty, in the disembowed, dismembered, and disfigured bodies of their brothers we leave behind us. And the German will not be able to help themselves from imagining the cruelty their brothers endured at our hands, and our boot heels, and the edge of our knives. And the Germans, will be sickened by us. And the Germans, will talk about us. And the Germans, will fear us. And when the Germans close their eyes at night, and their sub conscious tortures them for the evil they've done, it will be with thoughts of us, that it tortures them with.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all say;</context>
      <utterance>Sound good?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>.or you will die trying.</context>
      <utterance>That's what I like to hear. But I got a word of warning to all would-be warriors. When you join my command, you take on debit. A debit you owe me, personally. Every man under my command, owes me, one hundred nazi scalps. And I want my scalps. And all y'all will git me, one hundred Nazi scalps, taken from the heads of one hundred dead Nazi's...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HITLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much more of these jew swine must I endure? They butcher my men like they were fish bait! This pack of filthy degenerates, are doing what the Russian army didn't, and Patton's army couldn't. Turning soldiers of The Third Reich, into superstitious old women!</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hitler pounds furiously on the desk with his fist.</context>
      <utterance>Just the cowards among them mine Fuhrer.</utterance>
   <speaker>HITLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, no, no, no, no! I have heard the rumors myself! Solders of The Third Reich, who have brought the world to there knee`s, now pecking and clucking like chickens. Do you know the latest rumor they've conjured up, in their fear induced delirium? The one that beats my boys with a bat. The one they call "The Bear Jew"...is a Golem. A avenging jew angel, conjured up by a vengeful rabbi, to smite the Aryans!</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mine Fuhrer, this is just soldiers gossip, no one really believes The Bear Jew is a golem.</utterance>
   <speaker>HITLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not? They seem to be able to elude capture like a aberration. They seem to be able to appear and disappear at will.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HITLER</speaker>
      <mode>CON'T</mode>
      <context>The Fuhrer sits down at the table to compose himself, and wipe his greasy black hair out of his face.</context>
      <utterance>You want to prove their flesh and blood? Then BRING THEM TO ME! I will hang them naked, by their heels, from the eiffel tower! And then throw their bodies in the sewers, for the rats of Paris to feast!</utterance>
   <speaker>HITLER</speaker>
      <mode>DISGUSTED</mode>
      <context>He hits the button on the intercom on his desk.</context>
      <utterance>The Bear Jew.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>KLIEST1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>KLIEST VOICE comes out of the intercom;</utterance>
   <speaker>KLIEST'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Year mine Fuhrer.</utterance>
   <speaker>HITLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Did you get that Kliest?</context>
      <utterance>I have a order I want relayed to all German soldiers stationed in France. The Jew degenerate known as The Bear Jew, hence forth, is never to be referred to as The Bear Jew again. We will cease to aid the Americans any longer in there attempt to undermine the German soldier psyche.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLIEST'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes mine Fubrer. Do you still wish to see Private Butz?</utterance>
   <speaker>HITLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who and what is a private Butz?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELIST'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's the soldier you wanted to see personally. His squad was ambushed by Lt.Raines Jews. He was it's only survivor.</utterance>
   <speaker>HITLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Indeed I do want to see him, thank you for reminding me. Send him in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PVT.BUTZ</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Werner and I were the only ones left alive after the ambush. While one man guarded us, the rest removed the hair. All The Basterds wore German scalps tied to their belts.</utterance>
   <speaker>CU SCALPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>hanging from belts.</utterance>
   <speaker>PVT.BUTZ</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They not only took valuables...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PVT.BUTZ</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>Utivich RIPS the page out, and sticks it in his pocket. Tossing the torn book on the dead, scalpless body.</context>
      <utterance>.and tore out the identification page.</utterance>
   <speaker>PVT.BUTZ</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...They then removed their boots...</utterance>
   <speaker>CU GERMAN COMBAT BOOTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>laces untied.. .boot pulled off...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOCKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>removed, reveling dead bare feet...</utterance>
   <speaker>BASTERDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>tossing the boots off a hill.</utterance>
   <speaker>PVT.BUTZ</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Throwing them away from the bodies...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HITLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The dogsl He fights his frustration, then...</utterance>
   <speaker>HITLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Continue.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Hirschberg, send that kraut sarge over.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASTERD PFC.HIRSCHBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>KICKS Sgt.Rachtman in the back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PFC.HIRSCHBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sgt.Rachtman is a little slow to respond. So Hirschberg grabs him by the hair, YANKS him to his feet, and KICKS him in the ass, sending him on his way. Most of The Bastreds sit in a circle, Indian style, with Aldo in the middle. As Sgt.Rachtman walks towards this circle of Basterds, A OFF SCREEN LITERARY NARRATOR (not Pvt.Butz) speaks over the SOUNDTRACK in ENGLISH;</context>
      <utterance>You! Go!</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>stands straight before the sitting southern Lieutenant, and salutes his captor.</context>
      <utterance>Sgt.Werner Rachtman has seen many interrogations since Germany decided it should rule Europe. But this is the first time he's ever been on the wrong end of the exchange. It's always been his belief, only a weakling, in mind, body, and spirt complies with the enemy under threat of consequence. As Werner watched men cry like women, pleadingly offer their knowledge, in exchange for their worthless lives, he made a vow to himself. If his role is to die in this conflict. When they put him under the earth, his dignity would be buried with him. For in the other world, the gods only respect the ones they test first. Well Sgt, this is your test. And the gods are watching. The captured German Sgt, enters the circle of Basterds,</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.RACHTMAN</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>Aldo returns the salute, looking up at him.</context>
      <utterance>Sgt.Werner Rachtman.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You know what sit down means Werner?</context>
      <utterance>Lt.Aldo Raine, pleased to meet cha.</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.RACHTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then sit down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>2.5.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The German Sgt does.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aldo points at one of The Basterds in the circle,</context>
      <utterance>Hows your English Werner? Cause if need be, we gotta a couple fellas can translate.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then Aldo points to another Basterd. A big scary looking Basterd, in a German Sgt's uniform, named, SGT.HUGO STIGLITZ</context>
      <utterance>Wicki there, a Austrian Jew, got the fuck outta Saltzberg, while the gettin was good. Became American, got drafted, and came back to give y'all what for.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two German Sgt's look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>And another one over there, you might be familiar with, Sgt.Hugo Stiglitz. Heard of 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.RACHTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Basterds laugh, a couple pat Hugo on the back. The NARRATOR comes back on the SOUNDTRACK.</context>
      <utterance>Everybody in the German army's heard of Hugo Stiglitz.</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>WE SEE A PHOTO OF HUGO on the front page of the Nazi version of Stars and Stripes (the military newspaper).</context>
      <utterance>The reason for Hugo Stiglitz's celebrity among German soldiers is simple.</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As a German enlisted man, he killed thirteen Gestapo officers, mostly Majors.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>Hugo in chains, being put in a lone troop truck, part of a prison convoy, enroute to Berlin.</context>
      <utterance>Instead of putting him up against a wall, the High Command decided to send him back to Berlin, to be made a example of.</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Needless to say, once The Basterds heard about him, he never got there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hugo nods.</context>
      <utterance>Sgt.Hugo Stiglitz?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hugo nods his head, yes.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Lt.Aldo Raine, and these are The Basterds. Ever heard of us?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We all came here to see, if you wanna go pro?</context>
      <utterance>We just wanna say, we're a big fan of your work. When it comes to killin Nazi's, I think you show great talent, and I pride myself on havin a eye for that kind of talent. But your status as a Nazi killer, is still amateur.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now Werner, I'm gonna assume you know who we are?</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.RACHTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The circle of Basterds giggle.</context>
      <utterance>Aldo the Apache.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Basterds laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Well Werner, if you heard of us, you probably heard, we ain't in the prisoner takin business. We in the killin Nazi business. And cousin, business is boomin.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aldo takes out a map of the area, and lays it out in front of his prisoner.</context>
      <utterance>Now that leaves two ways we can play this out. Either kill ya, or let ya go. Now weather or not you gonna leave this circle alive, depends entirely on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Up the road a piece, there's a orchard. 'sides you, we know there's another kraut patrol fuckin around here somewhere. Now if that patrol were to have any crackshots, that orchard, would be a goddamn snipers delight. Now if you ever wanna eat a sauerkraut sandwich again, you gotta show me on this map, where they are, you gotta tell me how many they are, and you gotta tell me, what kinda artillery they carrying with 'em?</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.RACHTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't expect me to divulge information that would put German lives in danger?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Werner site, head held high, back straight, chin up, every inch the German hero facing death.</context>
      <utterance>well, Werner that's where your wrong. Because that's exactly what I expect. I need to know about Germans hidin in trees? And you need to tell me? And you need to tell me, right now? Now take your finger, and point out on this map, where this partys bein held, how manys comin, and what they brought to play with?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SGT.WERNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aldo jerks his thumb behind him.</context>
      <utterance>F I respectfully refuse, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WE RACK FOCUS to a one of The Basterds not in the circle. He's wearing a wife beater, and power hitting stones with a baseball bat. Werners eyes go to the ballplayer.</context>
      <utterance>You see that ole boy battin rocks?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Sgt.Donny Donowitz. But you might know him better by his nickname, The Bear Jew. Now if you heard of Aldo the Apache, you gotta heard about The Bear Jew?</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.RACHTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you hear?</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.RACHTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He beats German soldiers with a club.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He bashes their brains in with a baseball bat, what he does.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LT. ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now Werner, I'm gonna ask you one last-goddamn-time, and if you still, "respectfully refuse", I'm callin The Bear Jew over here, and he's gonna take that big bat of his, and he's gonna beat your ass to death with it. Now take your wennersitnitzel lickin finger, and point out on this map what I want to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.RACHTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you and your jew dogs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SGT.DONOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>he turns to CAMERA, and yells;</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.DONOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got a German here wants to die for country. Oblige him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.DONNY DONOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bat over his shoulder, smiles.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>.ya got the goddamn fuckin Germans, declaring open season on Jews in Europe, and I'm suppose to fly to the fuckin Philippines, and fight a bunch of fuckin Japs - not me pal. If we just go in this against the Japs, the whole U.S.of fuckin A can go take a running jump at the moon.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know they got a word for what your sayin Donny, it's called treason.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, stick your treason up your poop hole. If I'm gonna kill my fellow man in the name of liberty, that fellow man, will be German.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MR.GOOROWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello Donny, how are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, just dandy, Mr.Goorowitz.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR.GOOROWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your mother, your father - everything good there?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The store proprietor, extends his hand to the young man.</context>
      <utterance>There just fine. I'm shippin off next week.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR.GOOROWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good for you son. Kill one of those Nazi basterds for me, will ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the idea, Mr.Goorowitz.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR.GOOROWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can I do you for, Donny?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The store owner leads him to a basket with eight bats init. Donny starts going through them without saying anything.</context>
      <utterance>I need a baseball bat.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR.GOOROWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donny, concentrating on the bats, not looking up;</context>
      <utterance>You gettin your little brother a present before you ship out?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donny's "no", silences the gabby Goorowitz. He seems to settle on one, feeling it's weight in his hands.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I try this one on for size, outside?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>31.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Extending his arm;</utterance>
   <speaker>MR.GOOROWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The phone rings.</context>
      <utterance>Be my guest.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR.GOOROWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The proprietor answers the phone, and gets into a conversation with his OFF SCREEN Mother. Donny walks outside, WE STAY IN STORE, but can see him clearly through the stores big picture window. However, Mr.Goorowitz instinctively, turns his back to Donny to speak with his mother. Donny starts swinging the bat. It's pretty obvious he's pantomiming beating somebody to death with it. Then the he starts yelling;</context>
      <utterance>I'll get that, you go right ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr.Goorowitz, see's none of this, as he speaks to his mother. He hangs up the phone, just as Donny walks back into the store. Store owner turns to store customer.</context>
      <utterance>Take that ya Nazi basterd! You like fuckin with the Jews? Wanna Fuck with the Jews? The American jews are gonna FUCK with you... ..!</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this the heaviest ya got?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs.Himmelstein?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS.HIMMELSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>State your business young man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs.Himmelstein, I'm Donny Donowitz, my father Sy Donowitz, owns the barber shop on Greeny Ave, "Sy's Barber Shop".</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS.HIMMELSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've seen it. Do you live in the neighbourhood?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS.HIMMELSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Again, state your business?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I have a word with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS.HIMMELSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She thinks for a beat, then holds the door open for the young man.</context>
      <utterance>Our people in Europe.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS.HIMMELSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come in. Would you like some tea?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS.HIMMELSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donny chuckles at her little joke. The old woman remains stone. She wasn't joking. He places his saucer on the coffee table and begins;</context>
      <utterance>If you like tea.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs.Himmelstein, do you have any love ones over in Europe who your concerned for?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MRS.HIMMELSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What compels you young man, to ask a stranger such a personal question?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I'm going to Europe. And I'm gonna make it right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS.HIMMELSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And just how do intend to do that, Joshua?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MRS.HIMMELSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what exactly do you intend to do with that toy?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna beat every Nazi I find to death with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS.HIMMELSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought we were having tea together?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS.HIMMELSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And in this pursuit, how is it that I can be of service?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going through the neighbourhood. If you have any love ones in Europe, who's safety you fear for, I'd like you to write their name on my bat.</utterance>
   <speaker>BACK TO BASTERDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As WE CUT BACK and FORTH BETWEEN DONNY WALKING and WERNER WAITING, WE ALSO CUT BACK and FORTE BETWEEN DONNY and</context>
      <utterance>Donny takes a long walk to Werner...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You bet your sweet ass I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS.HIMMELSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donny steps up to the plate, looking down at the Nazi;</context>
      <utterance>Good. A Basterds work is never done. Specially in Germany.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Werner hands Donny up his papers. Donny RIPS the identity page out, and sticks it in his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Gimmie your papers.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS.HIMMELSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hand me your sword Gideon. I do believe I will join you on this journey.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>she signs the BAT, "MADELEINE"</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PVT.BUTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>watches. Hirschberg says to him;</utterance>
   <speaker>PFC.HIRSCHBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aldo points a finger at Butzsr and crooks it toward him.</context>
      <utterance>About now, I'd be shittin my pants, if I was you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PFC.HIRSCHBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A crying, visibly shaken, Butz site down in front of Aldo.</context>
      <utterance>That means you, cup cake.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna live?</utterance>
   <speaker>PVT.BUTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His arm shoots out like a rocket, and points out the positions.</context>
      <utterance>Point out on this map, the German position.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PVT.BUTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This area here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many?</utterance>
   <speaker>PVT.BUTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe twelve.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kinda of artillery?</utterance>
   <speaker>PVT.BUTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They have a machine gunn dug in here pointing north.</utterance>
   <speaker>HITLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WE SEE Pvt.Butz in The Fuhrer's room for the first time. He wears a Nazi cap, which is unusual in the presence of The Fuhrer, but he seems okay with it.</context>
      <utterance>How did you survived this ordel?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRVT.BUTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They let me go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now when you report what happened here, you can't tell 'em, you told us, what you told us. They'll shoot ya. But there gonna wanna know, why you so special, we let you live? So tell 'em, we let ya live, so you could spread the word through the ranks, what's gonna happen to every Nazi we find.</utterance>
   <speaker>HITLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not one word more.</context>
      <utterance>You are not to tell anybody anything! Not one word of detail! Your outfit was ambushed, and you got a away.</utterance>
   <speaker>PVT.BUTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes mine Fuhrer.</utterance>
   <speaker>HITLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did they mark you like they did the other survivors?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PVT.BUTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes mine Fuhrer.</utterance>
   <speaker>HITLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remove your hat and show me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now say we let ya go, and say you survive the'war? When you get back home, what'eha gonna do?</utterance>
   <speaker>PVT.BUTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will hug my mother like I've never hugged her before.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, ain't that's a real nice boy. Are you going to take off your uniform?</utterance>
   <speaker>PVT.BUTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The young German is telling Aldo, what he thinks, Aldo wants to hear. But the last answer didn't go down as well as he thought it would, evident by the frown on Aldo's face.</context>
      <utterance>Not only shall I remove it, but I intend to burn it!</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aldo removes a LARGE KNIFE from a sheath on his belt.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that's what we thought. We don't like that. You see, we like our Nazi's in uniforms. That way, you can spot 'em, just like that.  But you take off that uniform, ain't nobody gonna know you was a Nazi. And that don't sit well with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I'm gonna give ya a little somethin, you can't take off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MADAME MIMIEUX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So young woman, since it's beyond obvious we're closed for the evening. I must assume you want something. What can I do for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I sleep here tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME MIMIEUX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I gather your not a nurse?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME MIMIEUX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But your a bright little thing, that's clever disguise. Where is your family?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Murdered.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MADAME MIMIEUX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So your a war orphan?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were from Nancy. The Bosch found us</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME MIMIEUX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this a sad story?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oui.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME MIMIEUX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sad stories bore me. These days everyone in Paris has one. I haven't bore you with mine, don't bore me with yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can run the machines?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME MIMIEUX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Using her hands to pantomime the rotating film reels on a projector, she says;</context>
      <utterance>What machines?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The machines that show the film?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME MIMIEUX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The projectors? Yes, I own a cinema, of course I can operate them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, I saw you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>MADAME MIMIEUX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know at least six people who've been put up against a wall, and machine gunned for sheltering enemies of the state. I have no intention of being unlucky number seven. How long have you been in Paris?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A week, and a few days.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME MIMIEUX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How have you survived the curfew without capture?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I sleep on rooftops.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME MIMIEUX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Again, I'm forced to admit, clever girl. How is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cold.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME MIMIEUX</speaker>
      <mode>LAUGHS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can imagine.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Respectfully, no you can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME MIMIEUX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fair enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME MIMIEUX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you can't operate a 35mm film projector, you want me teach you, in order to work here, in order to use my cinema, as a hole to hide in, is that correct?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oui.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME MIMIEUX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whats your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shosanna.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MADAME MIMIEUX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Madame Mimieux. You may call me Madame. This is a cinema. Not a home for wayward war orphans. Having said that, what you say is true. If you were truly exceptional, I could find use for you. So Shosanna, are you truly exceptional?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oui Madame.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME MIMIEUX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will be the judge of that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>EXT - CINEMA - NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>"GERMAN NIGHT LENI REFENSHTAL in PABST WHITE HELL OF PIZA PALU" Shosanna emerges from the cinema carrying two buckets of LETTERS (for the marquee), and a tall ladder. Her chore here, obviously, is to change the show on the marquee. The LITERARY NARRATOR comes on the Soundtrack in ENGLISH;</context>
      <utterance>The MARQUEE READS in French:</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>Shosanna, by herself, perched up high on the ladder, changing the letters on the marquee. A YOUNG GERMAN SOLDIER(about the same age as Shosanna), walks out of the cinema. He sees the ladder with the young French girl on top, and walks over. They speak FRENCH, SUBTITLED into ENGLISH;</context>
      <utterance>To operate a cinema in Paris during the occupation, one had two choices. Ether you could show new German propaganda films, produced under the watchful eye of Joseph Goebbels. Or... .you could have a German night in your weekly schedule, and show allowed German classic films. Their German night was Thursday.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shosanna looks down, seeing the young German Solder smiling up at her from below.</context>
      <utterance>What starts tomorrow?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A Max Linder festival.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shosanna continues working, not adding to the conversation.</context>
      <utterance>Ummmm, I always preferred Linder to Chaplin. Except Linder never made a film as good as "The Rid". The chase climax of "The Kid", superb.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose now you could use a "M" a "A" and a "X"?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No need, I can manage.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands the French damsel the letters spelling MAX.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be ridiculous, it's my pleasure.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Merci.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I adore your cinema very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She busies herself with the marquee letters...</context>
      <utterance>Merci.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My aunt left it to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shosanna makes no reply back.</context>
      <utterance>Lucky girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Merci for hoisting a German night.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have a choice, but your welcome.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you chose the German films yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oui.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then my merci stands. I love the Refensthal mountain films, especially, "Pizu Palu". It's nice to see a French girl who's a admirer of Refensthal.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Admire", would not be the adjective I would use to describe my feelings towards Fraulein Refensthal.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She climbs down from the ladder and faces the German Private.</context>
      <utterance>But you do admire the director. Pabst, don't you? That's why you included his name on the marquee.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm French. We respect directors in our country.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Apparently even Germans.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to go back inside.</context>
      <utterance>Even Germans. Merci for assistance, Private. Adieu.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your not finished?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens the door to go inside.</context>
      <utterance>I'll finish in the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I ask your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands him her excellently forged papers. That's obviously not what he meant, but he takes them anyway to read her name.</context>
      <utterance>You wish to see my papers?</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Emmanuelle Mimieux. That's a very pretty name.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands them back.</context>
      <utterance>Merci. Are you finished with my papers?</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mademoiselle. My name is Fredrick Zoller. She gives no response.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives her a little salute, and walks into the black of a curfew imposed night. She looks after him. She didn't show it, but he kinda got to her. After all, for any true cinema lover, it's hard to hate anybody who, CINEMA MON AMOUR.</context>
      <utterance>It's been a pleasure chatting with a fellow cinema lover. Sweet dreams, Mademoiselle.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MADAME MIMIEUX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shosanna is shocked by this statement.</context>
      <utterance>if I ever see you light up a cigarette in my cinema again, I'll turn you into the Nazi's, do you understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oui, Madame.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME MIMIEUX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Do you understand me?</context>
      <utterance>And for bringing a open flame in my cinema, you deserve far worse then a Nazi jewish boxcar. With your thick head, what do you think the highest priority of a cinema manager is? Keeping this fucking place from burning down to the ground, that's what! In my collection, I have over 350, 35mm, nitrate film prints, which are not only immensely flammable, but highly unstable. And should they catch fire, they burn three times faster then paper. If that happens.. .POOF...all gone, cinema no more, every body burned alive. If I ever see you with a open flame in my cinema again, I won't turn you into the Nazi's I'll kill you myself. And the fucking Germans will give me a curfew pass.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out, Madame.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME MIMIEUX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you believe me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out, Madame.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAME MIMIEUX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You damn well better.</utterance>
   <speaker>BACK TO ROOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcel comes onto the roof.</context>
      <utterance>Shosanna exhales cigarette smoke.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you well?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even on the roof I can't smoke a cigarette without hearing Madames voice yelling at me. That's why I do it. To hear Madames voice again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We both miss her.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcel goes back inside, Shosanna smokes.</context>
      <utterance>I know. I'm fine, darling. I'll be to bed soon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I join you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look Fredrick -</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode>SMILING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- You remember my name?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes....Look, you seem a pleasant enough fellow -</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- Merci.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your welcome. - regardless, I want you to stop pestering me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I apologize mademoiselle, I wasn't trying to be a pest. I was simply trying to be friendly.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't wish to be your friend.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't act like a infant. You know why.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm more then just a uniform.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then TWO OTHER GERMAN SOLDIERS come over, obviously very impressed with Fredrick. They make a fuss over him in UNSUBTITLED GERMAN, which nether Shosanna, or the non German speaking members of the movies audience, can understand. He signs autographs for them, shakes their hands, and they go on their way. Shosanna's eyes narrow.</context>
      <utterance>Not to me. If you are so desperate for a French girlfriend, I suggest you try Vichy?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought I was just a uniform?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your not just a German soldier, are you somebodies son?</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Most German soldiers are somebodies son.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans in across the table, she leans in too, and he says;</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but your not just somebody. What are you, Hitlers nephew?</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leans back annoyed.</context>
      <utterance>No not really, I'm just teasing you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what is it? What are you, a German movie star?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>, what does that mean, "not exactly". I asked if you were a movie star, the answer to that question, is yes or no. Fredrick laughs at that line.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This catches young Shosanna off guard.</context>
      <utterance>When you said that just now, you reminded me of my sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I come from a home of six sisters. We run a family operated cinema in Munich. Seeing you run around your cinema, reminds me of them. Especially my sister Helga. She raised me, when our father wasn't up to the job. I admire her very much. You'd like her, she doesn't wear a German uniform.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were raised by Helga?</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All my sisters, I'm the baby, but Helga was the bossiest.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And your mother and father?</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My mother died. And my father was a loser. My fathers moto; "If at first you don't succeed, quit". The day he left, good riddance. My sisters are all I need. It's why I like your cinema. It makes me feel both closer to them, and a little homesick at the same time.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>is your cinema still operatiing?</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oui.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's it called?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Kino Haus.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How has it done durring the war?</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, in Germany, cinema attendance is up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No doubt, you don't have to operate under a curfew.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How often do you fill your house?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>, not since before the war.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So if you had one big engagement, that would help you out?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TWO MORE GERMAN SOLDIERS and their TWO FRENCH DATES approach the table. They ask for Fredricks autograph, he signs it for them. One of the French Girls says in FRENCH, how exciting it is to meet a real live German war hero. Shosanna hears it. They leave. So that's it, she thinks.</context>
      <utterance>Of course, but that's not likely to happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So your a war hero? Why didn't you tell me?</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody knows that, I liked you didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a sip of beer.</context>
      <utterance>What did you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You bet your sweet ass that got her attention.</context>
      <utterance>I've shot the most enemy soldiers in world war two...so far.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was alone in a bell tower in a walled off city in Russia. It was myself, and a thousand rounds of ammo, in a bird's nest, against three hundred Soviet soldiers.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's a bird's nest?</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A bird's nest is what a sniper would call a bell tower. It's a high structure, offering a three hundred and sixty degree view. Very advantageous for marksmen.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many Russian's did you kill?</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sixty-eight.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The first day. A hundred and fifty the second day. Thirty-two, the third day. On the forth day, they exited the city. Naturally my war story received alot of attention in Germany, that's why they all recognize me. They call me the German Sgt.York.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe they'll make a film about your exploits.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's just what Joseph Goebbels thought. So he did. It's called "Nation's Pride", and guess what, they wanted me to play myself, so I did. They have posters for it in kiosks all over Paris. That's another reason for all the attention.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Nation's Pride" is about you? "Nation's Pride" is starring you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, comical, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not so comical. So what are you doing in Paris, enjoying a rest?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shosanna, wasn't falling for the young German, by any stretch. However his exploits, as well as his charming manner, can't help but impress. But his referring to Goebbels as "Joseph", like their friends, is all she needed to get on the right side of things. This young man is trouble with a capital "T", and she needs to stay far fucking away from him. She abruptly rises, and says;</context>
      <utterance>Hardly. I've been doing publicity, having my picture taken with different German luminaries, visiting troops, that sort of thing. Goebbels wants the film to premier in Paris, so I've been helping them in the planning. Joseph is very keen on this film. He's telling anybody who will listen, when "Nation's Pride" is released, I'll be the German Van Johnson.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that, she disappears. Leaving the perplexed private alone.</context>
      <utterance>Well, good luck with your premier Private. I hope all goes well for Joseph and yourself. Au revoir.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXT - CINEMA MARQUEE - DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shosanna and Marcel are changing the letters on the marquee. Marcel excuses himself to visit the toilet. $hosanna is alone outside the little cinema, perched up on her ladder.</context>
      <utterance>It's the next day.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GESTAPO MAJOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mademoiselle Nimieux?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Telling his Driver in German to ask her in French;</context>
      <utterance>Oui?</utterance>
   <speaker>GESTAPO MAJOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>in French The Driver asks Shosanna;</context>
      <utterance>Ask her if this is her cinema?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>is this your cinema?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GESTAPO MAJOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell her to come down.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Driver opens the back door of the sedan, indicating for her to get in.</context>
      <utterance>Come down please. She climbs down the ladder.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand, what have I done?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She wants to know what she's done?</utterance>
   <speaker>GESTAPO MAJOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who says she's done anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then in her best imitation of Madame Mimeux's arrogantmanner.</context>
      <utterance>Who says you've done anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Driver begins to translate, when the Gestapo Major holds up his hand, telling him not to bother. The Major looks at the young French girl and tells her in German;</context>
      <utterance>Then I demand to know what this is about, and where do you propose to take me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GOEBBELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shosanna is lead through the French eatery by the Gestapo Major. Private Zoller see's her, and stands up, excuse's himself, and greets her before she reaches the table. Fredrick says in French, SUBTITLED in ENGLISH;</context>
      <utterance>- it's only the off spring of slaves that allows America to be competitive athletically. America olympic gold can measured in Negro sweat.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good you came. I wasn't sure weather or not you'd except my invitation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Invitation?</utterance>
   <speaker>THEN...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>.Goebbles Voice says OFF SCREEN;</utterance>
   <speaker>GOEBBLES</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context>Private Zoller turns in his direction, takes Shosanna by the arm, and leads her to him.</context>
      <utterance>Is that the young lady in question, Fredrick?</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joseph Goebbels, remaining seated, looks up at the young French girl, scrutinizing her as he spoons creme brule into his mouth. The excited Fredrick introduces Shosanna to the propaganda minister formally.</context>
      <utterance>Yes it is, beer Goebbels. Emmanuelle, there is somebody I want you to meet.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goebbels offers up his long spider-like fingers for Shosanna to shake. She does.</context>
      <utterance>Emmanuelle Mimieux, I'd like to introduce you to the minister of propaganda, the leader of the entire German film industry, and now I'm a actor, my boss, Joseph Goebbels.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOEBBELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks to Francesca to translate, but she's just taken a big bite of terri misu. They all laugh. Fredrick jumps in...</context>
      <utterance>Your reputation precedes you Fraulein Mimieux.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And normally, this is beer Goebbels French interpreter, Mademoiselle Francesca Mondino.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCESCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>looks up at Shosanna.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>5'?</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>NARRATOR'S VOICE comes on soundtrack;</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Francesca Mondino is much more then Goebbels French Interpreter. She's also Goebbels favorite French actress to appear in his films...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GERMAN  SOLDIER.</speaker>
      <mode>MOVIE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She speaks in FRENCH, SUBTITLED in to ENGLISH;</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCESCA/PEASANT GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A SUBTITLE APPEARS below naming the films title;</context>
      <utterance>I love you, I can't help it. My country or my heart, which do I betray?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FRANCESCA</speaker>
      <mode>ANIMAL-LIKE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do it! Do it! Fuck me - fill me!</utterance>
   <speaker>BACK TO FRANCESCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>looking at Shosanna.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCESCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bon jour.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bon jour.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>I</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>f.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Gestapo officer steps up and says, to Fredrick in German;</context>
      <utterance>And you've met the Major.</utterance>
   <speaker>GESTAPO MAJOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Gestapo Officer pulls out a chair, for the young lady to sit down. Shosanna takes the hot seat. Seated to her right is Private Zoller. To her left are the two curly pampered poodles. Major Helistrom pours Shosanna a glass of red wine from a small craft on the table.</context>
      <utterance>Actually, I didn't introduce myself.  Major Deiter Helistrom of the Gestapo, at your service mademoiselle.  Please allow me, have a seat.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try the wine mademoiselle, it's quite good. Goebbels looks across the table at her.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOEBBELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francesca interprets Goebbels German for Shosanna.</context>
      <utterance>well I must say, you've made quite a impression on our boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOEBBELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francesca interprets..</context>
      <utterance>I must say fraulein, I should be rather annoyed with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOEBBELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francesca interprets...</context>
      <utterance>I arrive in France, and I wish to have lunch with my star...</utterance>
   <speaker>GOEBBELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francesca interprets...</context>
      <utterance>Little do I know Be's become the toast of paris, and now he must find time for me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GOEBBELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francesca interprets...</context>
      <utterance>People wait in line hours, day's, to see me. For the Fuhrer and Private Zoller, I wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOEBBELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francesca interprets...</context>
      <utterance>So finally, I'm granted a audience with the young Private, and he spends the entire lunch speaking of you and your cinema.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOEBBELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Private Zoller interrupts -</context>
      <utterance>So Fraulein Mimieux, let's get down to business.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- Heer Goebbels, I haven't informed her yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOEBBELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francesca tells Shosanna in French;</context>
      <utterance>Unless the girls a simpleton, I'm sure she's figured it out by now, after all she does operate a cinema. Francesca, tell her.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCESCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zoller reacts.</context>
      <utterance>What they're trying to tell you Emmanuelle, is Private Zoller has spent the last hour at lunch, trying to convince Monsieur Goebbels to abandon previous plans for Private Zollers film premier, and change the venue to your cinema.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanted to inform her.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCESCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit. I apologize Private, of course you did.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FRANCESCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Private wanted to inform the mademoiselle himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOEBBELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nonsense. Until I ask a few questions, he has nothing to inform. Let the record state, I have not agreed to a venue change.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goebbels speaks German to Shosanna;</context>
      <utterance>Duly noted.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOEBBELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have opera boxes?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GOEBBELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More would be better. How many seats in your auditorium?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three hundred and fifty.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOEBBELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fredrick jumps in...</context>
      <utterance>That's almost four hundred less then The Ritz.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But beer Goebbels, that's not such a terrible thing. You said yourself you didn't want to indulge every two faced french bourgeois taking up space currying favor. With less seat's it makes the event more exclusive. Your not trying to fill the house, their fightin g for seats.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode>CON'T</mode>
      <context>Goebbels listens silently, then after a bit of a pause;</context>
      <utterance>Besides, to hell with the French. This is a German night, a German event, a German celebration. This night is for you, me, the German military, the high command, their family and friends. The only people who should be allowed in the room, are people who will be moved by the exploits on screen.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOEBBELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Table chuckles.</context>
      <utterance>I see your public speaking has improved. It appears I've created a monster. A strangely persuasive monster. When the war's over, politics awaits.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOEBBELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francesca interprets...</context>
      <utterance>Well Private, though it is true, I'm inclined to indulge you anything. I must watch a film in this young ladies cinema before I can say, yes or no.  So young lady, you are to close your cinema tonight, and have a private screening me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOEBBELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francesca asks..</context>
      <utterance>What German films do you have?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francesca interprets...</context>
      <utterance>My cinema , on German night, tends to show older German classics.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOEBBELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francesca asks...</context>
      <utterance>Why not my films?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francesca interprets...</context>
      <utterance>I draw a older German audience in my cinema, that appreciate the nostalgia of the earlier time.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOEBBELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fredrick Jumps in...</context>
      <utterance>That's nonsense fraulein. Us Germans are looking forward, not backwards. That era of German cinema is dead. The German cinema I create, will not only be thee cinema of Europe. But the worlds only alternative to the degenerate Jewish influence of Hollywood.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He chuckles, but alone.</context>
      <utterance>Along with being a cinema owner, Emmanuelle is quite a formidable film critic.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOEBBELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zoller, thinking fast, says;</context>
      <utterance>WSo it would appear. Unfortunately for the fraulein, I've outlawed film criticism.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you screen "Lucky Kids"? I'm sure Emmanuelle hasn't seen. it. And it's so funny, I've been meaning to recommend it to her, for her German night. That's a great idea, let's watch "Lucky Kids" tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOEBBELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We'll screen "Lucky Kids" tonight.</context>
      <utterance>Ahhh, "Lucky Kids", "Lucky Kids", "Lucky Kids". When all is said and done, my most purely enjoyable production. Not only that, I wouldn't be surprised, if sixty years from now, It's "Lucky Kids" that I'm the most remembered for. I know it doesn't seem like it now, but mark my words. Very well, I'll have a print sent over to the fraulein'.s cinema.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>63</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...the empty chair next to the young Jewish girl is suddenly filled with the bottom half of a grey S.S. officer uniform.</context>
      <utterance>As Francesca interprets this for Shosanna...</utterance>
   <speaker>GOEBBELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The S.S. Officer sits down, and it's our old friend from the first scene COL HANS LANDA.</context>
      <utterance>Ah Landa, your here, this is the young lady in question.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shosanna, this4pol Hans Landa of the SS., he'll be running security for the premier.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charmed Mademoiselle.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The table laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Better known as "The Jew Hunter".</utterance>
   <speaker>GOEBBELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Francesca, what was that funny thing the Fuhrer said about Hans?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCESCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOEBBELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francesca's memory is jogged.</context>
      <utterance>You know, you were there, it was a funny thing the Fuhrer said, about Hans...Something about a pig?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCESCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She repeats it by whispering it in Goebbels ear.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes of course.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GOEBBELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes of course, that's it. So the Fuhrer said, he wouldn't be surprised if Hans weren't rooting out Jews like a truffle pig from the play pen.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCESCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what we need, pigs that can root out Jews.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Big hearty laugh around the table.</context>
      <utterance>Who needs pigs when you have me?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOEBBELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have a engagement tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, as a matter of fact, I do -</utterance>
   <speaker>GOEBBELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- Break it. We're all going to the Fraulein's cinema tonight to view "Lucky Kids".</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then Reich Ministers companion mademoiselle Mondino,</context>
      <utterance>Splendid.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FRANCESCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And now I must get Reich Minister Goebbels to his next appointment.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOEBBELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everybody begins to stand up from the table... ..Francesca gathers the stupid dogs... .as Col Landa stands, he says;</context>
      <utterance>Slave driver! French slave driver! They all chuckle.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, in my role as security chief of this joyous German occasion, I'm afraid I must have a word with Mademoiselle Mimieux.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What sort of discussion?</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That sounded suspiciously like a Private questioning the order of a Colonel? Or am I just being sensitive?</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing could be further from the truth Colonel. Your authority is beyond question. But your reputation does proceed you. Should Mademoiselle Mimieux or myself be concerned?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOEBBELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laughter all around. The Reich Minister and his axis entourage, make their way to front of the cafe, with the two dumb dogs on a leash, leading the way.</context>
      <utterance>Hans, the boy means no harm, he's simply smitten. And he's correct. Your reputation does proceed you.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No need for concern, you two. As security chief, I simply need to have a chat with the possible new venue's property owner.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just hoping to escort Mademoiselle Mimieux back to her cinema.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOEBBELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Col Landa offers the young jew in hiding a seat at a small table in the outside patio area of Maxims. The fluency and poetic proficiency of the S.S. jew hunters french, revels to the audience, that his feigning clumsiness at french with Monsieur Lapadite in the films first scene, was simply a interrogation-technique.</context>
      <utterance>Nonsense! You can eat ice cream, and walk along the Sienne another time. Right now, allow Col Landa to do his job. Everybody saystheir farewells.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you tried the strudel here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's about to answer, when a WAITER approaches.</context>
      <utterance>It's not so terrible. So how is it the young Private and yourself came to be acquainted?</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Considering Shosanna. grew up on a dairy farm, and the last time she was on a dairy farm, her strudel companion murdered her entire family, his ordering her milk is, to say the least... . disconcerting. The key to Col Landa's power, and or charm, depending on the side ones on, lies in his ability to convince you he's privy to your secrets.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, two strudels, one for myself, and one for the mademoiselle. A cup of espresso, with a container of. steamed milk, on the side. For the Mademoiselle, a glass of milk.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So Mademoiselle, you were beginning to explain....?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode>ANXIOUSLY</mode>
      <context>We spoke a few times, but -</context>
      <utterance>Up untill a couple of days ago, I had no knowledge of Private Zoller, or his exploits. To me, the Private was simply just a patron of my cinema.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Colonel takes one look at it, and says to the Waiter;</context>
      <utterance>- Mademoiselle, let me interrupt you. This is a simple formality, no reason for you to feel anxious.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I apologize, I forgot to order the cream fresh.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He exits.</context>
      <utterance>One moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(Back to</context>
      <utterance>Wait for the cream.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSINESS)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So Emmanuelle - May I call you Emmanuelle?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oui.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Waiter returns, applying cream fresh to the two strudels. The S.S. Colonel looks across the table at his companion, picking up his fork, he says;</context>
      <utterance>So Emmanuelle, explain to me how does it happen, that a young lady such as your self, comes to own a cinema?</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shosanna takes a whip creamy bite of strudel, Landa follows her lead.</context>
      <utterance>After you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>.COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(Back to</context>
      <utterance>Like I said, not so terrible.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSINESS)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you were explaining the origin of your cinema ownership?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Col Landa removes alittle black book from his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>The cinema originally belonged to my aunt and uncle -</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- What is there names?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He records the names in his little book.</context>
      <utterance>Jean-Pierre and Ada Mimieux.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are they now?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My uncle was killed during blitzkrieg.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pity... . Continue.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aunt Ada passed away from fever last spring.'</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Regrettable.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, he's a Frenchman. His name is Marcel. He worked with my aunt and uncle since they opened the cinema. He's the only other one who works with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doing what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Projectionist.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he any good?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The best.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Can you operate the projectors?</context>
      <utterance>Actually one could see where that might be a good trade for them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course I can.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As if she has any say.</context>
      <utterance>Knowing the Reich Minister as I do, I'm quite positive he wouldn't want the success or failure of his illustrious evening, dependent on the prowess of a negro. So if it comes to pass we hold this event at your venue, talented no doubt, as your negro may be, you will operate the projectors. Is that exceptable?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Col Landa takes another bite of strudel, Shosanna follows suit.</context>
      <utterance>Oui.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So it would appear our young hero is quite smitten with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Private Zollers feelings for me aren't of a romantic nature.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mademoiselle...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Colonel, his feelings are not romantic. I remind him of his sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That doesn't mean his feelings aren't romantic.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I remind him of his sister who raised him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Landa takes out a handsome looking cigarette case, with a S.S. LOGO on it. Removing on of the fags, he lights it up with a fancy S.S. gold lighter. He offers one to Shosanna.</context>
      <utterance>It's sounding more and more romantic by the minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cigarette?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you smoke?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes one, but makes no move to light it. He inhales deep, and says;</context>
      <utterance>Then I insist, you must take one. There not French, there German. I hope your not nationalist about your tobacco, to me French cigarettes are a sin against nicotine.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Col Landa stands up, throws some French francs on the table, puts on his grey S.S. cap, touches his finger to his visor, saluting Shosanna, and saying:</context>
      <utterance>I did have some thing else I wanted to ask you, but right now, for the life of me, I can't remember what it is. Oh well, must not of been important.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that he's gone. Shosanna breaths a sigh of relief. The CAMERA begins to slowly lower from a MEDIUM CU to her feet ankles and floor. We see her shoes are in a puddle of urine. During her conversation and strudel with the man that exterminated her entire family, shosanna pissed herself. She drops the German cigarette in to the piss puddle by her feet.</context>
      <utterance>Till tonight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CU FRANCESCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laughing at the comedy, hand covering her mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>CU TWO BLACK POODLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pantingly watching the screen.</utterance>
   <speaker>CU MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smiling, smoking a French cigarette.</utterance>
   <speaker>CU COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smoking his calabash, amused.</utterance>
   <speaker>CU FREDRICK ZOLLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Truly enjoying himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>CU SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The LITERARY NARRATOR comes on the soundtrack.</context>
      <utterance>watching the screen.</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>We see her face get slightly distracted behind the eyes.</context>
      <utterance>While Shosanna sits there pretending to be amused by the aryan antics of Goebbels Frank Capra copy, "Lucky Kids", a thought suddenly comes to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>She chuckles at the thought, though it looks like she's laughing at the German comedy.</context>
      <utterance>What if tonight, accidently, the cinema burned down? The Third Reich would lose it's Minister of propaganda, it's national hero, and it's top jew hunter, all in one fell swoop.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILVER SCREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Nazi rouges gallery, and Shosanna, applaud the film.</context>
      <utterance>"The END" card for "Lucky Kids" is projected.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>Goebbels speaks GERMAN, and Francesca translates;</context>
      <utterance>The screening of "Lucky Kids" was a complete success. And Heer Goebbels conceded to have the venue changed to Shosannas cinema. Not only that, in a moment of inspiration, Heer Goebbels had a idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOEBBELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I must say, I appreciate the modesty of this auditorium. Your Cinema has real respect, almost church like. Not to say we couldn't spruce the place up a bit. In Versailles there's a crystal chandelier hanging in the banquet hall that is extraordinary. we're going to get it, and hang it from the very middle of auditorium roof. Also I want to go to Louvre, pick up a few Greek nudes, and just scatter them about the lobby.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>We see Private Zoller hanging back, so he.can say goodbye.</context>
      <utterance>As they left the little French cinema that night, all the Germans were very happy...</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>She closes the door on him. Watching the Nazi's walk into the Paris night. Their shadows, for a moment onAwall, look like grotesque Nazi charcthers. 4644 The Nazi's are gone. Marcel sits at the top of the staircase of the lobby, looking down at Shosanna. They speak in FRENCH SUBTITLED into ENGLISH;</context>
      <utterance>None more so then Private Zoller.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck are we suppose to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It looks like we're suppose to have a Nazi premier.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like I said, what the fuck are we suppose to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I need to speak with you about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About these Hun swine, commandeering our cinema.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slowly walks up the stairs to Marcel. She makes him part his legs, and sits on the lower step, between his legs. Her back up against his chest, his arms around her shoulders. Shosanna has only known this type of intimacy with Marcel.</context>
      <utterance>What about it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, when I was watching the bosch</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode>(Said in ENGLISH)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Capra-corn abomination,</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode>(Back to FRENCH)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got a idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm confused, what are we talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Filling the cinema with Nazi's and their whores, and burning it down to the ground.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not talking about that, your talking about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, we're talking about that, right now. If we can keep this place from burning down by ourselves, we can burn it down by ourselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shosanna -</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Marcel, just for sake of argument, if we wanted to burn down the cinema, for any number of reasons, you and I could physically accomplish that, no?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oui Shosanna, we could do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And with Madame Mimieux's 350 nitrate film print collection, we wouldn't even need explosives, would we?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean we wouldn't need any more explosives?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She begins kissing his hands.</context>
      <utterance>Oui, that's exactly what I mean.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode>CON'T</mode>
      <context>One of his fingers probes her mouth.</context>
      <utterance>I am going to burn down the cinema on Nazi night.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode>CON'T</mode>
      <context>The back of her head presses up hard against him, as his hand both caresses, and grips her lovely neck.</context>
      <utterance>And if I'm going to burn down the cinema, which I am, we both know, your not going to let me do it by myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode>CON'T</mode>
      <context>She then TWISTS around, so she's straddling him. They are now, face to face.</context>
      <utterance>Because you love me. And I love you. And your the only person on this earth I can trust.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode>CON'T</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But that's not all we're going to do. Does the filmmaking equipment it the attic still work? I know the film camera does. How about the sound recorder?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quite well, actually. I recorded a new guitarist I met in a cafe last week. It works superb. Why do we need filmmaking equipment?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because Marcel, my sweet, we're going to make a film. Just for the Nazi's.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MILITARY ATTACHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A snappy handsome British Lieutenant in dress browns, steps inside the room. This officer, who has been mixing it up with the Gerrys since the late thirties, is named LT.ARCHIE HICOX. A young George Sanders type(The Saint and Private affairs of Bel Ami, years). Upon entering the room, Lt.Hicox is gobsmacked. Standing before him is legendary military mastermind, GENERAL ED FENECH, a older George Sanders type (Village of the Dammed). But in the back of the room, sitting behind a piano, smoking his ever present cigar, is the unmistakable bulk of WINSTON CHURCHELL.</context>
      <utterance>Right this way, Lieutenant.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lt. Archie Hicox, reporting sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>if you offered me a scotch and plane water, I could drink a scotch and plain water.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>GEN.FENECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hicox heads over to the bar globe.</context>
      <utterance>That a boy, Lieutenant. Make it yourself, like a good chap, will you? Bars in the globe.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something for yourself, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEN.FENECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Lieutenant moves over to the Columbus-style globe bar, and busies himself mixing spirits, playing bartender chappy. Fenech, eyeing the Lieutenant's file.</context>
      <utterance>Whiskey straight. No junk in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEN.FENECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Back to them, mixing drinks, he says;</context>
      <utterance>It says here you've run three undercover commando operations in Germany, and German occupied territories? Frankfaurt, Holland, and Norway to be exact?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Extraordinary people, the Norwegian's.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEN.FENECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It says here you speak German fluently?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like a Katzenjammer Kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEN.FENECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His back still to us, as he bartends...</context>
      <utterance>And your occupation before the war?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. H I COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a film critic.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEN.FENECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>List your accomplishments?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As well as our sister publication.</context>
      <utterance>Well sir, such as they are, I write reviews and articles, for a publication called; "Films and Filmmakers".</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>GEN.FENECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that called?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Flickers Bi-Monthly". And I've had two books published.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEN.FENECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Impressive. Don't be modest Lieutenant, what are their titles?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. HI COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns around with his whiskey and plain water, and the Generals whiskey no junk. He finishes what he was saying, as he walks toward the General, handing him his drink.</context>
      <utterance>The first book was called; "Art Of The Eye's, The Heart, and The Mind:A Study of German Cinema in the Twenties". And the second one was called; ...</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Twenty-Four Frame Da Vinci". It's a subtexual film criticism study of the work of German director G.W. Pabst.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. HI COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What should we drink to, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEN.FENECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Down with Hitler.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All the way down, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEN.FENECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you familiar with German cinema under the Third Reich?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. HI COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Obviously I haven't seen any of the films made in the last three years, but I am familiar with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEN.FENECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Explain it to me.?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pardon sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEN.FENECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Explain to me UFA, under Goebbels?</context>
      <utterance>This little escapade of ours, requires a knowledge of the German film industry under the Third Reich.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SUDDENLY... Bellowing from the back of the room;</context>
      <utterance>Goebbels considers the films he's making to be the beginning of a new era in German cinema. A alternative to what he considers the Jewish German intellectual cinema of the twenties. And the Jewish controlled dogma of Hollywood.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCHELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's he doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. H I COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frightfully sorry sir, once again?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCHELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You say he wants to take on the Jews at their own game? Compared to say .Louis B.Mayer...how's he doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a puff of cigar smoke, Churchell says;</context>
      <utterance>Quite well, actually. Since Goebbels has taken over, film attendance has steadily risen in Germany over the last eight years. But Louis B.Mayer wouldn't be Goebbels proper opposite number. I believe Goebbels see's himself closer to David O.Selznick. Gen.Fenech looks to the Prime Minister.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCHELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brief him.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEM.FENECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lt.Bicox, at this point in time I'd like to brief you on, Operation Kino. Three days from now, Joseph Goebbels is throwing a gala premier of one of his new movies in Paris -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The General has to resort to peeking at his file.</context>
      <utterance>- What film sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEN.FENECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The motion pictures called; "Nation's Pride".</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you mean the film about Private Zoller?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEN.FENECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't have any intelligence, on exactly, what the film that night will be about.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it's called "Nation's Pride"?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEN.FENECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fenech can't help suppress a smile, they have the right man.</context>
      <utterance>I can tell you what it's about, it's about Private Fredrick Zoller. He's the German Sgt.York.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEN.FENECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In attendance at this joyous Germatic occasion, will be Goebbels, Gerring, Boorman, and most of the German High command, including all high ranking officers of both The S.S., and, The Gestapo. As well as luminaries of the Nazi propaganda film industry.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The master race at play, aye?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEN.FENECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Basically, we have all our rotten eggs in one basket. The objective of Operation Kino.... Blow up the basket.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"...and like the snows of yesteryear, gone from this earth". Jolly good, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>GEN.FENECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An American Secret Service outfit, that lives deep behind enemy lines, will be your assist. The Germans call them; "The Basterds".</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"The Basterds", never heard of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEN.FENECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whole point of the secret service, old boy, you not hearing of them. But the Gerrys have heard of them, because these yanks have been them the devil. Their leader is a chap named Lt.Aldo Raine. The Germans call him, "Aldo the Apache".</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do they call him that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEN.FENECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Best guess, is because he removes the scalps of the Nazi dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scalps, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEN.FENECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs his finger along his hairline.</context>
      <utterance>The hair.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEN.FENECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like a red Injun.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rather gruesome sounding little Dicky bird, isn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEN.FENECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No doubt the whole lot, a bunch a nutters. But you've heard the expression, "It takes a thief".</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>General Fenech continues on with his exposition, moving over to a military map.</context>
      <utterance>Indeed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>GEN.FENECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll be dropped into France, about twenty four kilometers outside of Paris. The Basterds will be waiting for you. First thing, you go to a little village called, "Nadine".  Apparently the Gerrys never go there. In Nadine, there's a tavern, called, "La Louisiane", you'll rendez-vous with our double agent, and she'll take it from there. She's the one who's going to get you in the premiere. It will be you, her, and two German born members of the Basterds. She's also made all the other arrangements your going to need.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How will I know her?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEN.FENECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suspect that won't be too much trouble for you. Your contact is Bridget Von Hammersmark.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bridget Von Hammersmark? The German movie star is working for England?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEN.FENECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the back of the room the bulldog barks;</context>
      <utterance>For the last two years now. one could even say Operation Kino was her brainchild.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCHELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Extraordinary women.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.BICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quite.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEN.FENECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll go to the premiere as her escort, lucky devil. She'll also have the premiere tickets for the other two. Got the gist?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three British bulldogs laugh.</context>
      <utterance>I think so, sir. Paris when it sizzles.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need a sync mark.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is a sync mark?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A action and noise put together, So we can sync up the picture and sound.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do we do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She does.</context>
      <utterance>Clap your hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She claps her hands in front of her face.</context>
      <utterance>In frame imbecile.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shosanna takes a deep breath, then;</context>
      <utterance>Ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Action.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But how do we get it developed? Only a suicidal idiot like us would develop that footage. How do we get a35mm print with a soundtrack?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know one person who can do both things?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He snaps his fingers.</context>
      <utterance>Of course Gaspar, very nice man, took care of all the experimental filmmakers. But nobody in their right mind would strike a print of what your talking about. If the Nazi's found out, their life wouldn't be worth this.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In a wolf fight, you ether eat the wolf, or the wolf eats you. If we're going to obliterate the Nazi's, we have to use their tactics.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We find somebody who can develop and process a35mm print. And we make them do it, or we kill them. Once we tell them what we want to do, if they refuse, we have to kill them anyway, or they'll turn us in.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Snaps her fingers.</context>
      <utterance>Like that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcel, holds his arm behind him, as he forces his head flat against the table top. Shosanna brings a HATCHET DOWN DEEP into the table, just by his face.</context>
      <utterance>Bring that fucker over here! Put his head down on that table.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ether do what the fuck we tell you to, or I'll bury this axe in your collaborating skull.</utterance>
   <speaker>GASPAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not a collaborator!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then prove it! Or does your manhood go no deeper, then standing to piss? Marcel, does his wife, and children know you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oui.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lifts up the hatchet, raises it high...</context>
      <utterance>Then after we kill this dog for Germans, we'll go and silence them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Prepare to die, collaborator fucker!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NADINE, FRANCE"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aldo is dressed like a French civilian. Hicox is dressed in a German grey S.S. Cap't uniform. They look out of a window, in a apartment, in the village of Nadine, overlooking the tavern.</context>
      <utterance>TWO SHOT LT.HICOX and LT.ALDO RAINE</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't say the goddamn rendez-vous was in a fuckin basement.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said it was in a tavern?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>it is a tavern.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wilhelm Wicki, joins the SHOT, dressed in a German S.S. Lieutenant uniform.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, in a basement. You know, fightin in a basement offers a lot of difficulties, number one being, your fighting in a basement.</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if we go in there, and she's not even there?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WE SEE the other Basterds, dressed in French civilian clothes, are in the room as well, they are, Donowitz, Hirschberg, and Utivich. And in the back of the room, dressed in the grey uniform of a S.S. Lieutenant, Hugo Stiglitz sits off by himself, sharpening his S.S. DAGGER on his leather belt looped around his boot. Anybody not in the scene from the Basterds opening chapter, is dead. Lt.Hicox watches Stiglitz off by himself on the other side of the room, SHARPENS his dagger menacingly. .Stiglitz is fucking werid... Lt.Hicox approaches Stiglitz...</context>
      <utterance>We wait. Don't worry, she's a British spy, she'll make the rendez-vous.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.NICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stiglitz, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>STIGLITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He continues bringing the blades edge, up, then, down on the leather strap.</context>
      <utterance>That's right, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meaning the blade. Stiglitz doesn't answer.</context>
      <utterance>I hear your pretty good with that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, we're not looking for trouble, right now. We're simply making contact with our agent. Should be uneventful. However, on the off chance I'm wrong, and things prove eventful. I need to know, we can all remain calm.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>STIGLITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't look calm to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hicox moves over to Aldo, and asks him privately;</context>
      <utterance>Well, now you put it like that, I guess you do. He turns his attention back to his blade.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. HI COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aldo just looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>This Gerry of yours, Stiglitz? Not exactly the loquacious type, is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that the kinds man you need, the loquacious type?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fair point, Lieutenant.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Make bets on how it all comes out?</context>
      <utterance>So y'all git in trouble in there, what are we suppose to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we get into trouble, we can handle it. But if trouble does happen, we need you to make damn sure no Germans, or French, for matter, escape from that basement. If Frau Von Hammersmark's cover is compromised, the mission is kaput.</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.DONOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Speaking of Frau Von Hammersmark, who's idea was it for the death trap redez-vous?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She chose the spot.</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.DONOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well isn't that just dandy?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's just a actress.</context>
      <utterance>Look, she's not a military strategist.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya don't got to be Stonewall Jackson to know you don't want to fight in a basement.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She wasn't picking a place to fight. She was picking a place, isolated, and without germans.</utterance>
   <speaker>PFC.HIRSCHBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They move to the window, and sure enough, ONE LONE NAZI PRIVATE, relieves himself against the side wall. Lt.Bicox, this was definitely, not the plan.</context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant, I hate to be contrary, but I got me a Nazi pissin on Louisianna two-o'clock.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sgt.Donowitz chides him;</context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.DONOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what do you think your fraulein Von Hammer -</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The British officer watches the German soldier, who's not suppose to be there. When Hugo Stiglitz joins him at the window. Stiglitz looks down at the urinating Nazi, S.S. dagger in hand.</context>
      <utterance>- Obviously, I don't know,Sgt.</utterance>
   <speaker>STIGLITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sheaths the dagger.</context>
      <utterance>If we're going, let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WINNETOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The whole table bursts out laughing.</context>
      <utterance>.okay, I'm not German. Am I American?</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE SGT/BEETHOVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes you arel</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR WALLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, not really.</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.POLA NEGRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, not really? Of course he is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EDGAR WALLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well if he's so American, how come he's never been translated into English? He's not American. He's suppose to be American, but he's not a American creation. In fact, he's something very different.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINNETOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, I'm a fictional, literary character, from the past, I'm American, and that's controversial.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WINNETOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is my bloodbrother, Old Shatterhand? The TABLE Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>WINNETOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the BACKGROUND, WE SEE, our three counterfeit German Officers, Hicox, Wicki, and Stiglitz, enter the basement tavern. They obviously. see the five German soldiers, but their too far away for us (the audience) to read their face. No doubt their less then happy. Fraulein Von Hammersmark see's them as well. Without getting up, she waves to them.</context>
      <utterance>Did Karl May write me? The TABLE Yes!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, my lovelies, I will join you in moments. I'm finishing up a game with my five new friends here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Take your time, enjoy yourself.</context>
      <utterance>No hurry, Frau Von Hammersmark.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WINNETOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The table CHEERS, and APPLAUD the Apache Chief, as he takes the card off his forehead. The other Four German Soldiers drink down there beer(part of the game). Bridget Von Hammersmark knock backs her champagne.</context>
      <utterance>I am WINNETOU, CHIEF of the APACHES!</utterance>
   <speaker>MATA HARI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frau Von Hammersmark, when your friends came in, did you realize you did a double take, like in the movies?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? No, I wasn't aware of that at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATA HARI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They must be second nature to you now? Did they teach you how to do a double take in the movies?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, yes they did, but it's not really that difficult.</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.POLA NEGRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bridget looks directly at the Master Sgt, and does a perfect, and perfectly funny, Double Take. The Table loves it.</context>
      <utterance>Do one for us. The Tableheartily agrees.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MATA HARI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mata Hari, looks directly at Beethoven, and does a Double Take.</context>
      <utterance>My turn, I want to try.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGER WALLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Soon the whole Table is doing dueling Double Takes.</context>
      <utterance>I want to try. He does.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks over, and joins the masquerading Germans table, the Gentlemen rise. She greets each warmly with a french cheek kiss, as if she knows them well. They all take a seat. The two Basterds, and one Brit, drink Whiskey. The taverns PROPRIETOR, a older, big bellyed Frenchman named EARL, comes over to the table, and pours more champagne into Bridget's Champagne glass. He leaves, returning back behind the bar, with the YOUNG FRENCH BARMAID, the only other person in the establishment. Obviously, they speak GERMAN, SUBTITLED into ENGLISH;</context>
      <utterance>Gengus Khaun! I would never of gotten that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought this place was suppose to have more French then Germans?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Normally that's true. The Sgt over there's wife, just had a baby. His commanding officer gave him, and his mates the night off to celebrate.</utterance>
   <speaker>WICXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should leave.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>F No, we should stay. For one drink at least. I've been waiting for you in a bar, it would look strange if we left before we had a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's right, just be calm, and enjoy your booze.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cinema venue has changed.</context>
      <utterance>There's been some new developments.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bridget's eyes bore holes in him.</context>
      <utterance>No one knows. But that in itself shouldn't be a problem. The cinema it's been changed to is considerably smaller then The Ritz. So whatever materials you brought for The Ritz, should be doubly effective here. Now this next piece of information is colossal, try not to over react. The Fubrer, will be attending tomorrow. Hugo Stiglitz does a SPIT TAKE.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hicox, seeing the German Master Sgt approach, signals for her to cool it.</context>
      <utterance>.the films gone through many delays, and Leni's heath is deteriorating, so if you have to speak...</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.POLA NEGRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frau Von Hammersmark, I was just thinking, could you sign a autograph to my son on his birthday?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Pretend Officers offer congratulations to the Sgt. The German Master Sgt, CLICKS his heels, and bows before his superior officers.</context>
      <utterance>I'd love to Wilhelm.  This handsome happy Sgt, just became a father today.</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.POLA NEGRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He raises his hand .... as do the seated phony officers; "Heil Hitler". As she takes a rather fancy fountain pen from her clutch..</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, heil Hitler.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So Wilhelm, do you know the name of this progeny yet?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SGT.POLA NEGRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Even the slightly psychotic Stiglitz, likes this German Sgt.</context>
      <utterance>I most certainly do, fraulein. His name is Maximilian.</utterance>
   <speaker>STIGLITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wonderful name, Sgt.</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.POLA NEGRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He thrusts out his beer stein, for the officers to cheers. They do. Bridget finishes signing her autograph, with a big flourish.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Lieutenant. When he's old enough to ride a bicycle, I will buy him a blue one. And I will paint on the side "The Blue Max".</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches into her clutch, and pulls out some lipstick. Applies some ruby red color to her lips, and then kisses the napkin, leaving a big red lip print. Then hands the treasured item to the young father.</context>
      <utterance>There you go. But wait, I'm not finished yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing but the best for little Maximilian.</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.POLA NEGRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then, to the whole tavern...</context>
      <utterance>Thank you fraulein, thank you. Max may not know who you are now. But he will. I will show him all of your movies. He will grow up with your films, and this napkin on his wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.POLA NEGRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This would be a good time for the German Sgt to go back to his table, and his men. And he almost does.... but... since he is drunk, and star struck, he out wears his welcome.</context>
      <utterance>I purpose a toast to the greatest actress in Germany! There is no Dietrich, there is no Riefenstahl, only Von Hammersmark! The whole room toasts.</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.POLA NEGRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, Frau Von Hammersmark, what brings you to France?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Table of game playing Soldiers, hear this, and get quiet.</context>
      <utterance>None of your business,Sgt. You might not have worn out your welcome with the fraulein, with your drunken boorish behavior, but you have wore out your welcome with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The German Master Sgt., looks quizzically at the officer.</context>
      <utterance>Might I remind you Sgt.,your a enlisted man. This is a officers table. I suggest you stop pestering the fraulein, and rejoin your table.</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.POLA NEGRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The whole room pauses-for different reasons...</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me Cap't, but your accent is is very unusual.</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.POLA NEGRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A silent moment passes between the two tables, then the two German born impostors spring into action.</context>
      <utterance>Where are you from?</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stiglitz, STANDS and YELLS to the other table;</context>
      <utterance>Sgt.! You must be ether drunk or mad, to speak to a superior officer with such impertinentness!</utterance>
   <speaker>STIGLITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(Pointing at</context>
      <utterance>I'm making YOU,...</utterance>
   <speaker>WINNETOU)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>.and YOU,..  .responsible, for him.  I suggest you take hold of your friend, or he'll spend Max's first birthday in jail for public drunkenness!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>WHEN...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A GERMAN VOICE rings out;</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context>The Five known Germans move aside, reveling the unknown German in the room, unseen till now, our old friend from before MAJOR DEITER HELLSTROM of the GESTAPO. The Major stands from the little table he was sitting at.</context>
      <utterance>Then might I inquire?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wicki jumps in;</context>
      <utterance>Like the young newly christened father, I too have a acute ear for accents. And like him, I too find yours odd. From where do you hail, Cap't?</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Major, this is highly inappr -</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>T wasn't speaking to you Lt.Saltzberg,</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode>(Turning to STIGLITZ)</mode>
      <context>(Looking at</context>
      <utterance>or you ether, Lt.Berlin.</utterance>
   <speaker>HICOX)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Gestapo Major is now standing beside Sgt.Pola, before the impostors table. Lt.Hicox, calmly explains his origin.</context>
      <utterance>I was speaking to Cap't I--don't-know-what.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was born in the village that rests in the shadow of Piz Palu.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The mountain?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. In that village we all speak like this. Have you seen the Riefenstahl film?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LT. HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you saw me. You remember the skiing torch scene?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Bridget Von Hammersmark places a cigarette in a ivory cigarette holder, which Hicox, as if on cue, lights for her, she says;</context>
      <utterance>In that scene was myself, my father, my sister, and my two brothers. My brother is so handsome, the director Pabst, gave him a Close Up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then....so does the Gestapo Major. He turns to the Sgt.</context>
      <utterance>Major, if my word means anything, I can vouch for everything the Young Cap't has just said. He does hail from the bottom of Piz Palu, he was in the film, and his brother is far more handsome then he. The impostors laugh.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Which the young Sgt is more then happy to do. That table begins playing there game again. Major Hellstrom, the highest ranking officer in the room, bows graciously to the female German celebrity.</context>
      <utterance>You should rejoin your friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I join you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Gestapo Major sits at the table, opposite Lt.Hicox, and Wicki. The French Barmaid brings over the Majors beer stein.</context>
      <utterance>By all means, Major.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So that's the source of your bazaar accent? Extraordinary. So what are you doing here Cap't?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aside from having a drink with the lovely fraulein?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well that pleasure requires no explanation. Chuckle...Chuckle</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean in country. Your obviously not stationed in France, or I'd know who you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT  I'! I COX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know every German in France?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR BELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Worth knowing.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuckle... Chuckle.</context>
      <utterance>Well, there in lies the problem. We never claimed to be worth knowing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All levity aside, what are you doing in France?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Attending Goebbels film premiere as the frauleins escort.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your the frauleins escort?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuckle chuckle.</context>
      <utterance>Somebody has to carry the lighter.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuckle chuckle.</context>
      <utterance>The Captain is my date, but all three are my guests. We're old friends Major, who go back along time. Longer then a actress would care to admit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, in that case, let me raise a glass to the three luckiest men in the room.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll drink to that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I must say, that game their playing looks like a good bit of fun. I didn't join them, because your quite right Cap't, officers and enlisted men shouldn't fraternize. But seeing as we're all officers here,</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode>(Bowing to BRIDGET)</mode>
      <context>Lt.Hicox begins to refuse, when Bridget (feeling she knows better), interrupts him;</context>
      <utterance>.and sophisticated lady friends of officers. What say we play the game?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>okay, one game.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(He SNAPS his</context>
      <utterance>So the object of the game, is to write the name of a famous person on your card. Real or fictitious, doesn't matter. For instance, you could write Confucius or Fu Manchu.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINGERS)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He demonstrates.</context>
      <utterance>Eric' More pens.  And they must be famous. No Aunt Inga's. When you finish writing, put the card face down on the table, and move it to the person to your left. The person to your right, will move their card in front of you. You pick up the card without looking at it, lick the back, and stick it on your forehead like so.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode>CON'T</mode>
      <context>As Major Hellstrom finishes explaining the finer points of the game, The CAMERA PANS OFF HIM, and BEGINS SLOWLY ZOOMING INTO STIGLITZ. The Majors dialogue begins to FADE AWAY. Untill we're in a SPAGHETTI WESTERN FLASHBACK. Which is RED FILTERED FOOTAGE of Hugo being savagely WHIPPED by somebody wearing a GESTAPO UNIFORM, SUPERIMPOSED over his CLOSE UP. The Flashback disappears. It's driving Stiglitz crazy, being this close to a Gestapo uniform, and not plunging a knife into it. The Majors Voice comes back on the soundtrack.</context>
      <utterance>And in ten yes or no questions, you must guess who you are...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everybody sticks their cards on their forehead...</context>
      <utterance>.So let's give it a try, shall we? Everybody write your names. The Five players write their names... Then move their cards to the right...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MAJ.KING KONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They laugh.</context>
      <utterance>I'll start, give you the idea. Am I German?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJ.KING KONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They laugh - but then Wicki says;</context>
      <utterance>Am I a American?</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute, he goes to</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be ridiculous, obviously he wasn't born in America.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJ.KING KONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Table says; "Yes".</context>
      <utterance>So... . I visited America, aye?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJ.KING KONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was this vist...fortuitous?</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJ.KING KONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Table confers, and decides, yes it is exotic.</context>
      <utterance>.Bummm. My native land, is it what one would call, exotic?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJ.KING KONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Tablesays; "Yes you are".</context>
      <utterance>Hummmm. That could be ether a reference to the jungle, or the Orient. I'm going to let my first instinct take over, and ask, am I from the jungle?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJ.KING KONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now gentlemen, around this time you could ask, weather your real or fictitious. I however, think that's too easy, so I won't ask that, yet. Okay, my native land is the jungle? I visited America, but my visit was not fortuitous to me, but the implication is that it was to somebody else. When I went from the jungle to America,... .Did I go by boat? "Yes".</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJ.KING KONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>"Yes".</context>
      <utterance>Did I go against my will?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJ.KING KONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On this boat ride, ... . Was I in chains?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MAJ.KING KONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>"Yes".</context>
      <utterance>When I arrived in America,...Was I displayed in chains?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJ.KING KONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Table says, "No".</context>
      <utterance>Am I the story of the Negro in America?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJ.KING KONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They applaud him.</context>
      <utterance>Well then I must be King Kong. Be throws the card on the table.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three counterfeit Nazi's knock back their whiskey.</context>
      <utterance>Nov since I answered correctly, you all need to finnish your drinks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, who's next?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Major, I'm afraid, you are intruding.</context>
      <utterance>Major, I don't mean to be rude. But the four of us are very good friends. And the four of us haven't seen each other in quite a while. So...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>How about it fraulein? Am I intruding?</context>
      <utterance>I beg to differ Cap't. It's only if the fraulein considers my presence a intrusion, that I become a intruder.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course not, Major.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Table's not sure what to do, is this a confrontation? Then, the Major laughs.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't think so. It's simply the young Cap't is immune to my charms.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just joking, of course I'm intruding.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Allow me to refill your glasses gentlemen, and I will bid you and the fraulein adieu.  Eric has a bottle of thirty-three year old single malt scotch whisky from the Scottish highlands. What do you say gentlemen?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your most gracious, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eric, the thirty-three, and new glasses! You don't want to contaminate the thirty- three with the swill you were drinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many glasses?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five glasses.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not me. I like scotch, scotch doesn't like me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lt.Bicox, hold up three fingers(pinky to index), to Eric the owner.</context>
      <utterance>Nor I. I'll stay with bubbly.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eric brings the three glasses, and the old bottle, pouring for the three soldiers. Major Helistrom lifts up his beer stein, and toasts;</context>
      <utterance>Three glasses.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all mutter, "a thousand year reich", and toast glasses. The Gestapo Major puts down his beer stein, and then WE HEAR a CLICK, under the table.</context>
      <utterance>To a thousand year Reich!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you hear that? That's the sound of my Luger pointed right at your testicles.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you have a Luger pointed at my testicles?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because you've just given yourself away, Cap't. Your no more German then that scotch.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, -Major -</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- Major -</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- Shut up slut.  You were saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was saying that makes two of us. I've had a gun pointed at your balls since you sat down.</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.STIGLITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That makes three of us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SGT.STIGLITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hugo alsobrings out his dagger, and sitcks it in the table top.</context>
      <utterance>And at this range, I'm a real Fredrick Zoller.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hummmmm ... Looks like we have a bit of a sticky situation here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. H ICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going to happen, Major, is your going to stand up, and walk out that door with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No no no no no no, I don't think so. I'm afraid you and I both know, no matter what happens to anybody else in this room, the two of us aren't going anywhere.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too bad about them though. They seem like a likeable  You two will have to shoot them.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then Major, i implore you. For the sake of those German troops, will you please leave with us?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lt.Hicox picks up his thirty-three year old single malt scotch, and says;</context>
      <utterance>Oh Bridget, your concern for German troops, gets me  .right here. You mean for the sake your whore legs, don't you? You can't afford to get any bullet holes in them, your not finished spreading them for all the Hollywood Jews.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Well, if this is it old boy, I hope you dont mind if I go out speaking the kings?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>The English film critic, commando, picks up the thirty-three the Nazi Major bought him, and says;</context>
      <utterance>By all means, Cap't.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He downs the stuff.</context>
      <utterance>There's a special rung in hell reserved for people who waste good scotch. And seeing as I might be rapping on the door momentarily...</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To the Nazi</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR)</speaker>
      <mode> MAJOR)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I must say, damn good stuff, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now about this, "Pickle", we find ourself's in. It would appear, there's only thing left for you to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what would that be?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.HICOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stiglitz.</utterance>
   <speaker>STIGLITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, auf wiedersehen to your balls!</utterance>
   <speaker>STIGLITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As does HICOX, HITTING not only Hellstrom, but BRIDGET as well.</context>
      <utterance>FIRES into HELLSTROM'S BALLS...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLSTROM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>FIRES into HICOX'S BALLS and KNEE CAPS.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SGT.POLA NEGRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>whole thehroom;,BWIPI NGERIC. The SHOOTING STOPS...the SMOKE caused by the gunfire ... starts to DISSIPATE... The only one in the room left alive, is the young German Sgt, with the machine gunn. WE HEAR the feet of the soldiers outside, reach the basement entrance. The door opens... , .The German Sgt, sends FIFTY BULLETS in the doors direction... No one goes through it. What we have here, is a rabbit hole like situation. No one inside is getting out, no one outside is getting in. The young German Sgt, YELLS in ENGLISH, to the outside;</context>
      <utterance>comes the a CHINE GUNN,</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN SGT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aldo's Voice YELLS down the hole;</context>
      <utterance>You outside! Who are you? British, American, what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALDO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were American's 1 What are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN SGT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a German you idiot!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALDO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You speak English pretty good for a German!</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN SGT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I agree! So let's talk!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALDO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, talk!</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN SGT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's not my fault!</context>
      <utterance>I'm a father! My baby was born today in Frankfurt! Five hours ago! His name is Max! We were in here drinking and celebrating! They're the ones that came in shooting and killing!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="143" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ALDO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context>What's your name soldier?</context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay, it wasn't your fault!</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN SGT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wilhelm!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALDO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the same name as one of the guys you just killed!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILHELM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They attacked us!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALDO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay Wilhelm... .is anybody alive on our side?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILHELM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear a VOICE OFF SCREEN, yell out;</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="144" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ALDO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILHELM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To BRIDGET,</utterance>
   <speaker>LOW)</speaker>
      <mode> LOW)</mode>
      <context>Meaning the muzzle.</context>
      <utterance>Make a sound whore, and I spit!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALDO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wilhelm, who is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILHELM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>is the girl on your side?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALDO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which girl?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="145" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>WILHELM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>1 Who do you think, Von Hammersmark!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALDO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, she's oar's!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILHELM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought so. So you run with the American's now, huh? Now times are bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALDO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is she okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILHELM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear The Basterds Curse their luck Off Screen.</context>
      <utterance>You despicable traitor.  She's been shot, but she's alive.  For now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALDO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay Wilhelm, what'd ya say we make a deal?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILHELM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALDO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aldo. Wilhelm, can I call yap Willi?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILHELM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALDO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So Willi, you know we could lob three or four or five or six grenades down there, and your little war story ends here. But good fer you, bad fer her, you die, she dies. So what say we make a swap?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep talking?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="146" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ALDO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context>Bridget watches Willi think...</context>
      <utterance>Okay, Willi here's my deal! You let me and one of my men come down to take the girl away! And we take the girl, and leave! That simple, Willi! You go your way, we go ours! And little Max, gets to grow up playing catch with his daddy! So what'ya say, Willi, we got a deal? Willi thinks...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aldo?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALDO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm here Willi!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to trust you.... But howcanI?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALDO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What choice ya got?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could kill the girl!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALDO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well now, Willi, that's true enough. But something you need to know, so you don't get the wrong idea. Ain't none of us give a fuck bout that girl. But, admittedly, if you kill her, it would fuck up our plans. But you'll be dead by then anyway, so what'd you care? And lets not forget that little gatzenjammer Max, growin up without a pop. So in the spirit of gettin you home to him, we got a deal, Willi?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aldo and Hirschberg come down the stairs, showing open hands. Willi keeps his machine gunn trained on them. Aldo with his hands up, says;</context>
      <utterance>Okay Aldo, I'm going to trust you! Come down, no guns!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="147" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Willi, what's with the machine gunny I thought we had a deal?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We do have a deal, now git the girl and go.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not so fast, Willi, we only have a deal, we trust each other. A Mexican stand off ain't trust.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need guns on me for it to be a Mexican stand off.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>you got guns on us, you decide to shoot, we're dead. Up top, they got grenades, they drop 'em down here, your dead. That's a Mexican stand off, and that wasn't the deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just take that fucking traitor, and go! See? Now your down here Now you get tricky - t</utterance>
   <speaker>ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- No tricks!- Ain't nobody gittin tricky, Willi; I swear to god, I'm too damn dumb toget tricky. But</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="148" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WILLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine. Take that fucking traitor and get her out of my sight.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Danka, Willi, danka. okay, Hirschbeg, you grab her shoulder -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="149" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the floor, the bloody, sweaty, and in excoriating pain (she'll probably lose that leg), German movie star, says to the two American soldier's she's just meeting for the first time;</context>
      <utterance>You fuckin bitch! I had a deal with that man!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was a enemy soldier, who knew who I was. He couldn't live.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="150" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HIRSCHBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ought'a beat your fuckin head in</utterance>
   <speaker>ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop it. Just pick her up, and get that bitch outta here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIRSCHBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aldo, she just-</utterance>
   <speaker>ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- She's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIRSCHBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said, she's right. He was a Nazi soldier. If he lived, he would doomed the mission.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="151" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SGT.DONOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>He nods his head, yes.</context>
      <utterance>Doctor? Are you a fucking doctor?</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.DONOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andi amo...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="152" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>I</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's still a doctor. If he can get a bullet out of a cow, he can get a bullet outta you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donny yells at the Old Man;</context>
      <utterance>Right now, we just need morphine.</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.DONOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Old Man tries to explain in French, that he's not a human doctor...</context>
      <utterance>Morphine! We need morphine!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="153" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(Pointing at</context>
      <utterance>And that ones...</utterance>
   <speaker>WICKI)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>.name is Weiheim Wicki. Bets Austrian born jew, who immigrated to the United States when things began turning sour for the Israelites. They are the two German born members of The Basterds. They've been known to don german uniforms, to ambush squads.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="154" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>.bending down, he examines fraulein von Hammersmarks two pretty dress shoes lying on the floor. One shoe is covered in blood. The other, while blood speckled, is fairly clean. Picking up the clean shoe, and holding it in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>But that doesnt look like this. This is odd. Looking down he see's something...</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A OFF SCREEN SOLDIER'S VOICE cries out;</context>
      <utterance>It would appear somebodies missing. Somebody fashionable.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIERS VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context>We follow Hans to the spot on the floor where Sgt.Willi lies. He's shot in the chest, but it looks like Max's daddy is still alive.</context>
      <utterance>Col, this ones still alive!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="155" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now 'fore we yank that slug outta ya, you need to answer a few questions</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Few questions about what?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About I got three men dead back there, and why don't you try tellin us what the fuck happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The British officer blew his German act, and a Gestapo Major saw it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'fore we get into who shot John, why did you invite my men to a rendez-vous in a basement with a bunch of Nazis?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can see, since you didn't see what happened inside, the Nazi's being there must look odd.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, we gotta word for that kinda odd in English, it's called, suspicious.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRI DGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aldo thinks for a moment...</context>
      <utterance>Don't let your imagination get the better of you, Lieutenant. You met the sergeant, Willi. He had a baby tonight. His commanding officer gave him and his friends the night off to celebrate. The Germans being there was just a tragic coincidence.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, I'll buy that. He was ether there with his men waiting for us, or he was there celebrating his sons birthday, he wasn't doin both.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="156" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did the shootin start?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The English man, gave himself away.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did he do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds up three fingers, index to pinky.</context>
      <utterance>He ordered three glasses.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds up three fingers, thumb to index.</context>
      <utterance>We order, three glasses.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the German three. The other is odd. Germans would, and did notice it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, let's pretend there were no Germans, and everything went exactly the way it was suppose to. What would of been the next step?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tuxedos. To get them into the premiere, wearing military uniforms, with all the military there, would of been suicide. But going as members of the German film industry, they wear tuxedos, and blend in with everybody else. I arranged a tailor to fit three tuxedos tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you intend to get them into the premiere?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They do. And she opens it, and takes out three tickets to the film premiere.</context>
      <utterance>Hand me my purse.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lt.Hicox was going as my escort. The other two were going as a German cameraman and his assistant.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="157" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LT. ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you still get us in that premiere?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you speak German better then your friends, no. Have I been shot, yes. I don't see me tripping the light fantastique up the red carpet any time soon. Least of all by tomorrow night.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode>PAUSE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>However, there's something you don't know. There's been two recent developments regarding Operation Kino. One, the venue has been changed from The Ritz, to a much smaller venue.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enormous changes at the last minute? That's not very Germatic. Why the hell is Goebbels doin stuff so damn peculiar?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It probably has something to do with the second development.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which is?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="158" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>1 2 Z.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Donny breaks the teams silence;</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.DONOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When the hell did this happen?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The venue change, two weeks ago. The Fuhrer's attendance, four days ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And how come London don't know nothing about that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need to get something straight, once and for all. Everything London knows, it learned from me. If I don't know, London doesn't know. So now, this is me, informing you, Hitler's coming to Paris.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="159" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you thinking?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm thinking getting a wack at plantin ole Uncle Adolph makes this a horse of a different color.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that suppose to mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It means, your gettin us in that premiere.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to probably end up losing this leg, bye bye acting career, fun while it lasted. How do you expect me to walk up a red carpet?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="160" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The doggie docs gonna dig that slug outta your gam. Then he's gonna wrap it up in a cast, and you gotta good how I broke my leg mountain climbing story. That's German, ain't it? Y'all like climbin mountains, don'tch?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't. I like smoking, drinking, and ordering in restaurants, but I see your point.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We fill ya up with morphine, till it's comin out ya ears. Then just limp your little ass up that rouge car-pet.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Splendid. When the Nazi's put me up against a wall, it won't hurt so much.  I know this is a silly question before I ask it, but can you American's speak any other language then English?</utterance>
   <speaker>HIRSCHBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Other then Yiddish?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donny referring to Aldo and himself.</context>
      <utterance>Preferably.</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.DONOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We both speak alittle Italian.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With a atrocious accent, no doubt. But that doesn't exactly kill us in the crib. Germans don't have a good ear for Italian. So you mumble Italian, and brazen through it, is that the plan?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's about it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="161" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That sounds good.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>it sounds like shit, but what else we gonna do, go home?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's good. If you don't blow it, with that, I can get you in the building.  So, who does what?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I speak the most Italian, so I'll be your escort. Donowitz speaks the second most, so he'll be your Italian cameraman. And Hirschberg third most, so he'll be Donnys assistant.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIRSCHBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't speak Italian.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like I said, third best. Just keep your fuckin mouth shut. In fact why don't you start practising, right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the little one?</utterance>
   <speaker>UTIVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you mean me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean any offence.</utterance>
   <speaker>UTIVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>None taken you German cunt.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Utivich is the chauffeur.</utterance>
   <speaker>UTIVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bridget SCREAMS in frustration;</context>
      <utterance>I can't drive.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You Americans are fucking useless!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="162" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>UTIVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>IVGimmie a break, I'm from Manhattan.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No worries, son. We got over fourteen hours before the movie tomorrow. More then enough time for you to learn to drive.</utterance>
   <speaker>UTIVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>NO no no no, Lieutenant, it's not!</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yes yes yes yes, Private, it is. And yes yes yes yes, you will.  Look Utivich, you and I both know, if we went to grade school together, you damn sure ain't copyin off of my test. Well I lern't to drive in four hours on a Tennessee mountain road. And I'm a shit for brains coal miner bootlegger. Hirschberg, you know how to drive, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>HIRSCHBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Teach 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All The Basterds, except Donny, burst out laughing.</context>
      <utterance>But there is a problem. I'm a movie star. This is a movie premiere. I can't show up looking like I was just in a Nazi gun fight. Now I have a dress for the premiere at my hotel. But sometime tomorrow, I have to get my hair done.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bridget rolls her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Sister, you must got wunderbar luck. Guess who went to beauty school? The CAMERA WHIP PANS to SGT.DONOWITZ.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="163" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ooh lala, Danielle Darrieux, this is so exciting. Pleased to meet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marcel lifts up the veil covering her face, and their lips meet.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up fool.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cheeky black bugger. I have to go down and socialize with these Hun pigs. Let's go over it again?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reel one is on the first projector. Reel two is on the second. Three and four are ready to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, the big sniper battle in the film begins around the middle of the third reel. Our film, comes on in the forth reel, so Somewhere towards the end of the third reel, go down and lock the doors of the auditorium. Then take your place behind the screen, and wait for my CUE, when I give it to you, BURN IT DOWN!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="164" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start to leave.</context>
      <utterance>I want everybody out of this room!</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks over to the Patient in the hospital bed, Its none other then SGT.WILLI, and yes, he's still alive. Landa pulls up a chair next to the bed, sits down.</context>
      <utterance>That means now, goddamnit! They RUSH OUT.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you speak, Sgt?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="165" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The THINK BUBBLE DISSOLVES away, reveling the entrance again, and as if on perfect cue, in walks Bridget Von Hammersmark, dressed lovely, leg in a big white cast. The three basterds in their tuxedos, flank her.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me everything that happened in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>CU COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He descends the stairs, towards the four saboteurs... They speak in GERMAN, SUBTITLED in ENGLISH;</context>
      <utterance>smiles.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fraulein Von Hammersmark, what has befallen Germany's most elegant swan?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dashing as ever I see.</context>
      <utterance>Colonel Landa, it's been years.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They chuckle, and air kiss.</context>
      <utterance>Flattery will get you everywhere, fraulein.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's happened to your lovely leg, a by product of kicking ass in the German cinema, no doubt.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chuckle-chuckle...</context>
      <utterance>Save your flattery, you old dog. I know too many of your former conquests, to fall into that honey pot.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seriously, what happened?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="166" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And this was the result.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I tried my hand, foolishly I might add, at mountain climbing.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mountain climbing? That's how you injured your leg, mountain climbing?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A brief moment passes between the two...</context>
      <utterance>Believe it or not, yes it is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="167" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Double meaning is not lost on the German actress.</context>
      <utterance>Forgive me, fraulein. I don't mean laugh at your misfortune. It's just .mountain climbing? I'm curious fraulein, what could of ever compelled you to undertake such a foolhardy endeavor?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I chant be doing it again, I can tell you that.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That cast looks as fresh as my old Uncle Gustave, when were you climbing this mountain, last night?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very good eye, Colonel. It happened yesterday morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then Landa laughs it off, taking them off the hook.</context>
      <utterance>Hummm. And where exactly in Paris is this mountain? This stops her for a seconded.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="168" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just teasing you, fraulein. You know me, I tease rough. So who are your three handsome escorts?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The German fraulein turns to the three tuxedo wearing Basterds.</context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid neither three speak a word of German. Their friends of mine from Italy. This is a wonderful Italian stuntman, Antonio Margheriti.  A very talented cameraman, Enzo Gorlomi.  And Enzo's camera assistant, Dominick Decocco.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode>ITALIAN</mode>
      <context>The Basterds know only too well who Landa the Jew Hunter is, but they can't show it.</context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen, this is a old friend, Col. Sans Landa of the S.S.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="169" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Margheriti...?</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode>ITALIAN</mode>
      <context>.Margheriti?</context>
      <utterance>Am I saying it correctly...?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. ALDO</speaker>
      <mode>ITALIAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Correct.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode>ITALIAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Margheriti.... Say it for me once please...?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Margheriti.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="170" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode>ITALIAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, again...?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I4argheriti.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode>ITALIAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Once more... .?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Margheriti.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nargheriti.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode>FRENCH</mode>
      <context>Turning his gaze to Donny.</context>
      <utterance>It means daisies, I believe.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode>ITALIAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your name again?</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.DONOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enzo Gorlomi.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode>ITALIAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Again... .?</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.DONOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gorlomi.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode>ITALIAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One more time, but let me really hear the music in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.DONOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode>HAMMY ITALIAN</mode>
      <context>Now to Hirschberg...</context>
      <utterance>Gorlomi.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode>ITALIAN</mode>
      <context>Then Hischberg breaks out the best Italian accent of the</context>
      <utterance>And you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="171" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>HIRSCHBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dominick Decocco.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dominick Decocco?</utterance>
   <speaker>HIRSCHBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dominick Decocco.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bravo... . Bravo.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode>GERMAN</mode>
      <context>Col.Landa stops a WAITER with a tray of champagne glasses.</context>
      <utterance>Well, my two cameraman friends need to find there seats.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode>GERMAN</mode>
      <context>Everyone gets a glass.</context>
      <utterance>Not so fast, lets enjoy some champagne.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode>FRENCH</mode>
      <context>Shosanna joins the circle, and is handed a champagne glass. This is the first moment The Basterds are aware of Shosanna.</context>
      <utterance>- Oh, Mademoiselle Mimieux, please join us, I have some friends I'd like you to meet.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode>FRENCH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I say Mademoiselle, you look divine.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode>FRENCH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Merci'.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode>GERMAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This lovely young lady, is Mademoiselle Emmanuelle Mimieux, this is her cinema, and she is our hostess for the evening.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="172" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bonjour.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bon jour.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode>FRENCH</mode>
      <context>All three smile goofy spaghetti bender smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid my companions don't speak any French, there Italian. This is Antonino, Enzo, and Dominick.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode>FRENCH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually fraulein Von Hammersmarks Italian associates, need help finding there seats. Perhaps Mademoiselle Mimieux would be so kind to escort them?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode>FRENCH</mode>
      <context>Donny hands her two tickets. She indicates for them to follow her. Donny and Hirschberg both exchange one last look with Aldo, then follow the young french girl into the auditorium.</context>
      <utterance>It would be my pleasure. Let me see your tickets?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="173" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GERMAN SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Col.Landa, Lt.Aldo, and Bridget are still together.</context>
      <utterance>Take your seats! The show is about to begin! Everybody take your seatsl</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode>GERMAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I must call The Fuhrer. He doesn't want to make his entrance untill everybody seated. Come with me Frau Von Hammersmark. The Fuhrer has heard your here, and he wishes to commend you personally.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode>GERMAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me? Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode>GERMAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be modest. Everybody is quite taken with your resolve. A accident, like you've just experienced, and yet you still show up to to a important Party event. The Fuhrer was quite adamant in his gratitude. We'll use Mademoiselle Mimieux's office.  I'm afraid I must rob you of your companion, but only for a moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode>ITALIAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, apparently The Fuhrer wishes to commend me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="174" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pointing at one lone chair in front of the desk. She lowers herself in the chair. Instead of moving around to the other side of the desk, opposite her. The SS Colonel pulls another little chair over, and places it in front of the fraulein. He sits. Their knees almost touching. The colonel points to the foot not in the cast.</context>
      <utterance>Have a seat fraulein.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode>GERMAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me see your foot.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode>GERMAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I beg your pardon?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="175" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>1 31</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Patting his lap.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put your foot in my lap.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Colonel, you embarrass me.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The nervous fraulein, lifts up her strapy dress shoe enclosed foot, and places it in the Colonel's lap. The Colonel, very delicately, unfastens the thin straps that hold the frauleins shoe on her foot... .He removes the shoe... .Leaving only the frauleins bare foot...</context>
      <utterance>I assure you fraulein, my intention is not to flirt. Patting his lap more with more aggression.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="176" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He removes her foot from his lap.</context>
      <utterance>What's that American expression... "if the shoe fits...you must wear it".</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode>GERMAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What now Colonel?</utterance>
   <speaker>COL LANDA</speaker>
      <mode>GERMAN</mode>
      <context>She stares defiant daggers into him.</context>
      <utterance>Do you admit you treachery?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="177" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode>GERMAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The only thing I will admit to, is resisting you...</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode>GERMAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Resist to your last breath"?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="178" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BANG?</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He releases the grip around her throat. His hands are</context>
      <utterance>She's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>TREMBLING...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Strangling the very life out of somebody with your bear hands, is the most violent act a human being can commit. Also, only humans strangle, the opposable thumbs being quite important part of the endeavor. As Hans Landa stands, the sheer violence he had to call on to accomplish this task, still surges through him. He tries to gain control of the trembling, that is rippling through his body. He takes out a silver SS FLASK(filled with peach schnapps), and knocks back a couple of swigs. He holds his hand out in front of him. The TREMBLING is beginning to subside. He picks up the telephone.</context>
      <utterance>He rises.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="179" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He then dials another number...</context>
      <utterance>Inform The Fuhrer the audience has taken there seats, and we're ready to begin. Step one, in Hans master plan, done.</utterance>
   <speaker>INT - LOBBY - NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aldo in the lobby...</utterance>
   <speaker>WHEN...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's THROWN ROUGHLY to the ground face first. Like the modern day Secret Service, within seconds, his wrists are handcuffed behind his back, he's searched, they find the BOMB attached to his ankle, it's removed, a BLACK CLOTH BAG is pulled over his head, then he's hoisted up, and RUSHED out of the building. This happens in mere seconds, and quietly too, no one in the auditorium is none the wiser...</context>
      <utterance>.he's JUMPED by the SIX NAZI USHERS...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="180" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COL.LANDA'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context>The faceless black hood does. Col.Landa, now standing directly in front of his hooded prisoner, says in ENGLISH;</context>
      <utterance>Shut up!</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As Stanley said to Livingston; Lt.Aldo Raine, I presume?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="181" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LT. ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hans Landa?</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches out with his finger, and lightly touches Aldo's face right in the middle of the hood. Aldo's head VIOLENTLY FLINCHES.</context>
      <utterance>You've had a nice long run, Aldo. Alas, your now in the hands of the SS. My hands to be exact. And they've been waiting along time, to touch you.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In German, he orders the men put Aldo in the back of a truck. Aldo, bound, and bagged, is put in the truck. Also in the truck is Utivich, wearing a makeshift chauffeurs uniform, bound, and bagged like the Lieutenant. The Truck drives off. Col.Landa turns around, and SEES FROM A DISTANCE, Hitlers motorcade pull up to the cinema.. Then the Fuhrer, Goebbels, Francesca, and the rest of the entourage, make there way down the red carpet into the cinema. Landa smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Caught ya flinching.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="182" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Utivich?</utterance>
   <speaker>UTIVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that you Lieutenant?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="183" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>UTIVIC}I</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hirchberg? The woman?</context>
      <utterance>Do you know what happened to Donny?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No I do not.</utterance>
   <speaker>UTIVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant, sorry I'm crying.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This bag, get to anyone.</context>
      <utterance>Nothin to be sorry about, son.</utterance>
   <speaker>UTIVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not exactly John Wayne, am I?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Utivich, giggles through the tears.</context>
      <utterance>John Waynes a pampered movie star. He burst into tears, if his cook, busts his yoke at breakfast. Just try puttin a bag over his head, and hear what kinda sounds he makes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aldo takes his foot, finds Utivichs foot, and places his foot on top. The TOUCH has a slight calming effect on Utivich. In the darkness, Utivich has reclaimed his dignity.</context>
      <utterance>I just want you to know, son, I was real proud of you tonight. Learnin how to drive overnight. Driving in that Limo line. You was in the hot seat, son, and you stood up real good. Utivich Cries LOUDER.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="184" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Italian? Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What could you have possibly been thinking?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I speak alittle Italian -</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Landas eyes go to the Two Nazi Guards behind the prisoners.</context>
      <utterance>I speak a little Tagalog, but I wouldn't begin to presume I could pass for Filipino. Don't get me wrong, I understand you were in a pickle, what with you losing your Germans. And I have nothing but admiration for improvisation. Still.... Chico Marx is more convincing. if the three of you had shown up to the premiere dressed in womans attire, it would have been more convincing.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode>GERMAN</mode>
      <context>They exit, leaving the Colonel, the Lieutenant, the Private and a German Radio Man in the corner.</context>
      <utterance>You may leave us. But stay alert outside.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="185" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So your Aldo the Apache?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So your The Jew Hunter?</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Jew Hunter? Just the name that stuck.</context>
      <utterance>Jew Hunter, , I'm a detective. A damn good detective. Finding people is my specialty. So naturally, I worked for the Nazi's finding people. And yes, some of them were Jews.</utterance>
   <speaker>UTIVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well you do hafts admit, it is catchy.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you control the nicknames, your enemies bestow on you? Aldo the Apache and The Little Man?</utterance>
   <speaker>UTIVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, The Little Man?</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Germans nickname for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>UTIVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Germans nickname for me is, The Little Man?</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or "The Little One, ether one means you. And as if to make my point, I'm a little surprised how tall you were in real life. I mean, your a little fellow. But not circus midget little, as your reputation would suggest.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is my men? Where is Bridget Von Hammersmark?</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bridget Von Hammersmark. Oh I'm sure she's in whatever, big bubbling cesspool in hell, the devil reserves for traitors of her ilk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="186" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LT. ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know our names?</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two Basterds don't believe this. It can't be true.</context>
      <utterance>Lt.Aldo, if you don't think I wouldn't interrogate every single one of your swastika marked survivors... .? We simply aren't operating on the level of mutual respect I assumed. Now, back to the whereabouts of your two Italian saboteurs. At this moment, both Hirschberg, and Donowitz, should be sitting in the very seats we left them in. Seats, 0023 and 0024, if my memory serves. Explosives, still around there ankle, still ready to explode. And your mission, some would call a terrorist plot, as of this moment, is still a go.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What's next, Eliza on the ice?</context>
      <utterance>That's a pretty exciting story.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>However, all I have to do, is pick pick up that phone right there. Inform the cinema, and your plans kupet.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>IF, their still there, and IF their still alive, and that's one big IF, there ain't no way, you gonna take them boys without settin off them bombs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="187" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have no doubt, and yes, some Germans will die., and yes, it will ruin the evening, and yes, Goebbels will be very very very mad at you for what you've done to his big night. But you won't get Hitler, you won't get Goebbels, you won't get Gering, and you won't get Boorman. And you need all four to end the war.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode>PAUSE</mode>
      <context>The Nazi Colonel lifts up the bottle of Chianti, and fills three glasses. As he pours, he says;</context>
      <utterance>But if I don't pick up that phone, right there, you may very well get all four. And if you get all four, you end the war...tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So gentlemen, lets discuss the prospect of ending the war-tonight. All three have their Chianti filled glasses.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Would you agree?</context>
      <utterance>So the way I see it, since Hitlers death, or possible rescue, rests solely on my reaction...If I do nothing ...it's as if I'm causing his death, even more then yourselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess so.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about you Uitivich?</utterance>
   <speaker>UITIVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess so too.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good, we more or less, all agree. Gentlemen, I have no intention, of Killing Hitler, and killing Goebbels, and Killing Gerring, and killing Boorman, not to mention winning the war single handedly for the allies, only later, to find myself standing before a Jewish tribunal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="188" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you want to win the war, tonight, We have to make a deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kinda deal?</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The kind you wouldn't have the authority to make. However, I'm sure this mission of yours, has a commanding officer? A General, I'm betting. For ..</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode>THINKING</mode>
      <context>Aldo's eyebrows reveal that was a good guess.</context>
      <utterance>.O.S.S. would be my guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oooh, that's a bingo. Is that the way you say it, That's a bingo?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just say, bingo.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bingo! How fun. But I digress, where were we? Oh yes, make a deal. Over there is a very capable two way radio. And sitting behind it, is a more then capable radio operator, named Herrman. Get me somebody on the other end of that radio with the power of the pen, to authorize my - Let's call it, the terms of my conditional surrender, if that taste better going down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="189" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In fact, I want all the members of "Operation Kino" to receive the congregational medal of honor. Full citizenship for myself - but that goes without saying. And I would like the United States of America to purchase property for me on Nantuckett island, as a reward for all the countless lives I've saved by bringing the tyranny of the National Socialist party to a swifter then imanged end. Do you have all that, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode>PAUSE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I look forward to seeing you face to face as well, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode>PAUSE</mode>
      <context>The Colonel hands the headphones and microphone to Aldo.</context>
      <utterance>He's right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We HEAR the VOICE on the other end of the radio, give Aldo his</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="190" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RADIO VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Colonel Landa will put you and Private Uitivich in a truck as prisoners. Then he and his radio operator, will get in the truck, drive to our lines. Upon crossing our lines, Colonel Landa and his man will surrender to you. You will then take over driving of the truck, a bring them straight to me for debriefing. Is that clear, Lieutenant?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Conversation is over, he puts the radio down. The three men look at one another. Landa picks up his wine.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="191" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The four men, Col.Hans Landa, Lt.Aldo Raine, Pvt.Smithson Uitivich, and Herrman, lift up four glasses of wine.</context>
      <utterance>So I suppose the only thing left to do is lift a glass, and toast to Donowitz and Hirschbergs success. You too Herrman, come over here.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen, To history, and it's Witnesses.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="192" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SGT.DONOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode>ITALIA-ISH</mode>
      <context>Hirschberg indicates/pantomimes, he can't set his bomb surrounded by all these Nazi's. Donowitz, pantomimes crossing his legs, setting bomb on ankle in his seat. Then getting up, and dropping it in the back of the auditorium, in the dark. Hirschberg doesn't get it.</context>
      <utterance>I-a Go-a Toilet-a, Set-ta Boom-a.  When-a I-a Go-a, you-a Set-ta Boom-a.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIRSCHBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donny pantomimes again, more exaggerated, and with less patience.</context>
      <utterance>What-a?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="193" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HIRSCHBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(Affirmative, affirmative)</context>
      <utterance>Affirm-ato, affirm-ato.</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.DONOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(They're looking at the screen, not you.)</context>
      <utterance>They-o Look-o Screen-a, Not-o You-a.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIRSCHBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fantastic-o.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="194" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SGT.DONOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After-teri, Set-ta, Five-o Moment-o</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.DONOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode>(Pointing to WATCH)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You-a, Pphisst.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIRSCHBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(What?)</context>
      <utterance>What-o?</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.DONOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Confuse-i, confuss-i, confuss-i.  What-a, and-o what-o, same-o?</utterance>
   <speaker>HIRSCHBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(Oh, sorry, I ment what.)</context>
      <utterance>Oh-o, sorr-o, I-o ment-a "What-a".</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.DONOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After-teri, you-a set-ta boom-a, five-o moment-o, you-a, fuck-o Pphisst.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIRSCHBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(Affirmative, Affirmative)</context>
      <utterance>Affirm-ato, affirm-ato.</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT.DONOWITZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(Good luck.)</context>
      <utterance>Good-a, Luck-a.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="195" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GOEBBELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He exits the opera box. And walks to the projection booth door. He raps on the door in a trying to be amusing way. The door opens, just a little bit, Shosanna not friendly, stares at him. Be, as per usual, is all smiles and charm. They speak in FRENCH, SUBTITLED into ENGLISH;</context>
      <utterance>Perfectly understandable, dear boy. You go now, and we'll see you after the show.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Are you the manager, of this cinema? I want my money back. That actor in the movie stinks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="196" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I came to visit you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't you see how busy I am?</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then allow me to lend a assist.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Fredrick prepares to tell his little tale, with all the charm at his command, Shosanna listens, knowing the third reel is just about over, and her big reel change is coming up.</context>
      <utterance>Fredrick it's not funny, you can't be here. This is your premiere, you need to be out there with them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="197" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Normally, you would be.right. And for all the other films I do, I intend to endure evenings like tonight, in the proper sprit. However the fact remains, this film, is based on my military exploits. And in this case, my exploits consisted of me killing many men. Consequently, the part of the film that's playing now,... .I don't like watching this part.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fredrick, I am sorry, but -</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- So, I thought, I'd come up here and do what I do best, annoy you. And from the look on your face, it would appear I haven't lost my touch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="198" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh please, it's been two years since i've done a reel change.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said, no.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, it's my premiere.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No subtitles for Fredrick needed this time, he gets it. He does a one-armed PILE DRIVE PUSH on the door, knocking both it OPEN, and Shosanna back into the room. Fredrick, a different cat then we've seen up till now, enters the booth, closing the door behind him, and LOCKING it. The quite startled Shosanna, says to Fredrick;</context>
      <utterance>Are you so use to the Nazi's kissing your ass, you've forgotten what the word,No" means? No Fredrick, you can't come in here, now go away!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fredrick, you hurt me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shosanna steps backwards...</context>
      <utterance>Well, it's nice to know you can feel something. Even if it's just physical pain. Fredrick steps forward...</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not a man you say, "Go away" to. There's over three hundred dead bodies in Russia, that if they could, would testify to that. After what I've done for you, you disrespect me at your peril.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="199" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CU SWASTIKA FOREHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>seeing him get closer...</utterance>
   <speaker>CU SWASTIKA FOREHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>seeing him closer still...</utterance>
   <speaker>CU SWASTIKA FOREHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>begins to notice...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="200" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FREDRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>While Fredrick's back is turned, Shosanna takes a GUN out of her pocket, and SHOOTS Fredrick THREE TIMES in the back... ..Be CRASHES HARD into the door, then FALLING FACE FIRST to the floor... Shosanna, gun in hand, looks out projection booth window into the audience... The ON SCREEN BATTLE rages so LOUDLY with GUNFIRE, that her weapon didn't stand a chance of being heard. Her eyes go from the audience... .up to the big screen... .Which holds FREDRICK ZOLLER in a tight handsome CLOSE UP. The Face on the silver screen, breaks the young girl's heart... .She looks to his body, lying face down on the floor, blood flowing from the holes she put in his back... .His body moves a little, and he lets out a painful MOAN... .DIEING though he is, at this moment, Fredrick is still</context>
      <utterance>What the hell was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALIVE...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>..She touches him, and he lets out another MOAN... .She turns his body over on it's back... ..he's holding a LUGER in his hand... .he FIRES TWICE...</context>
      <utterance>Shosanna moves to him...</utterance>
   <speaker>BANG BANG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THROWING HER against the wall, then FALLING FORWARD on her knees to the floor... ..Fredrick, Luger still in hand, takes aim from the floor...</context>
      <utterance>Two bullets HIT HER POINT BLANK IN THE CHEST...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="201" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SHOSANNAS GIANT FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a message for Germany. I'm interrupting your Nazi propaganda horse shit, to inform you despicable German swine, that your all going to die. HITLER and GOEBBELS react.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIRSCHBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>react.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>smiles.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOSANNAS GIANT FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I want you to look deep in the face of The Jew who's going to do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="202" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HERRMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the back of the truck, sit the two last remaining members of The Basterds, Lt.Aldo Raine, and Prvt.Smithson Uitivich, both with their hands cuffed behind there back. Landa and Herrman appear at truck rear, says in ENGLISH;</context>
      <utterance>These are the American lines, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay Gentlemen, you can climb down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="203" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>143</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Col.Landa indicates for Herrman to remove the handcuffs from the two prisoners. He does.</context>
      <utterance>Aldo and Uitivich climb down from the truck.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Col.Landa hands over his LUGER, and his very cool looking SS</context>
      <utterance>Herrman, hand them your weapon. He does.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="204" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am officially surrendering myself over to you, Lt.Raine. We are your prisoners.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you very much Colonel. Uitivich, cuff the Colonel's hands behind his back.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Uitivich cuffs the. Colonels hands behind his back, Aldo</context>
      <utterance>Is that really necessary?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="205" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then Aldo takes the Luger, and SHOOTS HERRMAN DEAD. The bound Col.Landa is appalled.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a slave to appearances.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you mad? What have you done? I made a deal with your General for that mans life!</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, they made that deal, but they don't give a fuck about him, they need you.</utterance>
   <speaker>COL.LANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll be shot for this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="206" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Raw I don't think so, more like I'll be chewed out. I've been chewed out before. You know, Uitvich and myself, heard that deal you made with the Brass. End the war tonight? I'd make that deal. How bout you Uitivich, you make that deal?</utterance>
   <speaker>UITIVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd make that deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For the first time in the movie, Col.Landa doesn't-respond.</context>
      <utterance>I don't blame ya. Damn good deal. And that pretty little nest ya feathered for yourself. Well, if your willing to barbecue the whole high command, I suppose that's worth certain considerations. Now I don't care about you gettin pensions, merit badges, ticker tape parades, who gives a damn, let's all go home. But .1do have one question? When you go to your little place on Nantuckett Island, I image you gonna take off that handsome looking SS uniform of yours, ain't ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I thought. Now that... .I can't abide. How bout you Uitivich, can you abide it?</utterance>
   <speaker>UITIVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not one damn bit, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens LandaSS DAGGER, and holds the BLADE in front of Hans face.</context>
      <utterance>I mean if I had my way, you'd wear that goddamn uniform for the rest of your pecker suckin life. But I'm aware that's ain't practical. I mean at some point ya gotta hafta take it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.ALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I'm gonna give you a little somethin you can't take off.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
