<movie id="307" title="Interview with the Vampire">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you want me to tell you the story of my life...</utterance>
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I do. I interview people. I collect lives. F.M. radio. F.F.R.C. I just interviewed a genuine hero, a cop who -</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd have to have a lot of tape for my story. I've had a very unusual life.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So much the better. I've got a pocket full of tapes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You followed me here, didn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Saw you in the street outside. You seemed interesting. Is this where you live?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just a room...</utterance>
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So shall we begin?  What do you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Malloy laughs.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a vampire.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You mean this literally, I take it?</context>
      <utterance>See? I knew you were interesting.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely. I was watching you watching me. I was waiting for you in that alleyway. And then you began to speak.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what a lucky break for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Still in shadow he turns from the window and approaches the table.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps lucky for both of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Malloy is uneasy as he studies the shadowy figure, fascinated but afraid.</context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you my story. All of it. I'd like to do that very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were going to kill me? Drink my blood?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis stands opposite, hand on the chair. Malloy is riveted.</context>
      <utterance>Yes but you needn't worry about that now. Things change.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You believe this, don't you? That you're a vampire? You really think...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't begin this way. Let me turn on the light.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I thought vampires didn't like the light.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis pulls the chord of the overhead naked light bulb.</context>
      <utterance>We love it. I only wanted to prepare you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good God! He struggles to suppress fear and understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The light appears to go out by itself and suddenly Louis is in the chair, dimly lit by the street-light from the window. The cassette is turning.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be frightened. I want this opportunity.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Malloy is speechless, frightened yet enthralled.</context>
      <utterance>The same way you do it. A series of simple gestures. Only I moved too fast for you to see. I'm flesh and blood, you see. But not human. I haven't been human for two hundred years.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can I do to put you at ease? Shall we begin like David Copperfield? I am born, I grow up. Or shall we begin when I was born to darkness, as I call it. That's really where we should start, don't you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not lying to me, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why should I lie? 1791 was the year it happened. I was twenty-four - younger than you are now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But times were different then. I was a man at that age. The master of a large plantation just south of New Orleans...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INFANT JEAN MARIE - 1791"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>inscription, then drinks from a pocket-flask. His face is ashen.</context>
      <utterance>Louis rips away the vines already covering the</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was twenty-four and life seemed finished. I couldn't bear the pain of their loss. I longed for a release from it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Louis displays a hand of four aces. A gambler at the table stands in fury, over turning money, cards, drinks.</context>
      <utterance>I wanted to lose everything. My wealth, my estate, my sanity. But Lady Luck didn't oblige.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're calling me a cheat?</utterance>
   <speaker>GAMBLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Gambler pulls out a pearl-handled pistol and points it at Louis. The crowd hushes and draws back. Louis smiles drunkenly and stands. he rips open his lace shirt, exposing his chest.</context>
      <utterance>I'm calling you a piece of shit -</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Gambler's finger on the trigger. His hand shakes.</context>
      <utterance>Then do me a favor. Get rid of this piece of shit...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LESTAT, a hooded figure in the corner, smiles from beneath the shadow of his hood. Gleaming blue eyes.</context>
      <utterance>You lack the courage of your convictions, sir. Do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The Gambler lowers his gun, scowling. Louis pockets the fistfulls of coins he has won.</context>
      <utterance>Most of all I longed for death. I know that now. I invited it, a release from the pain of living...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They would have killed you -</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then my luck would have changed.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want death? Is it death you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat floats down on top of him, then lifts him in the air, draws his head back by the hair and sinks his teeth in his neck.</context>
      <utterance>Yes...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis can barely get the words out.</context>
      <utterance>You still want death? Or have you tasted it enough?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat smiles and lets him go. Louis falls and plummets into the water below.</context>
      <utterance>Enough...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's how it happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. The Gift of Darkness requires more than that, as you'll see.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the hell are you? What are you doing in my house?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis takes aim. Lestat puts his hand over the barrel. Louis fires. The bullet tears a hole in Lestat's hand. Lestat is unfazed. He takes the gun from Louis' hand and throws it away. His hand begins to heal.</context>
      <utterance>And a beautiful house it is too. Yours is a good life, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not afraid of anything, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis reaches for his sword, hanging by the bed, and point it. Lestat laughs indulgently. He draws closer.</context>
      <utterance>Why should I be?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He comes closer to Louis, right up to his face, so the sword passes through his waistcoat.</context>
      <utterance>Are you going to put that through me too? Ruin my beautiful clothes?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches out with his now-healed hand and plucks out the sword.</context>
      <utterance>Were all last night's promises for nothing?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want from me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat sits down on the bed, drawing up one knee. Louis is becoming spellbound.</context>
      <utterance>I've come to answer your prayers. You want to die, don't you? Life has no meaning anymore, does it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The vampire theme rises, with the sound of a heartbeat.</context>
      <utterance>The wine has no taste. The food sickens you. There seems no reason for any of it, does there? But what if I could give it back to you? Pluck out the pain and give you another life? And it would be for all time? And sickness and death could never touch you again?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis and Lestat drifting, dreamlike, through the overhanging vines, comes to the grave of his wife and child. Above the crypt, the statue of angel, mother and child.</context>
      <utterance>Vampires, that's what we are. Creatures of darkness, only we see it that darkness more clearly than any mortal has ever seen...</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The marble fingers of the child on the statue move. The angel raises her head and has the face of Louis wife, Diane. she raises her hand and touches Louis tear- streamed face. The child speaks.</context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't it be sweet to bid pain goodbye? To wave away anguish and grief? To embrace the peace of the unending night?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARBLE CHILD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis reaches out to embrace them and finds himself touching cold marble. He cries out in anguish-</context>
      <utterance>Papa...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Diane!!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They are gone, Louis. Death took them. Death which you can now destroy...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to ask me for this. You have to want it, do you hear me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give it to me!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vampires. We thrive on blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat bends close as if to drink Louis' blood. Louis does not shrink back, but stares into his eyes. Lestat draws back, then stands up and goes to the French doors.</context>
      <utterance>I want it!</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks outside.</context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow night. You must prove yourself. I will give you the choice I never had.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaves. Louis sits dazed, staring at the empty French window. The sun rises with unnatural beauty, over the swamplands and the plantation, filling the room, striking water-pitcher, glass, mirror, and the picture of his dead wife.</context>
      <utterance>The sun's coming up. Watch it carefully. If you come with me tomorrow, you'll never see it again.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My last sunrise. That morning I was not yet a vampire, and I saw my last sunrise. I remember it completely, yet I don't remember any sunrise before it. I watched the whole magnificence of the dawn for the last time, as if it were the first. And the I said goodbye to sunlight and went out to become what I became.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the woods beyond the quarters, the white overseer is whipping a black slave, with horrifying savagery.</context>
      <utterance>Your grief has unhinged you. You've let your estate rot.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You let your overseer run riot, work your slaves to the bone. We'll start with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you mean, start?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis calls.</context>
      <utterance>Call him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The overseer turns and comes towards them, with the bloodied whip.</context>
      <utterance>Carlos!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The overseer looks into his eyes, shivers with terror, drops the whip and runs for the trees. Lestat is on him in an instant. He sinks is teeth in his neck. Louis runs to him, tries to pull him off. But Lestat turns to Louis and smiles, with his bloodied mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Why the bloody whip, Carlos?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's call that a start.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've just done it -</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He flees, as Lestat ends to finish off the overseer.</context>
      <utterance>Kill me if you will, but I can't do this...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. He was white trash, they come at two a penny. I dumped him in the swamp and untied the slave, licked his wounds clean.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's who you are.</context>
      <utterance>You're the devil, aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish I were. But if I were, what would I want with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't go through with it, I tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your perfect. Your bitter and you're strong.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But why do you want me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis takes out his flask and drinks. Drunkenly, he turns and heads for a nearby swamp.</context>
      <utterance>Because you're as strong as I was when I was alive.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really want to be with them?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Kill me. Kill me like you promised -</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In a quiet rage, Lestat raise his fist and shatters the marble face stone, revealing a coffin below. His fist shatters that in turn, revealing the half-rotted body of a women, holding an infant, no longer recognizable as individuals, a tangle of gruesome rotted hair, flesh, eaten away lace, insects and worms crawling over it. Louis gasps.</context>
      <utterance>You asked for death. I didn't promise it -</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat stares at him, smiling, becoming a hazy dreamlike vision, then hyperclear. Louis again is spellbound. He drops the flask, which shatters on the stones. Lestat appears angelic in his radiance.</context>
      <utterance>It's not your wife and child my friend. It's death. Just that simple. Think and choose. It happens to everyone. Except us.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis capitulates in one long sigh.</context>
      <utterance>We shall be this way always, my friend. Young as we are now. I'm lonely for a companion, lonely for your strength. But I'm not that lonely. Do you want to come or not?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat comes closer, smiling.</context>
      <utterance>Yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did I hear a yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat embraces Louis, obscuring his face. He drinks his blood. We hear two heartbeats, out of sync, coming together. We see Louis' face, growing paler, paler, as his blood is drained. His eyes stare upwards, losing their focus.</context>
      <utterance>Yes...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat lifts his hand to his lips and blows Louis a kiss.</context>
      <utterance>I've drained you to the point of death. If you drink from me you live for ever. If I leave you here you die.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat lifts his own right wrist to his teeth. Fangs slash his own flesh, blood falls.</context>
      <utterance>No. Don't leave me here. Give it to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis rises to accept the first drops with his open mouth. Lestat gathers him up, as Louis clamps his hand on Lestat's arm and drinks from the wrist. The VAMPIRE THEME swells. Lestat watches him drink his wrist with wry amusement. Louis finishes, staggers away from him as if drunk.</context>
      <utterance>Sure...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat leads him into the swamp. Everything astonished Louis, as if he's never seen it before. Louis is suddenly racked by shudders of pain.</context>
      <utterance>Stop staring at my buttons. Didn't I tell you it was going to be fun?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're body's dying. Pay no attention. It will take twenty minutes at most.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis dry-retches.</context>
      <utterance>Dying?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat wipes Louis' brow.</context>
      <utterance>It happens to us all.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come, you're going to feed now.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat laughs and his laughter echoes like bells in Louis' ears.</context>
      <utterance>I want a woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You'll see. Come...</context>
      <utterance>That doesn't matter anymore, Louis.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The slave walks towards them in the darkness. A crucifix gleams round his neck.</context>
      <utterance>They're all beautiful now. Men, women, the old, the young...simply because they are alive. -</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The crucifix -</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>Forget the crucifix. Take him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The slave looks up and sees them. Two gleaming white beings standing before him with devil's eyes. The he runs. Louis can resist him no more. He swoops on him with a vampire's rapid movement, brings him to the ground and sinks his teeth in his neck. Close on Louis feeding on the slave, the magnificent body shuddering in its death-throes. Lestat stands above, laughing. The slave dies. Louis rises from him, drunkenly, engorged with blood.</context>
      <utterance>Resist no more Louis. Feed...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What have I done?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis looks down at the body of the slave. Lestat's laughter echoes around him.</context>
      <utterance>You have fed. You were made for this...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dear God, what have I done?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat laughs harder. Louis runs from him, screaming in anguish.</context>
      <utterance>You've killed Louis. And enjoyed it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said the slave had a crucifix...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, that rumor about crosses?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't look at them...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nonsense, my friend. I can look on anything I like. And I am particularly fond of looking on crucifixes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The story about stakes through the heart?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bull shit.</context>
      <utterance>The same. As you would say today...</utterance>
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about coffins?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coffins... coffins unfortunately are a necessity...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, that's you, my handsome friend. And you'll look that way till the stars fall from heaven.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It can't be...</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give it time. You're like a man who loses a limb and still imagines he feels pain. It will pass. And we must sleep now. I can feel the sun approaching.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must get into it. It's the only safe place for you when the light comes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if I don't?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis approaches the coffin, hands trembling as he peers into it.</context>
      <utterance>The sun will destroy the blood I've given you. Every tissue, every vein. The fire in this lantern could do that too.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis crawls into the coffin, fearful yet fascinated.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be afraid. In moments you'll be sleeping as soundly as you ever slept. And when you awake I'll be waiting for you, and so will all the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat smiles bitterly and nods.</context>
      <utterance>You told me something earlier. You said you didn't have a choice. Was that true?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Total darkness. Sounds of Louis' panicked breathing. Of his prayer again.</context>
      <utterance>Someday I'll tell you. We have a lot of time to talk to each other. You might say... we have all the time we shall ever need. He closes the lid.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dear God, what have I done?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Lestat, totting up figures on a piece of paper.</context>
      <utterance>I awoke the next evening to a different world. And I realized there are as profound differences between vampires as between human beings...</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis just stares at him.</context>
      <utterance>Your wealth, dear Louis, is inestimable. Your income from cotton alone will keep us in comfort for a century.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Lestat looks up at him and grins.</context>
      <utterance>I sat there staring at him with contempt. He had the soul of a shopkeeper, he was the sow's ear out of which nothing fine could be made. I felt sadly cheated in having him as a teacher...</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll get used to killing. Just forget about that mortal coil. You'll become accustomed to things all too quickly.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yvette enters, stands behind him, staring at Lestat with loathing.</context>
      <utterance>Do you think so?</utterance>
   <speaker>YVETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are not hungry, sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat laughs loudly. Louis turns and looks at Yvette. Her beautiful forehead in the candlelight, the veins pulsing on her neck and her hands.</context>
      <utterance>Au contraire, my dear. He could eat a horse...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Yvette returns his stare, troubled.</context>
      <utterance>I looked at anything mortal and saw all life as precious, condemning all fruitless guilt and passion that would let it slip through the fingers like sand...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Yvette reaches for his uneaten plate. Louis stops her hand. Holds it for a beat too long, looking at the veins in her wrist.</context>
      <utterance>It was only as a vampire that I could see Yvette's beauty. Her fear of me increased my desire.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns and runs from the table. Lestat leans towards him.</context>
      <utterance>I will finish it, Yvette. Now leave us.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His hand snakes out under the table. It comes up holding a large grey rat.</context>
      <utterance>Can't you pretend, you fool? Don't give the game away. We're lucky to have such a home.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bares his fangs and slices the rat's throat. He pours the blood into a crystal glass.</context>
      <utterance>Pretend to drink, at least.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands the glass to Louis. Louis drinks the blood and stares at it in surprise, then at the dead rat on the fine lace tablecloth.</context>
      <utterance>Such fine crystal shouldn't go to waste...</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. It gets cold so fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>We can live like this? Off the blood of animals?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat strokes the belly of the dead rat, studying it sadly.</context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't call it living. I'd call it surviving. A useful trick if you're caught for a month on a ship at sea.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's nothing in the world now that doesn't hold some...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fascination...</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. And I'm bored with this prattle - He throws the rat away.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we can live without taking human life. It's possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rises. Louis follows.</context>
      <utterance>Anything is possible. But just try it for a week. Come into New Orleans and let me show you some real sport!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Louis and Lestat by a table, in the shadow of a tree. Teresa, a tavern wench, sits on Lestat's lap, pouring drinks for the two of them. She lifts a fresh glass to Lestat's lips as he flirts with her.</context>
      <utterance>This was New Orleans, a magical and magnificent place to live. In which a vampire, richly dressed might attract no more notice in the evening than hundreds of other exotic creatures.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERESA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, mon cher. The best in the colony. Once you touch this you'll never go to any other tavern again.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think so, cherie? But what if I'd rather taste your lips?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERESA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses him. He lets his tongue play with hers, then runs it down her neck. She swoons with pleasure. Then he sinks his teeth gently in her neck, looking playfully behind at Louis, who if appalled and fascinated.</context>
      <utterance>My lips are even sweeter still...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTICS ON THE STAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat slips the pale and dead Teresa into a chair beside him and folds her hands on the table. No one notices. He lays gold coins on the table and touches Louis' knee.</context>
      <utterance>Laughter rocks the tavern.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat rushes out, thrilled with himself.</context>
      <utterance>Let's get out of here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you ever been caught?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk down the crowded night street, full of ladies in their finery, freed slaves, whores, sailors etc.</context>
      <utterance>Of course not. It's so easy you almost feel sorry for them.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lestat killed two, sometimes three a night. A fresh young girl, that was his favorite for the first of the evening.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A youth of preternatural beauty, silhouetted against French windows. He is talking to an elegant widow, seated, holding two manicured poodles. Lestat stares at the youth with longing.</context>
      <utterance>But the triumphant kill of Lestat was a young man. They represented the greatest loss to Lestat because they stood on the threshold of the maximum possibility of life.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The trick is not to think about it. See that one? The widow St. Clair? she had that gorgeous young fop murder her husband. She's perfect for you. Go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But how do you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Read her thoughts.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leads Louis closer to them.</context>
      <utterance>The dark gift is different for each of us. But one thing is true of everyone. We grow stronger as we go along.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles at the young man, who smiles in return.</context>
      <utterance>Take my word for it. She blamed a slave for his murder. And do you know what they did to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The evildoers are easier. And they taste better...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WIDOW ST. CLAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leans towards him concquettishly. Louis, crazed with hunger, sees her as beautiful in the moonlight. He allows her lips reach his. He takes her in his arms, gently, romantically, and sinks in his teeth. She swoons.</context>
      <utterance>Now, young man, you really amaze me! I'm old enough to be your grandmother.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIDOW ST. CLAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis draws his lips away. She is weak in his arms, but still alive. He can't do it. The poodles growl. He shoots out an arm and grabs one, then the other.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, that's the melody, I remember it. Oh yes...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WIDOW ST CLAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat comes from nowhere, claps a hand over her mouth and breaks her neck. He spits in fury at Louis.</context>
      <utterance>My little papillions! My butterflies!!! He killed them!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You whining coward of a vampire who prowls the night killing rats and poodles. You could have finished us both!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What have you done to me? You've condemned me to hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis hurls him against tree after tree with a strength he never knew he had.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know any hell -</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drags him to the ground an throttles him. Lestat looks up at him, amazed and amused at the same time.</context>
      <utterance>You want to see me kill? Watch me kill you then -</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat squirms from his grip, seemingly effortlessly.</context>
      <utterance>What strength, my friend, what strength. I remember why I chose you now.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He ruffles Louis' hair, with wry affection.</context>
      <utterance>But you can't kill me, Louis. Nor I you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles. A sly, pleasurable secret secret smile.</context>
      <utterance>Feed on what you want, mon cherie. Rats, chickens, doves, goats. I'll leave you to it and watch you come round. Just remember, life without me would be even more unbearable...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Consider yourself lucky. In Paris a vampire has to be clever for many reasons. Here all one needs is a pair of fangs.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paris? You came from Paris?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As did the one who made me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me about him. You must have learnt something from him! It had to happen for you as it did for me!</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I learnt absolutely nothing. I wasn't give a choice, remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat spits out in anger.</context>
      <utterance>But you must know something about the meaning of it all, you must know where we come from, why we...</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The drumming grows outside.</context>
      <utterance>Why? Why should I know these things? Do you know them?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That noise! It's driving me mad! We've been in the country for weeks, with nothing but that noise!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They know about us. They see us dine on empty plates and drink from empty glasses.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come the New Orleans then. There's an opera on tonight. A real french opera! We can dine in splendor!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I respect life, don't you see? For each and every human life I have respect.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis stares. Lestat turns childishly, petulantly.</context>
      <utterance>Respect me a little then. I'm the only life you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks out, humming a French aria. Louis stares at his plate.</context>
      <utterance>You'll soon run out of chickens, Louis...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>YVETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis laughs harshly.</context>
      <utterance>Michi Louis? You don't want any supper?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yvette draws closer. Light reveals her beauty.</context>
      <utterance>No, ma cher. I need no supper. Is all well at Pointe Du Lac tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>YVETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>throat is long and slender, her breasts are gorgeous.</context>
      <utterance>We worry about you master. When do you ride about the fields? How long since you've been to the slave quarters? Everywhere there is death. Animals, men. Are you our master still at all? Louis watches her sadly. He's getting hungry. Her</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave me alone now, Yvette.</utterance>
   <speaker>YVETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She comes closer, and he can hear her beating heart. She touches his hair. He takes her hand and brings it to his lips.</context>
      <utterance>I will not go unless you listen to me. Send away this new friend of yours. The slaves are frightened of him. They are frightened of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her wrist. She suddenly gasps, sharply, withdraws her hand. She sees her wrist is red with blood. She sees the blood on his lips. She screams. Louis stands.</context>
      <utterance>I am frightened of myself, Yvette.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She screams even louder. Louis clamps his hand over her mouth. Her hand grips the table-cloth, pulls, bringing the empty glasses and crockery to the floor. In horror, Louis realizes he has broken her neck. He brings her cut wrist to his lips, then drops it, revolted. He carries her body outside, grief-stricken. The drumming grows louder.</context>
      <utterance>Hush, Yvette -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He places the body of Yvette in a rocking chair on the veranda.</context>
      <utterance>This place is cursed. Damned, do you hear me? And your master is the devil.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They don't move. They stare at him blankly.</context>
      <utterance>Get out while you can. You're free men.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns behind him, and looks at the mansion, all candelabra and chandeliers lighted, all windows open.</context>
      <utterance>Unlike me, you are no free men...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rushed up the stairs, snatches up the candelabra and sets fire to the drapes. He goes from window to window, lighting drapes, lace curtains, everything.</context>
      <utterance>Do I have to convince you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLAVES POV - MASTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They rush up the stairs with shouts of "STOP HIM, HE'S MAD". A wall of flame gushes out from the interior, blocking their way.</context>
      <utterance>Setting fire to the house.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You fool, what have you done?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis stands there, weakened, then collapses onto the floor. Lestat darts forward and catches him before he drops. He runs out the shattered window, carrying him on his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>What you wouldn't do. It's almost sunrise. It will be the sun or the fire. You said they can kill me. The sun or the fire!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are we?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis laughs softly.</context>
      <utterance>Where do you think, my idiot friend? We're in a nice filthy cemetery. Does this make you happy? Is this fitting and proper enough?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We belong in hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what if there is no hell, or they don't want us there? Ever think of that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You loved Yvette...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can a vampire feel love?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You loved your wife, surely.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks directly at Malloy, shocking him with his gaze.</context>
      <utterance>I was human then. Might as well ask can an angel feel love. Both are blesses or cursed with a certain... detachment. Though whether angels take as long to learn it as I, I will never know.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I loved Yvette. As I loved Pointe Du Lac. And as with each thing I loved, I destroyed it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lestat I did not love. And he survived.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>WHORE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're skin's icy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He presses his thumb on her neck and holds her tight, sinking his teeth into her neck. After a time she falls to the bed, dead. he turns to the other.</context>
      <utterance>Not always...</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your friend has no head for wine.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's stupid. I can warm that cold skin of yours better than she can.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rubs her breast.</context>
      <utterance>Do you think so?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why you're warm now.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bites her in turn, drinks her blood. She does into the swoon. Louis looks on in disgust. He stands.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, but the price is pretty high. Your sweet friend - I exhausted her.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat pulls away from the whore.</context>
      <utterance>I'm leaving you. I can't stand this any longer.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, no flowery speeches? About what a monster I am? What a vulgar fiend?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not interested in you. You disgust me. I'm interested in my own nature and know I can't trust you to tell me the truth about me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you imagine you are Louis?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't pretend to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girl moans.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you understand, Louis, that you alone of all creatures can see death with impunity... you alone under the rising moon can strike like the hand of God.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lestat, she's alive!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girl moans again, open her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Vampires are killers. Predators, who's all seeing eyes were meant to give them detachment.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The girl, Lestat -</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slashes her wrist with his teeth, and lets the blood drip into a glass.</context>
      <utterance>I know. Let her alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girls moans again. Lestat drinks that glass.</context>
      <utterance>You think you can be human. You think you can go back. But you can't. You live off the blood of rats now Louis. How human is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girl begins to scream. Lestat picks her up.</context>
      <utterance>Lie still, love...</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks to his coffin, puts her inside and sits on the lid. We hear muffled screaming and banging from inside.</context>
      <utterance>You're tired love, you want to sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you do this Lestat?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands up. The girl pushes the lid off, hysterical. She looks at Louis.</context>
      <utterance>I like to do it. I enjoy it. Take you aesthete's taste to purer things. Kill them swiftly if you will, but do it! For now doubt, you are a killer Louis. Ah!</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a coffin, a coffin! Get me out!</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis screams at Lestat</context>
      <utterance>Of course it's a coffin. You're dead, love.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lestat - finish this -</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You finish her - if you feel so much - The girl grabs Louis and pleads.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You'll save me?</context>
      <utterance>You won't let me die, will you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks her up again. He turns to Louis laughing.</context>
      <utterance>But it's too late, love. Look at your wrist, you breast.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unless I make her one of us...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God... to think you... are all I have to learn from...</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis leaves without a word.</context>
      <utterance>In the old world, they called it the dark gift, Louis. And I gave it to you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A smaller side street, in which every house is marked with an X. The street is crawling with rats, and Louis is following them. A man passes with a lantern.</context>
      <utterance>Am I damned? Am I from the devil? Is my very nature that of a devil? And all the while, as these dreaded questions caused me to neglect my thirst, my thirst grew hotter, my veins were threads of pain in my flesh, my temples throbbed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis smiles bitterly at these words, repeating them to himself.</context>
      <utterance>Don't go that way Monsieur. It's the plague. Go back the way you came.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks on, following the rats.</context>
      <utterance>The way I came...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A house, the door slightly open, marked with an X. The sound of a child crying inside. Louis walks towards it.</context>
      <utterance>... and finally, when I could stand it no longer, I stood in an empty desolate street and heard the sound of a child crying.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Louis enters, he sees the woman is dead. Her eyes are being eaten away by rats. Louis gasps in horror. Claudia turns. She is a radiant doll or angel as she stretches out her hand to Louis.</context>
      <utterance>Mama, please wake up. Mama, I'm frightened, please wake up.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She runs to him. Instinctively, he gathers her in his arms. He looks down pitying on her beautiful face.</context>
      <utterance>Monsieur, please help us. Papa's waiting for us at the ship. Please wake mama, Monsieur.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>She snuggles into him, suddenly utterly secure. She tugs at his hair, brings his head down towards her. And we see Louis shiver, as his lips go to her neck. Her breathing becomes calm as she goes into the swoon. Gradually another sound replaces it.</context>
      <utterance>And if I am damned, why do I fell such pity for her gaunt face? Why do I wish to warm her tiny arms? Comfort her beating heart?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis stares at the unconscious Claudia in horror, then lets her slip gently into a chair. Shamefully he wipes his mouth, sees the tiny wounds on her throat. Lestat snatches up the dead mother from the chair and begins to dance with her in great circles, humming and talking. Her head falls back. Black water flows from her mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, my philosopher, my martyr. "Never take a human life". Well you must admit it is funny. Or is it merely touching? I'm not sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis flees into the street.</context>
      <utterance>Let's make some party of it, shall we? Maybe there's some life in the old lady yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come back, Louis, you are what you are. The plague would have got her within hours anyway. Merciful Death how you love your precious guilt.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bends down to him, surprisingly gently and puts his own coat around him.</context>
      <utterance>All I need to find you Louis is follow the corpses of rats.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pain is terrible for you. You feel it like no other creature because you are a vampire. You don't want it to go on.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... They emerge from the sewer and walk along the waterfront.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do what it is in your nature to do. And you will feel as you felt with that child in your arms.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God Lestat. I felt peace. I felt an end to the craving.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts his arm around Louis, to stop his shivering.</context>
      <utterance>That and more.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evil is a point of view. God kills, indiscriminately, and so shall we. For no creatures under God are as we are, none so like him as ourselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is God merciless? Greedy and cruel?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis is baffled. He follows.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, but we have even more in common with our creator. come, I am like a mother tonight. I want a child.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's here, your wounded one.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat holds up a candle and walks towards a large four- poster bed. Claudia lies there, angelic, under the coverlet, two marks on her neck.</context>
      <utterance>You need company, Louis. More congenial than mine...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lestat!</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You remember how you wanted her, the taste of her -</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't want to kill her.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat shakes her gently.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, Louis, you're conscience is clear. You left her alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Claudia, Claudia, listen to me. You're ill, my precious and I'm going to give you what you need to get well.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis runs at him, but Lestat brushes him aside effortlessly, so he falls to the floor. Lestat bites his wrist and presses the bleeding wound to the child's mouth... He winces in pain.</context>
      <utterance>Lestat, what do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claudia sucks on the wound, reviving, making little noises like a person waking from sleep. Louis rises to his feet as Claudia clutches Lestat's arm, sucking the blood fiercely. Lestat moans.</context>
      <utterance>That's it dear. More. You must drink it to get well.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls her loose and she growls and stares at him with big clear astonished eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Stop, that's enough. No more.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want more.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat puts her down on the bed and sits beside her, holding his wrist, obviously in pain.</context>
      <utterance>What have you done?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Still suffering, Lestat pulls the bell-rope.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, cherie, of course you want more. And I'll show you how to get it. You drink from morals, my beauty, but from me? Never again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>MAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The maid comes near the bed, kneels in front of Claudia. Lestat lays his hand on the maid's throat and Claudia watches keenly.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, quelle Belle enfant!</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>innocent. They must not be made to suffer. Claudia lunges for the throbbing vein in the neck, locking on to the flowing blood. The Maid is transfixed. Close on Louis, his anguish, his fascinated horror.</context>
      <utterance>Gently, cherie. They are so</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are the devil! You are the instrument of Satan!</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lets the dead maid onto the floor. Claudia looks at the corpse.</context>
      <utterance>That's enough, cherie. Stop before the heart stops.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want some more.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat and Claudia sit on the Louis XVI settee. Claudia is a vision, a doll made out of pearl. Animated, voice crisp.</context>
      <utterance>It's bet in the beginning, lest the death takes you down with it. yes, that's it. My child. My beloved child.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The words echo in Louis' head, as he puts his hands to his ears.</context>
      <utterance>Where is Mamma?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat takes out his comb and begins to comb her hair.</context>
      <utterance>Mamma's gone to Heaven, cherie, like that sweet lady over there. They all go to Heaven. And you did very well, cherie. Not a drop spilt. Very good! You're going to be our child now.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your mama's left you with us. She wants you to be happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are the devil! You are the instrument of Satan!</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shhhh! Do you want to frighten our little daughter?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not your daughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claudia runs over to him. She smiles at him.</context>
      <utterance>Yes you are, my dearest. You are mine and Louis' daughter. You see Louis was going to leave us. He was going to go away. But now he's not. He's going to stay and make you happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis is conflicted. He cannot leave her. He touches her cheeks, her hair. Same as his. Vampire skin and hair. He draws in his breath, shocked by her beauty, then he embraces her as a father might a daughter. He looks over her shoulder to Lestat.</context>
      <utterance>Lou...eee...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat smiles</context>
      <utterance>You fiend. You monster.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One happy family.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sees the tape has run out. He rapidly and clumsily sticks in another.</context>
      <utterance>A child vampire!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shall we go on?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He did it to make you stay with him!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps. He knew me. He knew I would love her more than the waking world. But there was more to it than that. Perhaps in the end he did it - to show me that he could. For he lavished affection on her, there was no doubt about that. Life was very different with madame Claudia, as you can imagine...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DRESSMAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She has pricked her hand. A spot of blood appears on her finger Claudia takes her hand.</context>
      <utterance>Monsieur, I need more light. I shall go slind if you do not bring me a lamp, or let me fit this child during the day. Ouch!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claudia brings the hand to her lips. The dressmaker abruptly pulls her finger away, in pain again. CLOSEUP - her finger, two holes showing.</context>
      <utterance>Let me kiss it better...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Lestat walks through - sees the dressmaker lying dead at Claudia's feet, Claudia still on the chair in the half-finished dress.</context>
      <utterance>A little child she was, but also a fierce killer, now capable of the ruthless pursuit of blood with all a child's demanding.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Claudia, Claudia, will you never learn? Who will we get now to finish your dress? A little practicality, cherie...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woman, all solicitude, goes to Claudia.</context>
      <utterance>Why are you crying, child?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you lost, my love?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mama...</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hush now, don't cry, We'll find her...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woman takes Claudia in her arms. Claudia nestles her head in her shoulder, her teeth near her neck.</context>
      <utterance>Mama...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They found death fast in those days, before she learnt to play with the, to delay the moment till she had taken what she wanted...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PIANO-TEACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claudia glares at him, then returns to playing, improving rapidly.</context>
      <utterance>The thumb girl! Mind the thumb!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOLLMAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They are expensive, my dear. Maybe too expensive for a young girl like you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claudia smiles to herself, keeps playing.</context>
      <utterance>Claudia, Claudia! Didn't I tell you, never in the house!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks up and sees Louis in the doorway, watching her.</context>
      <utterance>September 21st, one hour after sunset. The sky is still violet, the way Louis loves and as always Lestat was gone when we rose.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you learn to write, Claudia?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She closes the diary.</context>
      <utterance>The way I learn everything. By watching you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you never let me see you kill, Louis.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lestat taught you all you need to know about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Infant death, he calls me. Sweet daughter death. You know what he calls you? Merciful death.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He jests.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why does he call you that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens it. Inside there is a beautiful pen and ink portrait of Louis.</context>
      <utterance>Hush, Claudia don't talk about such things. Show me your book.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Claudia! You did that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sit still. It's not finished - She begins to fill in the sketch.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Time can pass fast for mortals when they're happy. With us it was the same.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Claudia, Louis and Lestat, dressed in the same clothes walking through a raucous carnival with sideshows. Crowd milling around, sailors, whores, children, thieves, freed slaves, Indians. They pass a Wild West display, jugglers, fire-eaters, three-card tricksters...</context>
      <utterance>It was a very different life. And a new century was beginning. what had once been a small godforsaken French colony was growing into a great port, giving us an endless train of magnificent strangers...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>They come to a raised platform where a troupe of perfectly-formed midgets do a burlesque show. Claudia stops. She stares, at these small, perfect creatures like herself, intrigued and troubled. Louis and Lestat walk on, not noticing as -</context>
      <utterance>All human life was here, for the taking. And we took, all three of us, in our different ways...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>YOUTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claudia walks up to him.</context>
      <utterance>You want to come inside, lovely?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claudia shakes her head. He kisses her. Claudia allow her to be kissed, then bites his tongue. he youth struggles, as Claudia holds him and drains him. She lets him go as Louis appears behind her.</context>
      <utterance>Ever been kissed?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis hurriedly draws her away.</context>
      <utterance>She's like me, Louis. Small and yet not small at all. Like me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I watched her grow yet stay the same, her doll-like face possessed of adult eyes, eerie, powerful, seductive...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FOCUS ON early 19th Century French dolls - wood, glass, wax, bisque - all around the bedroom, on chairs, on the bed. Some newish, some tattered old.</context>
      <utterance>Another doll? I have ten, you realize.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands her the box. It is a fine Parisian Jumeau doll. She likes it and stokes its face.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I thought you could use another.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why always on this night?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What night? What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You always give me the doll on the same night of the year.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't realize.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He examines the other dolls.</context>
      <utterance>Is this my birthday?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some of these are so old and tattered. You should throw them away.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have. Or there would be twice as many.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you're the fairest by far.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat doesn't answer. Claudia stands up quickly, and strides out into the -</context>
      <utterance>You dress me like a doll. You make my hair like a doll. Why?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want me to be a doll forever?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Claudia - don't -</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She continues cutting. She sees Lestat emerge from her bedroom in the mirror behind her then turns to him, an angelic little boy's face now with soft curls around her face.</context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks past him, back into her bedroom and slams the door. A beat. Louis looks from the mass of blonde hair on the floor to Lestat. Then a HORRID SCREAM pierces the silence. More screams, which become roars.</context>
      <utterance>Can't I change, like everybody else?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which of you did it? Which of you made me the way I am?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you are? You would be something other than you are?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if I cut my hair again?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It will grow back again!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it wasn't always so! I had a mother once! And Louis - he had a wife! He was mortal the same as she! And so was I!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Claudia - She turns on Lestat.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You made us what we are, didn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop her Louis!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And why should I tell you? It's in my power.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why yours alone? Tell me how it was done!!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He storms out. Louis goes to Claudia and picks her up in his arms.</context>
      <utterance>Be glad I made you what you are! You'd be dead not if I hadn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're immortal. You've always known that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis carries her outside, onto the porch. There is an old flower-seller going by.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me why... you've got to tell me...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see the old woman? That will never happen to you. You'll never grow old. You will never die.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She clutches Louis desperately.</context>
      <utterance>And it means something else too, doesn't it? I shall never, ever grow up.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis strokes her beautiful face, her hair.</context>
      <utterance>I hate him. But I cannot bear to lose you. You're the only companion I have, forever. You taught me everything I know. Please tell me Louis. Tell me how it came to be that I am this... thing...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come... I've something to show you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Louis back in the same street, outside the same house. He stands with Claudia at the window. There is a family inside, a picture of domestic tranquility.</context>
      <utterance>Though everything was changed, through the years had warped the contours of the streets, I found my way there, aware that I'd always known where it was and avoided it, not wanting to pass the doorway where I'd first heard Claudia cry.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claudia stares at him, suddenly very cold, very alert.</context>
      <utterance>I heard you crying. You were there in a room with your mother. You were hugging her for warmth, crying pitifully as you had been for days. Because your mother was dead...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He can't go on. Claudia's eyes are remorseless.</context>
      <utterance>I opened the shutters... I came into the room... I felt pity for you. Pity, but something else.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You... fed on me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And he found me with you. I ran, sickened at what I'd done. Then he cut his wrist and fed you from him. I tried to stop him, but you were a vampire then. And have been every night hereafter.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You both did it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claudia speaks through indrawn breath.</context>
      <utterance>I took your life. He gave you another one.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She runs.</context>
      <utterance>And here it is. And I hate you both.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But why did you tell her?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How could I not? She had to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And did you lose her? Did she go?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where would she have gone? She was a child, and beautiful, heartbreaking merciless child. And I had made her that...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A cathedral rising out of the mist, the doors open.</context>
      <utterance>I walked all night. I walked as I walked years before when my mind swam with guilt at the thought of killing. I found myself at the Cathedral.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis walks towards the doors, inside.</context>
      <utterance>I thought of all the things I had done and couldn't undo. And I longed for one second's peace...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis walking down the nave of the church. He stops by the alter.</context>
      <utterance>I had no fear. If anything I longed for something to happen, for the stones to tremble as I entered the foyer.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis sits in a pew.</context>
      <utterance>I almost genuflected from old habit. I almost prayed.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then it struck me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS' POV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The cross, the statues, the tabernacle.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly a hand is laid on his shoulder. Louis almost jumps. He turns and sees the face of a grey-haired priest.</context>
      <utterance>What if the statues gave an image to nothing? What if I was the supernatural in this cathedral? The only immortal under this roof. And I felt nothing but loneliness. Loneliness to the point of madness.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis stares at him, tears in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>You wish to go to confession? I was about to lock up the church.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are troubled, aren't you? Can I help?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's too late, too late -</utterance>
   <speaker>PREIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The priest gestures to the confessional. Louis rises, slowly.</context>
      <utterance>No, it's never too late. Come...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bless me father for I have sinned so often and so long, I don't know how to change nor beg for forgiveness.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son, God is infinite in his capacity to forgive. Tell him from your heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The hatch slams down. Louis rises, confused, and the door is flung open, the priest stands there.</context>
      <utterance>Murders, father, death after death. The woman who died two nights ago in Jackson Square, I killed her. And thousands of others before her. I have walked the streets of New Orleans like the Grim reaper. And fed on human life for my own. I am a vampire, father, and have turned the one I love most of all into on too -</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis rises. Walks out.</context>
      <utterance>Do you know the meaning of sacrilege?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His face comes into the light. The priest steps back, open-mouthed.</context>
      <utterance>Then there is no mercy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bares his fangs. The priest runs, screaming. Gets to the bellrope, begins to ring the bell. Louis swoops on him.</context>
      <utterance>You talk of sacrilege. Why if God exists does he suffer me to exist?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis takes him, lifting him from the floor, till his feet stop kicking.</context>
      <utterance>Why does he suffer me to live?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns, sees her sitting in the darkness. She is wearing a tiny nightgown of stitched lace and pearls, weirdly adult and seductive. She comes towards him.</context>
      <utterance>Locked together in hatred -</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sprays perfume over her body as she comes nearer.</context>
      <utterance>But I can't hate you Louis.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She whispers.</context>
      <utterance>Is this the aroma of a mortal child?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses his cheek.</context>
      <utterance>Louis. Lover.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes his face in her hands.</context>
      <utterance>I was mortal to you. You gave me your immortal kiss. You became my mother and my father. And so I'm yours. Forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But now's the time to end it, Louis. Now's the time to leave him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claudia smiles.</context>
      <utterance>He'll never let us go.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh... really?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So we made plans. She was convinced there were others of our kind in Europe, that they would have the answers Lestat couldn't provide. Lestat whom she now hated, who she thought she could be free of. I doubted, but then she had a surprise in store...</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Your very presence irritates me!</context>
      <utterance>What is it now? You irritate me!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. And I'll tell you something else! I've met someone who will make a better vampire than both of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that supposed to frighten me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're spoilt because you're an only child. You need a brother. Or I do. I'm weary of you both.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose we could people the world with vampires, the three of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not you my dear.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a liar. But you upset my plans.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What plans?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis perks up, puzzled.</context>
      <utterance>I came to make peace with you, even if you're the father of lies. I want things to be as they were.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop pestering me then!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Lestat. I must do more than that. I've brought a present for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claudia stares at him for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Then I hope its a beautiful woman with endowments you will never possess.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes his hand and leads him into an inner room. Louis follows behind.</context>
      <utterance>Better than that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You haven't fed enough. I can tell by your color.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Claudia, you've outdone yourself. Where did you find them?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I thought of you when I saw them.</context>
      <utterance>Drunk on brandy wine. A thimbleful.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claudia stares at him, sitting. She nods. Lestat bites into the neck of one of the youths, sucks greedily and horribly. Claudia watches him without expression. He finished one, is about to take the other when he staggers. He looks at Claudia.</context>
      <utterance>We forgive each other then?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absinthe? You gave them absinthe?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat stares wildly at her, tries to move towards her, then slips to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>No. Laudanum.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laudanum!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat tries to rise.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. It killed them, unfortunately. But it keeps the blood warm.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis watches, appalled. He goes to move.</context>
      <utterance>Ah Louis, Louis, she killed them... and let me drink...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't Louis -</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Louis, put me in my coffin...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls a knife out from under her shawl, walks rapidly to him and slashes his throat. Blood explodes from it.</context>
      <utterance>I'll put you in your coffin. Forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Claudia! Don't do this thing!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claudia lacerates his face. Blood pours from everywhere. She plunges the knife in his chest. He falls back, fangs bared, clutching the knife. Claudia leaps on him then, bites deep into his neck as he dies. Louis screams, runs forward, pulls her away.</context>
      <utterance>Louis, Louis, I gave you the gift - help me -</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drags her off Lestat, tries to pull her out of the room. She hisses at him.</context>
      <utterance>What have you done, Claudia -</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis looks. The floor is a sea of blood. Lestat has begun to shrivel, as if he'd been a bag of blood. His skin is shriveling against his bones like parchment, his eyes are slipping back into his skull-like face. His lush, beautiful hair remains unchanged. But his clothes are virtually being emptied of the body. It is no more than bones, wrapped in paper and the pupils of the eyes suddenly roll up into the papered skull.</context>
      <utterance>Louis! Look what's happening to him!!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lestat. Oh, God forgive us.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares at the shriveled skeleton in its skin wrapping. She is fascinated. She sees the vampiric blood flow all over the floor. She touches it and brings her finger to her lips.</context>
      <utterance>Don't mock me, Louis. Help me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis walks forward, touches the skeleton, the blonde hair.</context>
      <utterance>Goodnight, sweet prince, may flights of devils wing you to your rest.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's dead, Claudia, dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stands up, all business suddenly.</context>
      <utterance>The one good lesson he taught me, Louis. Never drink from the dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She drags the coverlet from the table, knocking the crockery over the dead youths, and wraps Lestat's skeleton in it. She takes a bunch of chrysanthemums and places them in his skeleton hands.</context>
      <utterance>Help me. We must get rid of him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should we burn him? Bury him? What would he have liked, Louis?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't mock, Claudia...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The swamp...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In Europe, Louis. We shall meet our own kind. Find the one who made him. Learn what it means.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And suppose the one who made him knows nothing and the vampire who made him knows nothing, and it goes back, nothing proceeding from nothing, until there is nothing! And we must live with the knowledge that there is no knowledge.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis drags out the bodies of the boys. He slides them into the waters of the swamp. We see ripples in the water and the churning of alligators, as they attack the corpses. Louis takes Lestat's skeleton in his arms. He slides it into the waters. The alligators speed towards it.</context>
      <utterance>And if we find the one who made him? Do we tell him we destroyed his own creation? The vampire Lestat?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He belongs with those reptiles, Louis. He deserved to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then maybe so do we. Every night of our lives. He was my brother. My maker. He gave me this life, whatever it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands there, saying nothing.</context>
      <utterance>I did it for us, Louis. So we could be free.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Louis, look at me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see her face, tears of blood running down it. She is heartbroken, lost.</context>
      <utterance>Claudia - You're crying -</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You never talked to me like that - in all these years.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you never cried -</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis gathers her in his arms.</context>
      <utterance>I can't bear it when you do - I would die rather than lose you Louis. I would die the way he died.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hush, Claudia, hush now my dear -</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me you don't hate me Louis. I did it for you - Louis walks her towards the carriage.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lifts her into the carriage and drives off, leaving the silent waters of the swamp.</context>
      <utterance>I love you Claudia. Always. And we are free now, Claudia. No Lestat. Just the two of us, beginning the great adventure of our lives.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens the cage, and the canaries fly around the room. There is a knocking on the door. Claudia falters.</context>
      <utterance>The birds. We forgot about the birds. There's nothing for it but to let them go.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes downstairs. Claudia plays a moment, then stops, perturbed. She goes to the window. Then sees something out there that makes her face go white. She screams.</context>
      <utterance>The workmen must have a trunk - don't stop, cherie -</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Louis!!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reaches the stairs. She screams -</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Louis has opened the door. Nothing there. He looks back at Claudia, puzzled, then at the door again when, swooping into his vision comes the nightmare image of -</context>
      <utterance>Don't Louis -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It can't be -</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Lestat crashes through the casement window, scattering blood everywhere, reefing himself on the shattered glass. He tumbles to the floor and gets unsteadily to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>It is! Take the back stairwell -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ship is sailing without us!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet. Holding her tightly, Louis runs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CITY OF NEW ORLEANS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With flame lighting up the sky.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Though the fire seemed to spread through the quartier, I stood on that deck until dawn, fearful he would come out again of the very river like some monster to destroy us both. And all the while I thought, Lestat, we deserve your vengeance. You gave me the dark gift. And I delivered you into the hands of death for the second time.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did he die in the fire?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That was all that mattered.</context>
      <utterance>He was dead to us. We were free.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A body is slipped into the sea. A priest reads last rites to a mourning family.</context>
      <utterance>Though the ship was blessedly free of rats, a strange plague nonetheless struck its passengers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sketch changes to a sketch of -</context>
      <utterance>Louis, your quest is for darkness only. This sea is not your sea. They myths of men are not your myths. Their history isn't yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE ACROPOLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the moonlight.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The sketch changes to a sketch of -</context>
      <utterance>We saw the Acropolis by moonlight, shades of grey and silver. And I longed for the brilliant white of those marbles in the hot sun of Homer...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The quest for these Old World vampires filled me with bitterness. We searched village after village, ruin after ruin and I was glad when always we found nothing. For what could the damned really have to say to the damned?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You found nothing?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peasant rumors, superstitions about garlic, crosses, stakes in the hear, all that - how do you say again? Bull shit. But one of our kind? Not a whisper.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No vampires in Transylvania? No Count Dracula?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>So we repaired to Paris...</context>
      <utterance>Fictions, my friend. The vulgar fictions of a demented Irishman...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis walks over, helps her with the earrings.</context>
      <utterance>Help me, mon chere...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do I look?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claudia laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Still my beautiful child.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A beautiful child! Is that what you still think I am?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns away.</context>
      <utterance>Yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She twirls, looking at herself in the mirror, then stops, stares at herself.</context>
      <utterance>Why do you turn away? Why don't you look.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want me to be your daughter forever, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis is stunned. He blushes.</context>
      <utterance>Well tell me, papa. What was it like making love?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't remember? Or you never knew.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was something hurries...and seldom savored... something acute that was quickly lost. It was the pale shadow of killing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares at him through the mirror.</context>
      <utterance>But how will I ever know, Louis?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll never find them, will I? My own kind...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She points to a beautiful French child walking by with her mother.</context>
      <utterance>Have I anything in common with her, Louis?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or her, or her - or any of them?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Claudia, you torture yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They are ducklings, that will grow into swans. Whereas I must be the duckling forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are more beautiful than any of them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are they my kind Louis? Dolls never change either.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Madeleine sees Claudia from inside. She waves.</context>
      <utterance>You are neither, Claudia. Now stop this -</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know her?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Should I take her, Louis? Among her dolls? make a doll of her in turn?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes her arm. But Claudia shakes him off, and moves into the shop.</context>
      <utterance>Come, Claudia...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For a time we had been almost human, in the sensual whirl of what Paris had to offer. But the human delights of that city only served to remind her of the ageless child she had become. I felt her pain as I walked until I become aware that I was being followed.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSEUP - LOUIS' FEET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis stops. Turns, sees nothing. Then walks again. The echoing steps begin again. Louis again. Sees a shadow, flitting.</context>
      <utterance>Walking. A step echoes his.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nothing. He walks again, hears the same effect. Then he stops. He stares at a gaslamp opposite.</context>
      <utterance>Claudia!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Santiago, a tall vampire, materializes under the gaslight. And Louis gradually realizes that this vampire has assumed the same attitude, posture, clothes and hair-style as Louis. Louis gives an involuntary shake of the head. Santiago mimics. Louis takes a step forwards. Santiago mimics. Louis folds his arms. Santiago mimics.</context>
      <utterance>So it was when I had given up the search for vampires that a vampire found me...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS &amp; STATIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clever.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean me harm?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis calculates.</context>
      <utterance>You mean me harm?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Santiago echoes the first word, but not the second. Louis has broken his composure. He turns his back on Santiago, only to come face to face with Santiago right in front of him. Again Louis turns this back to find Santiago facing him. Louis turns, glowers, refusing to look at him.</context>
      <utterance>Trickster. Buffoon!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>immortal and this is what I find? Slowly he looks up. Santiago draws close, breaking the mirror trick and suddenly slams Louis back against the wall. Louis is furious. He regains his balance, strikes out at Santiago and when Santiago vanishes, to reappear behind him, Louis slams back his elbow into his midriff. Santiago staggers, amazed and then rushes at Louis, throwing him down. Louis rolls back to his feet, then to his amazement sees two vampires, on in front, on behind. He looks both ways, then sees one has vanished. He stares, awestruck, at this new one:</context>
      <utterance>I've searched the world for an</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He looks like an angel.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches into his waistcoat, takes an engraved invitation out of his pocket and thrusts it at Louis. Louis reads it aloud, as we see:</context>
      <utterance>You are all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>"THEATRE DES VAMPIRES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By Special Invitation Friday, 9 p.m."</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis listens to the silence.</context>
      <utterance>Bring the petit beauty with you. No one will harm you. I won't allow it. Remember my name. Armand. Armand bows and vanishes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They draw close to:</context>
      <utterance>Remember what I've told you. They'll have different powers. They'll read your thoughts if you allow it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUGE POSTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reading -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But this can't be real. This is nonsense.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Warily, they show their invitations to the mortal ticket taker at the door. He glances away indifferently.</context>
      <utterance>Nonsense all right. But something tell me it's going to be the strangest nonsense we've ever seen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mortals, mortals everywhere. And lots of drops to drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An elaborate painted set of an Italianate castle. Death standing before it, the traditional image of the Grim Reaper, complete with magnificent scythe.</context>
      <utterance>They are here. I know they are. Listen for something that doesn't make a sound. Stage: curtain rises.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They use no paint. And the audience think it is paint.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A spotlight uncovers a mortal woman suddenly forced out upon the stage.</context>
      <utterance>How devilishly clever.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's no vampire.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The audience laughs uneasily, then stops as the Mortal Woman comes into the footlights. She is too beautiful, too confused. Santiago, as Death, advances on her. She backs away, terrified, then sees the other vampires, in a phalanx, advancing from behind, in a half-circle.</context>
      <utterance>No. She's frightened. She doesn't know where she is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTAL WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks around in panic. Santiago swoons, arms over his breast as if he is hopelessly in love.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to die!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Mortal Woman steps to the footlights.</context>
      <utterance>We are death!</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTAL WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis whispers to Claudia.</context>
      <utterance>Someone help me. Please... What have I done?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is no performance.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And no one knows but us...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Santiago gestures to the audience.</context>
      <utterance>We all die. Death is the one thing you share with all those here.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDIENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rapt faces.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MORTAL WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I'm young...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Death is no respecter of age. He can come any time, any place. Need I tell you what fate has in store for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTAL WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Please...</context>
      <utterance>I would take my chance. Let me go!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Santiago approaches her and tears the drawstring out of her peasant blouse. It opens completely and starts to slip. She tries to catch it, but gently stops her wrists. The blouse falls, exposing her young breasts.</context>
      <utterance>And if you take that chance and live, what is your fate? The humpbacked toothless visage of old age?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is monstrous!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, and very beautiful.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just as this flesh is pink now, it will turn grey and wrinkle with age.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTAL WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me live, please. I don't care.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes her head, confused. he catches her wrists behind her back.</context>
      <utterance>Then why should you care if you die now?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDIENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is awestruck by her beauty, her suffering.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Draws near her cheek.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And suppose death had a heart to love and to release you? To whom would he turn his passion? Would you pick a person from the crowd there? A person to suffer as you suffer?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDIENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A young girl cries out in jest.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Audience roars with laughter.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes, take me Monsieur Vampire! I adore you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Mortal Woman shakes her head in panic.</context>
      <utterance>You wait your turn. The audience laughs again.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, have you a sister, a mother, a daughter you would send in your place?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MORTAL WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shakes her head. She is helpless.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mortal Woman looks up on the verge of hysteria or fainting. But then her eyes mist over. She is being entranced.</context>
      <utterance>We alone can give death meaning. Do you know what it means to be loved by death, to become our bride?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No pain.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTAL WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Armand takes her by the naked shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>No pain?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your beauty is a gift to us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls the drawstring from her skirt and it falls revealing her nakedness. But she is spellbound.</context>
      <utterance>Who deserves such a gift?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTAL WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Armand embraces her, drinks, her naked body stark against her black clothes, then he passes her to the other vampires one by one.</context>
      <utterance>No pain...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who battles desire and hunger with anger.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've seen enough of this! I loathe it!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be still!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks around the empty theatre, more eerie now than when the play was on. The red curtain shifts slightly in a hidden breeze, a candle sputters and dies in a box. Then the candle flares again, and we see Armand in the box, looking down on them. He stares with a dreamy expression, saying nothing.</context>
      <utterance>Patience, Louis. Patience.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His voice echoes eerily. Armand gestures for them to follow him.</context>
      <utterance>We've been searching for you for a very long time...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HUGE UNDERGROUND BALLROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brueghel, Goya and Bosch depictions of death. Fine wooden coffins line the walls. Candles burn in sconces, casting alternate shadows and pools of light. Armand walks through, gesturing Louis and Claudia to follow him. As they walk through, vampire man and women appear out of the shadows like wraiths, startling them, drifting around them, stroking them, touching Claudia as if she were a doll. Shrieks of preternatural laughter. Armand gestures to the vampires to back off. All obey but ESTELLE.</context>
      <utterance>Walls are painted with famous copies of Durer,</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She menaces Claudia, her breasts enormous, her fangs bared. Armand throw her a look, and she is flung against the wall. Louis stares around. The vampires faces drift towards him and away, always disclosing the face of Armand, who seems some distance away, but strangely close, staring at Louis with a constantly calm, hypnotic gaze. Then a young mortal boy comes from the shadows with a candelabra, which he hands to Armand. Armand and the boy come towards them, leading them along the walls, his candelabra illuminating the ghastly murals, his face gleaming like an angel above the candleflame.</context>
      <utterance>Such a darling.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monstrous.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, and very beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your lips, they didn't move.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy is watching Louis. Armand's hand beckons and the boy draws up to Louis in the candlelight. He places his arms on Louis' shoulders. Louis glances at Armand, who smiles. Louis sees the puncture marks on the boy's neck.</context>
      <utterance>They did, but too fast for you to see them. No magic, just grace and speed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis is utterly confused. Can't resist. Drinks his blood. The boy's body presses against him, sensual, willing. The other vampires appear all around Louis, who suddenly senses it and draws away, ashamed. Claudia watches warily, from a distance. Armand beckons at her and Louis and open a door in the wall which reveals a stone staircase.</context>
      <utterance>He wants you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Disappointing, isn't it? To come so far and find so little. Jaded ingenues, amusing themselves with make- believe...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We had feared we were the only ones...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances at Louis, then at Claudia, who averts her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>But how did you come into existence?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't want to answer... Two vampires from the new world, come to guide us into the new era as all we love slowly rots and fades away.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you the leader of this group?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claudia stares at him constantly, guarded.</context>
      <utterance>If there were a leader, I would be the one.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you have the answers...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah! You have questions?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are we?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing if not vampires...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who made us what we are?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Surely you know the one who made you...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis looks at the picture. Armand watches him.</context>
      <utterance>But the one who made him, who made the one who made him, the source of all this evil...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is a picture, nothing more.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean we are not children of Satan?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles at Louis. A smile of infinite compassion.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand. I saw you in the theatre, your suffering, your sympathy for that girl. I saw you with the boy. You die when you kill, you feel you deserve to die and you stint on nothing. But does that make you evil? Or, since you comprehend what you call goodness, does it not make you good?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then there is nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He passes his finger through the candle flame.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And perhaps this is the only real evil left...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then God does not exist...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have not spoken to him...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And no vampire here has discourse with God or the Devil?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares at them, his face angelic, hypnotic, young. His eyes hold them both in a trance.</context>
      <utterance>None that I've ever known. I know nothing of God or the Devil, I have never seen a vision nor learnt a secret that would damn or save my soul. And as far as I know, after four hundred years I am the oldest living vampire in the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God... So it's as I always feared. Nothing, leading to nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares from Claudia to Louis. He seems to be reading their souls.</context>
      <utterance>You fell too much. So much you make me feel...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The one who made you should have told you this. The one who left the old world for the new...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He knew nothing. He just didn't care.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Knew? You mean he is... Claudia appears suddenly to Louis' shoulder, interrupting.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares hard at Armand. Armand looks from her to Louis.</context>
      <utterance>Come, beloved. It's time we were on our way. I'm hungry and the city waits.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He seems genuinely regretful. But Claudia pulls Louis out.</context>
      <utterance>So soon to go?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Suddenly a light comes on. They see they are in the empty theatre. Santiago stands on the stage, under a candle.</context>
      <utterance>The place was dark as we left, a darkness that confounded even Claudia. And as we blundered through it, again came the thought: I have wronged Lestat, I have hated him for the wrong reasons.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis is stunned.</context>
      <utterance>How did you wrong him?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You read my thoughts?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said a name -</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A name I don't want to say again.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Other vampires appear behind him.</context>
      <utterance>I seemed to recognize it...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at Claudia.</context>
      <utterance>There is but one crime among us vampires here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claudia laughs.</context>
      <utterance>You should know, who are so secretive about the vampire who made you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boredom!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is the crime that means death to any vampire. To kill your own kind!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aaaah! I was so afraid it was to be born like Venus out of the foam, as we were! Come Louis, let's go!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I loathe them! I can't stand the sight of them! Stupid bourgeois Parisians, all dressed in black like some private club! I've searched for them the world over and I despise them!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What danger?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They come to their room, enter.</context>
      <utterance>I can feel it from them! They want to know who made us, what became of him. They have their rules, their idiotic rules!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think I would let them harm you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you would not, Louis. Danger hold you to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Love holds you to me. And we are in danger, not you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles at him. A strange, sad, adult smile.</context>
      <utterance>Love?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You would leave me for Armand if he beckoned you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wants you as you want him. He's been waiting for you. He wants you for a companion. He bides his time that place. he finds them as dull and lifeless as we do.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not so.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know what his soul said to me without saying a word? When he put me in that trance...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you felt it too!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She touches his face.</context>
      <utterance>Let him go, he said. Let him go.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There are tears in her eyes. Louis lifts her up in his arms.</context>
      <utterance>Is that what I should do Louis? Let you go? My father? My lover? My Louis, who made me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He can protect us, Claudia.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really believe that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="34">
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was waiting for you...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He follows Armand into the room.</context>
      <utterance>Listen to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>daughter.</context>
      <utterance>Claudia is dear to me. My...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your lover.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, my beloved, my child.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you say so. You are innocent.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not innocent. But I'm afraid. She feels she's in danger from the others.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She is.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But why?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could give you reasons. Her silence. Her youth. It's forbidden to make so young, so helpless, that cannot survive on its own.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then blame the one who made her...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you kill this vampire who made you both? Is that why you won't say his name? Santiago thinks you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We want no quarrel with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's already begun. If you want to save her, send her away.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Armand smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Then I leave too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So soon? Without any of those answers you so longed for?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said there were none.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you asked the wrong questions. Do you know how few vampires have the stamina for immortality? How quickly they perish of their own will.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You would never give up life. If the world were reduced to one empty cell, on fragile candle, you stay alive and study it. You see too clearly. You see too much.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what the one who made me said.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Armand suddenly grips Louis close to him.</context>
      <utterance>How he must have loved you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis laughs bitterly.</context>
      <utterance>Louis, I need you more than he ever did. I need a link with this century. The world changes. We do not. Therein lies the irony that ultimately kills us. I need you to make contact with this age.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Armand smiles.</context>
      <utterance>He? Don't you see? I'm not the spirit of any age! I'm at odds with everything and always have been! I'm not even sure what I am!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis is stunned.</context>
      <utterance>But Louis, that is the very spirit of your age. The heart of it. You fall from grace has been the fall of a century.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the vampires of the Theatre?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis is speechless.</context>
      <utterance>Like moths around the candle of the age. Decadent, useless. They can't reflect anything. But you do. You reflect its broken heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are these not the answers you came for?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... My God...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A vampire with a human soul. An immortal with a mortal's passion. You are beautiful, my friend. Lestat must have wept when he made you -</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lestat! You knew Lestat!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Armand stands. He takes Louis by the arm, leads him towards the back wall.</context>
      <utterance>Yes I knew him. Knew him well enough not to mourn his passing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens a hidden door in the wall.</context>
      <utterance>But you must go now. You must get her safely out of Paris.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No-one else knows of this door. When you knock you will find me waiting...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Madeleine rises and comes towards Louis. She draws back the lace fringes round her throat, so he can see the two marks there. She says softly, dreamily.</context>
      <utterance>Madeleine... Louis is shy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADELEINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis turns away. Claudia speaks, icy, from the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis turns to Madeleine.</context>
      <utterance>Do it Louis. Because I cannot do it. I haven't the strength. You saw to that when you made me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You haven't the vaguest conception under God of what you ask!</utterance>
   <speaker>MADELEINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis pushes her away. Claudia screams.</context>
      <utterance>Au contraire, monsieur, I have.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis grips Madeleine and shakes her.</context>
      <utterance>You have found your new companion, Louis! You will make me mine!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do we seem to you? Do you think us beautiful, magical, our white skin, our fierce eyes? Drink, you ask me! Have you any idea of the thing you will become?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your evil is that you cannot be evil! And I will suffer for it no longer!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't make me, Claudia! I cannot do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She points to Madeleine</context>
      <utterance>Yet you could do it to me! Snatching me from my mother's hands like two monsters in a fairy-tale! Couldn't you have waited? Six more years and I would have had that shape! And now you weep! You haven't tears enough for what you've done to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She begins to weep, sobbing like a child.</context>
      <utterance>You give her to me! Do this before you leave me!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God! I love you still, that's the torment of it. But you know I must leave you Louis...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis looks at Madeleine</context>
      <utterance>And who will care for me my love, my dark angel, when you are gone?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You promise to care for her then?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADELEINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She wraps her arms around Claudia.</context>
      <utterance>And you know what you ask for?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADELEINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think she is, Madeleine? A doll?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADELEINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her finger clutches a locket around her neck, Louis touches it, opens it.</context>
      <utterance>A child who can't die...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the child who did die?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADELEINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis takes her chin in his hand, gently.</context>
      <utterance>My daughter...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at the gaslight. Don't take your eyes off it. You will be drained to the point of death, but you must stay alive. Do you hear me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADELEINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis pulls her to him and starts to drink her blood.</context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis speaks without turning.</context>
      <utterance>Louis!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She is dying. It happened to you too, but your child's mind can't remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But if she dies...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to look at Claudia.</context>
      <utterance>It's only mortal death.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bear me no ill will, my love. We are now even.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes his hand.</context>
      <utterance>What died tonight inside that room was not that woman. It will take her many nights to die, perhaps years. What has died in that room tonight is the last vestige in me of what was human.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bends down and kisses her. He looks up, at the wafting curtains. He sees -</context>
      <utterance>Yes father. At last. We are een.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANY VAMPIRE SHADOWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Silhouetted, coming closer.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks up and screams.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Armand! Get me Armand! he wouldn't countenance this -</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Santiago strikes Louis to the ground. As he struggles to his feet, he sees the vampires part around a figure coming through. He gasps at the sight of -</context>
      <utterance>You can make no demands here! Buffoon! Bastard -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Louis...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Is he the one?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, the child. The child was the one...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All the murderers!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat reaches out to Louis.</context>
      <utterance>You are alive, Lestat! It can't be murder! Tell them how you treated us...</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... You come back to me Louis...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you mad???</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The sentence is death! To all of them!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sound of something being dragged through the crowd. Horrible echoing, scraping - Lestat grips Santiago.</context>
      <utterance>Only the girl - it was the girl -</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares around him, confused. The scraping gets louder.</context>
      <utterance>You promised me - I could take him back to New Orleans - Louis - there's something I must tell you - about that night - that night I met you -</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You let her go, Lestat - you let her free - and I'll come back with you - Santiago grabs Louis by the neck.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see now what caused the scraping. A huge metal coffin being dragged through the vampires. Claudia screams.</context>
      <utterance>Death for the others. For you eternity in a box -</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The vampires grab Louis. They force him towards the coffin. Lestat struggles with them.</context>
      <utterance>Walled in a dungeon. Your only company will be your screams... Perhaps it will take centuries...</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's coming home with me - you promised -</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis struggles fiercely as he is forced into the coffin. Claudia weeps.</context>
      <utterance>We promised nothing!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis, struggling in the coffin. Then the lid is forced down, huge locks closed over it.</context>
      <utterance>They've fooled you, Lestat! You must reach Armand! Armand has the power!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Above him, reaching down to take his hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis gets out, into a vast long catacomb. Louis runs to the end of it, steps through a broken brick wall.</context>
      <utterance>Hurry. Don't make a sound.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is she? Where's Claudia?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to his cell at the end of the passage, the foot of the steps. Sound of rain beyond the door.</context>
      <utterance>Follow me - that way - through my cell -</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not without Claudia. Where is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't save her.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't believe I'd leave without her. Armand! You must save her! You have no choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis runs up the stone stairs. It leads to the ballroom. He enters. Estelle stands far off, looking at him coolly. She lifts the stage skull mask and laughs softly behind it. A male vampire slumps in a chair staring softly at Louis. Silence. Indifference. Louis sees Lestat sitting in a far corner. he rushes up to Lestat, who looks up at him, confused. He's holding something crumpled, made of cloth.</context>
      <utterance>Louis, I can't save her. I will only risk losing you -</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll come home with me Louis? For a little while... until I am myself again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I couldn't prevent it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe you. I do not have to read your soul to know that you lie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Louis, they cannot be brought back. There are some things that are impossible, even for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis climbs to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>You let them do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You held sway over them. They feared you. You wanted it to happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Louis, I swear I did not.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand you only too well. You let them do it, as I let Lestat turn a child into a demon. As I let her rip Lestat's heart to pieces! Well I am no longer that passive fool that has spun evil from evil till the web traps the one who made it. Your melancholy spirit of this century! I know what I must do. And I warn you - you saved me tonight, so I return the favor - do not go near your cell in the Theatre Des Vampires again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLOSEUP - CLOCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chiming five a.m.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looking at the paling sky. He is in an alleyway, outside of Armand's cell. He has a huge keg with him. he finds the door unlocked. He enters.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't even warm them, did you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And yet you knew what I would do.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the terrible dawn.</context>
      <utterance>I knew. I rescued you, didn't I?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were their leader. They trusted you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at Louis affectionately.</context>
      <utterance>You made me see their failings, Louis. You made me look at them with your eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your melancholy eyes...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a pair we are. We deserve each other, don't we?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARMAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Armand and Louis walk slowly through the Louvre together. Camera follows them for a while, then comes to rest on a sunrise by Turner.</context>
      <utterance>We are a pair, and that's what counts.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We left Paris shortly after. For years we wandered. Greece, Egypt, all the ancient lands. Then, out of curiosity, perhaps, boredom, who knows what, I took him home, to my America...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>On the screen, Murnau's "Sunrise", in black and white. We see a montage of sunrises, from a whole range of movies, in black and white.</context>
      <utterance>And there, a technological wonder allowed me see sunrise, for the first time in two hundred years...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what sunrises! Seen as the human eye could never see them. We would sit in the dark, night after night among nameless humans, entranced with the miracle of light. Silver at first, then as the years progressed in tones of purple, red and my long-lost blue... The SUNRISES continue, in color now, and the backgrounds in them change to the fifties.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The lights come up in a different theatre. Louis sitting there, alone, in a half empty theatre, dressed in the clothes of the fifties. He rises, exits with the others.</context>
      <utterance>And in time parted. We had become so alike, we both wanted the certainties of loneliness once more.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>CAMERA PANS OVER white-walled Lafayette cemetery and its surrounding mansions.</context>
      <utterance>And then on Prytania Street, only blocks from the Lafayette cemetery I caught the scent of death and it wasn't coming from the graves...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Louis sees rats darting across the street. They rush into a great overgrown garden surrounding a ruined mansion. No lights. Louis stops at a rusted gate. He forces it open and enters -</context>
      <utterance>The scent grew stronger as I walked. Old death. A scent too faint for mortals to detect.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Louis sees dead rats lying near the steps.</context>
      <utterance>They were like the doomed princess caught in the thorny vines of Sleeping Beauty's castle. I knew what it meant. A vampire had lured them here, but had been to weak to get rid of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Louis treads carefully on the rotted steps. he moves along the porch. More dead rats. He sees through the floor-length window into rooms lined with stacked books. Virtually walled with them. Water seeps down from the ceiling, gleaming as it streaks over the books. The floors of the splendid rooms are bare, except for a rotten French chair by a dead fireplace. A single mirror reflecting the moon. Dead rats. He moves along the porch to the parlor windows. The candle flickers inside. He sees -</context>
      <utterance>It spelt weakness, madness, the behavior of a dying animal that pollutes its own lair.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIS POV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>starvation. All his scars are gone, but he is almost a skeleton and his eyes are enormous in their sockets. His clothes are rags. Blond hair beautiful, as always.</context>
      <utterance>Lestat lying on the floor. He is gaunt to near</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lestat escaped the fire!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He hadn't even been there. And all those years I thought he was dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I've dreamed of your coming...</context>
      <utterance>I'm so glad you're here Louis...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't try to speak... it's alright...</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>that Santiago, he tricked me...</context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean to let them do it...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all past, Lestat.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and looks at Louis. Old, fearful, broken.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Past... she should never have been one of us...</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still beautiful Louis. You always were the strong one.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't fear me, Lestat. I bring you no harm.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis shakes his head. A series of police sirens go by, piercing the night sky. A helicopter goes overhead. Red flashes illuminate his face. Lestat shivers, covers his ears. He's terrified. Louis touches him, calming him, until the lights pass over.</context>
      <utterance>You've come back to me, Louis? You've come again to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's only a siren...</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't bear it Louis! The machines out there, that fly and that roar! And such lights! They make the night brighter than the day!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And they frighten you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know I love the dark. But there's no dark anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's false light, Lestat. It can't harm you...</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis shivers. He releases him.</context>
      <utterance>If you stayed with me Louis, I could venture out... little by little... become the old Lestat.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to go now Lestat...</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You remember how I was, Louis.. the vampire Lestat...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lestat shivers.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. I remember...</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tried to tell you Louis... that night in Paris... when I first came to you... no-one can refuse the dark gift, Louis... not even you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tried...</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the more you tried, the more I wanted you... a vampire with your beautiful, suffering human heart. And how you suffered... I need your forgiveness, Louis.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis walks slowly away from him. Lestat turns back to his candle, his magazine.</context>
      <utterance>You have it...</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A bluebottle buzzes by him. His hand shoots out and grabs it, squeezes the blood.</context>
      <utterance>You'll come back, Louis... take me out... little by little... and maybe I'll be myself again...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Lestat...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Empty.</context>
      <utterance>And my story ends there. But in fact it ended a long time ago, with Claudia's ashes in that theatre. My love died with her. I never really changed after that. What became of Lestat I have no idea. I go on, night after night. I feed on those who cross my path. But all my passion went with her yellow hair. I ma a spirit with preternatural flesh. Detached. unchangeable.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... it can't end like that...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it has. There is no more to tell.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you talk about passion, about longing, about things I'll never know in my life! It's still inside you, in every syllable you speak! And then you tell me it ends like that? Just empty?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's over, I'm telling you...</utterance>
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis looks at the cassettes on the table.</context>
      <utterance>You need a new passion, Louis, a new reason to feel... what a story you've told, you don't understand yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Malloy rises.</context>
      <utterance>Do what you want with it. Learn what you can. Give the story to others.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis is slowly horrified, then outraged and angry.</context>
      <utterance>You have another chance, Louis. Take me! Give me your gift, your power...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this what you want? You ask me for this after all I've told you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares at Louis.</context>
      <utterance>If I could see what you've seen, feel what you've felt I wouldn't let it end like this! You need a like to the world out there, a connection... then it won't end like this...</utterance>
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis turns away.</context>
      <utterance>You need me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dear God. I've failed again, haven't I?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at the boy. Then suddenly grabs him, lifts him off the floor, bares his terrifying fangs and brings them to his throat. Malloy screams, in involuntary terror.</context>
      <utterance>Don't say anymore. The reels are still turning. I have but one chance to show you the meaning of what I've said.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Malloy, now terrified, whispers</context>
      <utterance>You like it? You like being food for the immortals? You like dying? Is it beautiful? Is it intense?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis drops him.</context>
      <utterance>No... please...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Malloy, falls on the floor, terrified. When he looks up, Louis has vanished.</context>
      <utterance>Thank God.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Louis... Louis... He looks up at the tape. It is still turning.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shakes his head. He gets up, and with shaking fingers gathers his tapes. He runs out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>Holy shit...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>1791. That's when it happened. I was twenty-four. Younger then you are now. Suddenly a bony hand shoots out from the back seat, pulls his neck backwards -</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sinks his teeth in his neck.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>THE WHEEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Swinging free of Malloy's dying hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Veers wildly into oncoming traffic.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drinks regardless.</utterance>
   <speaker>A TRUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coming towards them, about to crush the car.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTAT'S BONY HAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grabs the wheel, jerks it as he drinks.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Misses the truck by inches.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
