<movie id="308" title="Into the Wild">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The figure with backpack and rifle, henceforth BACKPACK, stopping in his tracks, turns around in the direction of the truck.</context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>BACKPACK walks back to the truck. As he approaches the driver's door, we CUT IN TO: TIGHT SHOT over the back-packed shoulder onto the DRIVER.</context>
      <utterance>Come here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>We STAY on the DRIVER as BACKPACK speaks:</context>
      <utterance>You left your watch, your comb, your change...</utterance>
   <speaker>BACKPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want your money. And I already have a watch.</utterance>
   <speaker>BACKPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you don't take it, I'm gonna throw it away. I don't want to know what time it is, what day it is, or where I am.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BACKPACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The driver reaches behind the seat of the truck, pulls out an old pair of rubber work boots.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to see anybody. None of that matters.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a pause as Backpack considers accepting the boots.</context>
      <utterance>Take em.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>We can feel over Backpack's shoulder that he has taken the boots and is putting them on but we STAY on the driver.</context>
      <utterance>If you make it out alive, give me a call, and I'll tell you how to get the boots back to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BACKPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Backpack hands him an Instamatic camera and starts walking backwards. We PULL BACK with him. And he maintains his back to us. When he stops, we CONTINUE until he is FULL-FRAME, head-to-toe from behind, posing.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, do me a favor, will ya? Take a picture of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gonna be alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>BACKPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Backpack exits the frame, we SLOWLY ZOOM past the concerned face of the driver onto the loose change, the comb, and the watch on the dash.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be better than that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I say...Do what you are going to do, and I will tell about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who wrote that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands a book of Sharon Olds' poetry to her.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it could've been either one of us, couldn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a lot of great poems in there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris gives Carine a look. Walt extends his hand to Chris.</context>
      <utterance>You scared the daylights out of me, jumping on to that stage, oh my god.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all sit and pick up menus.</context>
      <utterance>Congratulations, son.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm starving.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My grades are gonna be good enough, I think, to get into Harvard Law.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a big deal. What do you have left in your college fund?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's an inheritance, dad. I've only been spending it as a college fund...Exactly twenty-four thousand five hundred dollars and sixty-eight cents.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's very specific.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had to go to the bank this morning.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>WALT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we'll certainly contribute the balance for Harvard.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I've got to figure out what I'm going to do. I got a lot of things to pack and organize here first.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so glad you're getting out of that place you're living. It was so much nicer when you lived on campus.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll come to Annandale before you disappear on us, won't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carine's not so sure.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, I will.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You promise?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, your father and I want to make a present to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We want to get you out of that junker.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Walt points outside to the Datsun.</context>
      <utterance>What's a junker?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Datsun?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. We want to get you a new car.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A new car? Why the hell would I want a new car? The Datsun runs great.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think I want some fancy boat? Or are you worried about what the neighbors might think?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We weren't going to get you a Cadillac, Chris. Just a nice new car that's safe to drive. You don't know when that thing's just going to suddenly blow up.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Under the table, Carine jabs Chris' leg. Chris returning to polite -</context>
      <utterance>Blow up? Blow up?! Are you guys crazy? It's a great car. I don't need a new car. I don't want a new car. I don't want anything. Thing, thing, thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, thanks anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything's gotta be difficult.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The group returns to some superficial calm.</context>
      <utterance>I said thank you. I just don't want anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't say no to a new car.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ivana Trump McCandless.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up, Chris.  Seriously, I'll pay you back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He indicates a hatchway in the floor leading to a brightly lit corridor below.</context>
      <utterance>This is Emory University freshman Chris McCandless reporting from the vault at Thompson Hall.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have just dynamited the hatchway and are the first human beings to step foot into this vault in over a hundred years. Somewhere in here lies the secret of the great beast within us all. A beast built on lies, corruption, and greed. We HEAR a GROWLING SOUND from behind Chris.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>CAMERA quickly PANS to a blanket-wrapped, crawling FELLOW STUDENT in a grotesque Halloween mask. We MOVE INTO CU on the monster growling. QUICK PAN back to Chris.</context>
      <utterance>And there it is! The legendary beast Mocra.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it looks like we've succeeded - We HEAR the monster's GROWL from above.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>We HEAR OS students commenting on Chris and his video crew:</context>
      <utterance>Once again, your humble reporter Chris McCandless.</utterance>
   <speaker>OS STUDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this? Filmmaking 101?</utterance>
   <speaker>OS STUDENT #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris speaking straight to camera, still tongue-in-cheek:</context>
      <utterance>Point the camera at me. I'm a star.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pay no attention to the voices behind the curtain.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TED TURNER/STUDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>McCandless, how many times have I had to tell you? I've had to tell you that you are a journalist and you can't get personally involved in your cases...or your stories.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ted! I know how to kill it. And I'm the only one who knows. You can't keep sending me on stories and expecting me to do nothing! I look like some kind of an idiot.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED TURNER/STUDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind Chris in the corridor outside Ted's office, a PANICKED STUDENT arrives at the door.</context>
      <utterance>Do you know who you're talking to? I'm Ted Turner.</utterance>
   <speaker>PANICKED STUDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He'll be out in no time.</context>
      <utterance>McCandless! You've got to hurry! The monster is scratching at the hatchway.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED TURNER/STUDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll mean your job, Chris McCandless.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the only thing that can kill the monster. It's gonna be risky but without great risk, there is no freedom. So we will now hear from the famous singer - Chris McCandless.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CARINE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Toward the end of June, Chris had mailed our parents his final grade report. Walt and Billie open the envelope.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARINE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>We observe Carine in a delicate afternoon light. She is sitting up on her bed with an unread book, looking out the window toward us.</context>
      <utterance>Almost all A's. "A" in Apartheid in South African Society and History of Anthropological Thought; A- in Contemporary African Politics and the Food Crisis in Africa; and on it went. Clever boy, my brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARINE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Carine's POV: Walt with his arm around Billie in the yard.</context>
      <utterance>But by the end of July we hadn't heard anything from him and my parents were getting very worried.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARINE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chris had never had a phone, so they decided to drive down to Atlanta and surprise him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARINE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We return to the image of Carine sitting on her bed as she plops on Chris' old graduation cap. We slowly ZOOM IN on her throughout the remaining V.O.</context>
      <utterance>Chris had instructed the post office to hold them until August 1st so that mom and dad wouldn't know that anything was up. Some part of me understood what he had done. That he had spent the previous four years fulfilling an absurd and onerous duty in graduating from college.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARINE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And now, at last he was unincumbered. Emancipated from the stifling world of parents and peers. Abstraction, security, and material excess. Those things that cut Chris off from the raw truth of his existence. I only hoped he was safe...and I missed him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FOREST RANGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now we see the FOREST RANGER appear from the thicket. Chris exits the tent, catching himself holding the knife.</context>
      <utterance>U.S. Forestry. Could you step out of the tent please?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. I thought you were a bear.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOREST RANGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't blame you. You're less than a hundred yards from the nearest den. That's why I came over here to talk to you. Do you have some identification?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I'm sorry. My name's Alex. I've been travelling a lot and I got robbed and my identification was taken.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOREST RANGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mind if I take a look in your tent?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Forest Ranger bends over. Pops his flashlight through the tent door and peers around a bit before re- addressing Chris.</context>
      <utterance>Go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOREST RANGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not the character who knocked down our sign, are ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOREST RANGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because there was a sign indicating that camping was allowed by permit only.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't have a permit.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOREST RANGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm sure you don't. Listen, it looks like you've got your food secured pretty good, so I'm not gonna make you move on tonight. But, these bears out here are nursing young and you know how that goes. Next time, stop at the Rangers station and get yourself a permit.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright. I appreciate it. I'm gonna be headed towards the coast tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOREST RANGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They shake hands and the Forest Ranger disappears into the thicket.</context>
      <utterance>Be careful.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is where I turn off.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris is dropped off. The driver veers off the highway and into the distance. Chris is left behind to hitch another ride.</context>
      <utterance>Alright man. Thanks a lot.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How're you doin' this evening?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm alright. What's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris does not oblige.</context>
      <utterance>You wanna put your backpack down on the hood of my car.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I asked you to, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I haven't done anything wrong. These are my personal items.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know that it's unlawful to hitchhike on this stretch of highway.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you see a safe area for a vehicle to stop? We got a tree-lined highway without a substantial shoulder here. And we've had a lot of accidents on this road from people stopping in the traffic lane for hitchhikers.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, but...I mean, you stopped your car. You're in the traffic lane. And you can see, there's hardly any cars out here. Plus, it's a straight road; you can see for a long ways.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's really been accidents along here?</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now Chris is worried.</context>
      <utterance>May I see some identification?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have any.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris shakes his head "No."</context>
      <utterance>You don't have any identification?</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Chris can't bring himself to lie.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm gonna site you for unlawful hitchhiking. You don't have to appear. You can send a check directly to the Humboldt County Clerks Office for restitution. If you don't pay it within 30 days, you're subject to fine and warrant. I'm gonna trust that you're gonna give me accurate information. What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>McCandless. Christopher Johnson McCandless.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. We just barely saw you there, under that crazy hat of yours. We couldn't back up - the van's reverse is broken.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. That's okay. Thanks for stopping.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with a little pulling, it opens. Indicating the pony- tailed and bearded driver (RAINEY), early 50's, definitely Woodstock...</context>
      <utterance>This door's a little tricky, I'll get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hop in, that's Rainey.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RAINEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I'm Rainey.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I'm Jan.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Rainey. Hi Jan. I'm Alex.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAINEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alex of the hat.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jan jumps back in passenger seat and the van rolls on.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RAINEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were you out there a long time hitching?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Couple of days. But sometimes I forget to put my thumb out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris checks himself in the rearview mirror and gets a kick out of what he sees (That hat's staying on.) Jan is looking at the rearview mirror too, observing Chris with mild concern.</context>
      <utterance>Probably, the rest of the time, that hat scares `em away.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Chris pulls out a bag of berries and edible plants he's collected.</context>
      <utterance>When's the last time you ate something?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jan steals a glance to Rainey. He's hip.</context>
      <utterance>See that? I've got this book and it shows you all the plants and berries that are edible. You can find things wherever you go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAINEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were just in town getting some beads and stuff. Jan does handicrafts, so we're usually going from one swap meet to another. She's so good at what she does, we sold everything. So, we set up camp at Orick Beach. You're welcome to camp there with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And eat there with us. Chris is beaming at the thought of real food.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, I just left the car. It was a great car too. I'd driven it cross country the first time when I got out of high school. I had some really great adventures with it. That thing would just go and go. I mean, it was an `82 but if I'd kept it, it would've lasted me forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAINEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, you're a leather now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rainey nods, smiling.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a leather?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's a leather?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a leather tramp. That's what they call the ones that hoof it on foot. So, we're technically rubber tramps.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>RAINEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rainey makes a move to put his arm around Jan. She goes a little stiff and fends it off. Chris notices.</context>
      <utterance>As we have a vee-hi-cle.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alex could have a vehicle. If he didn't burn his money. Why would you want to do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't need money. It makes people cautious.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you have to be a little cautious Alex. That book of yours is all well and fine but you can't depend entirely on leaves and berries.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know if you'd want to depend on much more than that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's your mom and dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Makin' their money somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on Chris. You look like a loved kid. Be fair.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fair?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll paraphrase Thoreau -- "Rather than love, than money, than fairness, give me truth."</utterance>
   <speaker>RAINEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all laugh.</context>
      <utterance>You look like shit. There's the truth.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Jan going?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAINEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris pulls out his pocketknife, cuts the twine that binds the firewood to his body, and takes a seat beside Rainey.</context>
      <utterance>Well, my friend, all is not well on the hippie front.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAINEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're an industrious little fucker, aren't ya... Yeah, it's funny how things happen at particular times. I've loved that woman for a lot of years. But you know, she's got a...story. We've been going through this thing real quietly cause, well...So, after running into you last night, this thing we were going through quietly, she started talking about. You know what I mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAINEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris is looking off at Jan walking in the distance.</context>
      <utterance>You think what?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think she's probably quietly disconnecting. It doesn't feel right to her to be close to you if there's a hole of some kind somewhere else.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAINEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a helluva insight. Jesus!... You're not Jesus, are you? You gonna walk on that water and get her back for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rainey gives him a sideways glance.</context>
      <utterance>Actually, I'm a little afraid of water.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's true. But it's something I've got to get over sometime.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, I'll swim in it if you'll carry the firewood back to the campsite.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAINEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that, Chris runs down the beach toward Jan. Rainey watches Chris and Jan chat briefly. Then they strip down to their underwear and jump into the ocean, splashing and laughing. ANGLE: Rainey. A warmth comes over him, watching his old lady having some fun. He grabs two armfuls of wood and heads to the campsite. ANGLE: Chris and Jan swimming in the chilly water, having a ball. Jan increasingly indulges herself a motherly closeness and joy with Chris. And Chris allows it. She pushes the stringy hairs from his eyes, worries when he descends below the surface for too many seconds, and smiles and laughs in tender relief when from below surface one of her toes is pulled on by the big fish Chris. As he re- surfaces, she gives him a splash right in the face.</context>
      <utterance>I'll carry. Shit-yes I'll carry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to go down the beach a ways and read a little bit. I'll bring the rest of that wood back before nightfall.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAINEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright. We might take a run into town to grab some food for tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He heads off down the beach.</context>
      <utterance>Sounds good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>RAINEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rainey takes a toke on the joint.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAINEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Rainey offers the joint to Chris. Chris passes it up with a hand gesture.</context>
      <utterance>You'd like that if you're still on the road. Lot of fellow travelers.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is that? The Slabs?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAINEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's down in Niland, California. You know where the Salton Sea is?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Near San Diego, yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAINEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well about 200 miles Northeast of there, but yeah. Niland's off the east shore of Salton. Wild place. The navy bulldozed and abandoned a base there. All that's left is a grid of concrete foundations. They're scattered over about a square mile or so.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When the weather turns cold across the rest of the country, people show up there by the thousands: snow birds...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAINEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drifters...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sundry vagabonds...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAINEY / JAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like ourselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Livin' on the cheap under the sun.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sell your handcrafts there?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah. And a lot of second-hand goods. There's a swap meet. The people are cool. There's even some kids running around sometimes. Most everyone there, if they're not avoiding the cold, are at least dodging the IRS.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAINEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three of them laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Or the FBI. CIA! DDT!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's good. You should check it out. If you come, I'll make a proper hat for you.  Well, Alex. I'm gonna clean up and the old man and I are gonna get some rest.  Looks like you got yourself a good bag there.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jan sees an almost imperceptible mother pang in Chris, but he pushes it away quickly.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah...my mother made it from a kit.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jan moves to Chris, hugs him, kisses him on the cheek.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna sleep out here by the fire. I want to read a little bit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're wonderful. Don't make me worry about you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He reminded me...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAINEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Go to WIDE SHOT: Jan and Rainey remaining as they were. FOREGROUND: Seagulls GLIDE THROUGH FRAME.</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, you and I have had our differences over the years...but on your birthday I want to tell you how grateful I am for all the things you've given me. And that you did it starting from nothing to working your way through college and busting your ass to support us kids. So, in return, I've been busting my ass a bit...at Domino's Pizza - Chris moves to the gift.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Chris holds the large gift toward Walt. Walt moves through his friends to Chris and strips the paper, exposing a beautiful Questar Telescope.</context>
      <utterance>and I've gotten you this token, this damned expensive token, as a token of that appreciation.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Walt holds the telescope up for all to see. And the party responds with applause. Chris walks through the cheering family friends to take his place beside Carine at the bottom of the steps.</context>
      <utterance>Would you look at that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, you must've had a lot to drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too much and not enough. I used to believe all that stuff. That whole story. I thought maybe if I said it again, I'd believe it. But I don't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Walt suddenly collapses to his knees weeping, heartbroken and ashamed on a quiet Annandale street in the shadowless light of dusk.</context>
      <utterance>He never did tell mom and dad that he knew. But Chris measured himself and those around him by an impossibly rigorous moral code. He loathed what he considered mom and dad's hypocrisy and resented what they considered guidance. Chris submitted to dad's authority through college but I knew he raged inwardly the whole time. It was inevitable that Chris would rebel. And when he did, he did it with characteristic immoderation.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARINE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father is a brilliant man. But he had made some terrible mistakes. And to some extent, it seemed Chris was making him pay an awful price. The image of Walt DISSOLVES INTO...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How're you doing? Wayne Westerberg.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi Wayne. Alex McCandless.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris nods with a laugh. Wayne continuing...</context>
      <utterance>Seems like every time I come on this road, there's somebody hitching out here who looks as skinny and unfed as you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Chris is not sure about the "drop something off" part.</context>
      <utterance>Look, I gotta stop in Ethridge to drop something off</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How `bout you and I grab something to eat down there?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I wouldn't want to burden you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long has it been since you've had anything to eat?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Couple of days. I kinda ran out of money.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wayne lights his cigarette, puts the truck in gear and they head down the road. As the sun dips behind the horizon we TILT UP off the departing truck to the sky. Ominously mounting clouds stunningly reflect the red rays of the hidden sun:</context>
      <utterance>Well, there's no choice about it. I'm gonna get you some dinner.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So where is it you're headed?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was thinking about doubling back through the Canadian side of Glacier Park.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I used to have a girlfriend who'd go there, camp on the Black Feet Res. She was into all that American Indian stuff.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can bring you to the border at Sweet Grass once you've had some food.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that'd be great. What do you do out here?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I do a lot of things. Computer programming. Video game repair. I'm a licensed pilot, own a grain elevator in Carthage and another one a few miles out of town. But in the summertime I run a combine crew, follow the harvest from Texas way the hell north to the Canadian border. We just got done cutting barley for Coors and Anheuser Busch. But then I got this little black box deal on the side</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean those free satellite TV deals?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris is dazzled by this renaissance man of the plains. Wayne stands to dish out a couple of plates of heated food. As Chris starts digging in, a major gust of wind rocks the trailer.</context>
      <utterance>You said it, not me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wayne gets a little giggle.</context>
      <utterance>Who are these guys?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those are my Hudderites. Agriculture's a pretty transient business. These guys come off the Hudderite colony looking for work. I always got work for people. Then that guy -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Kevin. He's with me most of the time. He's not a Hudderite. He's from Madison.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, the rain kicks in full gear outside, pounding the trailer shell. A couple hits of lightning follow.</context>
      <utterance>Madison. Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris looks about. There's not much room but it beats the pelting outside.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, you don't want to go out there on the road tonight. Why don't you just roll your sleeping bag out and play like a Hudderite until morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks Wayne. I will.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S</mode>
      <context>As Chris makes the attempt, we immediately hear the grinding of gears, the instrument alarms in chaos. WIDE SHOT: Chris and Wayne sit atop a combine. In the background we see Wayne's trailer and two other combines piloted by Wayne's crew members on the ocean of ripe blond grain. Chris tries his hand at the shifter once more. This time the thing starts to move.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Now take hold of the joystick, get the feel of header, idle it down with the toggle switch...</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Wayne jumps off the combine and Chris begins to cut his pattern, intermittently struggling with the shifter. Wayne laughs his ass off.</context>
      <utterance>That's it. That's it. Now take it on out and make yourself some money.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna break out some whiskey. Alex, you want anything other than that beer?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The group of men laugh at the youngster's order of a fancy drink.</context>
      <utterance>I'd take a White Russian if you've got it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you Alex, a Commie?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I just like White Russians.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't got anything like that here. But I tell ya what. And I know I speak for everybody. You wanna come work with us in Carthage, we'll hook you up on the grain elevator and get you a White Russian down at the Cabaret.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dawn tomorrow, engines roaring.  "Pot o Gold. Oh that pot o gold." They all join in to the chant/song:</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Pot o Gold. Gotta get that pot o gold!"</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To Carthage.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE AND HIS MEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To Carthage.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay Kevin, get all the machines back to the elevator. I'm gonna show Chris to his room.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEVIN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got dibs on that shower, that shower's all me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wayne signs off and veers off the road.</context>
      <utterance>First come, first serve buddy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wayne gives Chris a wink and exits, shutting the door behind him. Chris takes in his new surroundings. He's on a work crew and he likes it. Chris makes the move for the shower but by the time he opens his door to the hall, all the other crew members are barreling up the stairs in front of them, clamoring for dibs (Chris' POV)</context>
      <utterance>Shower's down the hall. If you hurry you can beat the rest of the boys to it. But you do want to grab a shower cause we're all heading over to the Cabaret in exactly thirty-six minutes. So, get your dancing shoes on. There's foo-foo in the medicine cabinet. I think it's Brut.  Then you want to put your charm in overdrive cause we like to PAH-TAY!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got first!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You had first last night!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if you wanna wash my back, cowboy...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You go ahead, fairy. Just don't use all the soap.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alex, this is Gail . This is the one to go to for that White Russian you've been wanting. Of course the quid pro quo can be hazardous.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up, Wayne.  You want a White Russian, sweetie?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes please, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wayne slaps Chris on the back.</context>
      <utterance>Yes please, ma'am?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't he great?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE: KEVIN. He looks every bit the Grizzly Adams part.</context>
      <utterance>Anything to do with hunting, preserving the meat, smoking it or whatever, you talk to Kevin over there. That's your man.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Outdoors-man. What's the interest in all that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm thinking about going to Alaska.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alaska, Alaska? Or city Alaska? The city Alaska does have markets.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Alaska, Alaska. I want to be all the way out there. On my own. No map. No watch. No axe. Just out there. Big mountains, rivers, sky. Game. Just be out there in it. In the wild.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the wild.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Maybe write a book about my travels. About getting out of this sick society.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Society, right.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because you know what I don't understand? I don't understand why, why people are so bad to each other, so often. It just doesn't make any sense to me. Judgement. Control. All that.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who "people" we talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Politicians and pricks.</context>
      <utterance>You know, parents and hypocrites.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a mistake. It's a mistake to get too deep into that kind of stuff. Alex, you're a helluva young guy, but I promise you this: You're a young guy. Blood and fire! You're juggling blood and fire!</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you to be giving advice to anybody?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gail pushes him off with mock disgust.</context>
      <utterance>Blood and fire...What? Mr. Happy. That's who I am. Gimme a kiss.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>On the television above the bar appears Reverend Jesse Jackson. We can't hear him but we can see him. Chris points at the television and yells out to the entire bar of cowboys and ranch hands -</context>
      <utterance>Come on, give Mr. Happy a kiss!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wayne buries his face in his hands.</context>
      <utterance>Now, that's who could be President!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(The working life)</context>
      <utterance>So, what do you think about all this?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like all this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris' POV: from high in the grain elevator. He watches Wayne below, as Wayne saunters out to the field to take a piss. With his back to us, Wayne whips it out and starts pissing about 25 yards from the grain elevator. CU Wayne. He looks up from his urination, the grain elevator behind him. We see a slight mischievous smile come to his face. He puts his hands up into the air when suddenly - Six unmarked FBI vehicles surround him. (Director's note: Triangulate three long lenses on Wayne as the mysterious cars enter each frame, as they skid to a dusty stop on all sides of him.) Chris and the men of his crew look on.</context>
      <utterance>I gotta take a piss.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Wayne is handcuffed and led away, he nods up to his boys.</context>
      <utterance>I warned him about those little black boxes.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna get that zipper for me?  Sorry boys. Gonna have to shut down for a while. Alex! You come back and work for me anytime.  Gail's got all your checks, guys. I shouldn't be away too long. With that, the FBI agents have hustled the good-natured Wayne into the back of one of the cars.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been thinking a lot about Alaska.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alaska? What kind of nut-nut are you? Alex, it's October for Christ's sake. You go to Alaska, you go in the Spring. This time of year you wanna head south. Personally, I like Las Vegas. One-armed bandit. That's what I like.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, maybe I ought to put off going to Alaska, at least so I can get settled up there in decent weather.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>South. You want to go south. You want me to take you out to the highway?</utterance>
   <speaker>GAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You take care of yourself now, Alex. You got a whole family here depending on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives her a kiss on the cheek and he's off.</context>
      <utterance>I will. Thanks Gail . And tell Wayne, I'll drop him a line.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>GREEN SUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. If I wanted to paddle down the river, where's the best place to launch out of?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREEN SUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"To launch out of?" What's your experience level?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not much.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREEN SUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any? Do you have a permit?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A permit for what?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREEN SUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't paddle down the river without a permit. If you like, you can apply for one here, get yourself some experience, and I'll put you on the wait-list.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait-list? To paddle down a river?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREEN SUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, how long do you have to wait?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREEN SUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got an opening May 2003.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twelve years?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREEN SUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you could always join a commercial raft trip and go with a licensed guide. They usually have a few last minute cancellations. I think it's about two- thousand dollars. Chris busts a gut.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Green Suit eyes Chris' departure with suspicion.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for your help.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MADS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris doesn't know quite what to do. But Mads seems quite comfortable inviting a stranger into the presence of his topless girlfriend.</context>
      <utterance>You can join us!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MADS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Chris - can't turn that down! He paddles to within feet of the water's edge.</context>
      <utterance>We have hotdogs!</utterance>
   <speaker>MADS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am Mads.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. Alex.</utterance>
   <speaker>SONJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris gives Sonja a little wave. She bypasses it, wading up to the Kayak, giving him a big hug.</context>
      <utterance>I am Sonja.</utterance>
   <speaker>SONJA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>This couple is extremely energetic. Can't wait to please. And a bona fide American adventurer in their midst. It's everything they could've wanted.</context>
      <utterance>Hello Alex.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are from Copenhagen. And you are from the rapids.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>SONJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My Got!</utterance>
   <speaker>MADS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mads grabs a hotdog from the Hibachi.</context>
      <utterance>Crazy man. You're a crazy man! Sonja, he is a crazy man.  I'll make you a hotdog.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Sonja has moved to the tent to put on a dry T-shirt. But as she moves back to the water's edge, those nipples keep saying Hello. Chris, meanwhile, simply cannot wipe the smile off his face in the presence of these warm, open people.</context>
      <utterance>Just one minute. One minute...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MADS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love this. Don't you love this? This is nature. We see it in the American movies. How come you're crazy?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well...</utterance>
   <speaker>MADS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mustard and relish?</context>
      <utterance>Because that's crazy! You come down the rapids. What do you want on your hotdog?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have ketchup?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I have mustard and relish.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mustard and relish it is then.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sonja, you want a hotdog?</utterance>
   <speaker>SONJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mads plops two more hotdogs onto the grill.</context>
      <utterance>Of course I want a hotdog. Why are you stupid?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She asked me why I'm stupid. And I say, well...like I ask you why you're crazy and you say "well." Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't decided.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We like it here very much. We went to Los Angeles. And then, we went to Las Vegas.</utterance>
   <speaker>SONJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Las Vegas is very nice. The universe is very good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MADS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Chris likes the idea.</context>
      <utterance>You can take kayak around Lake Mead and then take the river down to Mexico.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How far are we from Lake Mead?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sonja grabs a map from the tent, opens and scrutinizes it. We follow her finger tracing the river.</context>
      <utterance>Sonja, how far is Hoover Dam?</utterance>
   <speaker>SONJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>kilometers...like two hundred miles. Sonja walks the map over to Chris at water's edge and hands it to him. He studies it.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe three hundred thirty</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris traces his finger along the impossibly long route leading to El Golfo de Santa Clara.</context>
      <utterance>Man, I wonder if I could go all the way down into the Gulf of California.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I go with you. We leave Sonja here. You and me in kayak - we go to Mexico.</utterance>
   <speaker>SONJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mads with a burst of re-exhilaration, grabs Chris' hand, shaking it violently.</context>
      <utterance>You're embarrassing. Idiot.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like the meeting you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sonja heads back for her hotdog taking her T-shirt off on the move. Chris is about to bust a gut. Sonja returns to her sunbathing. These two are a hoot.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you. I'm very happy to meet both of you too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MADS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And miraculously, the river patrol makes an about face and heads in the opposite direction of Chris. Suddenly Sonja thinks Mads is the most clever man on earth. As she jumps his bones right there on the river's edge -</context>
      <utterance>He went thattaway! The crazy man - he went thattaway!</utterance>
   <speaker>SONJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just like in the movies.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CARINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When he was four years old...</context>
      <utterance>But why he didn't send a letter, maybe through a friend. I got mad. But I told myself it was good. It made me remember that there was something more than rebellion, more than anger that was driving him. Chris had always been driven, had always been an adventurer.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...he once wandered six blocks away from home at three o'clock in the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was found in a neighbor's kitchen, up on a chair, digging into their candy drawer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THINK OF YOU AS A FRIEND...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Continue letter on screen:</context>
      <utterance>Chris licks the stamp.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOD BLESS YOU, ALEXANDER.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The stamp comes down onto an envelope addressed:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>IMMIGRATION OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why'd you go to Mexico?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought I'd run the whole river into the Sea of Cortez. The stupid dams dried it up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>IMMIGRATION OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long were you on your own down there?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>36 days.</utterance>
   <speaker>IMMIGRATION OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We see Chris' fingers and toes. (DOWN ANGLE into interrogation room)</context>
      <utterance>Fingers and toes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After the river dried up, I ported the kayak and got a lift to Golfo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SOCIAL WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you lose your identification sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOCIAL WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris shakes his head apologetically.</context>
      <utterance>No birth certificate? Nothing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOCIAL WORKER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The social worker begins to write an address on a piece of paper.</context>
      <utterance>Ouch. Alright. Well you're gonna have to work that out with the DMV. You can catch them in the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOCIAL WORKER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The closest one is Montebello and we can help you with a bus voucher. She hands the Montebello address to Chris.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOCIAL WORKER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, just come to this desk when you need the voucher.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And, if I want to apply for a job somewhere, can you help me with that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOCIAL WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you know how to cook, we might have a space for you in our mobile kitchen. But I'll have to talk to my supervisor about it in the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright then. Thank you. Oh, one last thing. Do you have a bed for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOCIAL WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris begins filling in the form.</context>
      <utterance>Sure. Just fill this in and I'll get you all set up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BULL #2</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The bull shines a flashlight into Chris' eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Let me see your face.</utterance>
   <speaker>BULL #2</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Chris is trying to understand what the man is saying.</context>
      <utterance>I never, ever, ever forget a face. If I see yours again, I won't arrest you. I'll kill you. This is the god-damned railroad. And we will do whatever we have to, to keep you freeloaders from violating our liability.</utterance>
   <speaker>BULL #2</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If one of you people gets hurt on our train, we are liable. Do you understand that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>BULL #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have I.D.?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>BULL #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course you don't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He closes the door and the car drives off. We follow Chris as he goes to the overpass edge. He drops his pack over the side. Chris climbs down the edge of the overpass, grabs his pack, and scurries into the UNDERPASS below. (We suddenly recognize this as his pre-river run campsite) He digs up his buried belongings, returning them to his pack. Last to come out of the ground, Chris' copy of Jack London's Call of the Wild. He pulls off a temp wrapping and dusts it off. Chris lights his candle lantern and begins to read. O.S. VOICES from the PAST:</context>
      <utterance>Thanks very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLIE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Feet stomping off.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not talking about this anymore!</utterance>
   <speaker>WALT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't walk away from me WOMAN!</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLIE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Sounds of scuffle.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you! I hate you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WALT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Billie returns to him, punching on his chest:</context>
      <utterance>I'll just cancel Christmas then!</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who do you think you are? God?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris puts his hand out to Carine. She looks up to him. He gives her a smile and a wink. She takes his hand and they exit frame as the argument continues.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. I'm God!</utterance>
   <speaker>WALT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do you kids think you're going?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLIE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>We HEAR a DOOR SLAM OC.</context>
      <utterance>Kids, get back here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who do you think you are? God?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I'm God.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see Billie driving out of the Annandale supermarket onto the boulevard. She sees a hitchhiker roadside. She cranes her head - is it Chris? It's not.</context>
      <utterance>But instead when I open my eyes, what I see is my mother, sitting at the dining room table, sifting through photo albums and pictures of Chris. It's all she can do to examine the snapshots. And, though she breaks down from time to time, she studies them with a sort of hungry intensity - like looking at food you can't eat, or into a window at a family around a table that you were once a part of and can be no more.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARINE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She convinces herself it's Chris; that it's her son, whenever she passes a stray. And I fear for the mother in her...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TRUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know where to drop you. Bullhead's kinda haphazard - there's no "center." You sure you don't want to be in Laughlin? It's casinos versus chiropractors.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, no. This is good. Right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls over. Chris grabs his pack and exits the truck in front of a laundromat. As the truck pulls away, Chris sees a "Help Wanted" sign for Burger King on the laundromat window.</context>
      <utterance>Alright then. Chiropractors it is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chris, you gotta go faster. We've got a line out the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But then just continues on at his leisurely daydreaming pace. Lori is about to say something but by now she knows there's no getting through to him. She looks down to the floor where we see that Chris wears no socks.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chris, I don't mean to be on you about everything. You're doing a great job.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LORI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to keep you on. And we all want to help you get to Alaska, but you've got to start wearing socks.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right, right. I forgot.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And please. Hurry. We're ten deep.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the pace remains.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much do I have in the account now?</utterance>
   <speaker>TELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It looks like...let me see. Including this latest deposit...One thousand, two hundred and fifty two dollars and...twenty-two cents.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the interest on twenty-two cents? The young teller giggles.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lori, I'm punching out.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Just put it in the drop.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I mean I'm punching out for good.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've made our quota, have we?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Also, I've got to do some things before I head north.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright Chris. Well, we've enjoyed knowing you. I won't be able to get that last check to you right away though.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's okay. I'll let you know where to send it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright then Chris. Bye-bye now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Sunni has sniffed out Chris' large backpack leaning against the rear of the van. Jan is just beginning to recognize it, when from behind the van appears Chris, looking like a million bucks.</context>
      <utterance>Sunni! Come here boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Surprise!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE: Rainey hearing his name, jumps up from his stool to join them. Big embraces all around.</context>
      <utterance>Alex! As she goes to hug him -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you've made yourself a friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's only a teenager.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girl finishes her song.</context>
      <utterance>Good luck.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAINEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long can you stay with us?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm waiting on a check from my last job to come into Salton City the day after Christmas. I've got to start thinking about getting ready for Alaska. When the sun gets a little lower tonight, I'm going to start a calisthenics routine. I think after the check comes in, I'll try to find some mountains I can climb everyday till spring comes. I gotta see how far the money's gonna go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to have to pick up a lot of supplies before spring. So, I might take another job or I might be okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAINEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you know, we'll give you a little something for every day you work the booth.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not taking any money from you, Rainey. It's been a real great twist meeting you two. You look like you're doing good.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAINEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris looks up from his book to the wide open 16-year old smile of Tracy. Rainey laughs aloud. Chris smiles back, and against his better instincts, gives her a little wave- over with the paperback. Tracy jumps off her step, putting her guitar inside the rig, and trots like a little wood nymph to Chris.</context>
      <utterance>We are, and you were a big part of that, coming along when you did. Yep, things are good.  Man, I used to think Tantric sex was just a bunch of reading. Speaking of which, don't you think you ought to introduce yourself to Joni Mitchell over there?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You selling books?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am. We are.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I read a lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's good. I heard you play your song last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rainey amused by all of this.</context>
      <utterance>I'm terrible.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are not terrible.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You sing sweet.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. I was going to go watch the kids play in the mud. Do you want to go?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAINEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go on. I'll watch the store.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whoops, a slip on the name, but...</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. This is Rainey. And I'm Chris.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAINEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. Rainey. And this is Alex.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris realizes his slip but before Rainey can question anything, Chris stands and goes off with Tracy. Rainey and Jan share a conspiratorial smile.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Tracy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wasn't much older than Tracy when I got pregnant. And I thought my husband and I were going to invent peace on earth and stay together forever. But it didn't work out that way. He left. History. Now ancient history. And that was the end of that. So, I raised Reno by myself - that's my son. Then I met Rainey. And that was really good for a while. But Reno was already a teenager and was becoming a man in his own way. And then, I don't know. He kinda followed in his father's footsteps - out the door and gone. And I really don't know where he is. I haven't heard from him in two years.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jan looks into Chris' eyes and smiles with pure love. She leans over and gently kisses Chris on the cheek.</context>
      <utterance>I hope I get to meet him sometime.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris aims to deflect the question as Tracy enters the scene.</context>
      <utterance>Do your folks know where you are?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soup's on. Oh, I'm sorry. Are you guys getting heavy?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sweetheart. Just hungry. You've been doing a fantastic job over there.  Shall we eat?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tracy grabs Chris' hand and proudly leads him to supper. As they exit frame, we remain for a moment with Jan and her thoughts.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAINEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I really ought to get myself doing that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should Rainey. Makes that Tantric stuff go even better.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>RAINEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They share a laugh. Chris comes to the end of his sit- ups. Wipes his brow with a towel. Rainey squats down next to him.</context>
      <utterance>How the hell would you know? That poor girl over there is about ready to vault onto a fence post. And here you are, the monk of Jack LaLane.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAINEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The connection is not lost on Chris.</context>
      <utterance>I guess Jan filled you in. About Reno and everything. Children can be harsh judges when it comes to their parents. They don't grant clemency easily. I think Reno tended to see things in black and white. I just hope he lives long enough to forgive her.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAINEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But painful as it is, you turned a light on in her and I'm grateful.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me too.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAINEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris doesn't answer. A kid rides by on a bright new Big Wheel. Must be from the rich side of the commune.</context>
      <utterance>For what?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAINEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do your folks know where you are?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAINEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you think they ought to?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They should. But I can't. Not yet, anyway. I got a sister though, Carine. She's the most beautiful girl in the world. But, it's all got to stay behind me until I get where I'm going.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAINEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alaska?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello? Merry Christmas?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>As Chris mounts the steps, he finds Tracy laying on the bed inside, wearing a skimpy white girl's tank top and underpants.</context>
      <utterance>Come in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guess what.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My parents went into town.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, they did. They went to call my grandma for Christmas.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I mean, no, we can't do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris moves to sit on the edge of her bed. Tracy sits up beside him.</context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How old are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris throws her a look of doubt.</context>
      <utterance>Eighteen.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seventeen.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As soon as she has to think about it, the jig is up.</context>
      <utterance>What year were you born?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Shyly, she shakes her head "yes."</context>
      <utterance>You want to do something together?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can always get in touch with me by sending mail here. I don't know when I'll get it, but I'll get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're pretty magic.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hugs her. And kisses her. (cheek, lips? I don't know.) Jan pulls up in the van. Rainey walks over to Chris and gives him a paternal hug.</context>
      <utterance>I am?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAINEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You take care of yourself, kiddo.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris gives Rainey's gut a full-hand pinch.</context>
      <utterance>You too, Rainey. Thanks for everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Rainey gives him a wink and puts his arm around Tracy as Chris jumps into the car. Then he and Jan hit the road.</context>
      <utterance>New Year's resolution?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey boy. You are a handsome fellow.  Beautiful dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the girl continues on, the dog wants to stay with Chris.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he sorts through the various rice selections, brown, white, wild, we notice a MAN peering over the opposite shelf at Chris. This is RON FRANZ, between 70 and 80 years old, six-feet, thick arms, barrel chest, and large ears. He wears old jeans, an immaculate white T-shirt, a decorative tooled leather belt, white socks, and scuffed black loafers. His deeply pitted nose demonstrates a purple filigree of veins which unfold like an finely wrought tattoo. And on either side of it, the wary blue eyes of a soldier. He is the archetypical American man. Chris has caught his sympathetic eye. Chris moves to the counter to pay for rice.</context>
      <utterance>Go on, boy. Go on. And the dog obeys him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's your camp?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out past Oh-My-God Hot Springs.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ron leans across the bench seat of the truck, opening up the passenger door.</context>
      <utterance>I've lived in and around here six years now and I've never heard of any place that goes by that name.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Chris hops in beside Ron, who extends his hand -</context>
      <utterance>Show me how to get there.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ron Franz.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alex.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alex. Where are you from Alex?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>West Virginia.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris remembers now the dog in the store and why Ron must've thought to give him a ride. And they head off.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, Alex from West Virginia. I like a fellow who doesn't raise the pitch of his voice when he talks to animals...shows he doesn't condescend.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You live here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, we keep going. I'm further up. Another half-mile or so, out on the Bajada.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, this is somethin' out here. Don't you worry about those dope smokers and nudists down below there?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, they keep to themselves pretty much and so do I.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmmm. You strike me as a bright young man. Am I wrong about that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I got my head on my shoulders pretty good.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I mean. How long have you been out here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Couple of weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And before that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A lot of places. I've been moving around.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How old are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty-three.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty-three years old! Son, don't you think you should be getting an education? And a job? And making something of this life?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look Mr. Franz. I think careers are a twentieth century invention and I don't want one. You don't need to worry about me. I have a college education. I'm not destitute. I'm living like this by choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the dirt?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, in the dirt.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just don't know. Where's your family?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't have one anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris can see some deep sadness in this man.</context>
      <utterance>That's a shame.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ron follows Chris to the rockface we'd seen Chris running earlier. They begin to walk up it. It's tough on the old-timer, walking this steep hill. But he's a tough old- timer, at least for the moment... ANGLE: The two men nearly half way to the summit. It's getting steeper and higher. Ron stops.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Mr. Franz. I want to show you something.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is getting a little steep. And a little high for me kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their POV: Enormous beautiful vista all the way across the Bajada.</context>
      <utterance>Alright. But look out there. Even from half way out, it's quite a sight isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ron looks up the precarious rock wall. He ain't gonna be seeing the Salton Sea today.</context>
      <utterance>From the top you can see all the way to the Salton Sea too.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can see the Salton Sea from up there?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My goodness.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't want to go up?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris smiles and follows Ron. As they approach the bottom of the hill -</context>
      <utterance>Nope. I don't do these kind of things.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about you and me take a drive? About fifty miles or so up highway, I know a place that's got a view, great food, and requires no climbing. How's that sound? Chris thinks about it. Then -</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, sure. It'll take me a couple of minutes to clean up.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fair enough.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How old are you, Mr. Franz?</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seventy-nine years old.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seventy-nine...see, all due respect, but the real difference between people is the quality of their soul and not on how long they've trudged around like a dip-shit. Ron laughs.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it's true.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ron continues to let Chris vent.</context>
      <utterance>It is. No question about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The government's the same as my parents. They don't respect anybody. Regulation. Regulation. Regulation. WE can't do this. But THEY can do that. I mean, the hypocrisy of the whole...culture. Makes me crazy. My father was having children with two women at the same time, and then has the gall to think that he can be of some guidance to me? Make judgments on me? My mother, of course, goes along with all of it. Keeps the secret, which of course, makes my whole life a fiction. Everything I thought was, wasn't. They're such fools! Fucking idiots!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alex, please don't lump me in amongst your judges. And your tyrants. But I'd prefer to not hear that kind of language.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris smiles at Ron.</context>
      <utterance>You got a lot of passion, young man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thank you.</context>
      <utterance>Awww, that was a great time Mr. Franz.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look here. If Charles Manson and his buddies don't kill me on my way out of here, I'd like to cook you up a home cooked meal tomorrow night. If I come out here about, say, four o'clock tomorrow, how would that be?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ron is thrilled.</context>
      <utterance>That would be swell.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good, good. I'm no gourmet but I know where the spices are. Good night, kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good night Mr. Franz.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you find everything you need?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a lot of grime in that stuff.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I hope I don't wreck your machine.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's what it's for. How do these steaks look? Ron pops the steaks on the kitchen table.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ron grabs some silverware from a drawer, plops it down on the kitchen table with some paper napkins.</context>
      <utterance>Well, sit down.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a White Russian?</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nope.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beer?</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nope. Don't have any alcohol. I had to quit all that. How about a guava juice?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Ron gets the drinks -</context>
      <utterance>I'll take a guava juice, that sounds good.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I had a little spell with the bottle, you could say.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RON/CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cheers.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ron, spinning his body around, points to the photographs over the sink.</context>
      <utterance>I spent most of my life in the army. On New Year's Eve 1957, I was stationed over in Okinawa. My wife and son were here in the States, just driving down the road when a fellow who'd had too much to drink plowed right into them. Killed them both. Anyway, you might think that the last thing in the world I'd do, is go to the whiskey, but at the time, it felt like the only thing I could do. And I did it hard. But pretty soon, I figured I wasn't doing my wife and son any good, mourning them with a bottle. So, I pulled myself together and quit drinking, cold turkey. And then...</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see all these kids over here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I was gonna ask you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For the last picture frame, Ron stands and takes it off the shelf -</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that's...  Fuki, Kenjiro, Yoshiko, Keiko, Masaro, Junichi, Kimpei, Nayoko...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I unofficially adopted all of them. It did my heart some good but I guess really it was just writing a few letters and sending some money. Anyway, it was important to me. I get a letter from each of them from time to time. You know. So, since all that, this is pretty much me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you ever travel, Mr. Franz?</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I can't seem to get too far from my leather. I'll show you after you finish eating. I do a lot of leather engraving. I got a little workshop in the garage. Between that and my pension, I do pretty well. But every time I think I might take a trip somewhere, I get too far behind on orders and such to consider it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm finished eating. I'd love to see your workshop.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris nods.</context>
      <utterance>Would ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ron picks up the picture of Akira and replaces it on the shelf above the sink.</context>
      <utterance>Alright then.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode>O.S</mode>
      <context>Chris turns to the voice. And down at the bottom of the rock wall beside the campsite, is Ron holding up two fishing poles.</context>
      <utterance>How about some fishing?</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Chris has barely the breath to speak.</context>
      <utterance>That thing's twice as salty as the ocean. Did you know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ron shrugs his shoulders in a "who cares?" fashion. Chris laughs but nods in the affirmative and gives Ron the thumbs up.</context>
      <utterance>Anything alive in it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the N stand for?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...North.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris summits.</context>
      <utterance>Alaska?</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son, what the hell you running from?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Except I already know the answer.</context>
      <utterance>I could ask you the same question.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ron waves him off.</context>
      <utterance>I do, Mr. Franz. You've got to get back out in the world. Get out of that lonely house of yours, that little workshop, and go live on the road.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really. You're going to live a long time, Ron. You should make a radical change in your lifestyle. The core of man's spirit comes with new experiences. And there you are, stubborn old man, sitting on your butt.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ron gets up off the tailgate.</context>
      <utterance>Sittin' on my butt, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>And Ron starts making the old man hustle. Shifty shoulders and all, up the stone wall.</context>
      <utterance>I'll show you sittin' on my butt.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Stubborn old man." Chris is laughing and clapping.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, old man! Come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris is jumping up and down, thrilled for Ron's efforts. Now the old man's shuffle has turned into an old man's walk. But he ain't stopping. And bit by bit he shows he's got it in him after all. As Ron is just about to mount the summit, Chris extends a hand. Ron swats it away.</context>
      <utterance>Ya little pinhead.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ron drops down onto his back to catch his breath and let his thumping heart slow down.</context>
      <utterance>Ya little pinhead.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ron, after taking one more deep breath, sits up and Chris sits next to him. He's actually pretty happy with himself. He looks out and sees the distant Salton Sea.</context>
      <utterance>You alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to miss you when you go.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll miss you too, Ron. But you're wrong if you think the joy of life comes principally from human relationships. God's placed it all around us. It's in everything. In anything we can experience. People just have to change the way they think about those things. You ought to put a little camper on the back of your pick-up and go take a look at some of the great work god's done out here in the American west.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alex...You're probably right. And I'm going to take stock of that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>116.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chris offers a skeptical glance.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A second skeptical glance. Which Ron squashes with genuine sincerity.</context>
      <utterance>No, I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Chris buys it this time and feels he's accomplished something with Ron.</context>
      <utterance>I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Miraculously, it is just at that moment that the cloud clears from the sun and the light shines in Ron's eyes. Chris points at Ron's face at the light shining on him -</context>
      <utterance>But I'll tell you something. The bits and pieces I've put together, you know, what you've told me about your family. Your mother and dad. And I know you got your problems with the church too, but there's some kind of bigger thing that we can all appreciate. And it sounds like you don't mind calling it God. But when you forgive, you love. And when you love...God's light shines on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy Shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men, their eyes welling up, fall back laughing. EXTREME WIDE SHOT FROM BELOW: The two men on the summit with the echoing of laughter and Ron's screams -</context>
      <utterance>I told you about that language.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you so! I told you so!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>117.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ron appears in the doorway dressed for travel.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing up? It's three-thirty in the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris says nothing.</context>
      <utterance>Heard you get up off the couch half an hour ago, and had a funny feeling you might not be here for our breakfast.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to drive you a hundred miles to somewhere where you can pick up a train, a plane, or hitch a ride without getting stuck on this desert. I'd take you all the way to Alaska if I didn't have to get to an eight o'clock mass.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ron, you don't have to do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to do it. Get you started on this thing of yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On my Great -</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a machete, an arctic parka, collapsible fishing pole, and a few odds and ends I threw in there for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ron...</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris does, nodding his thanks.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, just take it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well my friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both of them are uncomfortable. Chris goes for the door handle. Ron's gnarled hand reaches out to take Chris' elbow. After a long beat, Ron speaks without looking at Chris.</context>
      <utterance>Yep.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This takes Chris by surprise. He knew it would be hard but not this hard.</context>
      <utterance>I had an idea. You know my mother was an only child. So was my father. And I was their only child. Now, with my own boy gone, I'm the end of the line. When I'm gone, my family will be finished. What do you say, you let me adopt you. I could be, say, your grandfather.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about we talk about this when I get back from Alaska, Ron. Would that be alright?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>119.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Silence. Ron nods. Releases Chris' elbow.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, Ron. We'll talk about it then.</utterance>
   <speaker>RON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep. We can do that, yep.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ron nods. Chris gets out of the truck. Ron watches as Chris saddles up his bag including the duffel that Ron gave him. Chris crosses the exit junction to where he can pick up a ride north on the far side of the road. We ZOOM SLOWLY through the windshield into Ron's face as he watches Chris hitching away. We HEAR the first bars of Neil Young's My My, Hey Hey. This will carry throughout the following MONTAGE.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Ron.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARINE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Carine, packing her belongings into boxes, stumbles upon the Sharon Olds book Chris had given her on his graduation day.</context>
      <utterance>About a month short of the second anniversary of Chris' disappearance, I had gotten engaged to my boyfriend Jerry Ray and was moving in with him...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARINE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>FLASH BACK: (From page 2-3)</context>
      <utterance>...when I stumbled upon the book Chris had given me on his graduation day. For some reason, it was the last line of the poem he read that really stuck out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and I will tell about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARINE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>What we SEE of Carine plays with the VOICE OVER TRACK and SILENT with the production track; in essence lip synching herself. Chris' dialogue comes directly from the flashback image.</context>
      <utterance>I asked Chris who had written the poem.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARINE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who wrote that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see pictures of Chris on the night-stand of Walt and Billie's bedroom</context>
      <utterance>Well, it could've been either one of us. Couldn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARINE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What would he tell about now? What did his voice sound like now?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARINE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I realized that the words to my thoughts were of less and less meaning. Chris was writing his story and it had to be Chris who would tell it. The pictures in the scene BLUR as -</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom, help me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WALT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Walt takes her in his arms, trying to squeeze life into both of them.</context>
      <utterance>I wasn't dreaming! I didn't imagine it! I heard his voice, Walt. I heard Chris.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris is cleaning up the bus.</context>
      <utterance>...the road. Escaped from Atlanta. Thou shalt not return `cause the "west is the best." And now after two rambling years, comes the final and greatest adventure.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Chris shoveling snow away from the bus entrance with a rock.</context>
      <utterance>The climactic battle to kill the false being within and victoriously conclude the spiritual revolution.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Back to Chris, REAL TIME as he continues to write as he speaks:</context>
      <utterance>Ten days and nights of freight trains and hitchhiking, bringing him to the great white north.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No longer to be poisoned by civilization, he flees, and walks alone upon the land to become lost in the wild. Chris signs his doctrine -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>131.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>3. The diary/log: COLLECT SKINS AND FEATHERS TO SEW INTO</context>
      <utterance>Chris building a bathtub out in the front.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOTHING.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4. The diary/log: CONSTRUCT BRIDGE ACROSS NEARBY NARROW</context>
      <utterance>Chris hunting and skinning.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Chris, Walt, and Billie on the cusp of a jubilant and loving embrace!</context>
      <utterance>What if you saw me running into your arms...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The DRUMMING resumes with a BLAST OF BASS and before an embrace is possible...</context>
      <utterance>Would you see then...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...what I see now?</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
