<movie id="319" title="Jaws">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHRISSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She runs headlong into the inviting sea, plunges cleanly into the water with a light "Whoops!" as the cold water sweeps over her. Behind all this, we continue to hear the sentimental, beery chorus of alma maters. Then we see it -- a gentle bulge in the water, a ripple that passes her a dozen feet away. A pressure wave lifts her up, then eases her down again, like a smooth, sudden swell.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks around for him, finds him still on the beach, his feet tangled in his pants, which have dropped around his ankles. She starts to swim back in to him.</context>
      <utterance>Tommy? Don't dunk me...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>RADIO ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Ellen Brody burrows her head under the covers, avoiding morning for a few precious minutes more.</context>
      <utterance>Hayes Landing reports conditions good, with stripers and jacks. The Coast Guard has no storm warning from Block Island to Cape Hatteras; a light chop with freshening winds, continued clear and mild...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come the sun didn't used to shine in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear the scampering toenails of two cocker spaniels scrabbling around the foot of the bed. Brody swings out of bed, wearing shorts, socks, and tee shirt.</context>
      <utterance>'cause when we bought the house it was Autumn. This is summer. Feed the dogs.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you see the kids?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably out in the back yard.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In Amity, you say 'Yahd.'</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The kids are in the yahd, playing near the cah. How's that sound?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like you're from N'Yawk.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leads the dogs out of the bedroom and down to the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Give me 30 years, I'll get it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you burn another kettle? Y'know you're a fire hazard? This is the third one!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never hear the whistle.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen Brody, a tall, attractive blonde woman, enters from upstairs. She's still slightly sleepy, not what you'd call an "Instant-On" person. Mornings are not her best time.</context>
      <utterance>Feed the dogs.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to go through those?  I'm taking them to the Thrift Shop. It's Marcia Vaughn's pet charity. Pick out what you want to keep -- it's mostly your city clothes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I used to wear this to the Garden. Garbage strikes. Dog shit. Muggers.  Ship it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Brody can answer, Michael, his oldest boy, enters, holding his hand. There is bright new blood on it, but he is sensibly unconcerned. It's a normal childhood scrape.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be silly -– You're going to make summer better for them...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cut my hand. Hit by a vampire.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On the swing? I told you not to play near there until I sanded it down.  See what your son did?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael goes on out and upstairs. Ellen fumbles in her pocket and produces Brody's new glasses, which she holds out to him.</context>
      <utterance>Go upstairs and bring Mommy a band- aid.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't forget these.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah.  How do I look? Older, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody reacts to this, and bends to kiss her lightly. Then more seriously.</context>
      <utterance>I think they make you look sexy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sexy, hm? What was I before?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Older, sillier.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks out the window to the view beyond, discovering some new wonder in the fresh sunlit morning.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to depend on these things, y'know -– sometimes you can weaken your eyes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The phone rings.</context>
      <utterance>Let's see...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael reenters in bathing trunks, with a towel on his shoulder, his hand washed, holding a band-aid ready for application. Ellen takes it, and bandages the finger with care and affection.</context>
      <utterance>Brody... yeah, what's up... mmm... Well, what do they usually do, float or wash up? Really?... okay, I'll meet both of you at the beach in  ...20 minutes, okay? Okay.  First goddamn weekend of the summer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael heads toward the beach.</context>
      <utterance>There.  What was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets his shirt on with Ellen's help. She flicks imaginary dust from the badge on his chest.</context>
      <utterance>The office.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be careful.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives her a light kiss, starts to go, with his cup.</context>
      <utterance>Here? You gotta be kiddin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Love ya.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christine what?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Worthingsly... Worthington -- no one ever died on me before.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You picked her up on the ferry.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And nobody else saw her in the water?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody could've -- I was sort of passed out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think she might've run out on you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, no, sir. I've never had a woman do that. I'm sure she drowned.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You from around here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Cambridge. Harvard. My family's in Tuxedo, New York, though.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You here for the summer?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some friends and me took a house.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What d'you pay for a place just for the summer?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A thousand apiece, something like that. There's five of us. And we each kick in a hundred a week for beer and cleaning, stuff like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A shrill whistle makes them turn. Hendricks is fifty yards away, on his knees. He blows again, a feeble report this time.</context>
      <utterance>Pretty stiff.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody runs toward Hendricks, Cassidy hesitates, then follows with:</context>
      <utterance>Maybe that's your girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't make me look -- !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody slips behind his typewriter, putting paper in the machine with the effortless ease of years of practice. He's obviously no stranger to paperwork. He touch types, hardly ever looking down, checking his notes and listening with one ear to Polly. He is affected by what he's seen, but there's work to be done.</context>
      <utterance>If this is going to work, you've got to keep current stuff out here, and put 'closed' files in there. The 'Pendings' stay on my desk, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>POLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is in no order of importance, Chief: There's a meeting on the Amity Town Council on Aging this Monday night, Bentoncourt Hall. The Fire Inspector wants you to go over the fireworks site with him before he catches the one o'clock ferry. Mainly, you have a batch of calls about that new Karate school.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>POLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The phone rings and Polly picks it up.</context>
      <utterance>Searle's Rent-a-Bike, the Rainy Ale, Tisberry's Hardware... they say it's those nine-year-olds from the school practicing karate on all those nice picket fences.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody nestles the phone between ear and collar, listening, as he turns to the typewriter.</context>
      <utterance>It's the Coroner. Somebody pass away in the night?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Santos.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>POLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody takes a breath. A new resolve comes over him.</context>
      <utterance>What's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Polly, I want to know what water recreation is on for today.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody gets up and moves hastily toward the door.</context>
      <utterance>Right this minute?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY'S OUTER OFFICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cassidy and Hendricks look up as Brody enters.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd you hide the 'Beach Closed' signs?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENDRICKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A local merchant comes through the door.</context>
      <utterance>We never had any. What's the problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOCAL MERCHANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody pushes past him and out the door.</context>
      <utterance>Glad I caught you. There's a city truck with New Hampshire plates parked right in front of my...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KEISEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody nods yes, and starts to move away, but Keisel holds on to him.</context>
      <utterance>Wait-a-minute.  Glasses, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>KEISEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up bicycle. The bicycle's spokes are bent and broken from some sort of blows.</context>
      <utterance>Look at those fences! Little guys about eight to ten years old. And look at this!</utterance>
   <speaker>KEISEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They did that with their bare hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call me later in the day, okay, Harry?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HENDRICKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Polly told me to tell you there's a scout troop in Avril Bay doing the mile swim for their Merit Badges. I couldn't call them in, there's no phone out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get out of there – take these back to the office and make up some 'Beach Closed' signs, and let Polly do the printing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENDRICKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter with my printing?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What have you got there, Lenny?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENDRICKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn and group exchange horrified looks, but we get the impression it is not in response to the shark-attack news.</context>
      <utterance>We had a shark attack at South Chop this morning, Mayor. Fatal. Gotta batten down the beach.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who've you told this to, Lenny?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENDRICKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just found out about it -- but there's a bunch of Boy Scouts in the water a coupla miles down the coast from where we found the girl. Avril Bay, thereabouts. Chief went to dry them off.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take my car, okay?  You come with us, Lenny.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENDRICKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got all these signs here...</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all crowd into a Cadillac El Dorado with Vaughn Realty signs on the doors.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, it'll give us time to think about what they're going to say.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Martin!  Are you going to shut down the beach on your own authority?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I need any more authority?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEADOWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Technically, you need the instruction of a civic ordinance, or a special meeting of the town selectmen...</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's just going by the book. We're just a little anxious that you're rushing into something serious here. This is your first summer.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now tell me something I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All I'm saying is that Amity is a summer town -- we need summer dollars, and if they can't swim here, they'll use the beaches at Cape Cod, or Long Island.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So we should set out a smorgasbord?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEADOWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not even sure what it was.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What else could've done that?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boat propeller?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think, possibly... sure. A boating accident.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some weekend tramp accidentally goes swimming too far, she's a little drunk, a fishing boat comes along --</utterance>
   <speaker>MEADOWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men all laugh, ad lib their remembrances of this foolishness.</context>
      <utterance>Remember when Fred Ganz went scalloping in his BVD's? He was going to swim to New Bedford, he said.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEADOWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and Bill Mayhew almost caught him in his net...?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doctor, you're the one who told me what it was!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was wrong. We'll have to amend the report.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEADOWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We never had that kind of trouble here.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think you can appreciate the gut reaction people have to these things.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody looks out to the water where the scouts are rounding another buoy on the home stretch.</context>
      <utterance>I was only reacting to what I was told.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn indicates the beach where the Scouts are flopping out onto the sand, exhausted, glad to be finished.</context>
      <utterance>It's all psychological, anyway. You yell 'Barracuda' and everyone says 'huh'. You yell 'Shark' and we've got a panic on our hands. I think we all agree we don't need a panic this close to the 4th of July.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't work in a vacuum. Why don't you make Hendricks Chief? His family's been here since the Puritans -- half this island are his cousins.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All ad lib agreement.</context>
      <utterance>Martin, we hired the best man we could find.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need someone who isn't prejudiced by old feuds or family ties, someone who can referee things.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEADOWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have our complete support.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others surround Brody as Vaughn leads the way back to the cars, ad libbing their problem with the little karate choppers. Hendricks puts the signs back into the trunk of Vaughn's Cadillac. Vaughn waves casually to the Scouts and swimmers who are vigorously toweling off in the background.</context>
      <utterance>Now then. We've got a vandalism problem we ought to talk about...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SHOPKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Mr. Quint.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four spools of Number 12 piano wire, Okay? I ordered them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOPKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yessir, right here. What do those fish do, eat this stuff?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without waiting for it to be wrapped, he picks up the gleaming wire in his gnarled fist, and drops a bill on the counter.</context>
      <utterance>They choke on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOPKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer from Quint, who stops and sings along with the boy. The little kid's music degenerates into a series of awkward squeaks and blurps, as Quint stares at him. Quint continues out the door, threading his way through the people in the street like some great fish. As he gets up into the cab of his pick-up, its door swings open so we can see a crude stylized shark decorating its side. It slams behind him as Quint gets in and drives away.</context>
      <utterance>Bye now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAX TAFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like another big season. Gets worse every year.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TAFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody (and we) hear a shrill scream from the water. He stretches to look past the group, to see what's happening out there.</context>
      <utterance>And none of them from the Island. Just a lot of bother.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen captures Sean, and holds him playfully, an example.</context>
      <utterance>Present company excepted, but off- islanders are a pain in the butt. Pardon my French.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about this kid? What if he were born here. That make him an islander?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just 'cause a cat has kittens in an oven, it don't make them muffins.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody rumples his hair and sets him off to play.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not a muffin! I'm a boy!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MRS. KINTNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alex! Alex Kintner! Where do you think you're going?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Water. Just once more, please?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. KINTNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me see your fingers -- He holds out his hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. KINTNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex starts for the ocean. Behind him, Michael and his gang are also heading for the inviting waves. Brody is watching them go, his spine rigid with tension.</context>
      <utterance>They're beginning to prune. 10 minutes more.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's the water?</utterance>
   <speaker>KEISEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too cold. I'm going in again Labor Day. Hope we get this weather next weekend.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're very tight, y'know?  Right there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ow.  He's gotta be more careful in the water...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TOURIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something in the water. Right there! Didn't anyone see it?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's blood in the water.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody is pelting towards the water. He kicks sand over an annoyed Mrs. Kintner, who looks up, just in time to hear Brody's bellow.</context>
      <utterance>What is it...?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His urgency communicates itself to the others. Ellen snatches Sean up from where he's been playing in the sand. Other parents are calling their kids, hysteria mounting. People rush into the water, dragging their children and families bodily out of the ocean. The first kids coming out of the surf are frantically trying to wash the sticky blood off their bodies. The sight of the red sends the beach into a full panic.</context>
      <utterance>Michael! Sean! Out of the water. Everybody out of the water! Michael! Get out!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I've got to talk to her. This isn't a contest we want the whole country entering.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEADOWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I agree. If she's going to advertise, I wouldn't recommend out-of-town papers. Amity people could take care of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm responsible for public safety around here...</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a flurry and a bustle as everyone rearranges themselves and makes their way into the Amity Selectmen's Council Chambers.</context>
      <utterance>Then go out tomorrow and make sure no one gets hurt.  Everybody, could I have your attention? Since this affects all of us, I suggest we move into council chambers, where there's more room...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, here we all are; anyone have any special questions?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENHERDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(laughter from all)</context>
      <utterance>Is that $3000 bounty on the shark in cash or check?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's private business between you brave fishermen and Mrs. Kintner.  -- Chief --</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to tell you what we're doing so far. These are some of the steps I've taken as Chief of Police...</utterance>
   <speaker>MEADOWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All react.</context>
      <utterance>What's going on with the beaches, Chief?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll get to that in a minute. First, I plan to start our seasonal summer help early, and to use shark spotters on beaches open to the sea. I'd like cooperation from local fishermen, and I've also contacted the Oceanographic Institute over on the mainland.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No need to involve outsiders in our business, Martin.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you going to close the beaches?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pandemonium. A collective nerve has been touched.</context>
      <utterance>Larry and I have also decided to close the beaches for a short time.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only 24 hours!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't agree to that!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TAFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That official business could take all summer!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. KEISEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two opinions have been expressed, and the crowd takes sides vociferously, ad libbing assent or dissent depending on the point of view held forth.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's better to close.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MR. WISEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should make sure there is no danger.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. HASSETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't raise my kids to be some fish's lunch!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MRS. TAFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The motel is all I own -- you pull the plug on this town and I go down the drain with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. POSNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody's seen a shark.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. POLK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll lose business, we lose taxes, we lose our shirts!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crowd reaction.</context>
      <utterance>You all know me. You know what I do for a living. I'll go out and get this bird for you. He's a bad one and it's not like goin' down the pond chasing blue-gills and tommy- cods. This is a fish that can swallow a man whole. A little shakin', a little tenderizing and down ya' go.  You gotta get this fellow and get him quick. If you do, it'll bring a lot of tourist business just to see him and you've got your business back on a paying basis.  A shark of that size is no pleasure and I value my neck at a hell of a lot more'n 3,000 bucks.  I'll find him for three. But I'll kill him for ten.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The bastard is costing you more'n that every day. Do you wanna stay alive and annee up the ten or play it cheap and be on welfare next winter.  I'm gonna kill this thing... just a matter of whether I do it now -- or at the end of summer.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you very much, Mr. Quint, the Selectmen will take your offer under advisement</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you stand something to eat?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen walks past Brody to the window and looks out the window which overlooks the south bay. It is the hour of dusk.</context>
      <utterance>Love a cup of tea. With lemon.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mikey loves his birthday present.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody gets up, concerned, and joins her at the window.</context>
      <utterance>He's sitting in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey. He has it tied up to the jetty with a double-knot.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son! -- Out of the water now!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My boat's neat, dad!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want him out of the ocean.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's three feet deep, Martin</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Michael! Come inside!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's his birthday present, and you closed the beach, Honey. I told him not to go in the water after what happened yesterday. I don't believe he'll ever do it again.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen's eyes drift down to the open book, which is displaying a reproduction of the famous painting "The Gulf Stream," showing a black fisherman in a small dinghy similar to Michael's being assaulted by the jaws of three man-eating sharks, circling his boat.</context>
      <utterance>I told him not to go out until he memorized the handbook and the safety safety regulations, until he was sure of himself...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You heard your father! Out right now!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DENHERDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna call it a night after here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's only two-thirty. What, are you tired?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENHERDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Denherder hefts a bloodstained laundry bag from the wheelbarrow, revealing about a hundred feet of coiled dog chain and a large patched inner tube. Charlie takes out a monster hook and together they push the wheelbarrow onto the rickety pier that is only about five feet across.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Charlie, I got my second wind three nibbles back.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENHERDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leg of lamb this time?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Screw lamb -- let's shoot the sirloin!</utterance>
   <speaker>DENHERDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One more after this, then I'm going home.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Denherder tugs the chain against the piling to prove that it is. Charlie heaves the bait. Splash! The inner tube follows and both men eagerly watch as it floats seaward, the chain playing out from the wheelbarrow.</context>
      <utterance>Set?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie lights his pipe and sits back against a piling. He turns on his transistor radio and loops one end around a fractured board. Denherder paces, bored to death.</context>
      <utterance>Tide's taking it right out.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENHERDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do this all the time, right, Charlie?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty years.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENHERDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe that people pay money to go fishing. This is really dumb. This isn't even relaxing... it's just boring.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DENHERDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The chain is coming out so fast that it begins to drag the wheelbarrow to the end of the jetty. A section of chain tangles around the handle and flips the entire machine into the air. Both men watch dumbfounded as the inner tube, racing out to sea in a wake of white water, suddenly dips under.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! What's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at him take it!</utterance>
   <speaker>DENHERDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I set the goddam hook?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is then that the chain whips taut against the narrow pilings.</context>
      <utterance>Let him do it! Go-go-go-go-go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Denherder steps up on the broken-off piling just to be out of the water.</context>
      <utterance>Holy Jesus Christ!</utterance>
   <speaker>DENHERDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie, inhaling terror, trying to slog to shore. The jetty is getting closer. Suddenly, an enormous black fin breaks water like a periscope, making course corrections as it comes for Charlie. Denherder jumps from piling to piling, almost losing his balance on his way to help Charlie. Charlie has reached the last pylon toward open sea, and his hands clamber for a hold. But --</context>
      <utterance>Get the hell out! Charlie! Swim!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HENDRICKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...So then Denherder and Charlie sat there trying to catch their breath, and figuring out how to explain to Charlie's wife what happened to her freezer full of meat.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some of the locals greet Hendricks with occasional nods of recognition, or an ad libbed "Hi, Lenny," or "Hey, Lenny."</context>
      <utterance>That wasn't funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENDRICKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Kintner must've put her ad in Field and Stream.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks more like the readers of the National Enquirer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OUT-OF-TOWNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're charging me double the usual rent! I didn't come up here all the way from New Rochelle to be gouged by some Yankee Cracker!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOAT RENTAL MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Prices go up June First every year. You want a nice cheap, leaky boat, you go down to the Hamptons.  Right, Chief?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! You know how many men that's supposed to hold?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN BOAT</speaker>
      <mode>WALTER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever's safe, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you got ain't safe. You take some guys off or you don't go out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's standing near where Brody is finishing after his encounter with the chummers. Brody approaches Ben Gardner.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, back.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You going out too, Ben?</utterance>
   <speaker>GARDNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Mate nods "Yes" and starts to prepare to get under way. Ben and his Mate move away from the dock, headed towards the channel and the open sea leaving Felix and Pratt to scamper around the dock looking for another ride.</context>
      <utterance>Might give it a try. That three thousand bounty beats working for a living.  We ready?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amidst all this, we can hear the angry shouts of the entangled crews.</context>
      <utterance>Just back up! No, the other way! Cut it to your left! Your other left! The big boat, your front end is out way too far. Little boat, stay still!</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIPPER 1</speaker>
      <mode>THE SAILBOAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dammit, a vessel under sail has the right of way!</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIPPER 2</speaker>
      <mode>MOTORBOAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You schmuck, you ain't under sail, you're goddam drifting!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahoy, sail! You got an oar? Well, scull it out!</utterance>
   <speaker>SAILBOAT SKIPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell that stinkpotter to belay!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTORBOAT SKIPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell that ragsetter I'm going to poke him in the snoot!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just cast off in turn and make for the channel, OK?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody starts back towards the shore, Hooper is by his side.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before he can finish, Brody spots something on shore that moves him to shout to his deputy.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, I wonder if you could tell me...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody looks, and stops by a boat that's about to cast off. He holds out his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Is that dynamite?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If that's dynamite, give it here, or don't leave port.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, c'mon, it's just fireworks. Sharks like fireworks, it attracts them.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man passes Brody a cigar box filled with dynamite sticks. Brody tucks the dynamite under his arm, and continues down the pier. Hooper is still with him. All around them are two distinctly different breeds; the quiet pros, like Ben Gardner, in well-worn, comfortable clothes, with efficient, sensible gear, and the amateur crazies, with all manner of weapons and impractical, silly tourist clothing.</context>
      <utterance>Hand it over.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a fantail launch out there that won't make it beyond the breakwater.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're tellin' me. I swear, this town has gone crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Officer, I wonder if you could tell me where I could find Chief Brody?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(holds out his hand)</context>
      <utterance>Hooper, Matt Hooper. From the Oceanographic Institute.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLOSE - PRATT AND FELIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They spot it and sour.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The owner of Pratt's boat throws it forward and Pratt removes a .45 automatic from the holster of his belt. He tests it, firing once in the air. As they near the scene of the struggle, eleven other boats begin converging, until --</context>
      <utterance>Well, get over there! He ain't caught it yet!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PRATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of his party in the over-filled boat grabs a gaff and leans out to grab the moribund shark. But Harry won't give up the line, still reeling in.</context>
      <utterance>Hand me that pole! Quick!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beat it! I hooked him!</utterance>
   <speaker>PRATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's the family, Harry?  Go on and do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN WITH GAFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pratt nods reluctantly. The man swings, lodges the gaff and hauls the shark up onto the gunwale. A paroxysm of cheers from the surrounding boats. Smoke flares are fired into the air.</context>
      <utterance>We split down the middle?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is a ten-foot tiger, and what a mess -- splattered with bullet punctures, gashes, bleeding from several orifices. But it is not dead -- it kicks back to life and threatens to capsize the boat. Pratt panics and fires six times with his .45. The bullets pierce the shark's head, pass through, and split the fiberglass hull through which a flood of water rises. Everybody stands up as the boat slips beneath them.</context>
      <utterance>Let go my shark!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sheet has just been lifted, and Hooper stares down at the lump on the slab. He stops, turns off his recorder as emotions wage war with his senses. Rationality wins, and he turns on the recorder again.</context>
      <utterance>Victim One, identified as Christine Watkins, female Caucasian...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...height and weight may only be estimated from partial remains. Torso severed in mid-thorax, eviscerated with no major organs remaining. May I have a drink of water? Right arm severed above the elbow with massive tissue loss from upper musculature. Portions of denuded bone remaining.  -- did you notify the coast guard?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it was local jurisdiction.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Left arm, head, shoulders, sternum and portions of ribcage intact.  Please don't smoke. With minor post- mortem lacerations and abrasions. Bite marks indicate typical non-frenzy feeding pattern of large squali, possibly carchaninus lonimanus, or isurus glaucas. Gross tissue loss and post-mortem erosion of bite surfaces prevent detailed analysis; however, teeth and jaws of the attacking squali must be considered above average for these waters.  -- Did you go out in a boat and look around?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, we just checked the beach...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wasn't an 'accident,' it wasn't a boat propeller, or a coral reef, or Jack the Ripper. It was a shark. It was a shark.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MEADOWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he and the photographer turn to mob, we see Hooper and Brody arriving from the morgue. Hooper immediately heads towards the shark, while Brody pauses and we see a look of relief and delight cross his features.</context>
      <utterance>Ginny, get this out on the state wire to AP and UPI in Boston and New York. Have one of them pick it up for the national and call Dave Axelrod in New York and tell him this is from me and he owes me one... let's get a picture.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if one man can catch a fish in 50 days, then I guess 50 of these bozos can catch a fish in one day -- beginner's luck.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Men ad lib "No, I caught it..." "I hooked him," etc.</context>
      <utterance>You did it! Did Ben Gardner catch this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEADOWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He continues to call directions and move people out of the way to set up his shot. Hooper is measuring the shark.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, everybody, I want to get a picture for the paper -- could everyone clear out of the way?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEADOWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could you get out of the shot, young man?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men (Felix, Pratt, et al) get Brody to join them in the shot. The whole town and the Armada fishermen all line up in a classic "high school" graduating class shot with the victorious fishermen kneeling in front, and the rest of the Armada and Townspeople arranged behind them. Hendricks hold up the "Beach Closed" sign in ironic victory.</context>
      <utterance>Who, me? Okay...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Larry, if you'd see these clowns leave, you'd never believe they'd come back with anything. But they got him!</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's good. That's real good. Ben Meadows getting pictures for the paper.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure he is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Hooper enters the circle, and picks up where he left off, measuring the shark's teeth. Others watch him. Charlie and Denherder walk over to the shark. Charlie punches it.</context>
      <utterance>It's a tiger shark. Very rare in these waters, and definitely a maneater.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY AND VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They are walking down to the shark together.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's that young man?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Matt Hooper, the specialist they send down from the Oceanographic Institute.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whadya mean, 'Bite Radius?' What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GAFFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Teeth are teeth, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't say this wasn't the shark, I just said I wasn't sure this was the one...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What d'ya mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are hundreds of different kinds of sharks; makos, blues, hammerheads, white-tips... any one of them could've attacked. Look -- shark digestion is slow. We could open this one up, and find whatever he's been eating is still inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's disgusting! This is the largest, meanest, most vicious shark ever landed off Amity Island, and a known maneater!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's just cut him open and see what's inside...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not, Larry? We could get a positive confirmation that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be reasonable, boys -- this isn't the time or the place to do some kind of half-assed autopsy on a fish. Ben...  do you have all the pictures you need?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEADOWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Plenty.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Felix, Pratt and the others ad lib disagreement. "You're not gonna cut up my trophy," etc.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute...</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see Mrs. Kintner approaching, dressed in black.</context>
      <utterance>I am not going to stand here and watch this fish cut open and see some kid fall out on the dock. Besides...</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chief, I'll take responsibility for this. Boys, cut this ugly sonofabitch down before he stinks up the whole island. Harve, tomorrow you and Carl take him out and dump him right in the drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. KINTNER JOINS THE GROUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She seeks out Brody, and stops in front of him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. KINTNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods, she slaps him full across the face. There is an embarrassed silence. Some people leave, following a trend that began with the first mention of cutting open the shark.</context>
      <utterance>Chief Brody?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. KINTNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops, unable to continue. Her father takes her arm and leads her away. Pratt, Harry and the others trail off after her. During the rest of the scene, the camera tightens in on Brody to the exclusion of the others.</context>
      <utterance>My Alex was a beautiful little boy and you killed him. Did you know that? You knew there was a shark out there. You knew a girl got killed here last week. I just found that out. But you knew. You knew it was dangerous, but you let people go swimming anyway. You knew all those things, and still my boy is dead now and there's nothing you can do about that. My boy is dead. I wanted you to know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Martin. She's in a sick, terrible state.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Hooper can finish, Brody's shoulders slump and he goes slack.</context>
      <utterance>Look, maybe this is the wrong time to pursue this, but I'm not sure...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's all get out of here, this place stinks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and leaves abruptly, surrendering the dock to Vaughn and Hooper, who eye each other with mutual dis-admiration.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="48">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mere and give Daddy a kiss.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sean gives Daddy the kiss. Brody shoos him and Michael off to bed. Ellen, who is feeling progressively more left out with each passing moment, gets up abruptly and clears a few dishes. Brody is not letting her into his world for the moment, and it shows. There's a knock at the door.</context>
      <utterance>Because he needs it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Ellen opens the door for him.</context>
      <utterance>Martin Brody residence?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. I'm Matt Hooper. If your husband is here, I'd like to talk to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooper enters. He's carrying a couple of bottles of wine which he picked up in town. He sits down near Brody.</context>
      <utterance>So would I. Come on in.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like something? Some coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts in on it, as soon as someone has indicated "go ahead."</context>
      <utterance>Is anyone having this...?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dynamite!  How was your day...?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They exchange a long look that evolves into a slightly desperate, but shared laughter.</context>
      <utterance>Swell.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They laugh some more. Ellen is again left out of it.</context>
      <utterance>Here... one red, one white.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody begins stripping the foil off the wine, screwing in a corkscrew, etc.</context>
      <utterance>Ummm. Really good.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My husband tells me you're in sharks.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't put it that way. But I love sharks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You love sharks?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do.  But you've still got a problem here, there's a shark just off the island somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come you have to tell them that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, but what are you talking about? Didn't they catch the shark this afternoon? It was on the Cape station news.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody has the cork out of the wine. Pop.</context>
      <utterance>They caught a shark, not the shark. Big difference. I could've proved it this afternoon, by cutting that one open and examining his stomach contents. Also, his bite was too small.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody takes the fine wine, and pours it into his drink glass filling the tumbler to the top with ice cubes, diluted scotch, and the wine.</context>
      <utterance>I was lucky to find that in town -- it's an estate bottled vintage year...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We ought to let it breathe... Whatever.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He extends the bottle to Hooper, who politely accepts a token sip. He takes some for himself, and offers some to Ellen.</context>
      <utterance>Let's all have a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You too, sweetheart...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's to your husband, the only other rational man on the island. Day after tomorrow, I'll be gone, and he'll be the only one.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're leaving?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Going out on the 'Aurora.'</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that a boat?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it! The best-funded research expedition to ever study the shark... around the world in 18 months.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like those Cousteau specials on television? I think it's for the kids, but I love them.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better than Cousteau, or Compagno with computers, telemetry, Defense Department funding...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw a show with sea otters, and a big turtle... Mikey loved it. Made me promise to get him one. Will you live on the boat?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Martin hates boats. Hates the water. On the ferry to the mainland, he sits in the car the whole way over. He's got this childhood thing, there's a clinical word for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drowning. Lemme ask you something. Is it true most attacks take place in three feet of water, around 10 feet from the beach?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Like the kid on your beach. I wish I could've examined that shark they caught...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something else. Do most attacks go unreported?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About half of them. A lot of 'missing swimmers' are really shark victims.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a kind of a lone shark, called, uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rogue?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Rogue. Picks out an area where there's food and hangs out there as long as the food supply lasts?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's called Territoriality. It's a theory.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And before 1900, when people first starting swimming for recreation, before public bathing and resorts, there were very few shark attacks, cause sharks didn't know what they were missing?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody digests all this; confirmation of facts he has gleaned in his newly acquired knowledge of the shark species. There is a long pause.</context>
      <utterance>You could say that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't we have one more drink, you and I, and then we go down and cut open that old shark and see for sure what's inside him, or not.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am Chief of Police. I can do anything I want.  You want to come?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets up and they both start out. Ellen watches them go.</context>
      <utterance>I'm flattered you should ask.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...And it was Dartmouth Winter weekend, and she was Homecoming Queen, and I was her date; then she got into the fact that her family had more money than my family, and she was right -- her great-grandfather was in mining, and my ancestors were Yankee shipbuilders. So we broke up and I went home with some beatnik from Sarah Lawrence.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What stinks so bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They bend over the shape like 18th century graverobbers.</context>
      <utterance>Our friend, the shark.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear a slurp and a squish as Hooper produces a big knife and dips into the shark with a major incision.</context>
      <utterance>We always had a summer place on the water -- Newport, the Vineyard, so I figured I'd major in something I knew about. Oceanography, marine biology. It was that, or design racing yachts like my older brother. Hmmm. He we go. Up the old alimentary canal. Hold the light.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From his vantage point, Quint watches, unseen by the two men. Brody is holding the light, fighting the gag reflex, fascinated by the bizarre ritual.</context>
      <utterance>We open the abdominal cavity and check the digestive tract. Simple.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Half a flounder. Hmmm... a burlap bag... a paint can... aha!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just as I thought. He drifted up here with the Gulf Stream, from southern waters.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you tell?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Florida license plate.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He ate a car?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kicks the remains around below camera.</context>
      <utterance>No, but Tiger sharks are the garbage cans of the ocean. They eat anything. But this one didn't eat any people. There's nothing here...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do we do?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're looking for a shark, you don't look on land. You go out and chum for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chum?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only one sure way to find him -- offer him a little something to eat. Chum -- blood, waste meat, fish, anything. They can sense it miles away. If he's out there, we might be able to get a closer look at him.  It's a good time, too. They're night feeders...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody, bored, tired, and slightly queasy, is trying to concentrate on anything but the motion of the boat. He stares at the sophisticated electronics displays.</context>
      <utterance>That's the Cape Light -- we're on the stretch where he's feeding, if he's still here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is all this stuff?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Depth-finder, fathometer, sonar, closed-circuit TV -- fore and aft -- RDF, single side band...  And two loose nuts behind the wheel.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you tell from that if a big man- eater is around?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes.  Look here -- something big, probably a school of mackerel clumped together. And staying right with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSERT - ELECTRONICS SCREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's blipping and peeping.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd you get all this?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I Bought it. Both sets of grandparents set up trust funds for me; stocks went up, so I don't have to touch my principal.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're at the Institute full time? Or do you have a job?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is a job. I'm not fooling around like some amateur. It's my life!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We gotta get back soon...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooper looks up and cuts the wheel hard, as the same time dropping the engines into neutral, and then reverse. The sudden change throws Brody to his knees.</context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HOOPER'S BOAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something he has seen moves Hooper.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sticks his head over the side, into the black water.</context>
      <utterance>I want to check something. Hold my feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't they have lifejackets or something? An extra boat?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They must've hit something.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSERT, ELECTRONICS DISPLAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blip, chatter, blip, chatter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He didn't have a dinghy aboard. I'm going down to take a look at his hull.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't we just tow it in?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We will. There's something I've got to find out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooper takes a last few breaths, orients himself, takes a long, hard look at the quiet, open ocean, and falls into the sea.</context>
      <utterance>Be careful, for chrissake.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A White! A Great White, I found a tooth buried in the hull. He must've attacked... I knew it... Gardner's dead in there. I didn't see the mate...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooper, despite his shock and surprise, is strangely elated, almost giddy with the wonder of his discovery.</context>
      <utterance>No shark did that to a boat!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody sinks weakly into a chair. Brody huddles in the stern, Hooper kicks the engine in with a roar, and still a-shiver with excitement, turns the boat and its grim tow back to port.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ! A Great White! Who'd believe it! We're not talking about a shark, we're talking about a Shark!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is a kind of shark called a Great White Shark that every expert in the world agrees is a maneater.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're situation here suggests that a Great White has staked out a claim in the waters around Amity Island, and that he will continue to feed here as long as there is food in the water.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no limits to where he can strike, and we've had three attacks and two deaths in the past few days. It happened like this before, in 1916, when a Great White killed five swimmers at Jones Beach, in Long Island.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A shark's attack is stimulated by the kind of splashing and activity that occurs whenever humans go swimming -- you can't avoid it!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A 4th of July beach is like ringing a dinner bell, for Chrissake!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just pulled a shark tooth the size of a shot glass out of the hull of a wrecked boat out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We towed Ben Gardner's boat in, Larry; he was dead and his boat was all chewed up.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that tooth here? Did anyone see it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He lost it on the way up.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of a shark did you say it was?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carcaradon carcharias. A Great White.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm not going to commit economic suicide on that flimsy evidence. We depend on the summer people for our lives, and if our beaches are closed, then we're all finished.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have got to close the beaches. We have got to get someone to kill the shark, we need non-corrosive mesh netting, we need scientific support... It's gonna cost money just to keep the nuts out and save what we have.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't thing either of you is familiar with our problems...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm familiar with the fact that you are going to ignore this thing until it swims up and bites you on the ass! There are only two ways to solve this thing: you can kill it, or you can cut off its food supply...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That means closing the beaches.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leads Brody around to the front of the billboard, on which we see that some pranksters have painted a huge shark fin in the water behind the swimmer, so she looks now like a frantic bather fleeing a pursuing monster.</context>
      <utterance>Come here, I want to show you something.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sick vandalism! Brody, that's a deliberate mutilation of a public service message! I want those little paint-happy bastards caught and hung up by their baby Buster Browns!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it! I'm standing here arguing with a guy who can't wait to be a hot lunch. Goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute! I need you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out there is a Perfect Engine, an Eating Machine that is a miracle of evolution -- it swims and eats and that's all. Look at that! Those proportions are correct.  I know sharks.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd love to prove that. Getting your name in the National Geographic.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Larry, we can re-open the beaches in August.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>August! Tomorrow is the 4th of July, and we are going to open for business. It's going to be our best summer in years. If you're so concerned about the beaches, you two, you do whatever you have to to keep them safe, but with you or without you, the beaches stay open this weekend.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Martin Brody?  I'll need your signature here... here... and here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody signs. The Officer shakes his head as Brody makes an error.</context>
      <utterance>Authorization for direct payment of flight expenses not directly connected to a normal mission of this command.  You pay for the gas.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I signed on the wrong line...</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody complies, shaking his head. The Officer snaps him a salute, jogs lightly back to his idling copter, buckles in, and gives Brody a "thumbs up" as he lifts off in a flurry of sand and ice-cream wrappers.</context>
      <utterance>Just erase your signature and initial your erasure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Men ad lib responses: "Happy to do it," "Any time," "When's lunch?" "I hate holidays," etc.</context>
      <utterance>I want to thank you guys from local agencies for cooperating, and I hope we won't actually be needing your services. But I'm glad to have you here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ENSIGN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods to his men, who head for some Boston Whalers (or similar boat with surf-riding capability) and push off into the surf to patrol the swimming areas.</context>
      <utterance>I want to get our lines and repellent out, so we better shove off.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone kind of nods acknowledgment.</context>
      <utterance>We're all on one channel, so let's keep radio traffic to a minimum, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope we get some more help.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish it would rain...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>TV DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the "Tape 1" and "Line" monitors, we see Vaughn being interviewed by the Announcer in the blazer.</context>
      <utterance>Put 1 on the line. In five. 4. 3. 2. 1. Roll.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and with me is the Mayor of Amity, Lawrence Vaughn. Mr. Vaughn, how about those rumors?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MONITOR: CAMERA 1: As Vaughn speaks to us on the monitors, the monitor for Camera 1 pans over to show a Sightseeing Bus pull up in the parking area, and a horde of media vultures spilling out, carrying cameras with long lenses and tripods, telescopes, sunshades and parasols, all the equipment of the curious and none of the equipment of the holiday bather or swimmer. TAPE 1 AND LINE MONITORS: Close on the Announcer, Vaughn out of the picture.</context>
      <utterance>How about them indeed. I'm pleased and happy to repeat the news that we have, in fact, caught and killed a large predator that supposedly injured some bathers here. As you can see, it's a beautiful day, the beaches are open, and the folks here are having a wonderful time. Amity, y'know, means 'Friendship.'</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Also here today is a Marine Biologist and Research Fellow from the Oceanographic Institute, Matthew Hooper. Mr. Hooper, what've you heard?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooper's voice fades off as someone at the mixer panel dials his mike off, and brings up the Announcer's lavalier.</context>
      <utterance>What I've heard and what I've seen are two different things. I believe there is a large Great White Shark -- Carcharodon Cacharias - in the waters off this very beach, that he has killed and that he will kill again...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, I just don't have the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>TV DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MONITORS: CAMERAS 1, 2 and 3: The cameras seek out the appropriate activity as the Director calls for it.</context>
      <utterance>Recue the machines. 2, pan off the Chief and show me some tits and ass. 1, get me some cute kids. 3... see if you got a shot at the water.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mayor, 43 seconds, Biologist 45 seconds. That's equal time, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.  Jerry, come on in and look at this.  Roll 2. In five, 4. 3. 2. 1.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. MONITOR</mode>
      <context>His voice is dialed under as the Announcer himself appears in the control room to watch himself on the monitors.</context>
      <utterance>Amity Island is famed for its clear air and white sand beaches. But a cloud appeared...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>LIVE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at that shine on my nose. It's a beacon.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Vaughn begins his spiel again, the other monitors show us the action on the beach.</context>
      <utterance>Close enough for remote.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I'm pleased and happy...</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think we ought to stick around?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What else you got?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Teachers' strike downtown.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAMERAMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christenson, this is Al. Union says time for Engineering Five.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's five minutes, guys. Coffee.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you get in the water?</utterance>
   <speaker>SELECTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to wash off my suntan lotion. I'll get a burn...</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On an adjoining blanket, a spirited Ruth Gordon type is sitting, watching brightly as her manservant, a polished Eric Harrison type, prepares some tea from a thermos.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody's going in!</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there nobody going in? What a shame. Arthur, should I be going in?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode>THE BUTLER</mode>
      <context>He puts down the tea service, and leads her towards the water. At the edge of the sea, she stops, and he walks in.</context>
      <utterance>If you'd like.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He ducks his head under for a final look around. His dripping head rises triumphantly from the surf.</context>
      <utterance>It's very nice. Not too cold... Quite refreshing... Very pleasant....</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts into the water, he takes her parasol, escorting her the rest of the way into the ocean.</context>
      <utterance>No sharks, m'lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is marvelous! Arthur, I want to come back to this very spot. Will you make a note of where we are?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>VOICES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's scared to go in! I was in! Up to your knees, yeah -- So come with me -- I'll go again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEADOWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A group of youngsters playing with Michael Brody's dinghy. They are hauling it toward the surf.</context>
      <utterance>Beautiful day, Chief!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael turns as Brody trots toward him.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Mikey -- !</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not going to the ocean with that, are you son?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm all checked out for light surf and look at it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do me this favor just once. Use the ponds.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, the ponds are for old ladies.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a favor for your old man.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, Dad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>COPTER SPOTTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Copter to Daisy! Red Four, Red Four!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOAT #7 - HENDRICKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guns are up, heads turning everywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENDRICKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where -- ?</utterance>
   <speaker>COPTER SPOTTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Coast Guard sonar operator spots it and pales. A slick black dorsal fin is slicing a wake toward the swimming area.</context>
      <utterance>Went under your -- There!</utterance>
   <speaker>SONAR OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ -- Shark!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A lifeguard in a loft behind him begins blowing on his whistle.</context>
      <utterance>Everybody out! Out of the water, please -- leave the water, please --</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE - BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>shouting hysterically.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No whistles! No whistles!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CLOSE - ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A sudden turn. She runs.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE - HOOPER IN BOAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got the walkie-talkie to his mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Three boats racing to carry out the orders. The black fin re- passing the two children, racing to get out. Hooper reaches the mouth before the others. The fin won't veer off. It smacks into the little vessel, bumping it aside. The fin is left racing into open water. Blood leavings. Hooper leaping over the side, slogging towards Michael.</context>
      <utterance>Block the estuary! The estuary!</utterance>
   <speaker>WIDE ON WATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Copter roars in buzzing the shark, but too late.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The doctor said it's okay -- mild shock. He can come home in the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, big guy -- you want anything from home?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My cars. And a comic book.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here --  Take him home.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Home... New York?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen exits.</context>
      <utterance>No. Home here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got a pen on you?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's only one thing you're good for anymore -- signing a damn voucher. Here. It's an authorization to employ a contractor.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know if I can do that without a...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to hire Quint to kill the fish. I want to see that shark dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe we can save August...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it. This summer's had it. Next summer's had it. You're the mayor of Shark City. You wanted to keep the beaches open. What happens when the town finds out about that?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was acting in the town's best interests...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The best interest in this town would be to see that fish belly-up in the water with a hole in his head. You do the right thing. You authorize me.  Right there. Whatever it costs.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My kids were on that beach...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn signs, and Brody takes the paper and exits.</context>
      <utterance>Just sign it, Larry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This has got to be one big violation...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is quite a place.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He emerges from the steam and smoke.</context>
      <utterance>Keep your hands off my stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you bring a check?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cash? Or do we do this on a handshake and a promise?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm authorized by the township of Amity to hire you as an independent contractor. We'll meet your price.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="34">
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And my regular daily rate -- $200, whether we catch him or not.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And incidental damages, if any...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you get the Mayor off my back with this zoning crap. Nobody tells me how to run my property.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And, uh, a case of apricot brandy and you buy the lunch.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two cases. And dinner when you land.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody tastes.</context>
      <utterance>Try some of this. I made it myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Herschel interrupts. He's stopped working, and is wiping his hands on a bloody rag.</context>
      <utterance>Here's to swimmin' with bowlegged women.</utterance>
   <speaker>HERSCHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quint wheels to face him.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Quint...</utterance>
   <speaker>HERSCHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not goin'. No sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to get paid, you go.</utterance>
   <speaker>HERSCHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget the money. You can't pay me enough. I ain't crazy. I worked some big mean fish with you, but I ain't goin' on this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the last time I hear from you. I don't want anyone with piss for blood on my vessel. Put that blackfish on board, pump the bilges, and top off the fuel tanks, and finish up in the morning. Then you're on the beach.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quint turns to see this new voice, and starts walking towards him.</context>
      <utterance>You're going to need an extra hand...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Matt Hooper...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know who he is...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's from the Oceanographic Institute.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been to sea since I was 12. I've crewed three Trans-pacs --</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Transplants?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- and an America's Cup Trials...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not talking about day sailing or pleasure boating. I'm talking about working for a living. Sharking.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I'm not talking about hooking some poor dogfish or sand shark. I'm talking about a Great White.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooper ties the knot effortlessly.</context>
      <utterance>Are you now. I know about porkers in the water --  Here. Tie me a sheepshank.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't need to pass basic seamanship.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes Hooper's hands in his own big bloody fists, and feels them as he talks.</context>
      <utterance>Let me see your hands...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ha. City hands. You been counting money. If you had a $5000 net and $2000 worth of fish in it, and along comes Mr. White, and makes it look like a kiddy scissors class has gone to work on it and made paper dolls. If you'd ever worked for a living, you'd know what that means.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I don't need to hear any of this working class hero crap. Some party boat skipper who's killed a few sharks...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. Knock it off. I don't want to have to listen to this while we're out there...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean 'We...?'</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's my charter. My party.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, Commissioner. But when we're on my ship, I am Master, Mate and Pilot. And I want him...  ...along for ballast.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he talks, we see Hooper coming down to the dock. Wheeling a wagon behind him are two long-haired Research Assistants from the Institute. On the wagon, among other things, is a big shark cage. At dockside, Hooper checks his list, as he signs for his issue.</context>
      <utterance>5 lengths of 1/2-inch, 20 number 14's, straight gaff, flying gaffs, tail rope, eye splice, M-1, 20 clips, pliers, irons...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Powerhead, CO2 darts, hypo, regulator, tanks, depth gauge, camera, extra magazines, cage...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got everything you asked for?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All of it. And thank Dr. Miro for me. And tell Borack I'll catch up with them in New Zealand.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is actually a killing expedition?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An eye for an eye, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Squirt! You want to stow this gear or you want me to use it for ballast? It ain't good for much but bait.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooper sees his gear approaching.</context>
      <utterance>I'll see ya. Tell Dorothy hello.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Junior. What are you? Some kind of half-assed astronaut?  Jesus Christ, when I was a kid, every little squirt wanted to be a harpooner or a sword fisherman. What d'ya have there -- a portable shower?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anti-Shark cage.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooper indicates "me."</context>
      <utterance>Who's inside, you or the shark?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooper nods. Quint sings "Spanish Ladies" half to himself.</context>
      <utterance>You're in the cage?  The cage is in the water?  The shark is in the water too?  You're in the water with the shark.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Comin' aboard...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She straightens his coat, and gives him a shaving kit to carry aboard with his toiletries. From the deck, Quint whistles derisively.</context>
      <utterance>Did you take your dramamine?  Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hurry up, Chief, daylight's a wastin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that him?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Colorful, isn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You going to be all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing to worry about -- I'll survive this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody nods, and holds her hand for a wordless moment.</context>
      <utterance>I'll see you back soon. There's an extra pair of glasses in your black socks, and there's some suntan lotion and blistex in your kit.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Here is the body of Mary Lee. For 15 years she kept her virginity. Not a bad record for this vicinity.' There is a sputter and roar as the Orca's diesels kick on.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo-ho-ho and a bottle of rum.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'll I tell the kids?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They laugh together, and exchange a short, fierce kiss.</context>
      <utterance>Tell 'em I went fishin'!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Its diesels chugging, the Orca pulls away from the pier. Ellen has already resolutely turned her back on it, and is walking off the dock back onto dry land.</context>
      <utterance>Cast off the bow line! Now your stern!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Front-Bow, Back-Stern, Port, Starboard. Aloft, Below. It's not a staircase, it's a ladder, it's not a rope, it's a line, and if you don't get it right...  I'll throw your ass through that little round window. He laughs at his joke. This is probably something he tells all his charters.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts moving gear around, preparing chum barrels, setting hooks, Hooper gives him a hand, Brody stays out of the way.</context>
      <utterance>Now hear this. You're aboard the fishing vessel 'Orca,' and I'm her Captain, Master, Mate, and Owner. You'll jump when I holler. We're doin' a job here, and Christ, I ain't got time to watch you birds get hooks in your ass and fall overboard. Ship with me, and you'll do all right. Cross me, and I'll slap you upside your heads. Now -- if you boys are ready -- let's go fishin'.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that supposed to prove?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a little appetizer. I want our porker to know we're serving. I want to put some iron into that big yap...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep that chum line going -- we've got five good miles. Don't break it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's driving the boat?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody. We're drifting with the current.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing. Nothing, nothing, nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody goes to unlash a fresh barrel, but can't figure out the knots. He finally tugs on a piece of rope, and it all comes loose... barrel, shark cage, and, most important, Hooper's tanks, clattering and rolling on the deck.</context>
      <utterance>Get a fresh barrel.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watch it! Compressed air -- you screw around with one of those and Boom! Careful, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Real fine stuff but it won't mean a thing to Mr. Whitey, of course... he didn't go to schools in electronics. He was born with what he does best. Eat. He's a swimming appetite. 'Course he might eat this stuff, but then I've seen him eat a rocking chair, too.  Next time, ask me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's pilot whale, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody shades his eyes from the white sun as Quint baits up.</context>
      <utterance>It ain't a Big Mac.  The expert don't approve. What do you thing? You're closer to the situation.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are we way out here, when the shark's back there?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...'cause this is where he lives. You gotta think like they do.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now if he weren't around, we'd of hooked something else by now, wouldn't we? But he scared 'em all away. Big lonesome son of a bitch...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quint tightens drag and strikes. The line goes whizzing out. Brody runs to Quint's side. Hooper springs up to the flying bridge.</context>
      <utterance>-- he'll gulp it down now...  Hooooooo!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got it?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody goes to get water, the boat surges, he staggers. Brody pours water on the screaming reel, nearly unspooled now. Hooper is turning the boat around and the line changes direction.</context>
      <utterance>Get behind me, dummy!  Reverse her and turn -- he's taking too much line!  Wet my reel, quick!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Starboard, for Chris'sake -- Hooper steers it sharply.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, you! Farmer! Half-speed there...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again the line changes direction, down this time.</context>
      <utterance>Aye, Aye SIR. Stand by to repel boarders. Poop the mainsail. Argh, Jim Boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quint reeling in like mad.</context>
      <utterance>Neutral!  Where the hell is he going?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He ad libs brief instructions to Brody as the line rushes out and there is less tension. Quint is horsing up and down, reeling in.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, this ain't foolin' me --  Sure -- try it!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The line is almost vertical, and Quint shows a hint of bafflement. He reels in suspiciously.</context>
      <utterance>Makin' believe it's easy now.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gettin' ready to run again -- no? No?  What's he playin' here?  Put the gloves on!  Let's see who's gonna tease who now!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let it go, don't waste your time.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooper is rushing down.</context>
      <utterance>Down here, Hooper!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what it is, but it's not a shark.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The leaders show above the water line. Brody is wide-eyed, waiting for that first look.</context>
      <utterance>Look -- you may be a big Yahoo in the lab, but out here you're just supercargo, and you'll do as I say, or you can take your gear and backstroke home. Now get down here!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The wire's showing!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unbuckle me -- fast!  Grab the leader. He ain't normal, this one... they never --</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooper snaps the rope onto the leader and holds on.</context>
      <utterance>It's too wild, too erratic. It's a marlin or a stingray. It's a gamefish.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before he realizes what's happening, Brody is clumsily clutching at the big rod, appalled. Quint skips away for a flying gaff. He picks one, turns... That's when the leader lashes free, sending Hooper crashing backward in a serious fall, and the rod whips at Brody's forehead, drawing blood. Quint snatches up the rod and reels in. The wires have been bitten through.</context>
      <utterance>Watch your hands --  Grab onto this!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A marlin, or a stingray. Huh. Don't ever tell me my business again. Get back up on the bridge.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm okay...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fasten the pole.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the point with hooks and Lines? --</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooper shakes off his dizziness and obeys. Brody watches Quint rig up a new leader, hook up the same bait.</context>
      <utterance>Don't tell me my business!  Quarter-mile, that way. Full throttle.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How -- if they're gonna keep on breaking?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody goes inside to inspect his forehead.</context>
      <utterance>What I do is trick him to the surface, got that? Then I can jab him, understand?  Think I'm gonna haul it in as if he's a catfish, like everyone else does?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Over there!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you see?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE - QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>looking hard at something.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE - BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>staring, eyes widening.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE - HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>moving in, surprised, interested, fascinated.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>20 feet, if it's an inch...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooper is nearly beside himself with a strange ecstasy. He leaps toward his gear.</context>
      <utterance>25 feet. And three tons of him there.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never saw one that big.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quint ignores him and moves off into the pilot house, where he swiftly takes out his green case, and opens it to begin to assemble something inside it. Brody is alone on the deck with Hooper.</context>
      <utterance>What do we do? Get some help? Radio in?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooper is contained in his own excitement. He has finally come up with what he was looking for -- an expensive Nikon through which he peers intently at the shark alongside. He is talking half to himself as he fine-tunes the range finder and focus. He is squeaking and bubbling in an unsuppressed emotional boil.</context>
      <utterance>How're we gonna handle this?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(ad libs ecstasy)</context>
      <utterance>There's a formula! Girth, about 150 inches, squared, divide by 800 -- son of a bitch, they are not going to believe this! -- divide by 2000... three tons!  You're right, you old fart! Three tons!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>RADIO VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Quint snaps the mouthpiece to his lips.</context>
      <utterance>Amity Point Light Station to Orca. This is Amity Point Light Station, to Orca...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Orca here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have Mrs. Martin Brody here...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put her on.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...push this? Oh. It's working. Hello, Martin?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Quint, Missus.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just wanted to know if you were all right... the Coast Guard let me use their radio. Is Chief Brody there?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's busy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... is everything all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He snaps off the radio, and, for good measure, pulls the plug from the power source.</context>
      <utterance>Just fine, Missus. We'll be back soon. Everything's fine. We haven't seen anything yet. Orca out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He indicates the barrels on the foredeck.</context>
      <utterance>Here. Rig this to the forward keg up there.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hurry up, rig the line!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The shark is in position, Hooper shouts, a moment too late.</context>
      <utterance>Get clear, damn you!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quint fires. The harpoon slams into the shark behind his head, half-way along the back in front of the big dorsal fin.</context>
      <utterance>Clear!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus H. Christ On a Crutch!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't we go in? Get another crack at him tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooper throttles back, and the roar of the diesels subsides and the boat resumes an even keel, slowly circling the ocean.</context>
      <utterance>We got a barrel on him. We can't lose him. We stay out here until we find him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's call in -- we can radio and have a big boat here in an hour...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You hired me, remember? It's my $10,000. It's my shark...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He corrects course slightly to keep the barrel buoy in sight. Hooper is sitting at the table, morose. Brody is staring at a couple of open cans of beans or beef stew, or some other crappy rations Quint has on board. Dirty spoons stuck in the open cans show us this has not been a formal dinner. Quint fumbles on the chart shelf and produces some of his home brew. He takes a pull, and hands it to Hooper, who takes a double. Brody touches the fresh abrasion on his forehead, where the fishing rod caught him. Quint bends forward and pulls his hair aside to show something near the crown.</context>
      <utterance>He's up again.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody looks politely. Hooper stirs himself.</context>
      <utterance>That's not so bad. Look at this: ...St. Paddy's Day in Knocko Nolans, in Boston, where some sunovabitch winged me upside the head with a spittoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quint is amused. He presents his own formidable forearm.</context>
      <utterance>Look here.  Steve Kaplan bit me during recess.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wire burn. Trying to stop a backstay from taking my head off.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody is fascinated. Quint and Hooper take a long pull from the bottle.</context>
      <utterance>Moray Eel. Bit right through a wet suit.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Face and head scars come from amateur amusements in the bar room. This love line here...  ...that's from some crazy Frenchie come after me with a knife. I caught him with a good right hand right in the snot locker and laid him amongst the sweetpeas.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hauls up his pants leg, revealing a wicked white scar.</context>
      <utterance>Ever see one like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bull shark scraped me while I was taking samples...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing! A pleasure scar. Look here -- He starts rolling up his own dirty pants leg.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody is drawn into their boasting comparisons. He secretly checks his own appendix scar, decides not to enter the contest.</context>
      <utterance>Slammed with a thresher's tail. Look just like somebody caressed me with a nutmeg grater...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll drink to your leg.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They toast each other. Brody looks around, sees the strobe blink once through the darkened window.</context>
      <utterance>And I'll drink to yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts lowering his pants to reveal a place on one hip where the tissue is scarred and irregular.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute, young fella. Look. Just look. Don't touch...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Mako. Fell out of the tail rope and onto the deck. You don't get bitten by one of those bastards but twice -- your first and your last.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooper is pulling at his shirt, trying to get it off, but it's tangling its sleeves, and won't come undone.</context>
      <utterance>I think I can top that, Mister...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody lends a hand. The shirt slips part way off.</context>
      <utterance>Gimme a hand, here. I got something to show you --</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men raise their mugs in a toast.</context>
      <utterance>There. Right there. Mary Ellen Moffit broke my heart. Let's drink to Mary Ellen.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drinks, Hooper follows.</context>
      <utterance>And here's to the ladies. And here's to their sisters; I'd rather one Miss than a shipload of Misters.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look a' that -- Bayonet Iwo Jima.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon. Middle appendix --</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody is looking at a small white patch on Quint's other forearm.</context>
      <utterance>I almost had 'im.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that one, there?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tattoo. Had it taken off.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't tell me -- 'Death Before Dishonor.' 'Mother.' 'Semper Fi.' Uhhh... 'Don't Tread on Me.' C'mon -- what?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'U.S.S Indianapolis.' 1944.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that, a ship?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quint remembering.</context>
      <utterance>You were on the Indianapolis? In '45? Jesus...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a brief, eerie pause. Quint breaks the silence by muttering into song, which he slowly swells.</context>
      <utterance>It's a whale out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Show me the way to go home... I'm tired and I want to go to bed. I had a little drink about an hour ago, and it went right to my head.  Gradually, Hooper and Brody join in, and the pilothouse becomes a warm cozy place.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Brody hears this and is about to stop singing, the boat is suddenly bumped from below, and the gentle scraping turns to a violent assault somewhere on the understructure of the vessel. Water bubbles up into the hold. Brody starts, and looks at the radio. He is about to move towards it when Quint's urgent instructions stop him.</context>
      <utterance>Start the engines.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's busting the shaft! Start the pump!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where...?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaves Brody in the pilot house, and runs onto the deck, grabbing his M-1 rifle as he goes. Brody hits a switch and we hear the pumps starting.</context>
      <utterance>The bilge pumps. There --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooper does.</context>
      <utterance>Cut the engines!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boat is assaulted again. Quint fires over the stern, emptying a clip into the water.</context>
      <utterance>Rudder bearings?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody moves cautiously up to the bow.</context>
      <utterance>Get up forward! Watch for him!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooper stands ready on the bridge, Quint pacing the stern deck.</context>
      <utterance>Keep your eyes open, Mr. Hooper!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He jams a fresh clip into the M-1. The men scan the seas around them. Quint resumes their song, louder this time, more defiant.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody sleeps! Nobody.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Show me the way to go home... I'm tired and I want to go to bed.  Hooper and Brody join in from their respective positions.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody tries to comply.</context>
      <utterance>More left rudder! More! Left hand down now, Chief.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quint hammers again.</context>
      <utterance>Lemme get a better angle on it. Now.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And we can. The Orca's diesels are no longer smooth. Brody suddenly sees something, and points.</context>
      <utterance>He's bent the housing. You can hear it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The strobe light winks at them. Quint holds up a hand: "Quiet!" Everything stops as they watch the barrel coming slowly up on them.</context>
      <utterance>The barrel!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a killing lance from the rack. Hooper gets a boathook.</context>
      <utterance>It's him.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooper leans out gingerly, snagging the barrel with the hook. It bobs lightly in the water, an innocent bystander. Hooper shifts his pole, takes hold of the rope, poling it in.</context>
      <utterance>He's under the keg. Careful --</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here -- gimme. I don't see what he's been doin'.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The diesels start with a terrible grinding.</context>
      <utterance>Haul in that rope -- it'll foul us!  Start the engine!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy! It'll tear right out!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooper slams the hatch, kicks the tools to one side, clearing the deck for action once again.</context>
      <utterance>The shaft is giving.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it! Radio in for help!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up! Just pump her out!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody heads for the radio in the pilot house.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Captain, as soon as I make a call.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Duty first and pleasure after --</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE - BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>looking up in horror, covering his face.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody's adrenaline turns his fear into rage. His glasses are cracked or broken by flying pieces of radio. He seizes the bat, and pound the shattered radio for emphasis.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His tirade is interrupted by an urgent bellow from Hooper.</context>
      <utterance>Some great idea! Now where are we? Some goddamn skipper you are. You're certifiable, y'know that? You're a real treat! Certifiable! Bananas!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE - HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pointing at the fin.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coming right to us!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- comin' right at us! Slow ahead, he'll hit us head on --  Slower! Throttle back ---</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooper pulls the boat into a tight turn and Quint has a shot at the upward rolling flank. He sinks it with careful precision.</context>
      <utterance>Hard to port!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody emerges from the cabin as the rope zips overboard, and the barrel, changing over, catapults into the air before plunging into the ocean in a cloudy splash.</context>
      <utterance>Try shakin' that out!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you get him in the head?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! No! No!  Swing around! After him!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More gas... go to half! Get me right alongside him -- The engine thuds and knocks.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly the barrel gongs into the side of the Orca.</context>
      <utterance>We can't rev it up this high --</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooper skillfully avoids the speeding rope.</context>
      <utterance>Watch it!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quint leans to one side, harpoon over his head. The Great White breaks water and...</context>
      <utterance>Atta boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sinks it deep. We hear shots. As the new rope whips out, Brody can be seen standing on the gunwale, in regulation police combat pistol stance, holding his .357 in both hands, firing at the shark's head. Quint shakes his head in amused disbelief at this, as the barrel goes over.</context>
      <utterance>Take two, they're small!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't shoot him any more! He's crazy on his own blood already!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't stand here doing nothing!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Order in the court!</utterance>
   <speaker>WATER LEVEL ANGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He has seen the two barrels pop to the surface.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He yells to Hooper and Brody as he swings behind the controls.</context>
      <utterance>Three'll do it! He's havin' trouble with two!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quint steers "Slow Ahead," engine protesting, as he maneuvers toward the moving barrels. Quint peers down, steering closer and closer.</context>
      <utterance>Grab yourselves a couple of poles!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Together Brody and Hooper hook a barrel-rope and hold on for dear life as the shark changes course.</context>
      <utterance>Get ready! Now snag 'em!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody and Hooper pull in with all they are worth as Quint helps out by wheeling in a circle. He laughs to himself, enjoying the spectacle.</context>
      <utterance>Pull in the ropes and tie 'em onto the transom -- free ride.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FLYBRIDGE - QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>sees the fin ahead. It is pulling the boat.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The shark leaps partially out of the water, and the sight is both horrifying and awesome. Its jaws break water, snapping at the ropes that have him snarled and frustrated. Quint throws the Orca into neutral and shouts down:</context>
      <utterance>Get tired! That's the idea! Here's a little reverse for you!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that, Quint slides down to the prow, putting another shaft onto his gun, finding satisfaction in its heft and balance. The shark can be seen directly ahead, threshing closer.</context>
      <utterance>Haul in -- watch the prop!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He fires the iron, and the shark veers downward in a gushing shower of spray.</context>
      <utterance>Now! Untie 'em! Quick! He'll tear us to pieces.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody looks down at his feet. There is salt water up to their shoe tops.</context>
      <utterance>He can't go so deep. Not with all those on him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about us?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The barrels start a wide circle, each cuts through the water, pushing a wave before it and leaving a wake behind.</context>
      <utterance>Have to pump her steady, s'all.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quint tosses Brody the hand pump, then picks up his M-1, and checks the load.</context>
      <utterance>Follow him --  You start pumpin' out here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's heading under -- !</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way! He can't!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brody looks around. Hooper on the flying bridge searching in all directions. Quint is looking more appalled every second.</context>
      <utterance>Where'd he go?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He can't stay down with three barrels on him! Where is he?!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you ever had one do this?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Booming thud at the keel. Brody slides on the wet deck and Quint loses his footing, falling into Brody's arms.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Follow him!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's under!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The barrels have surfaced and we see the monster shadow sliding under the Orca, seemingly endless. Violent scraping sounds.</context>
      <utterance>There!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's trying to sink us!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quint is grimly silent. Brody senses that Quint is in the fight of (and for) his life. The Orca taking evasive action. But the three barrels are closing the gap, the engines coughing and missing, destroying themselves with every rotation of the damaged shaft.</context>
      <utterance>Dead astern! Zig-zag!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's chasing us! I don't believe it.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Full throttle! To port!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaps to his gear, trying desperately to get his dart gun. Just then, the shark attacks, breaking water and rising over the boat like a rocket; snout, jaws, pectoral fins, belly, falling sideways. A vast spray drenches the men. Quint fires into the belly, the bullets pocking the smooth whiteness.</context>
      <utterance>Hold her.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boat surges, the shark gives a final unbalances wrench, and disengages. The dorsal fin circles off, beginning a wide loop around the boat. The engine quivers and dies, the boat without power, rolling half awash, a wounded victim. The fin dips, the barrels follow, the shark disappears beneath the waves. There is complete silence.</context>
      <utterance>Throttling back!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can that gun of yours do?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Power head with 20 ccs of strychnine nitrate. If I can hit him. I can kill him. But I gotta be close. Very close.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta go in the water...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>QUINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's comin' up -- !</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's taken him!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quint...?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(notices something</context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
   <speaker>O.S.)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think we can get back with those?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What day is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wednesday... No, it's Tuesday, I think.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think the tide's with us?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just keep kicking.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'know, I used to hate the water...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't imagine why.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
