<movie id="320" title="Jay and Silent Bob Strike Back">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks up at the bright sun, shielding her eyes slightly, then looks back at the baby on the ground. She takes off her baseball cap and places it on the baby.</context>
      <utterance>Bobby-Boy stay here while mommy picks up the free cheese, 'kay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks away, leaving the baby sitting against the wall. With the backwards baseball cap and the chocolate around his mouth forming something that resembles a beard, the kid looks kind of familiar. Then, another MOTHER (also very young) decked out in a KISS concert shirt from years gone by and huge, feathered hair enters, with a black skullcap wearing BABY slung at her hip. She sees the first Baby, sitting against the wall and sets her Baby down beside him.</context>
      <utterance>This'll keep the sun out of your eyes. You be good now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A PASSERBY enters, heading toward the convenience store. He takes note of the Babies and the Mother heading into the record store, and then stops and addresses her, disgusted.</context>
      <utterance>Don't fucking move, you little shit- machine. Mommy's gonna try to score.</utterance>
   <speaker>PASSERBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me--who's watching these babies?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The fat one's watching the little one.</utterance>
   <speaker>PASSERBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Passerby walks away. The Mother flips him the bird.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, nice parenting.  Leave'em out here like that and see what happens.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PASSERBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, keep on truckin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck, fuck, fuck...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pair of TEENS approach them.</context>
      <utterance>--fuck, fuck, fuck, mother-mother fuck, mother-mother fuck-fuck! Mother- fuck-, mother-fuck, mother-fuck, noinch, noinch, noinch, smoking weed, smoking weed, doing coke, drinking beers! Drinking beers, beers, beers, rolling fatties, smoking blunts! Who smokes the blunts? We smoke the blunts!</utterance>
   <speaker>TEEN 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lemme get a nickel bag.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fifteen bucks, little man. Put the money in my hand. If the money does not show, then you owe-me-owe-me- owe.  My Jungle Love! Yes, Oh-we-oh-we-oh! I think I want to know ya', know ya'--</utterance>
   <speaker>TEEN 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you singing?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know "Jungle Love"? That shit is the mad notes. Written by God Herself and handed down to the world's greatest band--the motherfucking Time.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEEN 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The guys in that Prince movie?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEEN 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Purple Rain.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEEN 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay suddenly grabs the kid by the throat, throwing him against the wall.</context>
      <utterance>Man, that shit was so gay--fucking eighties style.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, RANDAL exits the video store, locking the door behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Bitch, don't you NEVER say an unkind word about The Time! Me and Silent Bob modeled our whole fucking lives after Morris Day and Jerome! I'm a smooth pimp who loves the pussy, and Tubby here's my black manservant!</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He exits. Jay, Silent Bob, and the Teens watch him go. After a beat--</context>
      <utterance>What'd I tell you two about dealing in front of the store? Drop the kid and peddle your wares someplace else, burn-boy.  And for the record, The Time sucked ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo-youse guys wanna hear something fucked up about him and the Quick Stop guy?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>RANDAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, can't we do something about those two stoners hanging around outside all the time?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? What'd they do now?</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm trying to watch Clash of the Titans, and all I can hear is the two them screaming about Morris Day at the top of their lungs.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought the fat one didn't really talk much.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, am I producing an A&amp;E Biography about 'em? I'm just saying they shouldn't be loitering around the stores like they do.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Neither should you, but we let you stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, man--if you were funnier than that, ABC never would've canceled us.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Enter Teen 1 and Teen 2, chuckling.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEEN 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two packs of Wraps.  Yo--how was the service?</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What service?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEEN 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The one at the Unitarian church where you two got married to each other last week.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEEN 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jay said you had a Star-Wars--themed wedding and you guys tied the knot dressed like storm troopers.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEEN 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. And he said you're the bitch and you're the butch. Oh, sorry--the Leia and the Luke.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the bitch?!</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well if we were gay, that's how I'd see it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you shut up?!</utterance>
   <speaker>TEEN 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy shit, dude. The honeymoon's over.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not married to each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEEN 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, sure. Not in the eyes of the state or any real church, Skywalker.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That does it. I'm gonna do something about those two. I shoulda done a long time ago</utterance>
   <speaker>TEEN 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In a galaxy far, far away!</utterance>
   <speaker>TEEN 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May the Foreskin be with you. Hand Jabba the Hutt.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I want to report a couple of drug dealers out in front of the Quick Stop.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the Fuck, Serpico? What'd we do?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got a report that two guys were hanging around outside the stores, selling pot?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Teen 1 enters and hands Jay rolling papers.</context>
      <utterance>We don't smoke pot, yo.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEEN 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Teen 1 races off. Jay and Bob move to follow, but the Cop stops them, grabbing the rolling papers out of Jay's hand. He eyeballs the pair.</context>
      <utterance>Here're the rolling papers you wanted for your pot. And your change. Thanks.  And The Time sucks ass!</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No pot, hunh? What do you need this for?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay drops his pants and leans against the wall, looking back over his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>What? I got a wiping problem. I stick these little pieces of paper over my brown-eye, and bam--no shit stains in my undies.  You don't believe me? Lemme show you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just spread my cheeks a little and you can see the fucking stink nuggets--</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay bends down to pull up his pants and FARTS. Silent Bob cracks up. The Cop grabs them both, leading them toward the car.</context>
      <utterance>Pull up your pants up sir, Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's take a ride down to the station.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? It's suddenly a crime to fart, motherfucker?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>BRODIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dante and Randal slapped you with a restraining order?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Judge said if we go within a hundred feet of the stores, we get thrown into County.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you gonna abide by the court's ruling or you gonna go Bandit-- Reynolds style?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck yeah! You know what they make you do in county? Toss the fucking salad! I don't like this fuck's asshole; I'm gonna do it for some stranger?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess if you really wanted to hang out in from of a convenience store, you could just buy your own now-- what with all that money you guys made.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell yeah, bitch.  Wait a second--what money?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The money from the movie, dumb-ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck are you babbling about?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Bluntman and Chronic movie.  Oh my God--don't tell me you have no idea there's a movie being made of the comic you two were the basis for.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?! Since when?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brodie leads them back to the counter.</context>
      <utterance>Goddamit, man--  Here's the pulse, alright. And here's your finger--  --far from the pulse, jammed straight up your ass.  Say--would you like a chocolate covered pretzel?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brodie hands Jay and Silent Bob a copy of Wizard, opened to the headline: Snootchie Bootchies! Bluntman and Chronic Get Big Screen Treatment! There are pictures of HOLDEN MCNEIL AND BANKY EDWARDS, as well as drawings of Bluntman and Chronic.</context>
      <utterance>You see, kids, if you read Wizard, you'd know it's the top story this month. Check it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When the fuck did this happen?!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, after X-Men hit at the box office, all the studios started buying up every comic property they could get their hands on. Miramax optioned Bluntman and Chronic.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miramax? I thought they only made classy flicks like The Piano and The Crying Game?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well once they made She's All That, everything went to hell. So you're saying you haven't gotten a cut of the movie? Didn't Holden McNeil and Banky Edwards used to pay you likeness rights for the comic book?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We haven't seen a fucking dime for no movie!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well boys, I'm no lawyer, but I think Holden and Banky owe you some of the proverbial phat cash. I mean they're making a movie based on characters that are based on you and Quiet Robert.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It ain't me and Quiet Robert. It's a pair of stupid-ass superheroes that run around saying "Snitchy-Nitchies" or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I believe it "Snootchie Boochies." Regardless--you're getting screwed. If I was you guys, I'd confront Holden McNeil and ask him for my movie check.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit yeah. We gotsa get paid.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRODIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay lays down a House bass beat. Brodie complements it with his own beat.</context>
      <utterance>And on that note, we cue the music.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay and Silent Bob enter. Holden closes the door, following them.</context>
      <utterance>Well! I have been waiting years to do this.  Look at these morose motherfuckers right here. Smells like someone shit in their cereal. Bunngg!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck took you so long answering your damn door? You trying to talk another girlfriend of yours into some of that gay-ass three-way action with your buddy?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silent Bob shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>No, I was just showering your mother's stink off me after I gave her a quick jump and sent her home. But now that you mention it--  Thanks, you know. You could've made the moral of that story you told me a bit more clear.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what brings you two dirt merchants to my neck of the woods?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'll tell you what our necks are doing in your woods-- Silent Bob holds up the Wizard article.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's our motherfucking movie check?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You heard about that too, Hunh? Well, I've got nothing to do with it. That's Banky's deal. He owns the property now. I signed my half of the Bluntman and Chronic right over to him years ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why the fuck would you do a thing like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silent Bob nod like he's finally understood. Jay looks at him, hurt, and Bob tried to downplay the comment's truth.</context>
      <utterance>Because I'm almost thirty, for God's sake--why on earth would I want to keep writing about characters whose central preoccupations are weed and dick and fart jokes? You gotta grow, man. Don't you ever want more for yourself?  I know this poor, hapless sonovabitch does. I look in his doe eyes and I see a man crying out, "When, Lord? When the fuck can your servant ditch this foul-mouthed little chucklehead to whom I am a constant victim of his folly, and who bombards me and those around us with grade-A foolishness that prevents me from even getting to kiss a girl? Fuck! When?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the chucklehead? Fuck you--you're the dumb-ass who gave away his comic, and now you ain't got no fat movie check neither.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When you're right, you're right. I wish I'd broken off a little piece for myself. Because if the buzz is any indication, the movie's gonna make some huge bank.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What buzz?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Internet buzz.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck is the Internet?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="34">
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Internet is a communication device that allows people the world over to bitch about movies and share pornography with one another.  Here's what we're looking for: "Movie PoopShoot.com"</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"PoopChute." Yeaaahhh.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the computer monitor, we see the site mainpage load up. Holden begins navigating the site.</context>
      <utterance>This is a site full of militant movie buffs: sad bastards who live in their parents' basements, downloading scripts and trading what they believe to be inside info about movies and actors they despise yet can't stop discussing. This is where you go if you wanna hear frustrated would-be filmmakers mouth off with their two- bit, arm-chair-director's opinions on how they all could've made a better Episode One.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here. This is about the Bluntman movie.  "Inside sources tell me Miramax is starting production this Friday on their adaptation of underground comic fave Bluntman and Chronic."</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Friday?! Shit. Does it say who's playing us in the movie?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, but if it's Miramax, I'm sure it'll be Ben Affleck and Matt Damon. They put'em in a bunch of movies.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know--the guys from Good Will Hunting.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean the fucking movie with Mork from Ork in it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'm not too big a fan either. Though Affleck was the bomb in Phantoms.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holden and Jay slap hands. Holden points at the monitor again.</context>
      <utterance>Word, bitch. Phantoms like a motherfucker.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now down here is where you can gauge the buzz. This is the Shoot Back area. It's where people who read the news get to chime in with their two cents. Here's what a guy who goes by the chick-magnet Net handle of "Wampa- One" thinks about Bluntman and Chronic.  "Bluntman and Chronic and their stupid alter egos Jay and Silent Bob only work in small doses, if at all. They don't deserve their own movie."  He's got a point.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck him. What's the next one say?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Bluntman and Chronic is the worst comic I ever read. Jay and Silent Bob are stupid characters. A couple of stoners who spout dumb-ass catchphrases like a third-rate Cheech and Chong or Bill and Ted. Fuck Jay and Silent Bob. Fuck them up their stupid asses."</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the fuck said that shit?!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A guy who calls himself "Magnolia- Fan." Check out what the guy after him said: "Jay and Silent Bob are terrible, one-note jokes that only stoners laugh at. They're fucking clown shoes. If they were real, I'd beat the shit out of them for being so stupid. I can't believe Miramax would have anything to so with this shit. I, for one, will be boycotting this movie. Who's with me?"  And then there are about fifty more posts from people who agree to join Spartacus-here's boycott of the flick.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna kill all these fucks--</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, let it go. Number one, they're a bunch of jealous little dicks who use the anonymity of the Net to insult people who're doing what they wish they were doing, and number two, they're not really talking about you guys--they talking about Bluntman and Chronic.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But they said Jay and Silent Bob! They used our real names. It doesn't matter that there's a comic book version of us and a real version, 'cause nobody knows we're real in real life.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah! And all these people who read that shit think the real Jay and Silent Bob are a couple of faggots 'cause of that all these dicks are writing about the comic book Jay and Silent Bob! And maybe one night, me and Lunchbox'll be macking some bitch, and she'll be like "Oooo! I want to suck youse guys dicks off. What's your names?" And I'll be like, "Jay and Silent Bob." And she'll be like, "Oh--I read on the Internet that youse guys were little fucking jerkoffs." And then she goes and sucks two other guys's dicks off instead! Well fuck that! We gotta put a stop to these hateful sonsa- bitches before they ruin our good names!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First off, I don't know how good your names really are. Secondly, there's not much you can do about stopping this bile. The Internet's given everyone in America a voice, and everyone in American has chosen to use that voice to bitch about movies. As long as there's a Bluntman and Chronic movie, the Net-nerds are gonna have something negative to say about it. Jay steams, thinking. Then, a light dawns on him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But wait a second--if there wasn't a Bluntman and Chronic movie, then no one would be saying shit about Jay and Silent Bob, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're not saying anything about you now--they're talking about fictional characters!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So all we gotta do is stop 'em from making the movie!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holden, Jay and Silent Bob pause and look at the camera for a beat. Then--</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, and kiss-off the hundreds of thousands of dollars in royalties you're due in the process. Are you fucking retarded? Look, I'm probably not alone in the opinion that this flick is the worst idea since Greedo shooting first. I mean, a Jay and Silent Bob movie? Who would pay to see that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But since it is happening, you might as well just ignore the idiots on the Internet, go find Banky, and get your "motherfucking movie check." As you so succinctly put it. That's what's important here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Holden McNeil--what's important here is that there's a bunch of motherfuckers we don't even know calling us assholes on the Internet to a bunch of teenagers and guys who can't even get laid. Putting a stop to that is the most important thing we could ever do.  When did it say they're making that movie?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They start this Friday.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So if today's Tuesday, that gives us--  Eight days.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's more like three days.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay and Bob stand and look at each other, filled with purpose.</context>
      <utterance>Right. Three days to stop that stupid fucking movie from getting made! C'mon, Silent Bob--</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stride off. Holden shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>We're going to Hollywood.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now that's what I call the Blunt leading the Blunt.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They head toward the depot.</context>
      <utterance>Tickets? Since when did they start charging for the bus?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't we used to ride that shit to school every day for free?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We in Hollywood yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a three--day ride to Los Angeles, sir. We left twenty minutes ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't ask you about Los Angeles. I asked you about Hollywood.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hollywood's in Los Angeles, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't change the subject! Are we in Hollywood yet or not?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay glares at the Driver and heads back to his seat.</context>
      <utterance>Please sit down, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you take your seat Ralph Kramden-- Jay slumps into the seat beside Silent Bob.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silent Bob mimes jerking off.</context>
      <utterance>I'm fucking bored, man. There ain't shit to so on this bus.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silent Bob shrugs, looking out the window, Jay looks across the aisle and spots a CHILD IN A HELMET playing a handheld video game. He leans over to him.</context>
      <utterance>I already did that. Twice.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo, Gretzky--lemme get a turn.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHILD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Child gives him the finger. Jay goes wide-eyed, turning to Silent Bob.</context>
      <utterance>Leave me alone, little kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silent Bob offers an incredulous look, as if to say, "He's ten years old."</context>
      <utterance>That fuck called me a little kid and gave me the finger! Go kick his ass!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silent Bob kind of nods.</context>
      <utterance>You're my muscle, ain'tcha?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silent Bob sighs and stands. He climbs over Jay into the aisle and stands in front of the child. He looks at him and registers doubt. He looks back to Jay, who waves him on. Silent Bob steels himself, looks back to the kid and reaches for his game. The Child emits a high-pitched scream and starts punching himself in the head. Silent Bob dives back into his seat, trying to look nonchalant. The Child stops crying. Jay looks at Silent Bob.</context>
      <utterance>So go open a can of whup-ass on that little fuck, and get me his game!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're one tough motherfucker, you know that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PASSENGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bus Driver bangs on the bathroom door and shouts.</context>
      <utterance>They been in there going on half an hour now! Two of them! Doing God knows what!</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer. The Bus Driver bangs on the door harder.</context>
      <utterance>This bus isn't moving another inch unless you clear out of there right now!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This sucks balls, man. How come we ain't getting no rides?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay and Bob look behind them. There's a GUY hitching as well.</context>
      <utterance>'Cause you're doing it all wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta induce the drivers a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like how?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The GUY holds out his sign to them. It reads: Will Give Head For Ride.</context>
      <utterance>Like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but what happens when you get in the car, and you don't make with the head? Don't they kick your ass to the curb?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay and Bob look at him for a long beat. Then--</context>
      <utterance>Sure--if you don't make with the head.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eww! You eat the cock?!?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. If it'll get me a few hundred miles across country. I'll take a shot in the mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but we ain't gay.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, neither am I. But have you seen the price of bus tickets lately? Shit--I don't wanna cough up two hundred bucks just to get to Chicago.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't wanna cough up some dude's sperm!</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be so suburban--this is the new millennium. Gay, straight--it's all the same now. There're no more lines. Jay draws a line on the ground with his foot.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's one. On this side of it, we ain't gay.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All hitchers do this. Why do you think people pick us up? If you get a ride, it's expected--I don't care who the driver is. It's the first rule in the Book.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What book?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A TRUCK starts to pull over to the side of the road. The Guy points to it, as if to say "See?" The passenger-side door opens. The Guy climbs into the truck and closes the door. He looks out the window at Jay and Bob.</context>
      <utterance>The unwritten Book of the Road.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Through the windshield, Jay and Silent Bob see the Guy go face-first into the TRUCK DRIVER'S lap. The Truck Drivers smiles, and the truck takes off, roaring down the road. Jay and Silent Bob watch the truck disappear. Then, a CAR pulls up. The NUN driving rolls down the passenger side window and leans toward them.</context>
      <utterance>Follow the rules of the Book, and you'll get where you're going in no time. Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You two boys need a ride?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silent Bob shakes his head "no" to Jay. Jay shrugs and climbs up front.</context>
      <utterance>You both don't have to sit back there. One of you can sit up here with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So where are you boys from?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>New Jersey.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What brings you to Indiana?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to Hollywood.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hollywood, hunh? That's a long ways away.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah--we're lucky you picked us up.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, do unto others. That's what the Book says.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute--you follow the Book, too?</utterance>
   <speaker>NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I live my life by it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? You?</utterance>
   <speaker>NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course. You know how lonely it gets on the road? Thanks to the Book, I'm never alone--if you know what I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess. This guy back there explained it to us. But I didn't think you'd be into that.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding? I've dedicated my life to it. Every hour of every day.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit--you nuns are alright.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You live by the Book, too?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You picked us up, didn't you? I gotta.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's good to hear. But it takes deed, not words. It's a lot easier to say you live by the Book than to actually do it.  Can you do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want me to do it right now?</utterance>
   <speaker>NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay looks back at Silent Bob. Silent Bob shakes his head "no." Jay shrugs them flips his hair over his shoulder, and starts to bend down.</context>
      <utterance>No time like the present, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay disappears below the dash, The Nun goes wide-eyed.</context>
      <utterance>Alright.  You hear that? She's not a Catholic. She's a Presbyterian.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dude--she had seventies bush.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A familiar-looking VAN pulls up in the other side of the raid, The horn beeps. Jay and Bob look at each other, shrug, and race across the street, get in. The van pulls off.</context>
      <utterance>I can't believe this shit. Five hours and not a single ride. Every day, millions of people hitch to Hollywood and stop studios from making movies about 'em. But when you and me try it, it's like we're trapped in a fucking cartoon!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zoinks, yo</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And now we can finally solve the mystery of the Hitchhiking Ghouls! Pull off their masks and let's see who they really are!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOKISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think they are masks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think they're Hitchhiking Girls either.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOKISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ghouls, you fucking moron. Not Girls.  Though I wish they were hitchhiking girls. Sexy, skimpily clad hitchhiking girls--</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's kick them out. We've got a mystery to solve.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The only mystery here is why we take our cues from a dick in a neckerchief!</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep it up, Beatnik! I'll feed you to the fucking dog!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GREAT DANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Great Dane rolls over, revealing its RED THING sticking way out of its sheath. It's monstrous. Jay and Bob go wide- eyed.</context>
      <utterance>Ri, Ray rand Rirent Rob</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We cut back to the gang, who now appear as they did prior to Weed-Vision. They stare at the O.C. Jay and Bob.</context>
      <utterance>Look at his fuckin' lipstick!!! He's got a stoner-boner!!! Jay and Bob smile and pass out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think they passed out.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great. What do we do with them now?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's cut out their kidneys to sell on the black market and leave them in a seedy motel bathtub full of ice.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOKISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God, not again?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob shrugs, heading for the terminal. He inserts a dollar and types, following it up with a mouse click. The pair look at the screen and go wide-eyed.</context>
      <utterance>Yo--check that shit out: the Internet. Let's see if those fucks said something new about us and that stupid flick.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay and Silent Bob look at each other, wide-eyed.</context>
      <utterance>"Any movie based on Jay and Silent Bob is gonna lick balls, because they both, in fact, lick balls. Namely each other's."</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silent Bob starts typing as Jay dictates.</context>
      <utterance>Eww.  "Yes--they are real people. Real stupid people. Signed, Darth Randal."  Motherfucker! It's time we wrote something back! Type this shit down.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silent Bob finishes typing and presses "Return". He and Jay nod at each other, then head over to the counter line, looking up at the menu board.</context>
      <utterance>All you motherfuckers are gonna pay. You are the ones who are the ball- lickers. We're gonna fuck your mothers whole you watch and cry like little bitches. Once we get to Hollywood and find those Miramax fucks who are making the movie, we're gonna make 'em eat our shit, then shit our shit, then eat their shit which is made of our shit that we made 'em eat. Then all you motherfuckers are next. Love, Jay and Silent Bob.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Jay finishes speaking, he looks to the O.C. doors and freezes. A gorgeous GIRL walks through the front doors, all in SLO-MO to the tune of Prince's The Most Beautiful Girl in the World. She's bathed in light, glowing. She bats her eyelashes, gliding toward us. Jay is mouth-agape wide eyed. Silent Bob looks at him, then at the O.C.Girl. He slowly waves his hand in front of Jay's eyes, getting zero response.</context>
      <utterance>That'll fucking show 'em. Now we eat our Egga-Mooby-Muffins, then get back on the road, get to Hollywood, and stop that fucking movie from getting made. No more hairy-bush nuns, no more dogs. We keep our eye on the prize, and not let nothing-- and I mean NOTHING--distract me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God. Do you get free refills with that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, what--this? I just wear this for protection. You know--so no guys try to grab my shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. I'm Justice.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I am so fucking yours-- Silent Bob pokes Jay, who shakes of his daze.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean hi. I'm Jay. And this is my hereto life-mate, Silent Bob.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's nice to meet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Justice, hunh? That's a nice name.  Jay'n'Justice, sitting in a tree. F-</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm not from around here. My friends and I are taking a road trip, and we just stopped to grab something to eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your friends, hunh? Where they at?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay and Bob look past Justice to see a VAN with three other gorgeous GIRLS stretching outside of it, throwing their hair around, looking incredibly sexy. Without looking at Silent Bob, Jay quietly says to him--</context>
      <utterance>Out there. By that van.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dude--I think I just filled the cup.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ladies, ladies, ladies! Jay and Silent Bob are in the Hizz-ouse!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the fuck are these guys?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Jay and Silent Bob.  Guys, this is Sissy, Missy, and Chrissy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where the fuck did they come from?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I met 'em inside. They're gonna hitch a ride.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know if that's such a great idea. Jussy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure it is, Juggs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my god--he just called Sissy "Juggs"!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chrissy lunges toward Jay, pulling a knife.</context>
      <utterance>I'm on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sissy stops Chrissy, shoving a burger into her hands.</context>
      <utterance>Chrissy, no!</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're in the middle of suburbia, Chrissy. Let's try to act like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what-stupid ass little foul- mouthed bitch-boys don't get their balls cut off in suburbia?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's with the knife? We having cake or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy shit--he's retarded, to boot.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo--she called you retarded.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with you, Justice? You do remember where we're going, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That we do have a job to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're just gonna tag along for a few miles. They won't get in the way, I promise.  Please?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine--they can ride with us. But they're so out of here before we get to Boulder.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honest Injun.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Honest Injun"?  I can't believe what a pushover you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, Jay and Bob are parted by BRENT, who's getting into the van.</context>
      <utterance>And I can't believe fine-ass bitches like yourselves eat that shit. Don't you know fast food makes girls fart?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sissy, Missy, and Chrissy immediately go from disgusted to sweet and airy, totally switching characters.</context>
      <utterance>Say--what's all this talk about farting?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY/CHRISSY/MISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi Brent!</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Brent. He's with us, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brent, tell these sillies that girls don't fart.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The very white Brent puts his hand out to be slapped by Jay and Silent Bob.</context>
      <utterance>Of course they don't! Only skeevy stoners fart.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay and Bob look at each other and roll their eyes.</context>
      <utterance>What up, homies?  Wow, Three guys, four girls--  What's the count boys?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>BRENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey there mister science-guy. Don't spray that aerosol in my eye. For I don't really want to die. I'm a noble rabbit!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you guys, like a cover band or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're the Kansas State chapter of S.A.A.C.--Students Against Animal Cruelty.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone lets out a whoop, except Jay and Bob.</context>
      <utterance>And we're on our way to Colorado to give Provasik a piece of our minds!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck are you bitches babbling about?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay and Silent Bob eyeball Brent, until Justice distracts them.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Watch the language little boy. There are females present.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Provasik Pharmaceuticals is a medical lab where they perform gross experiments on animals.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, what kind of animals are we talking about here--like bears and rhinos?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay sees this and his eyes flare over the competition. After a beat, he relaxes.</context>
      <utterance>No--more like rabbits, dogs, cats... heck, even monkeys, If we don't speak for them, who will?  Right, Jussy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brent joins Jay, strumming his guitar. Jay addresses him confidentially.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, uh--Brent? Can I talk to you over here for a second?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be honest, yo--you're down with this for the fine-ass pussy, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm down with this because I love animals, stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even sheep?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course. Sheep are beautiful creatures.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They are beautiful, aren't they?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So then you'd fuck a sheep?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is your damage little boy? You've got a sick and twisted world perspective.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you misunderstand me, Prince Valiant. I mean if you were another sheep. Would you fuck a sheep if you were another sheep?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I--suppose so.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I thought.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="32">
   <speaker>CHRISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck are we gonna do now?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the back, Justice studies some blueprints. Jay joins her, and she quickly folds them up.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up, I'm thinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is Hollywood near where we're going?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that where you guys are from?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ch'yeah, right. Jersey represent!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, a Jersey Boy. What brings you all the way out here?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we couldn't hang in front of the Quick Stop no more, 'cause of the strainen-en order, which sucks ass 'cause it's been like our home since we were kids. Silent Bob even busted his cherry there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, fuck that fat fuck--I'm trying to tell a story here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyway, we were talking to Brodie and he said there's gonna be a Bluntman and Chronic movie. So we went to see Holden McNeil, and he showed us the Internet, and that's where we found all these fucking little jerkoffs were saying shit about us. So we decided to go to Hollywood and stop the movie from getting made. And now we're here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. I have no idea what you just said.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I get that a lot. So you like animals, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's cool. Even snakes?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't exclude an animal just because it's not cuddly. Of course I like snakes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about trouser snakes?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, a little JAY DEVIL appears on Jay's left shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>What's a trouser snake?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY DEVIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck are you waiting for? She went for the setup! Reach in your fucking pants, and pull yer cock out, bitch! That's the kinda shit girls like! Suddenly another little JAY DEVIL appears in Jay's right shoulder.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY DEVIL 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They disappear in little puffs of smoke and Jay shoves his hand down his pants, getting ready to whip out his dick, when suddenly a little JAY ANGEL appears on his shoulder, rubbing a swollen jaw.</context>
      <utterance>Right about here's where the angel's supposed to show up and tell you not to pull your dick out. But we bitch- slapped that little fuck and sent him packing, so it's smooth sailing. Let 'er rip, boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay thinks, then nods "Yes." The Jay Angel rolls his eyes, and slaps him.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry I'm late. So what's the deal here?  Oh, shit--you're not thinking of whipping your dick out at this fine piece of woman, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay looks to Silent Bob. Silent Bob looks from Jay's hand in his pants to Jay and shakes his head "no," sternly. Jay withdraws his hand from his pants. The Jay Angel nods, satisfied.</context>
      <utterance>Tell you what: look at Silent Bob. See if he thinks it's a good idea to whip your dick out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it, boy--put the dick down. You gotta go from the heart, yo. No little perv bullshit will do for this one. Be smooth. Be Don Juan de la Nootch. Now I gotta go beat the shit out of two suckerpunching little bitches. Remember--don't pull your dick out until she asks you to.  Or until she sleeping. Bunnnnggg! The Jay Angel blinks away. Justice looks at Jay, a bit confused.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't ask.  So, uh--what can a pimp-daddy like me do to help the animals?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really don't want to help us--</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Justice smiles. Jay tries to recover.</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck are you talking about? Sure I do. I'd do anything for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, youse guys! I'd do anything for youse guys. For the lift and shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, I'm sure. I said it, didn't I. Fuck</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well--okay. Let me talk it over with the other girls and get back to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay takes Justice's hand and kisses it.</context>
      <utterance>You do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He winks at her, smiles and moves to the other side of the can, near Silent Bob. He's still smiling at Justice and winking when he looks to Silent Bob who stares at him blankly, then imitates Jay's hand-kissing back at him, Jay scowls.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you. Fatty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys want anything from inside?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Justice smiles and heads inside. Jay and Silent Bob study the front of the foreign convenience store. They look for a place to lean, try a few spots out, then settle into one. After a beat--</context>
      <utterance>No, we're cool, thanks hon.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silent Bob shakes his head "Yeah."</context>
      <utterance>It just ain't the same, is it? This place licks balls compared to Quick Stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And speaking of licking balls--how 'bout that Justice chick? She is too fine. And she smells so fucking pretty. She's got a nice voice, too. And that body? Smoking. You know, she never once said "fuck off," when I was talking to her, or pulled out the pepper spray, or nothing. I tell ya, Lunchbox--she could be the one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>MISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smooth move, Justice.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice going, Four Eyes!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ow!</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why the fuck did you let that little stoner throw Brent our of the van?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh please--if I had to listen to one more of those stupid songs, I was going to throw him out myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We needed Brent, Justice! He was our patsy!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll find someone else. Besides, I didn't see you trying to stop Jay from throwing him out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I didn't want to blow our cover!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cover, shmover--you all hated his songs, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Justice offers Chrissy a cold glance,</context>
      <utterance>Not as much as I hate you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck, if I don't get to kill someone soon, I'm gonna--fucking kill someone!</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't mind Chrissy. She's just a little too wound for sound.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chrissy grabs Missy forcefully and the pair make out, hot and heavy in the middle of the convenience store. Other customers regard them wide-eyed.</context>
      <utterance>Then how about you help me take the edge off?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're really good friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode>TO CHRISSY AND MISSY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you two knock it off? We're in the fucking heartland here! Try to blend!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They already do--she's the milkmaid, and she's the cow.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm a cow, am I? I'm a mad cow, bitch. And now I'm gonna rip your head off and fuck your spine stump.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enough!  We have a very simple gang here, Justice. I'm the brains, Chrissy's the brawn, and Missy's the tech-girl. But lately, I'm having a hard time figuring out what you're doing here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That makes two of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit--your name doesn't even fit the rhyme scheme.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's because very few names rhyme with "douchebag."</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chrissy drags Missy off. Justice and Sissy watch them go.</context>
      <utterance>You're dancing on my last nerve, Strawberry Shortcake.  You deal with the weak link. I'm gonna take Missy into the dirty convenience store bathroom and hate- fuck the shit out of her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you said letting them read all that Anais Nin wouldn't amount to anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't change the subject. You know what you have to do now, right? Since you let our patsy slip away, you've gotta convince the little kid and that fat guy to take his place. They've gotta break into Provasik now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-uh!</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh. You'll do it; or you're out of this gang. Just use the little one's crush to convince him, since he's so fucking in love with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jay? No he's not.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What--am I blind? He wasn't kissing your hand back in the van like he was fucking Lord Byron?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, maybe he was just raised with manners.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the one that brought the kid in, Jussy. So you've gotta make amends.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jay is not taking Brent's place as the patsy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That kid and his quite friend are our only options at this point. Now we got about two hours before we get to Boulder. That gives you plenty of of time to work on him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not gonna do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why the fuck not?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Justice looks out the window and smiles, seeing Jay dancing alongside Bob.</context>
      <utterance>Because he's just to so innocent!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at him--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Justice looks at Sissy. Sissy nods at her. Justice looks back out at Jay.</context>
      <utterance>Who's it going to be, Jussy--him or us?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Steal a monkey? Shit--no problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not really stealing--it's liberating it, and--  Wait a second--did you say, "No problem"?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silent Bob glares at Jay.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Fuck--we steal monkeys all the time.  Right, Lunchbox?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not like it's a bad thing. It's for a good cause.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, it for the best cause, mon cheri--  The cause of love.  Snoogans--</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the heck is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Snoogans," I believe it was.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck do you think it means? It means "I'm kidding."</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles at Jay, touches his chin and heads to the front of the van. Jay plays it cool until she's out of sight, then humps silent Bob's leg like a dog.</context>
      <utterance>Ohhh. Well, that's too bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay looks at Silent Bob, who clearly disapproves.</context>
      <utterance>I can't believe I'm gonna get some pussy for stealing a monkey!  If I'd known it was that easy, I'd've been stealing monkeys since I was like seven and shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Up front, Justice talks to Sissy, while Missy drives.</context>
      <utterance>Don't, motherfucker. Don't you ruin this for me. Me and Justice are gonna get married one day, so don't be giving me that "we-ain't-stealing-no- monkey" look. I'm Morris Day; you're Jerome, bitch. Don't forget that. That girl? That girl's in love with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're gonna do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Justice eyes Sissy, then slumps in her seat.</context>
      <utterance>Good. They do their part--  And we'll do ours.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember--we meet back here when you're done. You sure you're okay with this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chrissy lunges at Jay, Missy holds her back, dragging Chrissy away.</context>
      <utterance>As sure as I am that you're the hottest bitch I ever seen.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's twisting that bitch's tits?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's because women don't like to be called "bitches," Jay.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't? Well how 'bout "piece of ass"?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about not.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what the fuck am I supposed to call you, then?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something sweet, you big goof. Something nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boo-boo kitty fuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sissy jumps out of the van, holding the video camera, aiming it at Jay and Bob.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. That's a start.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jay, before you go, could you say something into the camera about the clitoris.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man you are such a bitch--</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's just a little embarrassed. See, Jussy and I are putting together this documentary for our Human Sexuality class, and we need a male perspective on the clitoris.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The female clitoris?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh--yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She elbows Sissy.</context>
      <utterance>Jay, you don't have to do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay proceeds to make some pussy-eating faces. Justice shakes her head at Sissy, who snaps the camera closed and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Nah, it's cool, hon. There's a few things I can say about the clit that I's like you to hear.  I am the master of the clit! I make that shit work! It does what ever the fuck I tell it to do! No one rules the clit like me!  Not this little fuck! None of you little fucks out there! I am the clit commander!!! Remember that-- commander of all clits!</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sissy climbs back into the van.</context>
      <utterance>Awesome. Knock 'em dead, Tiger.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So--can I get a little kiss for good luck? Justice smiles at Jay, then kisses him sweetly on the lips.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Justice smiles and pulls Jay's mask down. He heads off, revealing Silent Bob behind him, lips puckered, handing in midair. Jay reached back into the frame, pulling Bob out. Justice watches them go.</context>
      <utterance>So--can I get a little blow job for good luck?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Justice climbs back into the van.</context>
      <utterance>Jussy. C'mon.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Lover-girl. You cock-block my authority again, you lose your fucking fronts, you got that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sissy takes the tape out of the camera and hands it off to Missy, beside whom is a bag full of high-tech equipment.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Phase One, down. While we're executing Phase Two, you edit that tape and grab a new car.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No sweat.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's suit up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You fat fuck--</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They in?</utterance>
   <speaker>MISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can say that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Time to shine. Let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chrissy sticks a box on the door and presses a button. On a digital readout, numbers roll until they stop on four different digits. The door lock CLICKS open.</context>
      <utterance>You are so gay.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Justice blows her off. Sissy enters the building, followed closely by Chrissy. Justice lingers at the door, taking one last look back at the Provasik Building, fretting for Jay and Bob.</context>
      <utterance>Once we're inside, I want complete silence.  Missy whipped this up. It counts our decibel level. If it goes into the red--alarm, we're dead. So not even the slightest noise, got it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Justice heads inside. We PAN up to reveal a sign that reads:</context>
      <utterance>Justice! Move your ass!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silent Bob nods and clicks on a flashlight. The pair wade through the cages. Jay stops at an EMERGENCY BOX hanging on the wall. Inside it, there's a pistol.</context>
      <utterance>Stay frosty, you big fucking softie. We've got a job to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay elbows the glass, breaking it. He takes the gun out and tosses it to Bob.</context>
      <utterance>Check this out, Lunchbox. Animal tranquilizer. This shit fucks you up like Percocets!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silent Bob rolls he eyes and sticks the gun in his coat. The pair look through the cages, until HEAR the distinct SOUND OF A MONKEY. Jay directs Silent Bob's flashlight to the cage from where the sound emitted. He smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Hold this. Later, me and Justice can shoot each other with it and fuck like stoned test bunnies. Bunnggg.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Suzanne." Boo-yah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CHRISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Missy tosses a metal box to Chrissy, who catches it and races toward the van, while Sissy and Justice pile into the convertible.</context>
      <utterance>Boom Box!</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe it. Months of planning and it's all blown by a fucking fart.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't just leave them like this! That alarm's gonna bring the cops here any minute!</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chrissy attaches the metal box to the side of the van.</context>
      <utterance>That was always the plan, Justice! They take the heat off of is long enough until we can get out of town!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girls pull up in the convertible and Chrissy jumps into the car with them.</context>
      <utterance>Kaboom, you little stoner fucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The convertible screeches away, leaving the can sitting there. The metal has magnetically attached to the side is counting down from two minutes.</context>
      <utterance>It's set. Let's roll.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silent Bob half-gestures to the cages, forlorn. Jay shakes his head frustrated.</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck are you looking at? There ain't no snacks here, man! Now we got what we came for, so let's get the fuck out!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silent bob offers Jay a look.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it's sad! But what the fuck are we supposed to do about it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Willenholly emerges from the bathroom, holding the magazine. There's a massive wet spot on the front of his pants.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, we got a report of a break-in at Provasik Pharmaceuticals' testing lab.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Deputy looks at the stain on Willenholly's pants, then at Willenholly.</context>
      <utterance>Have you read this article on the mule-suckers in Tijuana? Good God, I wish that was in our jurisdiction-- I'd shut down every last one of those ass-cock chuggers, personally.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? "Ass" means "donkey."</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(hands him a fax)</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boulder, hunh? Well, gas up the jet.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't have a jet, sir. And Boulder's only ten minutes away.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then gas up the next best thing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My, oh my, oh my. Who let the cats out?  Wait--is that right?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP 1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Willenholly rips down the Velcro patch on his jacket, revealing a badge.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me--who the hell are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Federal Wildlife Marshal. This investigation is now under my jurisdiction.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh really? And why is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because someone let a whole mess of animals out of their cages, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we believe that was just a diversionary tactic used to call attention away from the real heist over here at the Diamond Exchange.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Willenholly and the Cop look at the camera. Then, another COP joins them.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, right. That's a believable scenario. It sounds more like something out of a bad movie.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, the Provasik people say they've rounded all their animals up, except for one: an orangutan.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen up, ladies and gentlemen! Our fugitive has been on the run for 6 hours! Average simian foot speed over uneven ground--barring injuries or preoccupation with tire tubes, mites or bananas--is four miles an hour. That gives us a radius of twenty miles.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP 3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty-four, sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP 3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six hours times four miles an hour is twenty-four.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Yes, you're right. My bad. Twenty- four miles. Now what I want out of all of you is a hard target search.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP 4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP 4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does that mean, exactly--a "hard target search"? What's a "hard target"?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well. It's--a target--that's--hard. Anyway--</utterance>
   <speaker>COP 4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So are you referring to the search's level of difficulty? Or is the hard target the monkey?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP 3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The COPS now chatter amongst themselves, to the effect of "Yeah--It could mean that too--He's got a point--,"etc. Willenholly rubs his temples.</context>
      <utterance>Or the people who stole the monkey?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, how about this? What I want out of all of you is a thorough search of every gas station, residence, warehouse, farmhouse, henhouse, outhouse, and doghouse in that area! Checkpoints go up at fifteen miles!</utterance>
   <speaker>COP 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They begin chattering amongst themselves again. Willenholly looks at them all, defeated. He starts to cry.</context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't it make sense to put them up at every twenty-four miles--seeing as that's how far they'd have gotten in the last six hours?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is so frustrating. It's just so hard sometimes--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>COP 5</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, this was just delivered to the station.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP 5</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a tape from the terrorists who're claiming credit for the break-in.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it VHS or Beta? You know what-- never mind. Do you have a VCR?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God--  Have the jet gassed up and ready to go at a moment's notice.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, we don't have a jet; just a helicopter.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't anybody have a jet anymore?  Plafsky? It is Willenholly. You gotta get me on the national news, pronto. Why?! Because we may very well be dealing with the two most dangerous men on the planet!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silent Bob offers the ape a weak wave. Suzanne drops her hands from her face and waves back. Jay cranes his neck to see over silent Bob.</context>
      <utterance>Do something. Tons of Fun!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suzanne nods. Jay steps out from behind Bob. They state at the ape.</context>
      <utterance>Is that fucking thing waving at us?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suzanne offer them a "raspberry." Spitting as if the comment was ridiculous. Jay and Silent Bob react with surprise at this.</context>
      <utterance>Holy shit? That monkey understood us! Maybe it's some sort of super- monkey!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suzanne holds her nose, as if to say, "Congo stunk." Silent Bob smiles in agreement and amusement. Jay looks at him, stung.</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck was that for? It's not a stupid idea! I seen it in Congo?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay looks around the woods, formulating a thought. Silent Bob moves toward the ape, extending his hand to shake hers.</context>
      <utterance>You're my bitch. You get my back. Don't go joining this chimp's side.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JAY'S DELUSION: We enter into JAY'S HEAD and see--</context>
      <utterance>Yo--what if there's more super monkeys up in the lab? Maybe they're making an army of 'em up there! Holy shit! Maybe it's a conspiracy--like on the X-Files Roswell--style!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silent Bob helps Jay to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>Alright--you can live. For now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see that? Bitches love me.  Besides--we're in the fucking clear, yo. It's not like anyone knows we stole the monkey.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANCHORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A graphic of the C.L.I.T. logo appears beside him, nailing home the joke.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Reg Hartner and this is a News Now bulletin. A Provasik animal testing facility in boulder was the focus of an attack by a terroristic primate rescue syndicate calling themselves the Coalition for Liberation of Itinerant Tree-Dwellers. Or simply, C.L.I.T.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANCHORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A VIDEO CAPTURE of JAY and SILENT BOB from pre-break--in appears on screen.</context>
      <utterance>In a videotape sent to authorities this morning, credit for the liberation of an orangutan from the lab last night is taken by these men--</utterance>
   <speaker>ANCHORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On screen is the C.L.I.T. Logo. A digitized voice narrates.</context>
      <utterance>--identified in literature that accompanies the tape as Jay and Silent Bob. In this chilling clip, they make it very clear that they are in control of the C.L.I.T.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGITIZED VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The logo gives way to the video of Jay and Bob that Sissy shot before the Provasik break-in. Jay's yelling into the camera.</context>
      <utterance>We are the C.L.I.T. None of you are safe. Now tremble before the might of our merciless leader.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ANCHORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PULL OUT to reveal Willenholly beside the Anchorman.</context>
      <utterance>Terrifying. Here to help us understand this footage is Federal Wildlife Marshal Willenholly.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANCHORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marshal, what can you tell us about the C.L.I.T.?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From the intelligence we've been able to gather, we've discovered that the C.L.I.T. is a tiny offshoot of the L.A.B.I.A.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANCHORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Liberate Apes Before Imprisoning Apes movement.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly. The men you saw in the video are believed to be the masterminds responsible for the frenzied C.L.I.T. activity last night. They go by the obvious code names "Jay" and "Silent Bob."  If you should come across them or any other C.L.I.T.-ies, please-- exercise extreme caution.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANCHORMAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marshal, how do you respond to allegations that Federal Wildlife Marshal's Office allowed the C.L.I.T. to slip through their fingers?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nonsense. We're all over the C.L.I.T., Reg.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nights like this, I miss dating a lesbian.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANCHORMAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there also speculation that Jay and Silent bob may be responsible for the Diamond Exchange jewel heist that occurred in the same vicinity of downtown Boulder last night?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's nothing to suggest that, no. But these men are still to be considered very dangerous.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you that restraining order was a good idea.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>ANCHORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that your cell phone?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Justice turns the TV off and yells up to Sissy.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Excuse me.  Federal Wildlife Marshal. I'm on my way!  We got 'em. They're in Utah.  Citizens of Utah--steer clear of the C.L.I.T. Stimulation of the C.L.I.T. is not recommended.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your tape worked. The news is all about Jay and Silent Bob's Provasik break-in, with almost no mention of the Diamond heist.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you those two were the perfect patsies. Now we lay low for awhile-- just in case--and start planning the next job.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you feel any regret? Jay and Bob don't deserve this. They were really sweet.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The only thing I regret is not gutting that little trout-mouthed prick like a fish and playing Twister with his vitals.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are so nasty.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll show you nasty, you little slut.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you two get a room?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chrissy dances away with Missy, heading inside. Sissy rolls her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Fine--we'll take yours.  I am gonna stain your sheets, bi- otch.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sarah Lawrence girls. Go figure.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're your gang.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh and not yours? You know, I don't get you, Justice. You used to be all about the girl stuff: stealing, boning, blowing shit up. Now you're like this little priss with a conscience. It's really a fucking drag.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We all gotta grow up some time.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If moping around over some little boy you're crushing on is being grown- up, then pass me my Wonder Woman underoos.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you feel the least bit of guilt for what we did to those guys?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sissy dumps the bag of diamonds over the side of the terrace. They rain down on Justice below. Just then a PIZZA DELIVERY GUY approaches the lower terrace, carrying a stack of pizzas.</context>
      <utterance>Awww. Does Jussy-wussy feel all dirty about setting up her boyfriend? Then how about taking a shower?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIZZA DELIVERY GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You the gals that ordered the pizzas?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This dopey bitch ordered the large plain, but I could go for some hot, thick, Sicilian.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIZZA DELIVERY GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No charge, lady. He rushes into the motel, Justice sighs, looking up at the stars.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Jay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silent bob and Suzanne are oblivious, digging into their food.</context>
      <utterance>You know, Justice died trying to save this monkey, so maybe we should keep her around. That way, we can honor her memory.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(singing, a la NWA)</context>
      <utterance>Look at you Tubby Bitches. I'm waxing all sentimental, and you're all about a fucking meal and shit. Now ain't you glad we stopped to eat? And you were all piss-scared the cops'd bust us or something. You know what I say?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>YOU HAVE SIXTY SECONDS TO COMPLY.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Willenholly rushes up, dramatically ducking behind the car, gun drawn.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck it, Let's give 'em thirty.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ape.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An orangutan's a member of the great ape family. It's not a monkey.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(into bullhorn)</context>
      <utterance>Look, who's the Federal Wildlife Marshal here?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silent Bob looks to Jay, shocked.</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck are you waiting for? Go out there and give 'em the monkey.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob pulls Suzanne close to him, welling up with tears. Jay rolls his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, what, man? I said that shit before I knew they were gonna shoot us! Yes--Jussy was a hottie, but I ain't takin' no bullet for no monkey!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suzanne shakes her head "no." Bob points to her, as if she's strengthening his point.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, brother--this is like something out of fucking Benji! Look man, maybe it's not that bad back at the lab! Maybe they experiment on 'em by, like making 'em fuck a bunch of different, good-looking monkeys. We don't know! Maybe they got it real sweet!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--kid</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From behind the cop car, the Sheriff looks to Willenholly.</context>
      <utterance>Don't shoot! We're just trying to take our son out of this hostile environment!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Their "son"?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay seizes on the idea. Silent Bob nods fervently.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe they're one of those gay couples?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah! We're gay! And this is our adopted love child! We're not from around here! Don't make us go back to our liberal city home with a tales of prejudice and bigotry in the heart of Utah!  You see the shit I gotta put up with for you! Now I got this guy thinking I'm gay!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God, this is the last thing I need--a bunch of uppity homosexuals shooting their mouth off in the liberal press that the Federal Wildlife Marshal's Office persecutes gays.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay is whispering to Silent Bob, still vexed by--</context>
      <utterance>You see this badge? I think I'd recognize an ape if I saw one. And the only thing I do recognize here is a political fiasco I'm, going to avoid by letting this butt-fucking Brady Bunch go!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I'll tell you another thing: what if that guy shows up around the stores one day and starts telling everybody you and me are poo-gilists? How are we gonna get any pussy then, hunh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So we can just go?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir--or ma'am. Please accept my apologies for detaining you and your unorthodox-but-constitutionally- protected-family unit.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Un-fucking believable.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to offer a big gay thank- you, sir. We'll tell all our gay friends that Utah is Gay friendly country for gays who are gay.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure Utah appreciates that. You might also want to make it clear that the Federal Wildlife Marshal's Office is also pro-'mo as well.  And might I add, that's one fine- looking boy you're raising.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's 'cuz he's from my sperm. See, I knocked up a hot woman friend of ours who I also fuck on the side. So as not to be all-the-way-gay. But my tubby husband here is one hundred percent queer. He loves the cock.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He certainly looks insatiable.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Bye</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay, silent Bob and Suzanne head off down the road. Willenholly and all watch them go. The Sheriff is livid.</context>
      <utterance>'Bye</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Willenholly suddenly freezes, thinking. He looks to the Sheriff.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it's not my way--but damned if there doesn't go one happy family.  Now, we just shoot some tear gas into that diner, and when the two guys run out with the monkey, we'll--</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was the them, wasn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>GUNSHOTS RING OUT, and bullets whiz by the trio, who are now in full panic mode. Willenholly and the Cops race after them, firing. Jay, Bob and Suzanne race away, ducking bullets.</context>
      <utterance>I said you "love the cock"! I gotta be the craftiest motherfucker alive!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silent Bob struggles while Jay and Suzanne try to pull him through the hole.</context>
      <utterance>You fat fuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just--had to--order pancakes-- didn't ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fire a warning shot into that bulbous ass!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One rectal breach, coming up!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow! That was an incredibly daring escape!  You must see that a lot, hunh?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Willenholly starts rolling up his sleeves as the sheriff looks on.</context>
      <utterance>Sire, you're very taciturn.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You and your men stay up here. When I corner them, I'll call you for back-up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you doing? They're trapped. The only way they can get out of there is right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Willenholly embraces the Sheriff.</context>
      <utterance>A Federal Wildlife Marshal doesn't wait for his prey to come to him. He comes to it. Or goes to it. Is it "comes to it" or "goes to it"?  I'm going in there. I'm counting on you Sheriff.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Willenholly then climbs into the sewer, disappearing. The Cops look at the Sheriff for a beat, who heads O.C. saying--</context>
      <utterance>You've taught me so much.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck this asshole. Let's go back to the station and get some donuts.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PULL BACK to reveal Jay, Silent Bob and Suzanne standing at the precipice of the sewer tunnel that pokes out of a DAM. Water rushed below.</context>
      <utterance>This reminds me of the night I fucked your mom, yo. One big-wet, smelly, gaping hole, and me wishing I had a board tied to my ass--</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--to keep from falling in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silent Bob indicates themselves.</context>
      <utterance>Man! Who the fuck just steals a monkey?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silent Bob mimes that they should go after Suzanne.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah.  Well this fucking blows! We got one more day to stop those fucks from making that movie, and someone goes and takes the only thing I had left from the one woman I ever loved enough NOT to try to stick my hand down her pants!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silent Bob mimes in the direction the car went. Jay stares at him.</context>
      <utterance>Go after the monkey? How the fuck are we supposed to know where that thing's going?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob starts an elaborate pantomime. Jay tries to guess what he's saying.</context>
      <utterance>What? What is that supposed to mean?! Don't just fucking point like--  You ain't the broad in the Children of a Lesser God. Use you fucking mouth for more than eating, ya tubby bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob's on the verge of tears, trying to mime out his message.</context>
      <utterance>You gotta take a shit? No--you gotta take a salad? Take a salad? What the fuck are you trying to say?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if it isn't the wildlife experts. Did you come to it or go to it?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have a microwave here, Sheriff?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have a toaster oven. Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I need to dry my gun out so I can SHOOT YOU WITH IT ! TWICE!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This might cheer you up.  Your office just faxed this over. Guy there say it's a post from an Internet chat board, signed by a "Jay and Silent Bob." Your man thinks it's a lead as to where those fellas are taking the ape.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"All you motherfuckers are gonna pay. You are the ones who are ball- lickers. We're gonna fuck your mothers while you watch and cry like little bitches. Once we get to Hollywood--"  They're going to Hollywood.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two HOOKERS approach them.</context>
      <utterance>What? It's not like it's cheating. Justice blew up.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, little man. You want some of this?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about you, Big Boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you've got fifty bucks we can get nasty.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah? How nasty?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As nasty as you wanna be, poppie.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hookers look at him, dumbfounded, Then--</context>
      <utterance>Alright--first, I'll want to tongue your bung while you juggle my balls in one hand and play with my asshole with the other. But don't stick you finger in. Then. I'll wanna pinky you and put it in your friend's brown, while Silent Bob spanks into a Dixie cup. After that, I'll wanna smell your titties, for a while, and you can pull my nutsack up over my dick, so it looks like a Bullfrog. Then I want you to flick at my nuts while your friend spanks me into the same Dixie cup Silent Bob jizzed in. Then we throw the Dixie cup out.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, that's it honey. I quit.  This job just passed the point of no return.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You one fucked up puppy, poppie.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?! You said 'nasty'?  Man, chicks in Hollywood are so stuck up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They pass a DEALER leaning against a wall, trying to make a sale.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, here's the plan: first, we find out where they're shooting that movie at. After we shut that shit down, we can start looking for the monkey. But before we do any of that shit, we gotta find a motherfucker in the know. Someone who's like, the mayor of Hollywood.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crack? You want some crack? Sweet- ass rock. Get you high.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No man, but you want some weed?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You on the job?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE ON THE CARD. It reads: UNITED JERSEY BROTHERHOOD OF</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, boy. Jersey Local 408.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEALERS, LOCAL 408.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a graphic of a stoner beside it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They shake hands, slapping each other on the back like Union brothers.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Los Angeles Local 305!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys got medical in Jersey yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit, no, we might have to strike in September.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Norma Rae like a motherfucker. You gots to get your benefits, you know what I'm saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hear that. Yo--maybe you can help us out. You know where they're shooting a movie around here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You in this town and you gonna ask that question? Be a little more specific.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay exhales. The Dealer stares at him for a beat.</context>
      <utterance>It's a Miramax flick. We gotta bust it up so people stop calling us names on the Internet, even though they're not really talking about us but these characters based on us, and at the same time, find my ex-girlfriend-who- got-killed-in-a-car-explosion's monkey.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know that the fuck you just said, little kid. But you touched a brother's heart, so I'm gonna help you out with some directions to the studio.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know where Miramax is at?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck, yes. Miramax accounts for seventy-eight percent of my business.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>STEVE KMETKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jules Asner is in front of the Miramax Studios main gate.</context>
      <utterance>Is Hollywood ready for Jay and Silent Bob? A source at the Federal Wildlife Marshal's Office tells us a posting was pulled off an Internet movie chat board that was allegedly written by the two domestic terrorists themselves. It's sending a shockwave through Hollywood. Jules Asner's on the scene at Miramax Studios, Jules?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES ASNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BACK TO STEVE in the E! Studio.</context>
      <utterance>Steve, the tenor of Tinseltown is one of terror today, after the Federal Wildlife Marshal's Office learned that hot, new terrorists Jay and Silent Bob are targeting Miramax Studios for their next campaign of blood, violence and monkey-theft. In the posting, pulled off Movie Poop Shoot.com, the gruesome twosome threatened, quote--  "Once we get to Hollywood and find those Miramax Expletive-Deleted who are making the Bluntman and Chronic movie, we're gonna make 'em eat our Expletive-Deleted, then Expletive- Deleted, which is made up of our Expletive-Deleted, then eat their Expletive-Deleted, which is made up of our Expletive-Deleted that we made 'em eat. Unquote. So far, we haven't been able to get a statement from anyone here are the studio.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BACK TO JULES at Miramax Studios.</context>
      <utterance>Jules, word has it that Ben Affleck and Matt Damon are on the lot, shooting a super-secret project. Have you seen then roaming around?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Steve. But I did see Casey Affleck buying a soda at a concession stand earlier.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But no sign of Jay and Silent Bob?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Jules speaks, Jay and Bob walk into the frame behind her, looking up at the studio sign. They then notice the camera and start waving behind Jules.</context>
      <utterance>None whatsoever. However, to be fair, all the feds have to work with is murky videotape, so no one's even a hundred percent sure what Jay and Silent Bob look like, exactly. For all we know, they could already be on the lot.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Justice looks around, panicky. Her eyes fall on-- The diamonds, sitting atop the satchel on the table. Justice looks at the diamonds, then the TV screen. She thinks for a beat, then--</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God! Jay! No!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pours the diamonds into the satchel, and shoves it in her pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That bitch! That fucking, fucking bitch!!!  Get dressed. We're going after her.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck that, I didn't get to cum yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sissy and Missy race back up the stairs. Chrissy stands there still, shrugs, then digs her hand into her panties.</context>
      <utterance>Which is more important to you: a fortune in diamonds or busting a nut?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chrissy! Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck-- Chrissy races back up the stairs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SECURITY GUARD catches up to them now, grabbing them by their shoulders, spinning them around.</context>
      <utterance>I hate how fake Hollywood is.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do you think you're going?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is L.A., sir. We don't rape our suspects in custody. We just beat them.  Echo Base, I've got a ten-o-seven here: two unauthorizeds on the lot. Request back-up.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought that was a ten-eighty-two.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir--a ten-eight-two is the code for vanishing a dead hooker from Ben Affleck's trailer.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, that Affleck. Backup on the way.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! I make you a deal: this guy'll suck your dick off if you let us go!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Contrary to what you believe, not everyone in the movie business is gay.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Security Guard stops, looks around, then releases them, reaching into his pants.</context>
      <utterance>Well, how about this deal: he sucks my dick while you watch and jerk off.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silent Bob looks at Jay, wide-eyed and scared.</context>
      <utterance>Alright. But make is fast. And sexy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silent Bob wells up with tears, slowly dropping to his knees, reaching for Jay's pants. The Security guard bends down low to watch at crotch-level. Suddenly, Jay hammers his two fists into the Security Guard's neck, knocking him out. Silent Bob falls into a sitting position on the ground, relieved. Jay looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Dude, it's either this or jail. And you know what they make you do in jail.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silent Bob points behind Jay, at the SOUNDSTAGE they're in front of. There's a LINE OF PEOPLE waiting at the door.</context>
      <utterance>Well what are you waiting for, bitch? Start sucking. Bunnggg!  Alright--where they shooting this movie at?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silent Bob shakes his head "no," wide-eyed as Jay heads off. When Jay's out of frame, Silent bob shrugs like, "Yeah--I guess I was."</context>
      <utterance>Worth a shot. Like a shot in the mouth, you gay bitch. Eww, dude--you were really gonna suck my dick.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>A.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The A.D. starts leading the crowd in. Jay and Bob blend in and follow inside.</context>
      <utterance>Alright--bar extras. Follow me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHONE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Federal Bureau of Investigation</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, this is Federal Wildlife Marshal Willenholly. Can I speak with Agent Sid Enmarty, please?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHONE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One moment, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPEAKER VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Agent Enmarty? A Marshal Willenholly calling.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(calling off)</context>
      <utterance>Holy shit! Yeah, put him through.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sid? Hey, buddy. I'm calling because I could really use your help on this killer case I'm working.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll bet, Will. What's it this time... Beaver trouble? Some kind of unauthorized marsupial trafficking? The agents crack up, stifling their laughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no--nothing like that. Say--there aren't other people listening in, are there?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way, man. It's just me and you talking here.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. I'm tracking a monkey down that's on it's way to Los Angeles, and I could use some bureau backup.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Agents crack up. Willenholly's catching on.</context>
      <utterance>Los Angeles, hunh? Maybe we should stake out Clint Eastwood's place. Didn't he used to drive around with a monkey that'd punch people and drink beer?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am, uh--Am I on speaker phone?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way--Dunston!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, now that's not fair. I know I didn't make it as high up as you guys, but my job's just as important.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Agents crack up even more, Willenholly's pissed.</context>
      <utterance>Calm down, Will. Don't go all... bananas on us!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I come to you as a friend--as a fellow professional--and this is the shit I get?!</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right, Will. Tell you what-- we'll get our best man on your case right away. You might've heard of him. He's a doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, a doctor?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Agents laugh hysterically, pounding the desk, Willenholly tears up, enraged.</context>
      <utterance>His name's Doctor Zaius!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gus Van Sant sits off to the side, counting a stack of money. He just shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Where are we taking it from, Gus?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm busy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a true artist, Gus</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just take it from "It's a good course."</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, now you're the director.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, shove it. Bounce-boy. Let's remember who talked who into doing this shit in the first place. Talking me into Dogma was one thing, but this--</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry this is taking you away from whatever-gay-killers-on-horses- who-like-to-play-golf-touchy-feely- flick you're supposed to be doing this week.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh--I'm touchy-feely? I take it you never saw Forces of Nature?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They take a beat and look at the camera. Then--</context>
      <utterance>You're like a child. What've I been telling you? Sometimes you've gotta do the safe picture. Sometimes, you do it for art. Sometimes, it's the payback picture your friend says you owe him--</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And sometimes, you go back to the well.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And sometimes, you do Reindeer Games.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay turns excitedly to Bob.</context>
      <utterance>Now that's just mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The A.D. grabs Jay and Bob by the arms and drags them onto the set, placing them near Ben and Matt in the scene.</context>
      <utterance>This has gotta be the Bluntman Flick, 'cause that's those two fucks from that Mork movie! Now all we gotta do is figure out a way to get close to them--</utterance>
   <speaker>A.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob goes a little wide-eyed. Jay smiles at him.</context>
      <utterance>Just stand there and react. Don't say anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's pretty funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On the count of three, we rush those fucks and beat the shit out of 'em. 'Cause if they're all fucked up, they can't make the move, right? Alright, then. One--two--</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAPPER/LOADER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Jay and Bob freeze and look at each other, then O.C. The Clapper/Loader holds a clapboard in front of Ben's face. It does indeed, read: Good Will Hunting 2: Hunting Season.</context>
      <utterance>Good Will Hunting Two: Hunting Season.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAPPER/LOADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Clapper/Loader claps the board closed and races off. Ben looks to Gus.</context>
      <utterance>Scene sixteen, take five.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gus looks up from counting his money.</context>
      <utterance>Action, Gus?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben shakes his head and then starts the scene with CLARK.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Ben--I said I'm busy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN/CHUCKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should check it out, it's a good course. But, you know, frankly, I found the class rather elementary.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I don't doubt that it was. I remember that class. It was just between recess and lunch.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN/CHUCKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we gonna have a problem, again?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no problem. I was still just hoping you might give me some insight into the evolution of the market economy in the Southern Colonies. See, Wood says--</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT/WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd I say? Didn't I say you'd be back here regurgitating Gordon Wood. But you forgot about Vickers--</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the background, Jay and Silent Bob get bored and head out of the shot. After a beat, they get pushed back in by the</context>
      <utterance>No, I just read Vickers, so I'm up on inherited wealth, Hunting. But you're not the angry, brilliant young mind you once were, just itching to vent your frustrations.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CLARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt/Will turns away angrily, facing Ben/Chuckie, looking downwards, steaming.</context>
      <utterance>Once Sean told you it wasn't your fault, you lost the edge, William. You stopped hitting the books with a vengeance, and now I've read shit you haven't even heard about yet. Face facts, my friend--love made you a soft little pussy boy, unable to stand up to an academic showdown, like you used to. You're just no longer that good--Will Hunting.  Now how do you like them apples?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN/CHUCKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't like the sound of them apples. Will, what're we gonna do now?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT/WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt/Will spins to face Clark with two huge guns in his hands. He blows Clark away, Jay and Bob hit the deck. Matt/Will stands there, guns smoking.</context>
      <utterance>Chuckie--  It's Hunting season.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN/CHUCKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly the door to the soundstage swings open, and the Security guard Jay knocked out rushes in, followed by other SECURITY GUARDS who comb the place.</context>
      <utterance>Apple sauce, bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry to interrupt, sirs, but have a ten-oh-seven on our hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Security Guard sees Jay and Bob crouched behind Ben, He points, screaming.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a second! I wasn't with any hookers today!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay and Bob then race out-of-frame, closely followed by the Security guards. Matt head off, arms thrown in the air.</context>
      <utterance>Affleck, you're the bomb in Phantoms, yo.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If anyone's looking for me, I'll be in my trailer trying to figure out how I got here from an Academy Award.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CLAPPER/LOADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scream four, scene thirty-seven, take one.</utterance>
   <speaker>WES CRAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Killer chases Shannen around the room, falling over stuff, until she hits him with a lamp, knocking him out.</context>
      <utterance>Action!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNEN DOHERTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shannen pulls the mask off the short performer to reveal</context>
      <utterance>Alright, you bastard! Let's see who you really are!</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZANNE.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jay and Silent Bob go wide-eyed.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNEN DOHERTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fucking Miramax--</utterance>
   <speaker>WES CRAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shannen, usually I say "cut."</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANNEN DOHERTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A monkey? Jesus, you guys aren't even trying anymore, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WES CRAVEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay and Silent Bob rush in, grab Suzanne.</context>
      <utterance>The market research suggest that people love monkeys.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="38">
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy shit--that looked like it hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay and Bob look at their twins, then at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Are you guys alright?  Hey! They've got a monkey!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo, I think that shit just kicked in.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>James and Jason help Jay and Silent Bob to their feet. All stare at one another, perplexed, Then--</context>
      <utterance>Let's get you guys on your feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See man? Its never, "Hey--you were in Loser, or, "Dude--you rocked in Boys and Girls." It always comes back to that fucking pie! I'm haunted by it.!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you put your dick in a pie, dude--</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enough!  Jason Biggs.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo-you really get to third base with the Russsian chick like you did in the movies?</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean Shannon? Sadly, no.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay mimes a series of sexual maneuvers. Jason and James look on, bewildered.</context>
      <utterance>She's fucking hot, man. If I was you, I'd been like--</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy shit? You're the Dawson!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's James, actually. James Van Der Beek.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo, what's up with Pacey stealing Joey away from you? If I was you, I would've drowned his ass in your Creek and shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, Because what--is Josh better looking than me? Fuck, no. I mean, who on earth is better looking that me? I ask you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Joey, man! She's too fine! Yo--did you ever get to third base with her?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, there was this one time--  Wait a second--who are you guys?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're our stunt doubles, dumbass.  Right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stunt doubles for what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The movie we start shooting in a few minutes--Bluntman and Chronic Strike Back.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're doubling me. I'm playing Bluntman, AKA Silent Bill.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bob</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. And he's playing Chronic. AKA Ray.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jay! Shit, did you even read the script?</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay and Bob stare at them, blankly. Then Jay puts up his finger, indicating they should wait a minute. He gets into a huddle with Silent Bob and Suzanne.</context>
      <utterance>There's a script?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silent Bob nods at Jay, then Suzanne. Suzanne heads off, leaving Jay and Bob to huddle.</context>
      <utterance>These are the guys who are playing us, yo. We take them out, and bickety- bam! No movie.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's with the weird, gay huddle going on over there?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's gay about it? It's two guys talking in a corner. Man--why are you such a homophobe.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not a homophobe.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are. You're always calling things gay. "Ooo--look at the gay huddle, dude!" Suzanne approaches them.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey--look at the monkey.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Next you're going to tell me the monkey's gay.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suzanne pulls Jason and James out of the frame. While Jay and Silent Bob continue to huddle, the sounds of a beating are heard, O.C.</context>
      <utterance>He's so cute--  C'mere. Monkey. C'mere--</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay and Bob spin to face Jason and James--only to go wide- eyed. Suzanne stands atop the fallen actors, who are bloodied and beaten and knocked out cold. She holds her hands skyward, clasped like a champion.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, here's what we do: start swinging, and don't stop until those young Hollywood fucks are out of commission. Ready? Break!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly there's a banging at the door of the dressing room.</context>
      <utterance>That's one funky monkey.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mister Biggs? Mister Van... Der-- Beek? This is Security. We've got a pair of intruders at large, and they crashed through a window we thought might be yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh--yeah. They're in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do they have you hostage? Should we call your publicists?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>NO! I mean, we kicked those guys' asses bad. They're--knocked out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great work, sirs! If you let us in, we'll take over--</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The Security guard look at one another.</context>
      <utterance>NO! Me and Jason Biggs are naked in here! Together!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Security Guards stifle a laugh, as one makes a blow job face to the rest.</context>
      <utterance>Uh--okay. We'll just be--outside the door, sirs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, and A.D. appears, grabbing them by the shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>This was a good idea, Lunchbox. In these outfits we're totally incognito.</utterance>
   <speaker>A.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mister Biggs? Mister Van Der Beek? Great--you've changed costumes already. Let's get you to set.  The director doesn't like to be kept waiting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A white P.A. brings a cup of latte to the Director.</context>
      <utterance>Look at all these crackers, Seventy million dollars and I can't even get a black grip?</utterance>
   <speaker>P.A.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's your coffee, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You spit in this? Because I know all you white folks are pissed off that the studio'd entrust a multi- million dollar to a brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>P.A.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't spit in it, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The P.A. takes the cup and sips from it. He tries to hand it back to the Director.</context>
      <utterance>Then taste it! Go on!</utterance>
   <speaker>P.A.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all good, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No it ain't all good. Oh, you think I want it now, after your lips touched the cup? Get the fuck off my set!</utterance>
   <speaker>P.A.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You the man, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Director glares at the scared P.A., as he cautiously skulks off. BANKY EDWARDS approaches.</context>
      <utterance>No you the Man! And that's the problem!</utterance>
   <speaker>BANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, Chaka? Yeah, hi--I'm Banky Edwards, the creator of Bluntman and Chronic. We met a few weeks back. I'm the executive producer.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR/CHAKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh--you're the executive producer, hunh? Well go "produce" me a latte no white folks spit in--okay Fucky?</utterance>
   <speaker>BANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Banky. I just wanted you to know that I respect your work as an artist. I'm something of an artist myself. I was the inker on the comic book.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Banky's face drops as the A.D. joins them.</context>
      <utterance>An inker? What, like you trace?</utterance>
   <speaker>A.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Biggs and Van Der Beek are on the set, Chaka.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(into bullhorn)</context>
      <utterance>I don't see 'em. Where are they?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This must've set 'em back a couple hundred bucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at this shit.  A gay hood ornament, and the color Purple.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the fuck are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the fuck am I? I'm the fucking director, is who I am. Chaka Luther King. The creator of all of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a sec--I thought Holden and Banky created this shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chaka heads back toward his monitor. Jay and Bob are confused.</context>
      <utterance>And I'm stealing it. I'm taking it back for all the shit you people have stolen from us! Did you know, I came up with the idea for Sesame Street before PBS? I was going to call it N.W.P.--Niggaz with Puppets.  Alright--enough small talk. Let's shoot it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, wait, wait!! Aren't you gonna direct us?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be directing you to the food stamps line after I fire your ass, if you talk back like that to me again!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we don't know what we're supposed to do here. We didn't even read the script.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay and Silent Bob go wide-eyed, as Chaka heads off.</context>
      <utterance>So? Neither did I. Shit, neither did the studio.  Look man, it's not hard. In this scene, the bad guy breaks into the Bluntcave. You make up some shit, fight him for a while, I film it, I yell "cut," and then head back to my trailer, where I got more white women waiting for me there than the first lifeboat off the Titanic!  They all want a part of the movie, and I got just the part for 'em.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>P.A.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chaka smacks the coffee out of his hand and sits down. The Clapper/Loader jumps in front of the startled Jay and Bob, getting ready. After a beat, he turns to Silent Bob.</context>
      <utterance>I got you another cup of coffee, sir. Spit free.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAPPER/LOADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(calling off)</context>
      <utterance>I just wanna say that I loved when you fucked that pie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JAY/CHRONIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, the wall to their left explodes. Jay and Bob hit the deck. Through the smoking rubble steps COCK-KNOCKER--the arch--nemesis of Bluntman and Chronic. He's a normal-looking man with huge, overgrown FISTS.</context>
      <utterance>Uh--Snootchie Bootchies.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY/CHRONIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck?</utterance>
   <speaker>COCK-KNOCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You thought I'd never find your precious Bluntcave, did you, Hemp Knight? But now you and your sidekick are finally in the grasp of Cock- Knocker!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY/CHRONIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cock-Knocker slams one of his huge fists into Jay's balls. Jay drops to his knees, wailing. Cock-Knocker then pulls a vibrator-looking device from his cape. He presses a button on it and a laser beam rises out of the vibrator, like a light saber.</context>
      <utterance>Why do they call you "Cock-Knocker"?</utterance>
   <speaker>COCK-KNOCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silent Bob quickly looks right, then left. His eyes fall on-- A wall of armaments, on which hands a SILVER BONG, under the placard: BONG SABER--EXTREMELY EXPERIMENTAL. DO NOT USE. It's out of his reach. Silent Bob closes his eyes, concentrating. He reached his hand out to the Bong Saber, attempting the Jedi Mind Trick. Suddenly, the Bong snaps from the armory into Bob's grip. The Bong Saber blasts to life and Bob strikes a defensive pose. Bob rushes the astonished Cock-Knocker and the pair start light saber dueling.</context>
      <utterance>Any last words before I bust your balls, Bluntman?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn! Now that was one special effect! This picture's gonna make House Party look like House Party Two!</utterance>
   <speaker>A.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or House Party Three?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cock-Knocker battles Bob back. He vogues some impressive blade handling, prompting Bob to make a run for it--up the ladder of the Bong Reactor and over Cock-Knocker's head. He lands behind Cock-Knocker, striking another pose. Cock- Knocker then high- kicks Bob in the face, knocking him on his ass across the floor. Cock-Knocker rushers over to deliver a saber kill-shot, when we hear--</context>
      <utterance>Shut the fuck up!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay leaps at Cock-Knocker, wielding the double-beamed Bong Saber.</context>
      <utterance>Call me Darth Balls. Bunngg.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think George Lucas is going to sue somebody--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Um--sorry. That was supposed to be a warning shot. Uh--it looks like I'm on the wrong, uh--wrong set. The Kids look at the fallen Mooby. On looks angrily at the O.C. Willenholly.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God--</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You killed Mooby--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All turn to see a roughed-up Willenholly, training his gun first on Jay, then Bob.</context>
      <utterance>Now whose balls have been busted, bitch? Suddenly, a gun shot rings out.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The C.L.I.T. stops here, Jay and Silent Bob!  Everyone stay calm. I'm a Federal Wildlife Marshal. These men are the leaders of a terrorist organization wanted for the abduction of a monkey.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>All turn to see Justice approaching from the shadows. Willenholly trains his gun on her. Jay's mouth drops.</context>
      <utterance>They didn't really steal that monkey.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Justice pulls the bag of diamonds from her jacket, revealing them.</context>
      <utterance>It was just a diversion so we could steal these.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And they're not the leaders of C.L.I.T. The C.L.I.T. is not real.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No--the clit's real. The female orgasm is a myth.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you guys alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you blew up, Boo Boo Kitty Fuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You remembered.  It was a frame-up, Jay. Sissy. Missy, Chrissy, and I are international jewel thieves. We were setting you up as a patsy, but I couldn't go through with it, because I... because I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? So that means you'll fuck me, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>All turn to see Sissy, Missy, and Chrissy slinking from the shadows, guns drawn.</context>
      <utterance>If she does, it'll be considered necrophilia.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because she's gonna be one dead bitch.  Hi, Jussy. We catch you at a bad time?</utterance>
   <speaker>MISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should've just let these guys go down, Jussy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I wanted to go down, but I was waiting until I got to know her a little better. See, there was this little angel on my shoulder, and he said--</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut the fuck up before I shoot you where you stand in your pansy red booties.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy shit, I am wearing pansy red booties!  Man--why the fuck didn't you tell me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's have those diamonds, Jussy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't do that, Sissy</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then lover--boy gets one in the brain.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHAKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He races off, passing Justice and Sissy, who circle each other defensively, striking kung fu poses.</context>
      <utterance>A shitload of white people with guns? Time to get my black ass out of here!</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really let me down, Justice. Throwing it all away for a little stoner with bad pronunciation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="60">
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's it gonna be, Sissy? Which fighting style do you want me to kick your ass in?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding me? I taught you all all your moves myself. There's not a style you can bust that I can't defend against.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're no match for my "Shaolin Monk."</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but I can bury you with my "Crouching Tiger."</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little "Venus's--flytrap"?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll counter with "Dragon Crane."</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about a little "Bitch, My Man Ain't Yo Baby's Daddy"?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Justice rushes Sissy and instead of sleek kung fu, they launch into a down-and-dirty, girl's cat-fight; hair pulling and screaming. Behind the Bluntmobile, Jay and Bob watch all the action.</context>
      <utterance>Bring it on.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both Bob and Jay smile at each other, nodding. Banky joins them, crawling in on his belly, covering his head.</context>
      <utterance>Yo--I hope one of 'em rips the other one's shirt off and we see some tit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mister Biggs? Mister Van Der Beek? I just wanted to say hi. I'm--</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Banky fucking Edwards! Just the motherfucker we came to see!</utterance>
   <speaker>BANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop the movie?! Are you crazy?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All these assholes are calling us names on the Internet, 'cause of this stupid movie!</utterance>
   <speaker>BANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel for you boys--I really do. Those Net snipers can be really cruel. But Miramax paid me a shitload of money for Bluntman and Chronic, so it occurs to me that people bad- mouthing you on some web-site is none of my FUCKING CONCERN!</utterance>
   <speaker>SILENT BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Banky stares at Silent Bob, agog, Jay rolls his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Oh--but I think it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here we go again--</utterance>
   <speaker>SILENT BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Banky stares at Bob, even more agog, joined by Jay. After a beat, Jay adds--</context>
      <utterance>Shut the fuck up.  We had a deal with you on the comics for likeness rights. And as we're not only the artistic basis but also the character basis for your intellectual property, Bluntman and Chronic, when we said property was optioned by Miramax Films you were legally obliged to secure our permission to transfer the concept to another medium. As you failed to do that, you're in breach of the original contract--ergo, you find yourself in a very actionable position.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Justice now has the advantage over Sissy, holding her head and kicking her in the face, repeatedly, screaming.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>BANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, what do you guys want, to go away and take your lady friends with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shitcan this movie so we don't get called names on the Internet anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>BANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the background, we see Justice high-kick Sissy into the air.</context>
      <utterance>Even if there's no movie, people are still free to talk shit about you on the Internet. That's what the Internet's for: slandering others anonymously. Stopping the flick isn't going to stop that!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On cue, Sissy drops from above, landing in Jay's lap.</context>
      <utterance>Well this isn't fair! We went to Hollywood, I fell in love, we stole a monkey, we got shot at, and got punched in the motherfucking nuts! We ain't leaving empty-handed!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's up baby? You look good!</utterance>
   <speaker>BANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't that your girlfriend's enemy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sissy races at Justice, leaping atop her, pulling her hair. Jay, Bob, and Banky continue.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah.  Get the fuck offa me, pig!</utterance>
   <speaker>BANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys are gonna ruin my movie career.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we want something for our mental anguish.</utterance>
   <speaker>BANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell you what: we'll settle this monetarily. I'll give you half of what I made.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Half?!?</utterance>
   <speaker>BANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Half's not good enough? Fine--I'll give you two-thirds of what I made!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silent Bob rolls his eyes, Banky shakes Jay's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck-you--you already said half? You can't take it back!</utterance>
   <speaker>BANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Justice throws Sissy off, onto the floor. Both get up, facing each other.</context>
      <utterance>Done</utterance>
   <speaker>SISSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your shit is so tired, Justice!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Justice high-kicks Sissy and she goes flying across the stage. Sissy sails toward the craft service table, landing atop Missy and Chrissy, knocking them out. Willenholly stands to see why the girls stopped shooting.</context>
      <utterance>Call me Boo-Boo Kitty Fuck--BITCH!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I think I killed both of them. Suddenly, he lets out a shriek and falls forward, revealing a tranquilizer dart in his ass, and SUZANNE standing behind him, holding the gun up in the air. Justice surveys her handiwork for a beat, then calls off toward the Bluntmobile.</context>
      <utterance>Hello? Truce?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay, Bob, and Banky pop up from behind the car and join her.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon guys. It's over.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then, the SOUND of SIRENS rings out in the distance.</context>
      <utterance>Yo, I was just about to jump in there and get your back.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy shit, the cops! We gotta get out of here!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Justice lifts Willenholly into a sitting position and taps his face.</context>
      <utterance>No. I'm tired of running.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You awake, Marshal? Marshal?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God, I'm paralyzed. The monkey shot me in the ass and paralyzed me! Oh the irony!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not paralyzed. It was just a tranquilizer.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus! Tranqued by a little monkey! My friends in the Bureau are never gonna let me live this down!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have friends in the F.B.I.?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They all made it in, but I failed the exam. Why the hell else do you think I became a Federal Wildlife Marshal? 'Cause I'm a joke! Justice looks toward the direction of the sirens, thinking. Then--</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe not. I can make you a deal that'll get you into the F.B.I., regardless of test scores.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of deal?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You drop the charges against Jay and Silent Bob and say you never found the ape. Make sure the world knows they're not in control of any C.L.I.T.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now wait a second--</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll explain later, Jay  In exchange, I'll give you the diamonds I stole, and turn in Sissy, Missy, Chrissy, and myself. But I want a reduced sentence.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd be willing to do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Justice stands and takes Jay by the hands.</context>
      <utterance>For him? I'd be willing to do anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm an international jewel thief who's facing a jail sentence.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's alright. I'm a junkie with a monkey.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I go to prison, will you wait for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Justice smiles and kisses Jay Passionately. The kiss should say it all, but--</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Will we fuck when you get out?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't change the subject. Will we fuck when you get out?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Justice and Jay kiss again. Suzanne reached up to Silent Bob, who picks her up. She grabs his face and kisses him. Willenholly looks to Banky.</context>
      <utterance>Snoogans.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. There's a lot of love in the room.</utterance>
   <speaker>BANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Regardless of what you may have heard. I do not kiss guys.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Justice. We've gotta go.  Hey--stop stealing monkeys.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Willenholly closes the door behind Justice and gets in the car.</context>
      <utterance>Fair enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay looks at Justice, confused, as the Cruiser pulls away, leaving Jay, Bob, Suzanne, and Banky. They start walking down the lot.</context>
      <utterance>What--here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, boys--you're rich in love--  Well, you're in love. And to top that off, you've got your own monkey. What more could two guys from Jersey possibly want?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All those fucks to stop talking shit about us on the Internet, for starters.</utterance>
   <speaker>BANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay and Bob suddenly freeze. They look at each other and smile.</context>
      <utterance>What do I keep telling you? There's not much you can do to stop that. Well, short of showing up at all their houses and beating the shit out of them, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know--with all that money we're gonna make we can buy a lotta plane tickets.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Ma'am, Does--  William Dusky live here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. He's my son.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May we talk to him, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks away. After a beat, a fifteen-year-old KID comes to the door.</context>
      <utterance>One moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo--do you post as--  Magnolia-Fan on Movie Poop Shoot.com?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And did you write "Fuck Jay and Silent Bob. Fuck them up their stupid asses?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jay and Bob nod at each other, then grab the KID, pull him outside, and start beating the shit out of him on his front lawn.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, a while ago. So?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On Movie Poop Shoot.com. did you say Jay and Silent Bob--  "--are fucking clown shoes. If they were real, I'd beat the shit out of them for being so stupid."</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again, Jay and Bob pull the Kid outside and beat the shit out of him.</context>
      <utterance>Really--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>RANDAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now that was worse then Clash of the Titans.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still can't believe Judy Dench played me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey--remind me to renew that restraining order.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STEVE-DAVE and WALT exit.</context>
      <utterance>Because I'm gonna blast the flick on the Internet tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE-DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why can't Hollywood ever make a decent comic book movie?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell'em Steve-Dave!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE-DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ALYSSA and TRISH come out.</context>
      <utterance>Would you stop saying that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that was just another paean to male adolescence and its refusal to grow up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALYSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, sis--but it was better than Mallrats. At least Holden had the good sense to keep his name off of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why wouldn't Miramax option his other comic instead? You know--the one he drew about you and him and your relationship?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALYSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BANKY and HOOPER exit.</context>
      <utterance>You mean Chasing Amy? That would never work as a movie.</utterance>
   <speaker>BANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so fucking embarrassed--</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey, you should be. They took your characters and reduced them to one ninety-minute-long-gay joke. It was like watching Batman and Robin again.</utterance>
   <speaker>BANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. That means a lot coming from the guy who pretends to be Shaft as opposed to the guy who takes shaft.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't hear you complaining nightly. In fact, the only thing I do hear you say is "Yes, Hooper! Cradle the balls and work the shaft!"</utterance>
   <speaker>BANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A guy behind them calls out to Banks.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Hey! What'd we say? Not in public!</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice movie, you fucking Tracer!</utterance>
   <speaker>BANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You--!</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Banky grabs the guy by the throat and starts choking him, while Hooper tries to break them up. WILLENHOLLY exits with Justice in hand-and leg cuffs and a prison uniform. They're flanked by two ARMED PRISON GUARDS.</context>
      <utterance>That's right, you sonovabitch! I'm back for round two!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I don't get out to the movies much. But I'd have to say Bluntman and Chronic was Blunt-tastic!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are these leg cuffs really necessary?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLENHOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And finally, Jay and Silent Bob come out.</context>
      <utterance>Don't make me shoot you, Justice.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
