<movie id="321" title="Jennifer Eight">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Curious thing about drunks. Their disease often amuses them. That's how crazy I was - I was sick for half a life till I finally found my san- ity again in these rooms. Don't take that drink - And for the one or two new faces I see here, I say this: just do it by the day. You gotta do it by the day - Don't take that drink. And keep coming to these meetings. Because here is where it works ..</context>
      <utterance>.. after my third recovery my wife made me swear I'd never bring another bottle into the house. And I never did. I bur- ied it under the lawn. Cut out a turf &amp; stood it upright with a piece of tin- foil instead of a cork. So here we are out in the yard, and she's happy because I'm getting healthy in a pair of swim- ing shorts &amp; no way near no booze. She decides to prune the roses. Meanwhile, I'm laying there with a straw stuck in- to the fucken lawn doing a quart of red ..</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ash into an ashtray and now a face. He's around 40 years old. Intense eyes &amp; dark hair. Probably good looking when the ang- le's right. But this is a bad angle. His name is JOHN BERLIN.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Benny .. We have a few more minutes .. Anyone else like to share? ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name's John .. and I'm an alcoholic ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, John.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't intend to speak today. Matter of fact, I wasn't gonna come to the meeting .. But I wanna say a couple of things I hope may be of use, particularly as Benny says, to the new faces here. I first came into this fellowship ten months ago. I came to a meeting I was convinced was gonna be my last - how could a buncha drunks help me? - Then someone got up, I think it was Micky, and described himself as "the shit around which the universe revolved." I don't know if that was original to him - it doesn't matter, it was the first time I'd heard it, and I still can't think of a better way to describe how I felt - We all have our own place in the darkness, and I was in such a mess I could hardly fucken see - I'd lost someone very dear to me - she hadn't died - I had - I don't know whether she left coza the drinking, or whether I drank coz I knew she was gonna leave - either way, the booze won - I replaced her with alcohol &amp; anger - I was angry with her, myself, everyone and everything - Where I was I wanted to be someplace else - any place but here - any moment but now - But here I am, and it is now, and there's a big change about to hap- pen in my life - and I'm going for it coz this time I know I'm not running away - I'm actually two miles into a 600 mile journey, and I feel good about myself going there - So I stopped off to share that with you - and to thank everyone of you, and everyone in this fellowship for letting me walk out of here, free ..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can drive down there, Sir ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of those walking with him is a 10-year-old Kid with a Dog. TRAVIS looks almost too young to own his struggling moustache.</context>
      <utterance>I'm already walking. Where is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On the infill. The guy from L.A.'s just gone down there ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He has? .. What's he doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The track sinks through a valley of a million discarded tires.</context>
      <utterance>He was waiting for you, Sir. Wait- ed a good while. Said he'd go down and take a look. I hope that's O.K.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn A, it's O.K. With a bit of luck I'm goin home. What we got?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A derelict.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIMBLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The information comes from freckles and a missing front tooth.</context>
      <utterance>They cut his throat ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIMBLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He wears glasses and wields a rusty .22 pump-action Remington.</context>
      <utterance>Trimble.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do you fit in, Trimble?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His father's the manager, Sir. The kid was up there shooting vermin, and he found the body.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIMBLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TRIMBLE speaks with some enthusiasm. ROSS looks back with none. They slit him from "ear to ear." Ya want me to make a statement?</context>
      <utterance>Get ready for it, coz I'm tell- ing ya, you're in for a shock ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not right now. No. Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="35">
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you bring it with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope I'm not intruding?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be my guest. What you got?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the next thing ROSS is looking at is a death in the trash. A massive dozer in the background. Everything else is garbage.</context>
      <utterance>Old guy, offed himself with a knife. I can't find the knife.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIMBLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They cut his throat.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another face here is so familiar ROSS hasn't bothered to ackn- owledge it. BLATTIS is a 32 year old local newspaper reporter. Little is visible of the body except a blood-stained raincoat.</context>
      <utterance>Would you get outside the tape. And tell your dad to put that fire out ... that ain't legal ...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wonder what would make him do a thing like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't annoy me, Travis.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truck horns wail in the distance. On the horizon it's thunder.</context>
      <utterance>No, Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BERLIN wears surgical gloves. Removes film from a small camera.</context>
      <utterance>So where's the knife?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dunno .. Guess the dozer musta shifted him? You need some hands up here to look ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Swatting smoke ROSS directs anger at a fat cop called VENABLES. You, too .. Move that ass .. BERLIN hands the film to ROSS as he gets into identical gloves. You done the pockets?</context>
      <utterance>You heard. Look for the knife.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Sir. I haven't started till Monday. I'm a "tourist."</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>By now ROSS is crouched next to the Corpse examining the wound. How long's he been feeling like this?</context>
      <utterance>"Welcome to Eureka."</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Week or two. Musta been on the ker- osene. Stinks like a diesel engine.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLATTIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fucken noddle's hanging off ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr Blattis, of our local news- paper. You sure it's a suicide?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh huh .. He's well rehearsed ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BLATTIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does that mean, Sergeant?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BLATTIS looks vaguely impressed. ROSS begins searching pockets.</context>
      <utterance>Cut your own throat, you're ner- vous about it, tend to hesitate. He's got three trial cuts, lower left side of the neck, before he works up courage for the big one.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLATTIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think Popeye would know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think Popeye would be here.</utterance>
   <speaker>VENABLES</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dead dog over here, Sir ...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Find the knife. And Venab- les, is the coroner called?</utterance>
   <speaker>VENABLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Sir .. He's delayed ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BLATTIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, gentlemen, I'm gonna leave you. I got a couple of questions for the paper, Serg- eant? Mind if I swing by later, wring out a tea-bag with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My pleasure .. Who's Popeye?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLATTIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Off he fucks under an ailing sky. BERLIN lands a friendly grin.</context>
      <utterance>Your predecessor. He did- n't like to get outta bed. Catch you later, Freddy T ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what happened to the barbecues, and fishing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He finds keys and change and a sandwich in the Wino's raincoat. How does anyone dead as this lose a knife?</context>
      <utterance>Watch my lips, coz you're not gonna believe this - this is a rare occurrence. We haven't had a body in eighteen months.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about that kid, Ross?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TRAVIS stares up like he just stuck his dick in a light socket.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, shit. Of course. The kid.  Travis. Find that kid and get the knife off him. He's gonna lie to you - but he's got it - so get it. Well, go on, get on with it. Whatta you staring at?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I found some- thing horrible, Sir</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatta you mean, "horrible?"</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I've found a hand.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BERLIN finally stands. Offs the flashlight. And hands it back.</context>
      <utterance>Looks like a woman's hand?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you're here all day.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He wears a rubber cape &amp; looks like a huge pissed-off Napoleon.</context>
      <utterance>How much longer we here? We're not gonna find nothing else .. ?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We give it one more hour. Did the photographer do the dogs?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The dogs?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And both turn towards a Voice shouting from deep in the gloom.</context>
      <utterance>Two dogs. He should do the dogs.</utterance>
   <speaker>VENABLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sergeant - we got a brassiere over here. Looks like it could be blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another intrusion from the radio. TRAVIS repeats the question.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, I'm coming ..</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The coroner wants to know if we can release the derelict?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ask him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, he can go ...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Did someone say something funny? Does BERLIN just about smile.</context>
      <utterance>Think I'll lay down with him. Only way I'll get outta here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And this is probably the only time ROSS will look happy today.</context>
      <utterance>It's good to be with you, Ross.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Glad you finally made it, Bro ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BLATTIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Proffers a big yellow one plus assistance carrying equipment.</context>
      <utterance>You want some umbrella?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this normal?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLATTIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raining hard enough to hurt. A brisk intimacy across the lot. Better in the summer. You get to fucka few tourists .. He hits a security code at the door. Obviously familiar with the station. Dialogue continues as they step into a corridor.</context>
      <utterance>Average rainfall, 48 inches. Pisses down, October to June.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>BLATTIS [BERLIN]</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not married are you, Sergeant? [No.] That's good, you get to fuck a few more. So how long you known Freddy?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Freddy? Forever - he was my serg- eant when I was a kid - don't get to see a lot of each other - but we been buddies two hundred years ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BLATTIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did he get you the job?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think he would have if he could have - been trying to get me up here long enough - I think he may have bribed the old guy to retire ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BLATTIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They push through doors into the biggest room in the building. A dozen desks back to back and all the clutter and clatter of typewriters and paperwork and Secretaries swapping the gossip. Too many cops to describe and no time to remember them anyway. But here's one making introductions. About 60 years old. Face a mix of brick and fat. The Chief of Eureka Police is CITRINE.</context>
      <utterance>Popeye wasn't old. Younger than you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Any handshakes and greetings that fit in around the equipment. Mr Travis, I think you know ..</context>
      <utterance>Sergeants Serato, and Taylor.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BLATTIS tosses his parasol "Don't lose it" and follows BERLIN.</context>
      <utterance>Do me a favor, Travis? Bring in the resta the stuff from my car?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLATTIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you find the knife, Sergeant?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No .. But we have a theory ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BLATTIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kid told me he didn't take it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>By now they're in an L shaped room with wood benches and bull- etin board all over the walls. Bullshit everywhere in packing cases. Dusty Playboy spreads amongst other junk on the boards.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe he's lying to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLATTIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he benches the aquarium as BERLIN loses the insulated box. Is that it?</context>
      <utterance>Is it true you found a hand?</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Interview over, Blattis ...</utterance>
   <speaker>BLATTIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Right now the box contains camera equipment which is unpacked.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Chief, if it's sensitive, tell me .. I'm not taking notes ..</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now you know as much as we do ..</context>
      <utterance>.. we got a body part. We don't know what it is - probably some kind of hospital debris - we're gonna try and check it out. O.K.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLATTIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grateful for your candor, Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then do me a favor, and keep this outta the newspaper - that dump serves a dozen different communities, we don't even know if it's ours? Till we do I don't want no one worrying about ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BLATTIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wasn't frozen, was it, Sergeant?</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A Woman's face around the door. "Los Angeles for Sergeant Ber- lin." And goodbye BLATTIS as Berlin reaches for the telephone.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Michael, outta here, the guys trying to move in. I told you what we know, something else, you- 'll be the first to hear about it ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did he ask if it was frozen?</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>by the time you're back it's gone .. CITRINE splits as BERLIN picks up "Hey, Ronzo, good of you to call." A long phone lead and he continues to unpack equipment. BERLIN (Phone) Listen, my time isn't good - but two things - really important - the bras- siere I sent you? - I need to know if those stains are human blood - and if they are, do they match the blood in the sample? - C'mon, gimme a break, I don't know anyone up here, it would take two weeks - C'mon, Ronny, I'm ask- ing nice? I really need to know wheth- er I'm interested in that brassiere? .. A cut-out of Popeye The Sailor with fist round a camera on the wall. Telephone resistance is collapsing and he breaks a smile. You're my favourite man - raining - I gotta go - Ronny - I gotta go - I got a house fulla removal men and a date at the morgue - And, Ron, Con- gratulations - you're my first call ..</context>
      <utterance>That, I couldn't tell you .. And don't worry about anya this crap,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PATHOLOGIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>.. if the knife hadn't killed him, the booze would .. I nev- er seen such a bad cirrhosis ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up a nicotine-stained left hand. Simultaneously a LAB TECHNICIAN wants BERLIN to sign in exchange for the picnic box.</context>
      <utterance>You say the cut's left to right?  Isn't that unusual? He's left handed?</utterance>
   <speaker>PATHOLOGIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess he was so drunk, he did- n't know which hand he was using.  What are you gonna do with it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands the clip-board back and remembers a question for ROSS. Oh, Ross, that newspaper guy at the station, asked me if the hand was "frozen?" Why would he ask me that?</context>
      <utterance>Depends how healthy it is. If it's any good, I'll try and get a print ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another fast fix on the Vic and BERLIN chews fresh gum. A need- le on a weighing machine quivers. "The liver weighs 1420 grams." A few beers wouldn't do that to you, would they?</context>
      <utterance>Frozen? .. I've no idea ..</utterance>
   <speaker>PATHOLOGIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Freddy .. Not a few ..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He emerges from the refrigerator wielding a bottle of champagne.</context>
      <utterance>You do a rush on three pizzas?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm gonna cook him a dinner.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not giving him Pizza. I haven't seem him for a year?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He detours via the kitchen door to shout upstairs. "Hey. Bobby.?"</context>
      <utterance>Dinner's another night, darlin .. This is a drive-by. I got an hour ..</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bobby's out .. What's the hurry?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Friday night at City Hall. Got a great chance to frighten the fat.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Freddy's new obsession ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is who?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ROSS fights a difficult cork "You wanna get some glasses, Honey?" She's an accounts-manager, very pal- ly with our mayor, up to her elbows in fraud, and I just can't prove it ..</context>
      <utterance>A professional, whining, con-person bitch with an ass the size of Africa ..</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So tonight she confesses?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cork explodes and he goes for glasses but one isn't willing.</context>
      <utterance>Tonight I'm feeling lucky ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not for me ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What d'you mean, I just opened it for you? This is French champagne.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No it isn't .. It's Californian ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even better.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not today .. I'm on a diet to- day .. I'll take a diet soda ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since when did you drink diet soda?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she's already at the fridge and popping a can of diet cola. Here you go, Honey .. You're looking wonderful, John .. I can't believe we got you here ..</context>
      <utterance>Stop nagging him. If he doesn't want it, he doesn't want it. You- 're quacking like an old duck ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's the new residence?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not too good in daylight ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, just shut your eyes until it's painted. You're gonna love it. This is "God's Country," John.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sure he will and six rolls of film are handed across. "Are you winning, Sir?" BERLIN smiles and VENABLES follows him out into the corridor. A couple of Coppers on their way in. One big and morose looking called BISLEY. The other we've already met. Tay- lor is a tall balding guy with hazy reddish hair "How you doin?" BERLIN responds a happy "O.K." with eyes returning to VENABLES. You know something strange about that hand? I think it was frozen?</context>
      <utterance>Would you drop these off for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>VENABLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frozen?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Apparently little. They arrive in the big room. It's deserted. C'mon, Venables, you're a policeman. And policemen always have an answer?</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. What does that mean to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>VENABLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Sir ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what?</utterance>
   <speaker>VENABLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A vacuum cleaner starts somewhere but BERLIN isn't hearing it. So it could be that some crazy's stored her hand in a freezer, and only now decided to get rid of it?</context>
      <utterance>Well, we had a very bad murder here, coupla years ago. Not act- ually in our county, but south of here. Girl with no head, no hands. You didn't read about it?  It was big shit. They had forty, fifty detective working it. Nev- er identified her. Never found the head, never found the hands ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do I find the file on that?</utterance>
   <speaker>VENABLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BERLIN is already looking. A last question as VENABLES leaves. Was it really frozen, Sergeant?</context>
      <utterance>In there if we got anything? I believe the code was "Jennifer."</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Been dead two weeks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What time is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A newspaper featuring a small photograph and article on Berlin. Holding the Finger he carefully inserts a hypodermic needle un- der the wire. Gently shoots in fluid to inflate the finger pad.</context>
      <utterance>Seven thirty-five .. Here, "Town Gets Top Cop." I was gonna pin it to your wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why so coy about the word "frozen"?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because, don't get into it ...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's nothing in the files?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Finger pad is sufficiently restored to try and get a print. It wasn't our case, wasn't our coun- ty, and got nothing to do with that.</context>
      <utterance>Watch my lips .. Don't get into it ..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The machine shunts up another slide. Now the back of the Hand. I count eleven scars on this hand, and four that might be? .. Now I count em on my hand? Five. I'm 42 years old. This girl's about 18? How come she's got so many scars? He walks out of the projection beam and neon light flutters on. So tell me about "Jennifer?" Reaches for a pack of cigarettes and perches on a nearby stool. You know I'm gonna find out. BERLIN counts out cigarettes. And destroys them in an ashtray.</context>
      <utterance>Look - 1 - 2 - 3/4 - 5 - 6 - 7 ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's an "unsolved." They spent 500 thousand dollars &amp; bought emselves a dead end - You might wanna check it with Taylor, he worked the case.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ROSS reaches for the paper &amp; thumb-tacks it to the wall "That."</context>
      <utterance>I already did. What's his problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He thinks you stole his promotion.  What exactly you doin there, John?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A Zippo opens (sports L.A.P.D. insignia) and BERLIN lights up. He takes a punishing hit and exhales a lungful across the lab.</context>
      <utterance>It's a method for quitting smoking.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Back on his feet BERLIN is about to begin more work on the Hand.</context>
      <utterance>That's an interesting method? Must help beat the withdrawal?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a technique I read about. If you smoke 60 a day, you buy three packs, throw one cigar- ette away, and smoke 59. Day 2, you throw 2 away and smoke 58 ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you throw them all away, and smoke none?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daftest thing Ross ever heard. BERLIN is poised to make a print.</context>
      <utterance>Because it's a ritual you gotta go through with. I'm down to 10.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want my advice?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Find yourself a farmer's daughter with nice big fucking tits, and shake that "bye-bye." Send it to Sacramento, John .. I sniff grief ..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The house is a zoo of furniture. Bullshit piled up everywhere.</context>
      <utterance>You're all done except the floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>By now she's got the apron off and her coat on. "C'mon, Bobby."</context>
      <utterance>You're a saint, Margie, thanks ..</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And off they go via a slammed door as the phone starts to ring.</context>
      <utterance>Don't forget the wagon, Darlin?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta stop smoking ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am stopping smoking ...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't mean this "system" shit that keeps you sucking, I mean stop .. I was exactly like you are .. I used to wake in the night - heart going so hard I coulda made love with my left tit .. If I can stop, you can ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd you do it, old man?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone bet me a dollar ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BERLIN manages to find air to sit. Reaches for the Ansa Phone.</context>
      <utterance>A dollar? .. Not worth giving up for a dollar ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>First call comes from Delaware Roofing vis-a-vis the estimate.</context>
      <utterance>Alright. I'll bet you fifty?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>During these proceedings the machine has moved to another call.</context>
      <utterance>Fifty dollars? You got a bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>[MACHINE]</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>[J.B./Ronzo/Got some results for you/ First/ the blood on the bra is human/ and it's not a popular brand/A.B. Neg and that's a rare one/Two/the blood on the brassie- re is compatible with the blood from the hand/Three/If you need anything else the official answer from all us Christians down here, is fuck off/Shoot me a duck/Bye]</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you gonna do, Soldier?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna dig up "Jennifer."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chief, I gotta talk to ya about this fat lady?</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about her?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CITRINE continues up the carpet. "Alright, we'll talk about it."</context>
      <utterance>She's making my life a misery .. I wanna give her a lie-detector test?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But CITRINE isn't interested in finger nails. He's staring at a polystyrene torso of a faceless girl. She wears a brassiere stuffed with newspaper and a black wig. (Welcome Jennifer Two) She's almost identical to Jennifer. Slim - White - same age - bra size is even the same. Nicely made lady. CITRINE stares at the Dummy like he's gonna ask it a question.</context>
      <utterance>Laser enhancement of the finger- tip .. it's really bothering me .. See these striations right here?  It's like she's always worrying the end of her finger? Rubbing it with a thumb nail, or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know her hair's black?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hair on her hand. Plus Jen- nifer had raven black hair.</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He waves a handful of teletype before dumping it on a bench. These cases aren't connected, John?</context>
      <utterance>What is all this Jennifer stuff?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Sir, I think they maybe. I think "Jennifer," and this lady got hit by the same guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the board is a super-imposed picture of a hand over a wrist.</context>
      <utterance>I don't see that at all ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got four points of posit- ive comparison on the cut ..</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A question he doesn't need because he hasn't an answer. CITRINE has an eye on further photographs relevant to the Jennifer case. I don't know nothing about this "Jenn- ifer" girl, cept what some of the guys told me - but principal feature of the case was a gruesome displayal of the body. He wanted it found. So if this is the same guy, why's he hidden this one? Another question he can't answer - and this time he doesn't get a chance - BISLEY walks in with an apology for the interruption. Got a face like Humphrey Bogart's mother fucked a different guy.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that's all very inter- esting, but where's the body?</utterance>
   <speaker>BISLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just wondered if you had time to get around to my pharmacy stuff?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll have it in the morning ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BISLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bisley has gone but his tension stays. BERLIN unwraps fresh gum.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, I'll try again tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He worked a lotta time on this.</context>
      <utterance>Probably making him feel a bit antsy seein it back on the wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought it was Taylor's case?</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is CITRINE's shop and BERLIN isn't gonna row it with him.</context>
      <utterance>Sucked in officers from all over the county. And it was the worst six months this station ever had.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want me to do, Chief?</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He refers to a little bicycle. Vouchered and obviously stolen. By now CITRINE is at the hinges. A pause before he disappears. Why don't you give it a minute, &amp; stop by my office. We should talk.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not telling you what to do. What I will say, is right now, that child's tricycle there is more important to me than this ..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>.. what does he think it is?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN [ROSS]</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He even tried a "self-inflicted."</context>
      <utterance>Everything it isn't [make a left].</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stop at a light and a beeper goes as warning to the blind. What's she gonna do? Dump her bra in one bag, her hand in the other, and wander off whistling Hey Jude?</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Ross, the bra and hand were in different bags a 100 feet apart ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BERLIN is worrying at his fingertip on the wheel of the Zippo. You can't stop it, can you?</context>
      <utterance>It's the garage on the far corner.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Worrying - clicking - picking - You may as well be back in Los Angeles.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The lights change and off they go and BERLIN waits for a turn.</context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, Ross?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Give the fucking F.B.I. a present?</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you dump it? Mail it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you dump the "Fat Lady?"</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I dislike her too much ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>O.K. and I'm not in love with this fukker? That's how I feel about him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And by now they've arrived and pulled up on the garage forecourt. It's indicative of their friendship that ROSS can talk like this. Wait for me. It might not be ready. He quits the car and BERLIN watches him scurry towards a service shop. Rain beats on the roof and BERLIN looks stubbed out. A lot of cuts coming up and here are some of them. Runs a hand through his hair in unconscious frustration. A finger constantly bothers the Zippo. Eyes towards ROSS who silhouettes in florescent light. Somewhere in the background the lights change to red. Once again the beeping sound of traffic-lights speaking to the blind. Maybe he looks across but that doesn't matter. Something just happens inside his head he isn't yet quite aware of. Everything in close up. Big on the Zippo. Big on BERLIN. And he leaps out of the car. BERLIN sprints through the weather. A station wagon is still in the air at the end of an hydraulic jack. Surprise from ROSS and a MECHANIC as BERLIN arrives. Fuck the fanbelt and listen to this.</context>
      <utterance>No you don't. That's how you think you feel about him. That's how you feel about yourself. You won't give yourself one-fucking-minute for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rain beats at the roof and the jack sinks the wagon behind them. She's blind, Ross - that's why all the scars - hear that traffic light? That noise is to help blind people - that's why the marks on her finger- tips? - this lady reads in Braille ..</context>
      <utterance>I just had this insane idea - if I'm wrong, I'll take a week off and redecorate your entire house ..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sticks a sheet of notes on his desk and he junks the last call. BERLIN (New call) Hello .. Yes .. This is Sergeant Berlin .. Yes, that's right .. I believe my assistant explained? .. How long ago was that? .. Uh-huh. O.K. .. Who is who? .. Whass his name? Goodridge? O.K. I'll hold .. ROSS in transit grinning from ear to ear. BERLIN interested in little but his notes and ROSS in nothing but obvious good news.</context>
      <utterance>Shasta-Trinity Institute. Line one.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pig Woman agreed to take a test.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I got something - twenty two years old, dark hair - study- ing mathematics -  - Last seen 5 weeks ago ..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>GOODRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As recent as we have .. What ex- actly is your interest in Amber?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid I can't give you an ans- wer to that, Mr Goodridge. As I ex- plained to your secretary, we're do- ing a lotta looking, but we're not even sure it's her we're lookin for ..</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what are you hoping I'm gon- na do? Dissuade, or persuade you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was hopin since we spoke that you might have remembered something that would give us an idea where she is?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't like them but not as much as ROSS doesn't like him.</context>
      <utterance>Then you could have saved yourself a lot of driving, Sergeant. What I said on the phone's the same as I'm saying now. I got no idea where Amb- er is, or who it was took her there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A blind girl can just walk out of here, and you don't know who with?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You find something curious in that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I guess I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then let me put your mind at ease .. Firstly, Amber isn't "blind" - she has some useful vision - and second, this isn't a prison, it's a college of higher education - a severe vis- ual disability doesn't mean my stud- ents don't value their independence as much as anybody else - and Amber was a very independent young woman - She decided to leave - so she left ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you got no idea with who?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ROSS could sock him in the crop but the phone rings and he ex- cuses himself to answer it. Whatever he hears he isn't liking. You have an appointment with Miss Robertson?</context>
      <utterance>No, Sergeant, I got no idea with who. And I might add, that in another six weeks, a hundred and fifty students will be leaving here, &amp; driving away for their Christmas holidays with pe- ople whose name I-won't-know-either ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As she's a member of my staff, may I ask what this is about?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, apparently, she saw Amber the weekend she left, &amp; was briefly in the room with the guy she left with.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOODRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see .. Well, she's teaching an- other class at four .. I'd apprec- iate it if you don't detain her ..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is everyone?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Here come footsteps and the door is opened by HELENA ROBERTSON. Early 20's and blonde and not immediately beautiful. But delic- ate features than need no make up and big dark eyes. They look away for introductions as though she's shy. ROSS &amp; BERLIN grab glances as they follow in. Neither expected HELENA to be blind.</context>
      <utterance>I dunno .. I guess this is staff side of the building?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What d'you wanna ask, Mr Ross?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Mr Berlin. Mr Ross is right here. And Mr Ross is maybe gonna take a few notes, if that's O.K.?  O.K. .. I'd like you to tell me in what ever way you want, what you can remember about the time you spent with Amber on the aft- ernoon she left? Take your time, and nothing's too trivial, O.K.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I think I told you on the phone .. I went up to her room to say good-bye, and we just sat on the bed and chatted a while, while her friend was coming in and out collecting her things ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lots of headshake. And lots of silences. "I really don't know." That's O.K. Can you give me any idea what this fellow was like? (Headshake) Well, d'you know how old he was? (Headshake) Alright, let me put it this way? How old d'you think I am? Twenty- six? Thirty-nine? Or fifty-three?</context>
      <utterance>What kind of friend? Was he a boy friend? An old friend? New friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Possibly the only grin ROSS is going to get out of this place.</context>
      <utterance>Fifty-three.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must have some idea about him.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When we spoke on the phone, did you know I was blonde?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A good point. And a point taken. And BERLIN might even say so. We don't have some kind of sixth-sense, you know. Ex- cept in ridiculous novels .. Now another silence overtaken by a low whistle in another room. He used a breath freshener ... A sardonic headshake from ROSS. Well that solves the case then! And I think his name was John?</context>
      <utterance>Why not? You heard my voice?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John? .. You never said that on the phone? .. What makes you think his name was John?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BERLIN would but ROSS wouldn't. She leaves and whispers begin.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I guess she must have called him John? I'm mak- ing tea. Would you like some?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This looks promising .. I think this one could be it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank Christ we got a witness.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She might remember something?</context>
      <utterance>Let me just keep going a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He thumbs a cluster of cheap busts of composers on an upright. We're better off having another pop at old Abe Lincoln down the- re? Get angry with the prick. Get some of his "useful visions" in? Someone must have seen something? Negative from BERLIN. Checked it out. Sunday and no one about. This is fucken crazy. Two hours here, two hours back, and the only word I've written is John .. A touch later and the sun is setting. ROSS stands at a window to watch it go. Watches one or two cars driving away. Watches a bird sitting outside on the fire-escape. BERLIN's voice can just about be heard off screen "You said he spoke? Can you re- member what he said?" ROSS saunters back into HELENA's answer.</context>
      <utterance>What? She's blind, Bro. You may as well ask one of these Beethoven guys on the piano?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Empty teacups and empty notebook. ROSS sits opposite BERLIN. And I remember, he was a lit- tle breathless from carrying the cases because the elevat- or had gone out that weekend.</context>
      <utterance>Well, he just said, come on, hurry up, will you, because it's starting to snow again.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The elevator wasn't working?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A clock strikes four somewhere. And BERLIN knows he's lost it.</context>
      <utterance>No, it has a mind of its own.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I see your hands?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes her hands and HELENA immediately looks uncomfortable. He examines scars and she stares at him with her useless eyes. I have a class. I have to go.</context>
      <utterance>My hands?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there anything else you can tell me? Anything about him or her? Doesn't matter how small?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Except he smoked. Like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A taut instant between ROSS and BERLIN. BERLIN caught out and he knows it. ROSS roars in silence "YOU LYING PIG" and writes in his notebook. The angle switches to see "BERLIN IS A LIAR." I'm late .. I really have to go .. Everyone suddenly on their feet and HELENA gets into a jacket.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I could smell it on his breath, like I can on your's.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>D'you have a dog? Seeing Eye Dog?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lotta scratch-marks on your door?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes I look after friends dogs, if they go to dances, or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tries to get his notebook under BERLIN's nose. But BERLIN isn't looking or listening but following HELENA into her hall.</context>
      <utterance>Could I just refer you to this memo here, Sergeant?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did Amber have a dog?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What color was it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens the door and ROSS is barely through before it slams.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bells the elevator refusing to acknowledge ROSS's bullshit. I'll leave a number with the office .. Lips drill a whisper into his ear. "Fifty fucken dollars, O.K." What exactly do you teach, Helena?</context>
      <utterance>.. if she writes, or calls, or any- thing at all, you let me know, O.K.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Music composition .. and cello ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meanwhile the elevator arrives triggering a Voice. "YOU ARE NOW ON THE FOURTH FLOOR." Doors slide open and Christ look at this? What kind of eye-defect needs glasses like this? Lenses like ei- ther half of a glass ball. He's early 30's and decidedly "iffy." Is he student/staff or what? As he exits they enter staring aft- er him. As the doors close the MYOPIC turns to stare after them.</context>
      <utterance>Fifty of em. And I want em now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Had a seeing Eye Dog since she was eighteen .. didn't I tell you those dogs meant something ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We gotta get back up that dump ..</context>
      <utterance>Alright, I didn't, but I nearly did, and if I had I'd have been right .. I knew there was some- thing about that Labrador, that dog was too good to be dead ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way .. not me, Mister. I'm not going up there again. Might find someone's prick in a hot-dog roll.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ROSS pops cans and hands one over. But BERLIN doesn't want it.</context>
      <utterance>Forget it. They got stringent hyg- iene rules. He's long gone in lime.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe not? I'm feeling lucky ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So am I. But where's my money?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't start again. If you win a bet, you can't keep winning it ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pay me, and I shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then give me that Zippo.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need some security. I don't trust you anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had one puff on a pipe.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Snaps fingers "Gimme the lighter." And he does to shut him up. I'll tell you what I'm gonna do? I'm gonna do you a big favor .. Forget the 50 and I'll keep this.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want excuses, I want that weird-looking stuff called "cash."</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want it for?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Does it as he says it. Bye-bye Zippo! BERLIN can't believe it.</context>
      <utterance>To throw out of the window.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I've had that 15 years! ..</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing, Ross?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not your friend. It keeps you sucking. Remem- ber the old Bum's lungs?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I remember the old bastard's liver! I don't believe you did that. I had a great sent- imental attachment to that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An academic question considering the Zippo went down a ravine.</context>
      <utterance>You want me to stop the car?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm gonna find that fucking dog!</context>
      <utterance>No! Get me to that garbage dump!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't shoot him did you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRIMBLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me .. I love dogs .. Ask him?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ROSS detours eyes to wave at his Son. "Watch those revs there." Would you shut it down a min- ute, Ross? This is important. ROSS signals BOBBY to turn off. And the diesel splutters down.</context>
      <utterance>.. I put the slug in for a ballis- tics report, the man tells me, for get it. Soft lead, it's worthless .. I think, fuck it. And fuck Citrine. I call a friend of mine in Los Ang- eles, and he runs our whole damned show through a main-frame looking for anything similar to our ladies shot with a twenty-two - you don't believe what he finds in San Diego ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, let's take a walk around the block .. I gotta buy a gasket ..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six girls over a period of 18 months, and give or take a head or two, the M.O.'s exactly the same. Dark hair. No hands. All shot with a high velocity twen- ty-two in the back of the head.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come the F.B.I. don't put anya this together? They work- ed over "Jennifer" for months?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They possibly did - but they nev- er had a head, so they never had a bullet - and they never got an I.D. - not on any of em - never bust a homicide unless you know who your victim is - we're the first to get a positive identity.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You need fifty detectives on this.</context>
      <utterance>Identity of whom? You got a girl, doesn't even have a driver's lic- ense? .. She's untraceable, John ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I'm here for. I want you to come and see Citrine with me? He's not gonna here it from me but I know he'd listen to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to me saying what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanna take that fucking Blind In- stitute to pieces .. Every address book, every phone call, everyone in and outta there in the last 5 years ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For a dead dog?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And this is the second time they stop and stare at each other. That old Wino on the heap wasn't a suicide. He stumbled into some- thing, saw something, and whoever took him out knew how to fake it.</context>
      <utterance>We've fused into a major series, Ross. This girl isn't the second victim. This is "Jennifer Eight."</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That isn't what you said before.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Says it with remarkable humility considering he's the "expert." I'm going in to see Citrine this afternoon. Will you come with me?</context>
      <utterance>I was wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They arrive at the Chandler's with BERLIN in no mood to smile.</context>
      <utterance>You're not .. He's in hospital .. He was trying out a new pair of skis in his hallway. The phone rings, and he goes for it, and falls off. He must be the only skier in Northern California to break a leg in his living room.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You believe me, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he doesn't really believe it. And doesn't enjoy saying no. But I can't help you with this. We can't go through the door with two contentious issues, you with a mass murderer, and me with the Mayor's best friend. Do that, we lose both. I'm sorry, Bro, you're on your own.</context>
      <utterance>What does it matter what I bel- ieve? .. What you gotta worry about is what Citrine believes ..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you been here long?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, just a minute or two .. I knocked on your door - no one home, so I followed the music ..</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I'll get my things.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But she's already fussing about stuffing sheet music in a bag. Matter of fact, I saw a little restaurant place down the road. Looked kinda pretty? I thought maybe we could have some lunch? No answer but the answer is no. BERLIN finds her book for her. Alright, whatever .. Was some- one in here with you? When I came in the door was flapping?</context>
      <utterance>No problem. I'm not in a hurry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so .. No one comes here at the weekends ..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose I'm the worst witness you've ever had?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta admit, you're one of them. Just wish I knew what you meant by a "hollow car?"</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Any moment now they turn a corner of the stairs into close-up. Maybe it was a foreign car? Our kinda cars sound "fat." The elevator is parked on this floor with its doors half open. Are you sure you wanna see it? It's another three floors up? Despite breathlessness he does. "How often does it break down?" Oh, all the time. They keep threatening to have it re- placed, but they never will.</context>
      <utterance>Well, some cars sound fat and some cars sound thin, and this kind of car sounded "hollow" ..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I came to the diner with you, would you bring me back?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His smile deteriorates as he realizes she's "staring" at him. What are you staring at, Hel- ena? .. I mean .. I'm sorry ..</context>
      <utterance>Of course I would ..</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nothing happening except the wind. Then a smile as she leaves. I'll get my coat, wait for you downstairs .. And he begins an exploration. Musty bathroom with old-fashion- ed fixtures. A tap leaking behind shower curtains. Nothing in the cabinet. Nothing under the sink. Six steps and he is in a kitchen. Finally finds something worth looking for. Tears the sack out of a vacuum cleaner. Discovers a knot of hair from a black dog. Simultaneously the door slams. Shock powers him in- to the sitting room in time to hear a key turning in the lock. Hits the door and shouts. Hears footsteps moving rapidly away.</context>
      <utterance>That's alright. You suddenly reminded me of him .. He was standing right where you are, kind of breathless, like you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, someone slammed the door on me. I couldn't get out.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hellava wind that turns a key! But he says nothing. Takes the book while she gets into her coat. She's obviously made an ef- fort. A change of clothes and her hair pinned up. But she has got the sweater on inside out and the label is under her chin.</context>
      <utterance>It was probably the wind.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you reading?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hamlet. Have you read it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>By now they're at the doors with BERLIN escorting her through.</context>
      <utterance>You should. It's wonderful.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HELENA sits frozen like she's waiting for results of an X-ray. I mean, we don't havta sit here waiting for me to ask the next question? You could ask one, too?</context>
      <utterance>.. I'll tell you what, if I prom- ise to stop being a cop, will you promise to stop being a witness?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you wearing a uniform?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm glad we got the conver- sational side of lunch over with.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry .. I don't like sitting in the middle of a restaurant .. I feel like everyone's looking at me ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he likes what he's looking at. And maybe HELENA senses it.</context>
      <utterance>There's no one "looking at you" .. There's hardly anyone in here. The only person looking at you, is me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you married?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was. But I don't like to talk about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just asked me to ask you questions.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, but you pick on the one time in my life I like not to remember. I was in the bad lands. Really not well. It's something that happens to a lota cops. We don't wanna talk about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Thoughts that lie too deep for tears."</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that'll do .. Is that "Hamlet?"</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His attention is temporarily elsewhere. A Lunch Party just arr- ived. It's clear GOODRIDGE is profoundly unhappy to see BERLIN.</context>
      <utterance>No, Wordsworth .. Do you like poetry?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, I haven't read much. I don't think poetry's my kinda thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you pray?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pray?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said, you were in the bad lands?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I don't pray .. Had a dream once, about God, just around the time I was getting well .. He was a nasty lookin little guy, moved into the apartment right on topa me .. I said, don't you listen to people's prayers? He said, prayers? Not often. They're Junk Mail.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pulls into a parking spot and the next sound is the hand brake. I couldn't take another minute of Los Angeles .. Felt like I'd said sorry in every street in the city ..</context>
      <utterance>.. I got really sick of the street .. so I went to school and became a Scientific Services Officer, which is basically a Scene of Crime Off- icer. Then this came up, and I got what they call a Lateral Transfer ..</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>.. sorry your father, mother sis- ter, whatever .. I couldn't take another day of it .. Come on, I'm gonna rob you of a cup of coffee ..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Time to go and both know it. Stale shadows and growing silence. Is it snowing now?</context>
      <utterance>Coz I wanted to feel the snow on my face .. I think that's when I heard her call him John?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And his eyes are searching her so hard she must be aware of it. You think you'd know this man? If he was in the room with you again?</context>
      <utterance>No. Getting dark though.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The silence is almost uncomfortable. BERLIN continues to stare. Amber's dead, isn't she?</context>
      <utterance>You've already asked me that ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I'm sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're pushing this too hard. It's like you want me to say stop? You must know that's the way this is going, John? There's other work to do, why don't ya ease off a little?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coz this is a major &amp; we're closer to this bastard than anyone's ever been.</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then where's the body? .. Where's the body, and why's he hidden it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He hasn't hidden it. He never made a hit this far north before, and he never read a weather forecast .. She's probably fifteen feet from the highway, three feet under snow.</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you got a match on the bullet?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you got a print from the hand?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It could be anyone's hand. Illeg- ally disposed of hospital debris ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her dog's shot. And she's missing.</context>
      <utterance>It's her hand. Her scars. Her dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's not "missing." Did she shout? Did she scream? Did he coerce her? No. She left of her own free will .. And if she gets on a plane and goes to Peru with the prick, she's still not missing. You got no case, John.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're not gonna hear me, Chief ..</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have heard you. You just don't like hearing me. You got this whole damned thing outta proportion. I don't know what you gotten used to in Los Angeles, but I don't believe there's a Police Chief, in this country, would put a task force together for a body part ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have a multiple homicide, Sir ..</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have a body part in suspicious circumstances - a tailor's dummy wearing a brassiere - and a bill for seventeen dollars for its wig!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did he shut you down?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All but .. How you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dunno, I daren't go in there - just about get her wired up, and the fucking mayor walks in - mad as hell - what are we doing fuck- ing with his staff? We should be out chasing major violators ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He almost does the whiskey but reaches for chewing gum instead. He thinks the kid shot the dog .. He looks at ROSS like what-are-you-looking-at-me-like-that-for? He didn't.</context>
      <utterance>I wish he'd tell that to Citrine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did I say he did?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You looked like you did?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I think you'll find I looked like he could have? By accident even? He's up here spraying the scenery all day.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SERATO walks in with a cigarette plugged into his ashen kisser.</context>
      <utterance>He didn't shoot it, Ross. And no way by accident. There's a flash-burn. It was point-blank.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Flying colors ...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say you didn't say that, Angelo?</utterance>
   <speaker>SERATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God Mother's shit. Are we in it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EXPERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the important one. She gets a dead straight line, and that's an exceptional reading ..</utterance>
   <speaker>SERATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>.. this is the stupidest thing we ever done. Fucking Citrine's gonna fire one of us for this ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe it. I just know she someway busted it.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXPERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is an honest girl. She couldn't lie if she tried ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For a moment there is an intense trust between ROSS and BERLIN.</context>
      <utterance>Is she lying, Ross?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alright fuck it. Let's go for broke. BERLIN grabs the read out. Fueled on residual anger he vanishes out the door. ROSS is fir- st at the mirror to see him reappear in the interrogation room.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the time is his. He knows what he's doing. And she doesn't. I been a policeman 17 years: 16 years 9 months of which with the L.A.P.D. I witnessed literally hundreds of lie-detector tests, and I never seen one like this?</context>
      <utterance>My name's Sergeant John Berlin.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What d'ya mean, Sergeant?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All he's doing is telling her truth. Up to her to interpret it. Thought you might wanna comment? A tongue slides through the lipstick like something being born.</context>
      <utterance>Well, look at it. Look at this line? That's the important one. Dead straight down the page. No- body gets a dead straight down the page. Even our expert says a dead straight's "exceptional."</utterance>
   <speaker>EMERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And suddenly the only thing holding her chops up is Max Factor. He's got her on the roll now and all it needs is one more push.</context>
      <utterance>I wasn't actually lying, Officer.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The quivering lip and flooding eyes amalgamate into a horrible sort of groan. She's bellied up and anxious to spill her beans. BERLIN better get through the door fast because he might laugh. You tell one more lie, you're go- ing in a cell. Sergeant Ross is coming in to take your statement.</context>
      <utterance>You busted the box, lady! You flunk- ed it .. You lied about things you didn't need to lie about .. The only truthful statement you made's your name .. Your name is Carol Emerson?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MARGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Such a shame .. She's a really sweet kid ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stairs descend to a cabin and ROSS interrupts himself to shout. Bobby, what happened to that beer? Rule one, is you don't diddle around with a witness.</context>
      <utterance>She's a doll. But I wish he hadn't brought her out here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's happy, darlin ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BOBBY clatters up the stairs clutching a six pack of Budweiser. Tell em I'm going up the coast a way, get out of this weather. BOBBY exits the wheelhouse and walks their eyes back to HELENA.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sure he is. But gettin in- to the "element" is a bad idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGIE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Except for the hair color, she looks just like Suzanne?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Cept she can't run away.</context>
      <utterance>Well, that's who she is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MARGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want something, darling?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In code so BERLIN won't understand. But he and ROSS swap grins. How much longer you on that diet?</context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't mind another B.E.E.R.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARGIE climbs the stairs with drinks and drinks a beer herself. Popped cans change the subject. This seems like a question BER- LIN doesn't really want to ask &amp; MARGIE doesn't want to answer. How's your little sister?</context>
      <utterance>I'm doing it by the day ...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's in Europe ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clearly a sensitive subject and ROSS decides the truth is best.</context>
      <utterance>Working?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She married some English prick.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not that bad of a guy ..?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The joke doesn't reach BERLIN. MARGIE's hand is on his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Got a handshake like a partially excited penis.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she heads for the lower deck. A sweet smile as she descends. Anyway, you're doing O. K. She's a sweet heart. And also playing the guitar "In My Life." And she does it well.</context>
      <utterance>Her loss, darlin ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why's she blind, Bro?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slow banging of something swaying. And this exchange goes slow. Whole family wiped out.</context>
      <utterance>Car accident.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A bleeper goes on one of the lines and ROSS twists in his seat. Strap me in. Here comes another. And he winds in yet another three quarters of a pound Mackerel. Worst day's fishing I ever had ..</context>
      <utterance>No shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ROSS dexterously extracts the hook with serious eyes on BERLIN.</context>
      <utterance>It's been a great day.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just go easy, Brother ...  Alright, we're all goin home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Silhouettes with exaggerated shadows walk across the car park. What does she do?</context>
      <utterance>I really liked Margie ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She runs a kind of hair dress- ing and you know, beauty salon ..</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you known her long?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The angle changes and is closer now. HELENA has taken his arm. You don't ask what I'm like?</context>
      <utterance>I was married to her sister ..</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know what you're like ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How d'you know what I'm like?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ross told me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? What did he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And you have a nervous tick.</context>
      <utterance>He said you're quite chubby.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said that? What else did he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just your age.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which is what?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BERLIN is more amused than annoyed. They arrive at the car and his suggestion is met with an appropriate response from HELENA.</context>
      <utterance>Fifty-seven .. I don't mind ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>"I can't drive a car." Doesn't like cars. But he's not hearing. C'mon it'll be fun. You can drive me around in circles .. No lady ever had a driving lesson like this before. BERLIN all but sits in her seat. Arm on the back of it. Hand on the wheel. For a split second they're doing 60. Now they're doing about 4. The Mercedes spirals in widening circles. Instructions and enc- ouragement from BERLIN .. O.K. .. Straight now .. The Mercedes straightens and heads through the dunes. "It's a big car park?" We're going along a little track. HELENA may like driving but she doesn't like the sound of that. It's O.K. It's not a public road. Headlights behind them approach quickly. Disappear and reappear as they follow the geography of the dunes. BERLIN only now bec- omes aware of them. one more dip and they slam in. Her anxiety is misinterpreted. He takes the wheel. No problem. Let him pass. The vehicle is right up behind them. As it overtakes HELENA is scared. And still scared even though BERLIN has stopped the car. It's alright, I'm sorry. It was my fault, it wasn't a good idea.</context>
      <utterance>You wanna drive? C'mon we're in a car park, miles from any- where .. There's nothing arou- nd but nothing and sand dunes ..</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just time to see tail lights of a van disappearing in the gloom.</context>
      <utterance>That was the "Hollow Car," John.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A Volkswagen van? Are you sure?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm shutting you down on this "blind thing," John.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that my punishment for embarrassing Mr Heineman?</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't underestimate me .. the Mayor's pissed - but that's nothing to do with this - sit down - How many times have you been up at that institute?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three or four.</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm talking, outside the girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Once.</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Says, you're upsetting his students?</context>
      <utterance>Got a letter from this Goodridge guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's bullshit,</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He floats the letter across the desk and hears the explanation.</context>
      <utterance>He says, you freaked one of em out?  "Asking a newly blind kid if he can 'see,' is both cruel, and dangerous" ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never asked if he could "see." I just asked one or two of the stud- ents if they remembered anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And did they?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CITRINE rubs his forehead in preparation to change the subject,</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>If there was any argument to be had BERLIN would be arguing it. I don't want you up at that institute again .. and I'm flat-out about that .. I'm sorry, I know it means something to you - you can go tell your witness if you feel you must - but as far as you're concerned, the case is closed ..</context>
      <utterance>I'm not a nasty man, John, I'm a nice man .. I get a lot of Christmas cards  .. and I'm getting a lot of complaints. The guy you replaced was something you- 're not - a lazy sonovabitch - but the reality is, I was getting a faster ser- vice outta Popeye than I am outta you .. I can't allow this to continue, John ..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, it pisses me off, Ross.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No God, Brother. If there was a God, asses wouldn't be at the perfect height for kicking.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>VENABLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I buy you a beer, Sergeant?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ROSS pokes VENABLES a surreptitious 20 with eyes on the BLONDE. Right now she's far end of the bar delivering a beer to BISLEY. (Look at those Amazingly Bos- oms) You wanna beer, King Jay?</context>
      <utterance>Don't try and ingratiate your- self with me, Venables. But just this once I'll have a Heineken .. and John here will have one, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TAYLOR gets a last cough out of a cigarette before stubbing it.</context>
      <utterance>No, I gotta go .. I'm nights ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BLATTIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gimme a ride?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he's already gathered his shit and halfway into his jacket. How's that hand-job comin along, John? BERLIN makes a gesture he'd have trouble understanding himself.</context>
      <utterance>Sure ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, we're not talking "talk" tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one's gonna make that Gent. Six months investigation, &amp; the nearest we got, we thought he was a sailor.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>By now TAYLOR is moving through the crush of faces behind them.</context>
      <utterance>A sailor?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Night, night, Freddy T .. John ..</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, in and outta Frisco on the big boats .. Every lead we had went right out to sea ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come he's suddenly so forth- coming? I'd like to kick him right in the ass. If he'd discussed it with me, I mighta gotten somewhere ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never knew about the sailor the- ory, Ross. He might have that one little thing I need in his files?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And just that one moment of insanity as BERLIN downs it in one. Alright .. Let's have some wine ..</context>
      <utterance>John, stop it. The case is on its ass, you're closed.  C'mon, let it go for once .. Have a drink. C'mon, relax, drink your beer ..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta stop calling Los Angeles .. You're dragging L.A. around with you like an addiction. Look at the shit you're putting yourself through? For what? For nothing, I know it, I been there. Remember me? Up to my asshole in anger, living off the vitamins in cigarettes? If there's a body under the snow, fuck it. Let somebody else worry about it. You gotta accept you stopped living in that world, &amp; try and give yourself a break in this ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just makes to so God damned mad ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Waving his empty at the bar ROSS communicates need for another. How d'you know this girl isn't lying to you .. Not lying as such, but mak- ing up stuff to keep you coming back?</context>
      <utterance>You're a fucking great policeman, but give yourself a break. You're here 5 minutes, you find yourself a fucking homicide? .. Not many people could do that in a place like this .. And you gotta admit, there's a lot of shaky areas in this case? .. I mean, stop me if I'm going up the wrong nostril ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She wasn't lying about the van.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, she wasn't lying about the van. But it could have been any van? Any little foreign diesel? .. She's blind, Bro .. It's sad .. She's pro- bably lonely, and you're a nice guy to have around .. But you're getting far too far into the element, Brother ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't need me to tell you what hap- pens when you get emotionally involved?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, enough, Ross. You'll bring on my "Nervous Tick" ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>.. feel like I'm getting close to this guy .. and all the time, feel like I'm sharpening a pencil with a broken load .. I'm sorry, King J ..</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you looking for?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vehicle references.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gestures to the right one. BERLIN feels about 2 inches tall. I'm gonna get some coffee. When you finish in here, maybe you'll let me know? .. I got a report to type up .. As he exits he tosses a bunch of keys. They crash uselessly on- to the desk. BERLIN looks like he couldn't get a fuck with mud.</context>
      <utterance>Wrong cabinet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to talk to you, Helena.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know? How do you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stands and collects the cups and gets halfway with a smile. I'll make some more coffee.</context>
      <utterance>Coz you hardly said a word since you got here. But you been thinking pretty loud ..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands it across and he inspects it coz that's what cops do. I noticed you coming outta the institute. You up there a lot?</context>
      <utterance>Got your driver's license?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, it was you that nearly ran into me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it was you that nearly ran into me .. You up there a lot?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess, more than usual this time of the year. My mother &amp; I run an Arts &amp; Crafts center, we buy a lot from the institutes ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's your store, Amanda?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hands the license back and is already heading for his Mercedes.</context>
      <utterance>Oakland.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Next pit-stop, you make sure your doors are locked. Merry Christmas.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just easy on the words you're putting in my face, Sergeant ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A question practically every expression in the place is asking.</context>
      <utterance>Whass going on here?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His blind friend got "attacked." Angelo went up there, and some- how, it got itself in the paper.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You put it in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I may have said some- thing. I don't recall.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't lie, Taylor. I just had this Blattis guy on the phone asking me for a comment - you gave him the whole damned case!</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His indifference inflames BERLIN. Smashes the newspaper at him.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, I gave him the case? .. So the case is closed, so what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So read it! You just hung a target around her neck!</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bullshit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you know nothing about this guy? He reads the newspapers. Col- lects the cuttings. When are they gonna find her? Now he's reading Helena Robertson's name, phrased like she's a fucking witness. You couldn't have done anything more stupid if you'd sat down &amp; tried ..</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, c'mon, country boys, let's all line up and hear the expert.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now the volume is going up. Now the whole department is silent.</context>
      <utterance>Just walk away from me, Taylor ..</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think you're the only guy ever worked a homicide? I was a big-city cop too. And I bust- ed the clock on fucken Jennifer. I know more about this man than you'll over know - and that's how I know it ain't him - you- 're investigating a soap-opera ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, guys. We stop this now.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>"Everyone" means ROSS. BERLIN looks at him. And his gaze hurts.</context>
      <utterance>He tells her, "bye-bye," and she gets "attacked." Well, give me a fucking break! There is no "Ser- ial Killer." Stick her name up in neon, there's still no Serial kil- ler! And I ain't the only one say- ing it. Everyone in this building is saying it. And I mean everyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up, King Jay ..</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, c'mon, Freddy, let's have this out &amp; over. You know what everyone thinks? They think you're making a case coz you found yourself a nice piece of ass. And no one's blaming you for it, I hear she's worth the flowers. But don't come in here get- ting holy over us. Sure I put it in the paper. Coz I wanted to stop this bullshit. I don't want you drunk out- ta your head searching my office ag- ain. it's pissing me, &amp; everyone off.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know what you done, Taylor.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His cigarette is already stubbed and he's already walking away. Why don't you get yourself a dict- ionary? Look up the word "witness?"</context>
      <utterance>If, your friend from San Diego was up here, and thought for one out of two fucken seconds, she was a danger to him, he'da taken her out weeks ago ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know what a "witness" is.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A big mistake Mister Taylor. Mister Berlin suddenly turns into Harrison Ford. TAYLOR slams into filing cabinets right next to the Christmas tree. Gets BERLIN's forearm under his throat and fucking lucky not to get the knuckles in his gut. Both men are heaving. No volume necessary in this room of paralyzed silence.</context>
      <utterance>Well, her, it ain't. That bitch is blind as a blonde fucken bat.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BERLIN moves away and the silence is brutal. Nothing happening but bad vibes. ROSS and BERLIN exchange glances, And this shit is really bad. BERLIN vanishes into his lab and the door slams.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna do something you never did, Taylor. I'm gonna catch this bastard. And when I do, he's gon- na find out just how good a "wit- ness" she is .. Meanwhile, you be aware of me - coz I wish you ill ..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing you gotta say do I wanna hear right now. So save yourself saying it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's a tough one to swallow, Bro?</context>
      <utterance>I'm not in here to apologize, John. I told you what was gonna happen &amp; it's happened? "Good-bye, Princess," &amp; the same night she gets attacked?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm already familiar with Taylor's opinion.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't really believe this?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And as long as you like evaporates before ROSS can speak again.</context>
      <utterance>One hundred fucking per cent! .. And you know why? Coz I never told her good-bye. O.K.? Is that good enough for the "committee?"</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well .. I didn't know that ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BERLIN is drinking whisky. Sticks another slug in the cup. Now realizes whose bottle this is. Slams it somewhere on the bench. Here. You left your booze in here.</context>
      <utterance>No .. You didn't know that ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ross gets the kind of smile a smart guy wouldn't give an idiot. You think it was him?</context>
      <utterance>Who d'you think it was?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a very stupid question, Ross.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm asking it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His hand has found the switch-blade. A nasty click as it opens. .. but definitely not him. This guy's in the trade. He's not gon- na stand there looking at her ass, if he's in the room, she's dead .. BERLIN puts the knife in his Dummy. If she's alive. She's dead.</context>
      <utterance>How the hell do I know who? Some jerk-off. Some peeping-tom prick.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ease off, John ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sick of this toy town shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything you say sounds reason- able. But there's also a reason- able explanation for the opposite.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This atmosphere would stretch any friendship to breaking point. And now I'm telling you. I'm looking you right in the eyes and telling ya, there's a "bad man" out there, and I don't know if he's in the next room, or the next state: and I don't know what his trigger is? But if he reads her name in the newspaper, I believe he'll be inclined to do something ab- out it. I've got a bad feeling. And I been doing this too long to be wrong. There are tough eyes to look into. And ROSS finally looks away.</context>
      <utterance>Don't give me that! Not another word! When you had the Fat Lady in there, and I asked you if she was lying, you looked me right in the eyes and said yes. So as far as I was concerned, she's ly- ing. And if the King of fucking England had walked in &amp; told me different, I wouldn't have bel- ieved him - because you told me ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dunno what I can do to help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I've gotta take her out of there ..</context>
      <utterance>I dunno what I'd do with your help.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Citrine?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Screw Citrine. He can fire me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Has he got your aunt's address?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so .. He said the police had been calling .. want- ed to ask me some more questions ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?  Probably Angelo .. I'll take care of it .. Don't worry, we- 're gonna find this guy, and everything'll be O.K. .. O.K.? Only thing he fails to mention is which guy he's talking about. Anyway the subject is already changed. He notices tapes in her bag. "Would you like me to put your music on?" No, she doesn't want music. O.K. He's gonna light the fire and make them lunch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're looking worried again, Helena?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No I'm not.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're looking more worried now than when you "decided to stop worrying"?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A log tangents off. BERLIN retrieves it. Tosses it in a barrow.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, I'm worried about Christmas. I wish I hadn't told him I'd be back ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A distant owl hoots. She knows he's smiling. She's smiling too.</context>
      <utterance>He'll get over it. I'll roast us a chicken, O.K. With cand- les around it. How about that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't it be better if I cook it? You said, you can only boil?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't thank you enough, Ross ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Swallowing beer ROSS exits the back door with BERLIN following. It's her invitation. And as far as Citrine in concerned, better we keep it like that. The wagon waits outside with a few crates left to unload, BER- LIN heads for his Mercedes with ROSS calling after him. "John. Here." Pulls a six pack from his supplies and throws it across. There's an old desperado in one of the cells. Why don't you give him this, and tell him happy Christmas from me?</context>
      <utterance>Don't thank me. Thank Margie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>MARGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slings the dress on the bed. It joins a pile of rehearsals. Moves deeper into her dresses and HELENA appears in the mirror.</context>
      <utterance>Not "you" blue. This isn't you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When did John divorce?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two or three years ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was she like?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Suzanne? Very pretty. She was a semi- professional model. But a policeman's wife she wasn't. So one day, she just packed it and left. And his whole life went straight down the nearest toilet.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pirouettes with black sequins. "What do you think of black?" Evidently not much and MARGIE is getting short of alternatives. Wait a minute, I just had the most brilliant idea ..</context>
      <utterance>You know, he crashed. He just couldn't come to terms with it .. John hates to lose, and he hated losing her .. Every spare minute, he's driving down to San Diego, having a terrible time with her, getting drunk, and driving back .. you just don't believe the amount he drank ..</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think he still loves her?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She emerges from the wardrobe with red satin high heeled shoes. Here .. try these .. if these fit, we got the perfect dress ..</context>
      <utterance>Think he still thinks about her. But not like then. Then was an obsession.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I don't think I could walk in these?</context>
      <utterance>I haven't worn heels since I was 16.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HELENA is excited to try them out. The experiment is a success. I'll go get the dress .. It's kinda sultry .. I only wore it once, coz in reality, I can't get away with it ..</context>
      <utterance>Sure you can. Anyway, parties are all about standing still ..</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think John would like it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think John, would love it ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SERATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>"How long have you got?" "One big drink." And they head for it. Did you get my message?</context>
      <utterance>Duty Sergeant fucked up .. can you believe it, I'm on tonight ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This last question to ROSS who delivers a typically large shot.</context>
      <utterance>I left a message on your machine. It wasn't me calling. Sam around?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah .. I guess she's in the kit- chen .. We got a so-called prof- essional cook out there having a nervous breakdown over a turkey ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure you didn't call?</utterance>
   <speaker>SERATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I spoke to old whass-his-name a couple of times. But not to her, and I never asked for her ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her who?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone's calling the institute to talk to Helena. Says he wants to ask her some more questions ..</utterance>
   <speaker>SERATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he pushes off to see his wife. BERLIN looks around worried.</context>
      <utterance>Not guilty ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a quiet phone somewhere?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, John, don't start getting antsy over this tonight. It may well have been the local cops?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's just what I wanna find out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you doing on those shoes?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Perhaps she is a tiny bit tipsy? MARGIE smiles and says "Press."</context>
      <utterance>Don't mix very well with beer.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A knock on the door. "Come in" and BOBBY sticks his head inside.</context>
      <utterance>Girl like you should be drinking chill white wine. Press. All done.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That woman in the kitchen says if she doesn't get help within 10 seconds, she's gonna resign.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to the mirror in exasperation and mends her own face. Alright, tell her I'm coming. No, wait a minute, honey. Take Helena for me, and find John? And don't let go of her hand until you do ..</context>
      <utterance>That woman is a disaster ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her protest is absorbed in sound. And anyway he's already gone. At once she is vulnerable. Doesn't know if she's staring at the back of a head or straight into someone's face. "Didn't we meet somewhere?" The question comes from the man with the scar. He's drunk as a dog and already got a tattooed hand around her waist.</context>
      <utterance>I'll just go see if he's in the kitchen .. you stay right here ..</utterance>
   <speaker>VENABLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Popeye!</utterance>
   <speaker>POPEYE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trash aftershave and lousy breath and clearly the answer is no. If I told you I'd driven all the way from Oakland would you dance with me? Willy Nelson starts to sing. And HELENA attempts to break away. What's so special about the other guy? You like cops, don't you .. I'm a cop .. HELENA finds the top of a couch. Holds it like a raft of secur- ity. But where ever she goes this frightful mouth is following. .. let me ask you a question? How do you know the difference between one guy and another? .. Maybe you don't .. Maybe you only know the "difference" when you're dancing? (he laughs) If you knew what I looked like, you'd dance with me. I look like John Wayne ..</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Fat Guy! Gimme 2 minutes. I'm about to ask this lady for a dance?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She navigates the back of the sofa. Collides with somebody and apologizes. "I'm sorry. Is anyone sitting there?" Enough ambiv- alence in the question for the guy not to know she's blind. No. No one sitting there. Simultaneously a pair of middle-age crew cuts occupy the sofa. A second later HELENA sits bang into one of the laps. Spilt drinks and surprise all round. Pleasant sur- prise for the victim. He's a lecherous looking old bastard and Helena's dress rides up for a damned good view of the lingerie.</context>
      <utterance>I know what you look like. Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLESHY VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Happy Christmas, Max ...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Every humiliation there is. However HELENA gets out of this is however she achieves it. But by the time she does she's crying.</context>
      <utterance>I normally get socks ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ROSS already arrived. BERLIN looks desolate. She can't go back. You better go talk to her .. ROSS watches him walk upstairs. His eyes an assessment of this absurd relationship. "All sorts of people fall in love, Darlin."</context>
      <utterance>She wants to go back to the institute ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know .. ain't it a shame ..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>BERLIN swings round in surprise. ROSS is half asleep on a sofa.</context>
      <utterance>You can't get in there .. That's "Comanche Proof."</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus. What are you doin?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>"Silent Night. Holy Night" and about two inches of Chivas left.</context>
      <utterance>I spose I'm drinking myself to sleep. It's Helena's Christmas songs .. they're really pretty ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BERLIN sticks a foot on a table. Pulls a .25 Walther automatic from an ankle holster. Ejects the mag and clicks out the slugs.</context>
      <utterance>Have you got any Glasers?  Twenty fives?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What exactly you doing, John?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going up to the institute.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ROSS unlocks a cabinet and BERLIN is about to load the Glasers. I checked with the locals and our station, no one's called. Whoever it is, isn't the police. I think this bastard's getting worried ab- out something? .. and I think the- re's just a chance he'll turn up.</context>
      <utterance>This "cop" that's calling, thinks she gonna be there over Christmas.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ROSS selects a 12 gauge Winchester and rams the mechanism open. And if he does, I'm gonna drop a bomb on the fukker.</context>
      <utterance>Well, let's hope he does ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, you don't havta come?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ROSS is stuffing solid lead "car killers" into the pump action. Watch my lips. I'm your partner.</context>
      <utterance>Hey ..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's your watch?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess by the bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yawns do a circuit. ROSS flops in his seat and the angle chang- es. The view from the rear covers windscreen and back of heads. A little young for you, Bro? (Gets his eyes) You think if she could see, she'd be hanging around with an old dog like you? You got a stomach growing around to meet itself behind your back.</context>
      <utterance>It's twenty of three.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bull shit .. I'm in my prime ..</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bits.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A star-light on the windshield. Distant and nobody seen it yet.</context>
      <utterance>What d'you mean, "bits."</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Policemen's bodies age at diff- erent rates. Look at me. Gut in its fifties. Balls in their six- ties. And feet in their eighties ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Urgency snaps him into close-up. Big noise as wipers clear the screen. "I thought I saw a light?" BERLIN stares at the instit- ute through small binoculars. "There. Flashlight went right ac- ross those windows!" Instant excitement as the adrenalin pumps in. "Fourth floor. See it? He's fucken in there!" And suddenly everything including super-sinister Music is happening at once.</context>
      <utterance>Hit those wipers, Ross.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if we need a back up?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O.K. it's channel 4 and copy? And they're already on their way.</context>
      <utterance>We're not here. I don't want the desk to hear us ..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright. I'll start at the top, and work down.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ain't going in alone?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Takes off up the stairs. ROSS watches him vanish. (Waiting out here ain't so tasty either.) The wind rages in nearby trees. A door slams repeatedly somewhere a long way away. [Ross?] "10/2" [I'm going in.] Big on ROSS and the radio. "You take care, Bro."</context>
      <utterance>That's a liability, Ross. I don't want you hanging on to my shirt. Anyone but me comes down these stairs, take em out but try and keep him alive. I want this bastard living ..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BERLIN [?]</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thank Jesus the anxiety's over. The 12 gauge drops to his side.</context>
      <utterance>Me, Freddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The light remains steady and blinding and straight in his face. Hey, c'mon, John .. Talk to me ... Just the sound of breathlessness. Plus a .25 Walther automatic. Jesus Christ .. What are you doing? It glints at the peripheries of his vision and ROSS is alarmed. What the fuck are you doing? - It's me - Holy shit! - John - John - Not you - Don't shoot you crazy bastard! Two deathly flashes in quick succession. The first practically taken Ross's hand off. The second slams into his guts and he's down. The Glaser is unequalled in ferocity by any other bullet.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell's going on up there, Brother? I been calling 10 minutes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stunned and stubbled and full of grief. And that's just SERATO.</context>
      <utterance>Where's Margie?</utterance>
   <speaker>SERATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This atmosphere is unbearable and even these whispers seem laud. They were going there anyway.</context>
      <utterance>Taken Bobby to her sister's ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SERATO shakes his head. Loses his cigarette. And SAMMY appears.</context>
      <utterance>Does he know?</utterance>
   <speaker>SERATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SAMMY SERATO is 30 and pretty. She continues collecting plates. Why'd you go up there, John? Knows he's not going to get a reply and doesn't bother to wait for it. HELENA materializes from the den like a shadow. Sallow for want of sleep and glad to have BERLIN's hand to hang on to.</context>
      <utterance>Thinks his dad's in hospital.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A suggestion that surprises HELENA. And clearly doesn't appeal.</context>
      <utterance>I want you to go to your Aunt's.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why can't I stay with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not possible right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>If silence can intensify it's now. Sound of the front door and then footsteps. BERLIN freezes as MARGIE appears. Wracked with grief. Dead sickness of tears. Like she cried bones out of her face. But no weeping now. Maybe shock. Maybe brave. Maybe both.</context>
      <utterance>Please don't ask no quest- ions now .. Not right now ..</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that Margie?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The strongest face in the house. And now HELENA is in her arms. Don't cry darlin .. he was a big old cop and he didn't like tears .. Dead echos of plates in the kitchen. And song of birds outside. Feels like every second in my life, was just the moment leading to this.</context>
      <utterance>I'm here, honey. I'm right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Margie ..</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raises her hand to silence him and this is silence Margie owns. Don't. Christ this is just awful. HELENA crying and BERLIN on the way. What's gonna happen now, John?</context>
      <utterance>Don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'll take her there tonight.</context>
      <utterance>She has an aunt, in Vermont.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going back to the institute.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No .. not now ..</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Footsteps again as she walks out and silence again like before.</context>
      <utterance>Helena can stay here if she'd like to .. I'd like her to .. I'll look after her .. and she can look after me .. I'm tired now .. I must sleep ..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing, Travis?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I been told to take your car in, Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flashes his light at a standard issue (brown) police Chevrolet. I'm sorry, Sergeant. I did knock a couple times. Didn't get any reply.</context>
      <utterance>I dunno, Sir. Brought you up a Chevy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a warrant for this?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who sought the warrant?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The man from the F.B.I.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BERLIN looks awful. Showered and shaved but just fucking awful. CITRINE slips focus to the man. And St ANNE imperceptibly nods.</context>
      <utterance>I want a 24 hour protection of Margie's house. Otherwise I'm not saying nothing. You give me that, or read me my rights, and talk to a lawyer.</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, you got it. And I'll be putting an Observer in with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want Serato ..  Why can't I have Serato?</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coz I'm short of men &amp; Ang- elo won't do it .. Who ever I got free first - you get ..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A side table features several pin sharp pencils. A Sony pocket recorder. Two packets of Pall Mall reds. Two yellow legal pads. The chair moves into reverse and he breaks a puke colored file. St ANNE Alright, let's not beat about the bush, what ever that may mean, and get down on it. You were specific- ally instructed by your chief, not to go anywhere near the blind inst- itute? So why did you go up there?</context>
      <utterance>I have done ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because of a feeling. I had a bad feeling this man was gonna turn up. St ANNE Which man is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The report that's in his hands. (St Anne knows well which man.) Is this an interview, or an interrogation? St ANNE It's an enquiry ...</context>
      <utterance>The man I detail in my report, Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles the non-smile. Tosses his pencil down. And sits back. So you thought your man might show?</context>
      <utterance>I'm not prepared to be interrog- ated. I'll be interviewed as an officer, who may be expected to cooperate with the investigator. St ANNE Well, that's fine by me, John. And I'm sure that's fine by your Chief.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. St ANNE Bit of a long-shot, wasn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was the only shot I had .. St ANNE So the one night you decide to go up there, he goes up there?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. Except I'd decid- ed to go up there every night .. St ANNE Despite the wishes of your Chief?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. St ANNE You were prepared to fal- sify your reports to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>St ANNE cuts him off to pick up the phone. Obviously something vital is needed. "Could you bring an an ashtray in here? Got a coupla guys who smoke in here." And attention back to the file. You don't mind if I jump around a little this morning, do you? Just while I'm easing my way into this?</context>
      <utterance>I had very good reasons for do.... St ANNE Just a second, John. I knew there was something missing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're asking the questions, Sir .. St ANNE You had an argument with Ross? Ass- aulted one of the officers, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't use the word "assault." St ANNE You got a "racy temper," Sergeant?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not especially. St ANNE Just something they did, on this occasion, made you lose your rag?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not they. He. Taylor put a piece in the newspaper, which in my op- inion put my witness in jeopardy. St ANNE From whom?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From the man I detail in my rep- ort. A crazy man, who to my cert- ain knowledge has killed at least eight girls. Six in San Diego, one someplace else, and one up here .. St ANNE Not a lotta support for that "scenario" though, is there?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not a lot. St ANNE Not even from Ross?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Is that why you lost your temper with him? Frustration? No one believing you? His ASSISTANT brings the ashtray. And St ANNE smiles gratitude. So what can you tell me about you man?</context>
      <utterance>No. St ANNE</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, Sir? St ANNE I mean, who is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know who he is. Who's "Jack The Ripper?" He's Jack The Ripper with an automobile. St ANNE You didn't run a profile?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Sir .. I didn't have the res- ources, and it isn't my expertise. St ANNE This crazy man? What makes you think he wants to eliminate Miss Robertson?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You read my report, Sir. St ANNE I'm asking a question ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is meant to humiliate and meant to annoy and it does both. Alright, we'll have plenty of time to discuss your "Mystery Man," and his "flexibility" later, Right now, I'd like to talk about the "event."</context>
      <utterance>Because he reads I'm investigating the disappearance of her friend, &amp; Miss Robertson becomes the focus of his anxiety. How good of a "witness" is she? He's crazy, but not stupid, he's intelligent. Got a flexible M. O., and he doesn't wanna get caught. St ANNE Just like "Jack The Ripper?"</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I realized the flashlight was at the bottom of the stairs St ANNE Did you check your weapon?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe. It would have been instinctive. All I know was I was in possession of it .. St ANNE You didn't check it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not that I specifically remember. St ANNE Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I wasn't think- ing about it .. I was dazed .. St ANNE You were woozy? Confused?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was unconscious 10 seconds ago. St ANNE I understand. Then?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I picked up the flashlight, tried to get Ross on the radio .. Nothing. Static. I got blood on my hand, realized my eye was cut. St ANNE Could you see out of it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I could see. Then I ran. Climbed out of the window, ran down the fire escape, and right at the bottom, I found Ross .. St ANNE Were you breathless?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure I was breathless ... St ANNE When did you realize you were no longer in possession of the .25?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not until I was in the hospital. St ANNE You figure you lost it in the hospital? Or on the way there?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I thought it must have fallen down the stairwell. St ANNE [BERLIN] Like the flashlight? [Yeah] Had you been drinking that night?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was Christmas Eve. St ANNE That wasn't my question?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. St ANNE [BERLIN] How about Ross? [Sure] Were you drinking in the car? [?] There was a bottle in the car?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think Ross had a mouthful? St ANNE But not you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>St ANNE motors off &amp; refers to notes without looking at BERLIN. Which hand was the flashlight in?</context>
      <utterance>I may have had a nip? St ANNE To keep out the cold? .. Very cold that night, very windy, wasn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My left hand. St ANNE And the Walther was in your right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The chair moves back in and its pilot has an icicle up his ass. You said you figured it had fallen down the stairs with the flashlight? You said you were confused? You pick up the flashlight in confusion, how d'you know you didn't pick up the 25?</context>
      <utterance>The Beretta was in my right hand .. St ANNE You said you didn't check it? So how d'you know which gun you're holding?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's not start playing games, Mr St Anne. St ANNE Games?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you, I'd lost the Walther .. St ANNE You told me you didn't know you'd lost it until you were in the hos- pital? So, if you didn't know till then, it coulda been either weapon?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dead smile and rubber in action. St ANNE changes his notes. St ANNE O.K. I'm corrected. I'm sorry, I made a mistake.</context>
      <utterance>The gun in my hand was a Beretta. And for the record, I want that note corrected. Now, please, Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With respect, Sir, you didn't make a mistake. I know who you are, and you're far too experienced for mis- takes. Now if you have doubts over the content, or veracity of my rep- ort, I wanna be made aware of them? St ANNE Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanna be made aware of them now. St ANNE Do you want a lawyer, Sergeant?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There you go again? "Do I want a lawyer, Sergeant?" It's a game question. What do I want a law- yer for? I got nothing to hide .. St ANNE You don't?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For the first time St ANNE moves his chair into BERLIN's space. St ANNE Where's the little gun, Sergeant?</context>
      <utterance>You know I don't. So let's quit the bullshit and get down to it. What's your "angle," Mr St Anne?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've no idea. St ANNE You don't?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Implications are ganging up quicker than BERLIN can focus them. And you don't know where that little twenty-five calibre Walther's gone? BERLIN confirms it. Looking very concerned. The wheels retreat. St ANNE shakes out a cigarette and takes his time with matches. O.K. Sergeant, here it is. I intend to produce evidence, that will prove you shot Frederick Ross with malice afore- thought. My angle therefore, is to pre- pare a case on behalf of your Chief, to prosecute you for first degree murder.</context>
      <utterance>If it isn't in the institute, the man who shot Ross took it. St ANNE The man who shot Ross, used it ..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your Daddy would have wanted you to be strong .. We gotta be strong for Daddy, darling ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want her in this house .. I want my Dad. Why did she have to come here .. I want my Daddy ..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. St ANNE Tell us what happened, then?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I already told you what happened .. You're looking for an inconsisten- cy, and you're not gonna find one, because I'm telling you the truth. St ANNE Tell me the truth again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess I was drinking too much. St ANNE I was talking about "cigarettes?"  Find yourself getting breathless?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. St ANNE Specially if you're running? Which floor did the elevator run up to?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You ran up to the fifth? You must have been real breathless by then? BERLIN doesn't know where this is going but he doesn't like it. Eyes to BERLIN now and his smile looks real for the first time. We're gonna get our "observer" in here this afternoon. Keep an eye on us? (He smiles) Notorious for withholding information, the F.B.I. St ANNE makes a note. Junks the pencil. Sits back in his chair. Were you aware there was a janit- or in the institute that night?</context>
      <utterance>Five. St ANNE</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. St ANNE You didn't check?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There wasn't time ... St ANNE That wasn't my question?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>St ANNE breaks off to blow his nose. BERLIN looks very worried. St ANNE I'm really catching cold up here? Must be all this fog?</context>
      <utterance>No, Sir, I didn't check.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the relevance of the janitor? St ANNE The janitor? Let me just ask you a question - before I forget - do you take any medication for that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For what? St ANNE Breathlessness?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>St ANNE Alright, let me answer your question? "What's the relevance of the janitor?" Hits the cigarette like this is the one that caused the cancer. Why don't I take you through it, from where I'm sitting .. At some time bet- ween 2 &amp; 2:30 a.m. the janitor thought he heard a vehicle approaching through the woods. He looks out, and sees noth- ing, no lights, nothing. Figures it must be hunters. Some time later, he thought he heard something else, like a door, or a window slam? He gets up, and between half past two and a quarter of three, he makes a search - with a flashlight - of the top 3 floors. Finds nothing untoward, &amp; goes back to his apartment in the roof. BERLIN looks grey as sick. Knows what's coming. And here it is. The flashlight you saw, was his. The "footsteps" you heard, were his. The elevator you were chasing up and down after was empty, and is prone to such activity, due to an electrical fault .. Apparently it happens frequently dur- ing gales. The gale that was swinging the door. That knocked you down. That confused you so much? And here we are, back to where I'm sitting. You wanna tell me what really went on that night? It seems St ANNE has effectively destroyed the "Serial Killer" scenario. Stubs his cigarette and waits for BERLIN's response.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>St ANNE is winning. And they both know it. And he almost grins. We just dealt with "the man?"</context>
      <utterance>Two people know I didn't kill him, Mr St Anne. One's me, and the other's the man that did. St ANNE What man?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>If St ANNE can raise an eyebrow he does. By implication BERLIN is ditching his "Killer." During this St ANNE rewinds his Sony. You're telling me it's his flashlight I saw, O.K., he sees my flashlight? And I'm coming up the stairs with a Beretta in my hand. And he's frightened. He hits the door on me. Picks up my gun. He's running. He runs into Ross, and in panic, he shoots him. The little Sony snaps to a stop and St ANNE looks at his watch. St ANNE Not unless he had a gun in one hand, and a phone in the other, he didn't. Ross was shot at ex- actly two fifty-seven a.m. The janitor put a call through to the local police, at 2:57 a.m. You obviously realize how I can get so accurate with my timing? St ANNE backs off and carefully replaces the Sony on the table. Ross switched into channel 8, &amp; we got a recording of the whole incident. I was gonna play it to you, but I got a meeting, we'll have to do it after lunch. It's one, let's make it back by three?</context>
      <utterance>How d'you know the Jan- itor didn't shoot him?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SERATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's in love with him, Chief, and try anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you going up there?</utterance>
   <speaker>SERATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I've got a call to make.</context>
      <utterance>No, I just sent Travis.</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the man? .. Has he seen this? .. [No he hasn't] .. Alright, make your call, and get up there ... Bullshit or not, I wanna proper statement ..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Sir, they just got back.</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ASSISTANT does it via phone. And BISLEY looks over unhappy.</context>
      <utterance>Would you ask Mr St Anne to come in here a moment?</utterance>
   <speaker>BISLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hear I've been nominated as an official "observer?"</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's either you, or Taylor?</utterance>
   <speaker>BISLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He don't wanna do it either.</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>St ANNE comes in blowing his nose. CITRINE shoves him the mess~ age. He reads it with similar incredulity (but perhaps a touch more amusement than Citrine) "What d'you wanna do with it, Sir?" What do you wanna do with it? St ANNE Let him have it .. I don't mind putting a little salt at the edge of his plate ..</context>
      <utterance>I'll toss a coin for you. But one of you is going in today ..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SERATO keeps it dispassionate. Ignores BERLIN's desperate eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I need a friend, Angelo.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Puts a thumb towards the house and already heading for his oar. She's a bad witness, John. But a fucking lousy alibi.</context>
      <utterance>You got one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>By now BERLIN and his glass of anaesthetic are well into frame. No one in the State of California is gonna believe that. They got the man in there - an A/1 F.B.I. inter- rogator, and he's taking me to pie- ces - doesn't believe a word comes outta my head - not a word - no one believes me - I don't believe me ..</context>
      <utterance>.. I know why you did it darlin, but you're not helping me. Every- thing they're hearing they think is a lie. Now here comes the man I'm desperate to prove exists, &amp; whadda-ya-know, he turns up at my house, and has a "chat" with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't say that. Don't you dare say that .. I believe you ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you're trying to help me, but you don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't want to. But now he's got to. And so here it comes.</context>
      <utterance>Then explain it to me. I got enough darkness, don't I?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The man who killed Amber is a psychopath. He was up at the in- stitute to kill you - he don't wanna kill Rose - he was there to kill you - that's the truth - and I didn't wanna tell it to you - but that's the reason I want you to stay at Margie's - coz I can't protect you here ..</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why does he want to kill me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coz he thinks you're a witness.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't identify him ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He don't know that. I didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Back at the booze and he's almost inaudible "Stop it, will you?" Why didn't he kill me, John? Something snaps in BERLIN and he throws his glass at the grate.</context>
      <utterance>Then why didn't he kill me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And just as suddenly he's full of remorse. Takes HELENA in his arms with a lot of sorrys. But she isn't interested in apology. There's a passion in her face. And fire even in her blind eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Will you fucken stop it. I'm not Serato .. He didn't kill you coz he wasn't here .. he isn't in the room with you, and lets you live ..</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kiss me, John .. Kiss me [he does] I love you, kiss me again [he does] I love you .. Are my lips lying to you? Kiss my mouth [he does] Is my mouth lying to you? He. Was. Here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>And BERLIN rolls out and stares up like a mechanic under a car. He used a breath freshener.</context>
      <utterance>I just remembered something ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HELENA stands in the doorway and BERLIN is already on his feet.</context>
      <utterance>A "breath freshener?"</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BERLIN wipes a thought through his hair with fingers. "I don't know what that means." Walks past into the bedroom. Everything taken apart. Every drawer open and the bed heaped with clothes.</context>
      <utterance>I heard it hiss, twice.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... he's either here to take something .. or leave some- thing .. I don't find nothing ..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another mouthful of scotch &amp; she hears the glass hit the table. He's glad you're drinking. Every drink you take you're helping him.</context>
      <utterance>You gotta stop drinking, darling.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He doesn't need my help.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know about alcohol, John.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's what she knows about alcohol and he'd prefer to be dead. I lost everyone I ever loved .. I lost my hopes .. my future .. I'm in love with you, John .. I don't want them to take you away from me ..</context>
      <utterance>I'm blind because my father drank.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ross was my best friend. St ANNE Did you shoot your "best friend?"</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The next time I ask you that quest- ion, you're gonna tell me the truth. St ANNE shunts back in his chair. Expands the frame as he goes. Sergeant TAYLOR sits on a chair with his back to the wall. Cig- arettes and ashtray on the table next to his. St ANNE lights a Pall Mall and as if it's an after-thought he snaps the Sony on.</context>
      <utterance>No. St ANNE</utterance>
   <speaker>[TAPE]</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BERLIN already looks devastated. He's about to got annihilated. "Me, Freddy." .. [Just the gale] "What the hell's going on up there, Brother? I been calling ton minutes." .. [Lungs heave for air) "Hey, c'mon, John, talk to me?" [Just the sound of breathless- ness] "Jesus Christ .. What are you do- ing? What the fuck are you doing? It's me - Holy shit - John - John - Not you - Don't shoot you crazy bastard! [2 shots] St ANNE clicks the Sony off &amp; BERLIN is too stunned to breathe. St ANNE That's second degree - you wanna stop at that? Will you give me that, John? BERLIN gives him nothing but silence. A knock on the door "Come in." And the ASSISTANT hands St ANNE a note. Reads it and excus- es himself. Leaves the silence for BERLIN. But TAYLOR breaks it.</context>
      <utterance>.. "Just be careful now, coz I'm coming up." .. [Footsteps on cast iron stairs] "Is that you, John? .. Answer .. Now .. or I blow this fucken staircase to pie- ces." [Sound of someone breathing hard]</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Why don't you take it ..</context>
      <utterance>He's offerin you a deal?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TAYLOR lights a cigarette and exhales. Something of a real red- headed fuck about him. And BERLIN would like to break his neck. You're letting it show, King Jay.</context>
      <utterance>He ain't offerin me shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rolls ash off his cigarette and pushes it round the ashtray. Your an alcoholic, aren't you? (BERLIN stares) It's written in your file .. The phone rings and TAYLOR answers. Puts his red eyes at BERLIN. They want you to look in the mirror. BERLIN has to find every strength for this one. Humiliation com- pounds. Gets up and stares at his own haunted face in the glass.</context>
      <utterance>I don't like you. But don't kid yourself .. I don't take no ple- asure sitting in on another cop ..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MYOPIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's escorted to the door and his space is occupied by CITRINE.</context>
      <utterance>Well .. I dunno .. it could be? St ANNE Alright, thank you, Mr Dawson ..</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>St ANNE on his way to the door now. He pauses for the question. St ANNE I can have him out of here on a sec- ond degree this afternoon. I own him, and he knows it. And, Chief, I'm still waiting for that warrant on his house?</context>
      <utterance>What's all this "deal" business?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't wanna sit here any more, sweetheart ..</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Something difficult to tell her and doesn't know how to say it.</context>
      <utterance>I wanna be near you ...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think they're gonna arrest me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want them to arrest you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her tears are close to his face. No one but him could hear her.</context>
      <utterance>It's not as bad as it sounds .. They can't refuse me bail. Raise bail of my own cognizance &amp; find the best damned lawyer there is ..</utterance>
   <speaker>HELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, John, I'd do anything, anything, to get you free.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've told you the truth. It isn't me .. I've never call- ed Ross "Freddy" in my life ..</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've heard you call him Freddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You haven't. And you got no voice in here, Taylor, so keep it shut. St ANNE Tell a lotta lies, don't you? Some- thing that comes naturally to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't lie. St ANNE Prepared to lie to your Chief?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Under exceptional circumstances. St ANNE What were the circumstances that caused you to lie to Freddy Ross?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shakes his head in confirmation. And St ANNE finds a notebook. Well, he thought you did? .. Wrote it down in his book? "John Berlin is a liar." Right here, underlined. BERLIN stares at the book &amp; can barely credit what he's seeing. Dated the day you got your first "break" with your "Mystery Man?" You don't know why he wrote that? (He doesn't) Maybe he thought there was no "Myst- ery Man?" That the investigation was bullshit? That you were making it up? And during the next attack St ANNE will work himself into rage. Coz you wanted to be "Top Cop?" Isn't that why you went running up that gar- bage dump, so everyone could stand in awe of the "Top Cop?" Isn't that why you came up here? Coz you couldn't make it in L.A.? Get yourself a pissy lit- tle degree, come up here, and be "Top Guy?" But Ross was "Top Guy", wasn't he? Always would be Top Guy? And you know what? He did it without even trying .. Everybody loved him. He had everything you wanted, didn't he? - Great woman - Great kid? - Everything you couldn't have? - And you wanted it to go away? Coz your life was lousy, wasn't it? - A lousy life, with a lousy wife, who was fucking everyone, wasn't she? Is that why you pick on a little Blind Girl? - coz you can control her? - Is that it? - Control who she's fucking? Tears of grief and tears of rage. BERLIN can't restrain either. You wanna lose your temper with me? C'mon, John, lose your fucken temper? You're good at losing your temper?..</context>
      <utterance>I never lied to Ross .. St ANNE You didn't?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BERLIN is a wreck of despair. But somehow he keeps his dignity.</context>
      <utterance>No way, Mr St Anne. St ANNE Lost your temper with Ross, didn't you? C'mon, tell me the truth. Is that what happened? You had an arg- ument in the car? Lost your temper with him? Stood over him, blew his fucking larynx out with a Glaser? - Where were you aiming, John? Going for his face? Blow his fucking face away, because you hated him so much.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And at last he looks pleased. Because he's got this man busted. What do you take for that breathlessness, Sergeant? Can't take anymore questions. Answers with a shake of his head. How about Aminophylline?</context>
      <utterance>I loved that guy .. &amp; the hard- est thing to take in here .. is knowing he thought I killed him .. St ANNE Well, that he did .. And that do I, Sergeant Berlin ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You don't? It's ant anti-asthma medic- ation, prescribed for breathlessness? Produces a capsule in a plastic bag and throws it on the table. Came out of the ashtray of your car? Every cell in BERLIN's body freezes. Misinterpreted by St ANNE. But you "don't know" what it is? But he does know what it is. The pill he found in the V.W. van. You don't know how it got there? TAYLOR stares a rock drill and St ANNE stares something similar. You don't use it for breathlessness? BERLIN focuses a fragment of hope. But no sign of hope in here. I'm running outta questions, John, and you're running out of lies? I'm offer- ing you one last chance, and you better take it, or the U.S. Attorney is gonna put you in the God-damned gas chamber ..</context>
      <utterance>I don't know what that is. St ANNE</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need .. some time .. to think Sir .. St ANNE Alright. Think about it. But don't you make a fool of me. You come in here with one more lie, and I bull- shit you not, I'm gonna press for the maximum penalty there is. And that's the death penalty, Sergeant.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another excruciating wait plus further explanations for MARGIE. I had the van - this guy drove that van takes his medication and loses one .. (Phone) - Dan - Hearing - Are you sure? - Would you try Frisco for me? - I'll try and get a second name .. Dumps the phone and stokes anxiety in HELENA and MARGIE's eyes. No Amanda with a white Volkswagen .. You don't have a Yellow Pages for Oakland, do you? (She don't) I got- ta get down there, find that store .. Everything happens in a hurry. He embraces HELENA. She'll pray for him. Already out the back door with MARGIE in tow. A black &amp; white parked in the drive with VENABLES stuffed inside. Plus a grim wind tearing trees. BERLIN pauses as he reaches his car.</context>
      <utterance>This capsule came out of a V.W. van - I didn't even think about it - stuck it in the ashtray - if I'd been smok- ing, ita been thrown away weeks ago ..  No, Amanda - it's definitely Amanda ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catches her eyes. Can barely look at them. They're full of hate.</context>
      <utterance>You be careful .. This man's close ..</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you find him, John. I want you to call me. I wanna know his name.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she stares like he does not. Before she stares like he does. You're Amanda? Remember, you near- ly ran into me? Way up in Trinity? His smile disarms the securities. And she opens the front door.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry to trouble you, but eh .. Wait a minute, don't I know you?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As I said, Sergeant, you nearly ran into me? What's the problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid it's the "van" again.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The van?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it your vehicle?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, my mother's .. You better stop in .. I'm just here to feed the cat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry to worry you with this, but we had a real serious robbery, and we- 're chasing a white V.W. van? You guy came up an the computer, so as a matt- er of routine we have to check. Could you tell me who's driven it recently?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only me and Mom ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about any guys on your staff?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We only got one .. He doesn't drive.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN [AMANDA]</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would he have lent it to anyone? [No] How bout your Dad? Husband? Boyfriend?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is my boyfriend. My fath- er's dead, and I'm divorced.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His hopes are collapsing by the moment and nothing else is left. Would you mind if I took a look at it?</context>
      <utterance>I see ...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Cat cries for its food and AMANDA begins to look suspicious. The only man that has driven it in the last 6 months is my uncle. And no way is he involved in a robbery.</context>
      <utterance>I thought this was "routine?"</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maybe too much charge in his head and she doesn't like the vibe?</context>
      <utterance>Could I have his name? Just so I can officially eliminate him?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sure she can and he searches for it. "Must have left it at home?" Then you better go and get it. I feel uncomfortable without an I.D. AMANDA opens the front door just long enough for BERLIN to leave.</context>
      <utterance>Could I see your badge again?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MALE REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>[2] Heineman's B.M.W. pulls up outside the police station and this is conducted on the move. A Reporter asks "What's the nat- ure of this meeting, Sir?" HEINEMAN is sorry but can't comment. He pauses briefly an the steps with the wind savaging his hair.</context>
      <utterance>Detectives spent several hours this morning at Sergeant Berlin's home .. various property was removed for ex- amination. Later in the morning, May- or Heineman arrived for a meeting with police officers from Shasta Valley ..</utterance>
   <speaker>HEINEMAN</speaker>
      <mode>T.V.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim unable to say anything right now, except, this is a very sad and tragic day. John Berlin lied to us all. Lied to me, and much worse, lied to every man, woman, &amp; child in this community ..</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode>T.V.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where was Mr Berlin arrested, Sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEINEMAN</speaker>
      <mode>T.V.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Near the Ross residence .. six a.m. ..</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode>T.V.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who made the arrest?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEINEMAN</speaker>
      <mode>T.V.</mode>
      <context>HELENA looks in utmost despair. "Is it true he resisted arrest?" You'll have to put that question to the Chief. I've nothing to add. BOBBY appears somewhere behind the Ladies. T.V. commentary con- tinues. "Meanwhile, Sergeant Berlin remains in a cell at police headquarters arraigned on what is believed to be a $500,000.00 bail. As Mayor Heineman said, this, is a 'sad day' for Eureka." Except for the one face that isn't sad and it belongs to BOBBY.</context>
      <utterance>Sergeant John Taylor. Assist- ed by Sergeant Angelo Serato ..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bring here her .. I want Helena here ..</context>
      <utterance>I'll sign anything you want. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>CITRINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ain't talking to no one, till you calm down.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he isn't and CITRINE moves off. BERLIN cracks blood out of knuckles on the glass. Hollers up the corridor after the Chief. Get St Anne .. I want St Anne ..</context>
      <utterance>I am calm .. I am calm ..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus. What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARGIE heads for a table and unloads a strong-box of documents. Is she going somewhere?</context>
      <utterance>Been trying to call, your line's down .. I just wanna let you know we're taking the guard off today.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He watches her select various papers aware of what she's about.</context>
      <utterance>I'm taking her back to the Instit- ute. Her new term starts tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HELENA reappears wearing a coat and TAYLOR is in generous mood. You want me to drive her? .. I'm through with my shift ..</context>
      <utterance>Not gonna try and bail him are you? I really wouldn't bother, Margie ..</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No .. I'll drive her ..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll sign anything you like - you write it, I'll sign it. But I want her and Margie here. I want an opp- ortunity to talk to them - that's all I'm asking? - That's my deal? .. St ANNE O.K. I'll put it to your Chief?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you'd better put it to him pretty dammed quick, Mr St Anne, because if you don't, she's dead. St ANNE Didn't push her down stairs on their previous meeting, did he?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Produces a Zippo in a plastic sack and BERLIN's senses capsize. Is it yours? A question for which St ANNE expects no answer and he is right. We found "Jennifer Eight." At least, we've found a headless and handless girl. A couple of hunters found her. Maybe BERLIN asks him "Where" or maybe his expression's enough? About 4 miles south of the institute, less than 50 feet from the road. This was less than 100 feet from the body. BERLIN can't believe it and knows St ANNE wouldn't believe him. Is it yours? - (no answer) - I know it's yours? - You know it's yours? The only prints on it are Freddy's? You wanna tell me how it got there? BERLIN wouldn't believe it either. Door open and TRAVIS enters.</context>
      <utterance>He was up there to plant the gun. St ANNE Did Taylor plant this, too?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>St ANNE and BERLIN look surprised. And BERLIN looks at St ANNE.</context>
      <utterance>Margie Ross put up your bond, Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>St ANNE examines the bail/bond paper and raises eyes to BERLIN. St ANNE I don't make the law.</context>
      <utterance>Are you getting in the way of it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no one here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BERLIN freezes. He maybe says "What?" He definitely says "When?" I dunno. How come they let you out?</context>
      <utterance>Mom took her back to the institute.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is Margie with her? Is she with her?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BERLIN has already grabbed a telephone. Aware it's dead before BOBBY tells him "They're all out around here." He wanders down- stairs in apparent oblivion to BERLIN's distress. BERLIN races back to the den and new problems. Desperate to get at the guns but all cabinets locked "Where's the keys, Bobby? I need a gun." They're my Dad's guns.</context>
      <utterance>No, she came back and went out ag- ain .. gone to see Auntie Charles ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BOBBY stares at BERLIN as though he's staring at that very man.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Bobby, for God's sake. I wanna get the man that killed him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns away into the darkness. BERLIN looks frantic and with- out options. Smashes the cabinets with a chair. Grabs a 44 rev- olver plus a 12 gauge Remington and the slugs that go with it.</context>
      <utterance>I hate you .. I really hate you ..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Intercutting BERLIN's fearful eyes with his P.O.V. of the road. St ANNE (V.O.) Havta be a real dope to kill her now, wouldn't he? I mean, we're talking real, full-blown, insane?</context>
      <utterance>Go take a look in his office. It's fulla rattan - that's the connect- ion, that's the "link" - that's why they never got an I.D. - He kills blind girls - put their picture in the newspaper, and 99 percent of the people who know them are blind ..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERLIN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Just the sound of tho phone and the road dissolving into black.</context>
      <utterance>He is insane. His fucken brain's upside down. But he's also very cunning. He's not going after her with a "Pearl Handled Colt," he- 'll just push her down the stairs ..</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
