<movie id="322" title="Juno">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WHISPERED VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know how long I've wanted this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHISPERED VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wizard.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see a teacup poodle tethered in the yard a few feet away from the abandoned living room set. The dog yaps again.</context>
      <utterance>Quiet, Banana. Hey, shut your gob for a second, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>She swigs from an absurdly oversized carton of juice and wipes her mouth with the back of her hand.</context>
      <utterance>This is the most magnificent discarded living room set I've ever seen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ROLLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, well. If it isn't MacGuff the Crime Dog! Back for another test?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rollo regards her with intense skepticism.</context>
      <utterance>I think the last one was defective. The plus sign looked more like a division sign.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rollo pulls the bathroom key out of reach.</context>
      <utterance>I remain unconvinced.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An eavesdropping TOUGH GIRL wearing an oversized jacket and lots of makeup gapes at Juno from the beauty aisle.</context>
      <utterance>This is your third test today, Mama Bear. Your eggo is preggo, no doubt about it!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOUGH GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pile of stolen COSMETICS falls out of the girl's jacket and clatters to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Three times? Oh girl, you are way pregnant. It's easy to tell. Is your nipples real brown?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOUGH GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno crosses and crosses her legs awkwardly, hopping. It's obvious she has to use the bathroom urgently.</context>
      <utterance>Balls!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you're having twins. Maybe your little boyfriend's got mutant sperms and he knocked you up twice!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rollo sighs and slips her the bathroom key. Juno races down one of the aisles.</context>
      <utterance>Silencio! I just drank my weight in Sunny D. and I have to go, pronto.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you know where the lavatory is.  You pay for that pee stick when you're done! Don't think it's yours just because you've marked it with your urine!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, I didn't say it was.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's not. You're not a lion in a pride!  These kids, acting like lions with their unplanned pregnancies and their Sunny Delights.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She places a giant licorice Super Rope on the counter.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, and this too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's the prognosis, Fertile Myrtle? Minus or plus?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes the stick desperately in an attempt to skew the results. Shake. Shake. Nothing.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. It's not... seasoned yet. Wait. Huh. Yeah, there's that pink plus sign again. God, it's unholy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That ain't no Etch-a-Sketch. This is one doodle that can't be undid, homeskillet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo-yo-yiggity-yo.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am a suicide risk.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this Juno?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No it's Morgan Freeman. Got any bones that need collecting?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only the one in my pants.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dude, I'm pregnant.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's just a food baby. Did you have a big lunch?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not a food baby. I took three pregnancy tests today. I am definitely up the spout.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you even generate enough pee for three pregnancy tests?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I drank like ten tons of Sunny Delight. Anyway, yeah. I'm pregnant. And you're shockingly cavalier.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this for real? Like for real, for real?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unfortunately, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God! Oh shit! Phuket Thailand!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the kind of emotion I was looking for in the first take.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, are you going to go to Havenbrooke or Women Now for the abortion? You need a note from your parents for Havenbrooke.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. Women Now, I guess. The commercial says they help women now.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want me to call for you? I called for Becky last year.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eh, I'll call them myself. But I do need your help with something very urgent.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heavy lifting can only help you at this point.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leah busts a gut laughing. It's a stunningly accurate portrayal of Bleeker's parents.</context>
      <utterance>That is sick, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, you were bored? Is that how this blessed miracle came to be?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah, it was a premeditated act. The sex, I mean, not getting pregnant.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When did you decide you were going to do Bleeker?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like, a year ago, in Spanish class.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aha! You love him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hefts a coffee table with her bare hands. She's wearing her father's LIFTING BELT.</context>
      <utterance>It's extremely complicated, and I'd rather not talk about it in my fragile state.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, what was it like humping Bleeker's bony bod?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was magnificent, man!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Bleek.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, cool tiger. Looks proud.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I swiped it from Ms. Rancick.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your shorts are looking especially gold today.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My mom uses color-safe bleach.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go Carole.  So, guess what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know...</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stunned silence. Juno pops up the footrest of the recliner and leans back comfortably.</context>
      <utterance>I'm pregnant.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Dancing Elk Prep cross country team runs past Bleeker's house in a thundering herd, wearing a motley assortment of warm-ups. Their momentum stirs the crackling fall leaves. They wave and holler at Bleeker and Juno.</context>
      <utterance>I guess so.  What are you going to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I see them all running like that, with their things bouncing around in their shorts, I always picture them naked, even if I don't want to. I have intrusive thoughts all the time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm supposed to be running.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's an awkward silence.</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, what do you think we should do?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought I might, you know, nip it in the bud before it gets worse. Because I heard in health class that pregnancy often results in an infant.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, typically. That's what happens when our moms and teachers get pregnant.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So that's cool with you, then?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, wizard, I guess. I mean do what you think is right.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm real sorry I had sex with you. I know it wasn't your idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whose idea was it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She mounts her bicycle and waves before riding off.</context>
      <utterance>I'll see you at school, O.K.?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whose idea was it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STEVE RENDAZO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, your book fell apart!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE RENDAZO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It must have looked at your face.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We see Steve looking back at Juno for a brief second with mixed feelings.</context>
      <utterance>The funny thing is that Steve Rendazo secretly wants me. Jocks like him always want freaky girls. Girls with horn-rimmed glasses and vegan footwear and Goth makeup. Girls who play the cello and wear Converse All-Stars and want to be children's librarians when they grow up. Oh yeah, jocks eat that shit up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We see Leah at the far end of the hallway, talking animatedly with a paunchy middle-aged teacher, KEITH.</context>
      <utterance>They just won't admit it, because they're supposed to be into perfect cheerleaders like Leah. Who, incidentally, is into teachers.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me too! I love Woody Allen!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>MR. TINKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno looks up and meets eyes with her longtime lab partner: Bleeker. Sound the gong of awkwardness! Juno and Bleeker head separately over to an available lab station and unpack their bags in silence.</context>
      <utterance>People! We're doing our photomagnetism lab today, so find your partner and break out into fours.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well! Nothing like experimenting.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slides a piece of graph paper in front of Juno without looking at her.</context>
      <utterance>I did the prep questions for this lab last night. You can copy my answers if you need to.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I couldn't copy your work.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you copy my work every week.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah. I'm kind of a deadbeat lab partner, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't mind. You definitely bring something to the table.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charisma?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other two LAB PARTNERS, a humorless couple, join them at the station.</context>
      <utterance>Or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, who's ready for some photomagnificence?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL LAB PARTNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a menstrual migraine, and I can't look at bright lights today.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY LAB PARTNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amanda, I told you to go to the infirmary and lie down. You never listen.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL LAB PARTNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No Josh, I don't take orders. Not from you and not from any man.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY LAB PARTNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, you've been acting like this ever since I went up to see my brother at Mankato. I told you, nothing happened!</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL LAB PARTNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something happened. Because your eyes? Are very cold? They're very cold, Josh. They're cold, lying eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY LAB PARTNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? My eyes are not lying!</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL LAB PARTNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno and Bleeker observe the argument like tennis spectators, fascinated by the dynamics of a real couple.</context>
      <utterance>Yes they are, Josh. Since Mankato, they have been lying eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay... I'm going to set up the apparatus. Juno, want to get a C clamp out of that drawer?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL LAB PARTNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to the infirmary.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY LAB PARTNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. Call me when you're OFF the rag.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL LAB PARTNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine. Call me when you learn how to love just one person and not cheat at your brother's college just because you had four Smirnoff Ices and a bottle of Snow Peak Peach flavored Boone's!</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY LAB PARTNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He furiously scrawls a fake memo in his notebook.</context>
      <utterance>Good, I'll be sure to do that, Amanda. I'll make a note of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bleeker reddens and continues constructing the apparatus. GIRL LAB PARTNER stalks off dramatically. Bleeker shakes his head and rifles through his textbook.</context>
      <utterance>Snow Peak Peach is the best flavor of Boone's. Right, Bleek?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Para instruciones en Espanol, oprima numero dos." She presses a few buttons in succession.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She SMACKS the phone a couple of times.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, hello, I need to procure a hasty abortion?... What was that? I'm sorry, I'm on my hamburger phone and it's kind of awkward to talk on. It's really more of a novelty than a functional appliance.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hangs up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Better? Okay, good. Yeah, as I said, I need an abortion, two... sixteen... Um, it was approximately two months and four days ago that I had the sex. That's a guestimate. Okay, next Saturday? Great.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate it when adults use the term "sexually active."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should have seen this octopus furnace. I had to get out my Hazmat suit just to get up in there...</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My dad used to be in the Army, but now he's just your average HVAC specialist. He and my mom got divorced when I was five. She lives on a Havasu reservation in Arizona...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's my stepmom, Bren...</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's obsessed with dogs...</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...owns a nail salon called Bren's Tens...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So Juno, how did your maneuver go last night?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bren speaks in her strong city accent.</context>
      <utterance>Which maneuver, sir? The one in which I moved an entire living room set from one lawn to another, or the one in which I cleared a sixty-four ounce blue slushie in ten minutes?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Juno? Did you happen to barf in my urn? Mac, you know that nice urn by the front door, the one I got up in Stillwater? I found some weird blue shit, I mean stuff, gunk, in there this morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see Liberty Bell blithely pouring bacon bits onto her dinner.</context>
      <utterance>I would never barf in your urn, Brenda. Maybe L.B. did it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Liberty Bell, if I see one more Baco on that potato, I'm gonna kick your monkey ass.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>LONE PROTESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno recognizes the PROTESTER as a classmate of hers.</context>
      <utterance>All babies want to get borned! All babies want to get borned!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, hi Su-Chin.</utterance>
   <speaker>SU-CHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, hi Juno. How are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. I'm good.  Did you finish that paper for Worth's class yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>SU-CHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not yet. I tried to work on it a little last night, but I'm having trouble concentrating.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should try Adderall.</utterance>
   <speaker>SU-CHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No thanks. I'm off pills.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wise move. I know this girl who had a huge crazy freakout because she took too many behavioral meds at once. She took off her clothes and jumped into the fountain at Ridgedale Mall and she was like, "Blaaaaah! I'm a kraken from the sea!"</utterance>
   <speaker>SU-CHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard that was you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She continues on toward the clinic entrance.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it was nice seeing you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SU-CHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Juno! Your baby probably has a beating heart, you know. It can feel pain. And it has fingernails.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She considers the concept, then pushes open the clinic door.</context>
      <utterance>Really? Fingernails?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PUNK RECEPTIONIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno flashes her best jazz hands.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome to Women's Choice, where women are trusted friends. Please put your hands where I can see them and surrender any bombs.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. I'm here for the big show?</utterance>
   <speaker>PUNK RECEPTIONIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your name, please?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The receptionist raises a pierced eyebrow and arranges some paperwork on a clipboard.</context>
      <utterance>Juno MacGuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The receptionist hands Juno the clipboard and a pen.</context>
      <utterance>She thinks I'm using a fake name. Like Gene Simmons or Mother Teresa.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUNK RECEPTIONIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The receptionist reaches into one of those ubiquitous women's clinic CONDOM JARS, and holds up a fistful of purple rubbers.</context>
      <utterance>I need you to fill these out, both sides. And don't skip the hairy details. We need to know about every score and every sore.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUNK RECEPTIONIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like some free condoms? They're boysenberry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No thank you. I'm off sex.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUNK RECEPTIONIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My partner uses these every time we have intercourse. They make his balls smell like pie.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes a seat in the WAITING ROOM and rifles through a pile of old magazines. The magazine selection is lots of "mommy mags" and health related periodicals. She selects an issue of Family Digest and gingerly flips through for a few moments. Then she looks over and notices the FINGERNAILS of a nearby teen, who looks as nervous as she does. The girl bites her thumbnail and spits it onto the floor. Juno looks away, but immediately notices another waiting woman, who absently scratches her arm with long fake nails. Suddenly, she sees fingernails EVERYWHERE. The receptionist clicks her nails on the front desk. Another woman blows on her fresh manicure. Everyone seems to be fidgeting with their fingers somehow. Juno suddenly looks terror-stricken...</context>
      <utterance>Congrats.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here, dumbass? I thought I was supposed to pick you up at four.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I couldn't do it, Leah! It smelled like a dentist in there. They had these really horrible magazines, with, like, spritz cookie recipes and bad fiction and water stains, like someone read them in the tub. And the receptionist tried to give me these weird condoms that looked like grape suckers, and she told me about her boyfriend's pie balls, and Su-Chin Kuah was there, and she told me the baby had fingernails. Fingernails!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, gruesome. I wonder if the baby's claws could scratch your vag on the way out?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm staying pregnant, Le.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep your voice down dude, my mom's around here somewhere. She doesn't know we're sexually active.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does that even mean? Anyway, I got to thinking on the way over. I was thinking maybe I could give the baby to somebody who actually likes that kind of thing. You know, like a woman with a bum ovary or something. Or some nice lesbos.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But then you'll get huge. Your chest is going to milktate. And you have to tell everyone you're pregnant.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. Maybe they'll canonize me for being so selfless.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe they'll totally shit and be super mad at you and not let you graduate or go to Cabo San Lucas for spring break.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leah sighs, as if there's no helping her nerdy friend.</context>
      <utterance>Bleeker and I were going to go to Gettysburg for spring break.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, maybe you could look at one of those adoption ads. I see them all the time in the Penny Saver.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are ads? For parents?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah! "Desperately Seeking Spawn." They're right by the ads for like, iguanas and terriers and used fitness equipment. It's totally legit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Leah. I can't scope out wannabe parents in the Penny Saver! That's tacky. That's like buying clothes at the Pump n' Munch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Penny Saver sucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They turn the pages in silence for a moment. Their lips and teeth are Windex-blue.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but it sucks for free.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at this one "Wholesome, spiritually wealthy couple have found true love with each other."  "All that's missing is your bastard."</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a guy in here who's giving away a piano. Free for the hauling! We should put it in Bleeker's yard.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not listening to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I heard you. I just can't give the baby to people who describe themselves as "wholesome." I'm looking for something a little edgier.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you have in mind, a family of disturbed loners who are into gunplay and incest?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was thinking a graphic designer, mid-thirties, and his cool Asian wife who dresses awesome and plays bass. But I'm trying to not be too particular.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, how about this one? "Healthy, educated couple seeking infant to join our family of five. You will be compensated. Help us complete the circle of love."</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeesh, they sound like a cult. Besides, they're greedy bitches. They already have three kids!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She points to the paper and motions for Juno to look. Juno scans the ad silently. We see the ad. It contains a photo of an attractive couple with ambiguous Mona Lisa smiles. It reads "Educated, successful couple wishes to..."</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Juno. Juno! Look at this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were Mark and Vanessa Loring, and they were beautiful even in black and white.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Bleeker picks up the phone. It's the same HAMBURGER PHONE Juno has. He reconsiders and puts it down. There's a knock on the bedroom door. BLEEKER'S MOM pokes her dowdy head inside.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Bleeker! Spank off to this with motion lotion. Just kidding  Your best friend, Juno.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul? Are you coming downstairs to eat?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ran eight miles today, Puppy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not hungry, oddly.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bleeker places his hand silently on his stomach.</context>
      <utterance>But it's breakfast for supper. Your favorite, Paulie. I made French toast and sausage. Patties, not linkies, just like you like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Juno MacGuff called while you were out running. She wants to know if you're coming to her little coffeehouse performance on Saturday.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the message.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know how I feel about her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've mentioned it about fifty times.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see that Bleeker is clutching a pair of PANTIES in one hand, which he slowly releases as the 45 ends.</context>
      <utterance>I just hope you don't consider her a close friend. Bleeker's mom gives up and closes the door.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="54">
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have no idea how to spit this out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hon, did you get expelled?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. The school would probably contact you in the event of my expulsion.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I was just asking. It seemed plausible.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you need a large sum of money? Legal counsel?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, I'm definitely not asking for anything. Except maybe mercy. Like, it would be really great if nobody hit me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What have you done, Junebug? Did you hit someone with the Previa?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Best to just tell them, man. Rip off the Band-Aid and let it bleed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bren and Mac are predictably speechless.</context>
      <utterance>I'm pregnant.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, God...</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leah presents the Penny Saver photos of the Lornings.</context>
      <utterance>But I'm going to give it up for adoption. I already found the perfect people.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They say they're going to pay my medical expenses and everything. I promise this will all be resolved in thirty-odd weeks, and we can pretend it never happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're pregnant?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so sorry, you guys. If it's any consolation, I have heartburn that's like, radiating down to my kneecaps and I haven't gone number two since Wednesday. Morning!</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno cringes upon hearing her most-hated term.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't even know you were sexually active!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is the kid?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The baby? I don't know anything about it yet. I only know it's got fingernails, allegedly.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nails? Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I mean the father! Who's the father, Juno?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bren and Mac burst into shocked laughter.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. It's, well, it's Paulie Bleeker.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paulie Bleeker? I didn't know he had it in him!</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He just doesn't look, well, virile.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, this is no laughing matter.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leah fires a be quiet glance at Juno.</context>
      <utterance>No, it's not. Paulie is virile, by the way. He was very good in... chair.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you say you were thinking about adoption?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, there's this couple who've been trying to have a baby for five years.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bren looks understandably alarmed. Juno hastily attempts to make the situation sound more legitimate.</context>
      <utterance>We found them in the Penny Saver by the exotic birds section.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But they have a real lawyer and everything. I'm going to meet with them next weekend.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Junebug, that is a tough, tough thing to do. Probably tougher than you can understand right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm not ready to be a mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn skippy, you're not! You don't even remember to give Liberty Bell her breathing meds.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Once! And she didn't die, if you recall!</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leah and Juno exchange glances.</context>
      <utterance>Honey, had you considered, you know, the alternative?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you're a brave young lady. You're made of stronger stuff than I thought. You're a little Viking!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cool it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First things first, we have to get you healthy. You need prenatal vitamins. Incidentally, they'll do incredible things for your nails, so that's a plus. Oh, and we need to schedule a doctor's appointment. Find out where you're going to deliver.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The term "deliver" is so weird. Can we not say "deliver"?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How does "crap it out" sound?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Juno, I want to come with you to meet these adoption people. You're just a kid. I don't want you to get ripped off by a couple of babystarved wingnuts.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mac nods, satisfied, then contemplates the situation dismally.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you were the kind of girl who knew when to say when.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have no idea what kind of girl I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno and Leah hightail it upstairs.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you girls go upstairs for a while? I think Mac's gonna blow.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just tell it to me straight, Bren. Do you think this is my fault? Her mother's fault?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think kids get bored and have intercourse. And I think Junebug was a dummy about it. But we have to move on from here and help her figure it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not ready to be a Pop-Pop.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not going to be a Pop-Pop. And Juno's not going to be a ma. Somebody else is going to find a precious blessing from Jesus in this garbage dump of a situation. I friggin' hope.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you see it coming when she sat us down here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God yeah. But I was hoping she was expelled or into hard drugs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was my first instinct too. Or D.W.I. Anything but this. And I'm going to punch that Bleeker kid in the weiner the next time I see him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mac shrugs in agreement.</context>
      <utterance>Oh Mac, no! He's a sweet kid. You know it wasn't his idea.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi! I'm Vanessa. You must be Juno and Mr. MacGuff. I'm Vanessa.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vanessa, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello. Thank you for having me and my irresponsible child over to your home.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no. Thank you. Come on in.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I take your coats?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes off her hooded sweatshirt and thrusts it into Vanessa's arms who sets it on a bench.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wicked pic in the Penny Saver, by the way. Super classy. Not like those other people with the fake woods in the background. Like I'm really going to fall for that, you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARK LORING appears next to Vanessa. He's a boyishly attractive guy in his mid-thirties. He glances sheepishly at Vanessa upon hearing the Penny Saver mention, then extends his hand to Mac and Juno.</context>
      <utterance>You found us in the Penny Saver?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. I'm Mark Loring. I'm the husband.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="49">
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is our attorney, Gerta Rauss.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Geeeerta Rauuuss!</utterance>
   <speaker>GERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice to meet you. Mac seizes Mark's hand and pumps it heartily.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Mac MacGuff, and this, of course, is my daughter Juno.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like the city in Alaska?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cool. Well, let's sit down and get to know each other a bit.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll get drinks. What would everyone like? I've got Pellegrino, Vitamin Water...</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A Maker's Mark, please. Up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's joking. Junebug has a wonderful sense of humor, which is just one of her many genetic gifts.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vanessa stares, unflappable.</context>
      <utterance>I also have good teeth. No cavities. We finally got fluoridated water in Dancing Elk. She bares them frighteningly to demonstrate.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mac and Juno join Mark and Gerta Rauss on the couch.</context>
      <utterance>We're fine, thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, Juno. First off, how far along are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a junior.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I mean in your pregnancy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vanessa enters with the refreshments on a tray.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Uh, my stepmom took me to the doctor yesterday and they said I was twelve weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, that's marvelous. So you're almost into your second trimester, then?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, apparently. I'm having it on May 4.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The tough part's almost over for you. I mean, my girlfriends always tell me the first couple months are the hardest.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but I hardly noticed it. I'm more worried about the part where I have to start wearing jeans with an elastic panel in the front.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think pregnancy is beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vanessa's looks to the ceiling.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you're lucky it's not you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, let's discuss how we're gonna do this... thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I just have the baby and give it to you, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>GERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark and Vanessa are willing to negotiate an open adoption.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait. What does that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>GERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It means they'd send annual updates, photos, let Juno know how the baby is doing as he or she grows up. Of course, Juno's legal rights would be terminated...</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoah. I don't want to see pictures. I don't need to be notified of anything. Can't we just kick it old school? I could just put the baby in a basket and send it your way. You know, like Moses in the reeds.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark and Juno lock eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Technically, that would be kickin' it Old Testament.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Yeah! The way people used to do it. Quick and dirty, like ripping off a Band-Aid.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, then we agree a traditional closed adoption would be best for all involved, then?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vanessa is clearly ecstatic.</context>
      <utterance>Shit, yeah. Close it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Obviously, we'll compensate you for your medical expenses.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you looking for any other compensation?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, no... I'm not going to sell the baby. I just want it to grow up with people who are ready to love it and be parents. I'm in high school, dude. I'm ill-equipped.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're doing an amazing and selfless thing for us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vanessa has wanted a baby since we got married.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno and Mac stare at her.</context>
      <utterance>I want to be a mommy so badly!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't say.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, haven't you ever felt like you were born to do something?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Heating and air conditioning.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I was born to be a mother. Some of us are.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark is caught off guard.</context>
      <utterance>Mark, are you looking forward to being a dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mac casts a subtle, dubious glance at Mark.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, why not? I mean, every guy wants to be a father. Coach soccer, help with science projects and... I don't know. Fatherly stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, shall we start looking over the paperwork? Gerta has already drafted some preliminary documents.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I use the facilities first? Being pregnant makes you pee like Seabiscuit.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. The powder room down here is being re-tiled, but you can use the master bath upstairs. Go up, then turn left and on your right...</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Room with a toilet, got it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoops! Yikes, I didn't expect to see you up here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. I was just getting something.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did your wife send you up here to spy on me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? No! Do we come off like paranoid yuppies or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you don't just invite a random pregnant teenager into your house and leave her unsupervised. I could be a total klepto, for all you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't get a klepto vibe from you. Evil genius? Maybe. Arsonist? Wouldn't rule it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds her WRIST up to Mark's twitching nostrils.</context>
      <utterance>I did steal a squirt of perfume. What do you think? It's Clinique Happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark inhales.</context>
      <utterance>Smell those sparkling topnotes!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I supposed to feel happy now?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should be happy, Holmes. I'm giving you and Vanessa the gift of life. Sweet, screaming, pooping life! And you don't even have to be there when the baby comes out of me all covered in...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Viscera?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blood and guts.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno mocks his use of "ASAP" silently.</context>
      <utterance>We'd better get back downstairs ASAP.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. That's, uh, my room. Vanessa lets me have a room for all my old stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow, you get a whole room in your own house? She's got you on a long leash there, Mark.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's beautiful. I've always liked Gibson better than Fender.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you play?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I rock a Harmony.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? I'm a pawn shop rocker.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno turns the guitar over, examining it closely.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry. I swear I'm not a gear snob.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is that, Mahogany? What happens if you crack the neck?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me about it. I used to play in a really tight band back when I lived in Chicago, and one night we opened for the Melvins... do you know who the Melvins are?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we were playing with them and I busted this guitar onstage. It cost me $800 and a dime bag just to have it fixed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When was this, like '96?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'93. I'm telling you that was the best time for rock and roll.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nuh-uh, 1977! Punk Volume 1. You weren't there, so you can't understand the magic.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You weren't even alive!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So. What's that thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A Pilates machine?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you make with that?</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't make anything. It's for exercising.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vanessa and Gerta have no response.</context>
      <utterance>My wife just ordered one of those Tony Little Gazelles off the TV, you know, from the guy with the ponytail?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, a shriek of AMP FEEDBACK, followed by loud, discordant GUITAR STRUMMING can be heard drifting down from upstairs. Vanessa's looks to the ceiling.</context>
      <utterance>That guy just doesn't look right to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you excuse me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JUNO AND MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Yeah, they really want you... they really want you... they really do." Building together.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO AND MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VANESSA appears in the doorway. Juno immediately puts down the guitar. Mark doesn't notice her immediately.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, they really want you... they really want you... and I do to.</utterance>
   <speaker>I WANT TO BE THE...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark clumsily puts down the guitar and stands up.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, sorry honey...</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys are playing music?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Juno just wanted a closer look at Kimber here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your guitar is named Kimber?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all right. My axe is named Roosevelt. After Franklin, not Ted. Franklin was the hot one with the polio.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark hangs the guitars back on the wall. He and Juno exit the room, chastised. Vanessa looks to Mark in question.</context>
      <utterance>I think Gerta is waiting for us downstairs with some important stuff for us to go over.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't mean to interrupt the jam sessions.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>GERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, look those over and give me a call at my office if you have any questions.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Juno, we'd really appreciate it if you could keep us updated on any doctor's appointments, ultrasounds, other things of that nature.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Sure. Of course you'd want to know how your kid is cooking.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mac STARES at Juno gravely.</context>
      <utterance>So, then, you really think you're going to go ahead with this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno looks at Mark.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. For sure. I like you guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark seems visibly embarrassed by Vanessa's manic demeanor.</context>
      <utterance>How sure? Percentage-wise, would you say you're 80% sure, 90% sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to say I'm 104% sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh really?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, if I could give it to you now, I would. But it probably looks like a Sea Monkey at this point, so I think we should leave it in there for a while until it gets cuter, you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think that's a great idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's great, right? Stellar news. Well, you guys drive safe, and we'll hear from you soon, all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno and Mac exit. Mark shuts the door. All is silent in the foyer. Mark, Vanessa and Gerta stand motionless. Gerta pumps her fist triumphantly, trying to create a mood of celebration.</context>
      <utterance>All right, take care of yourselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vanessa buries her head in her hands and weeps hoarsely.</context>
      <utterance>All RIGHT!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey man.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, hey Vijay.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you hear Juno MacGuff is pregnant?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yup.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just like our moms and teachers!</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yup.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you hear it's yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yup.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a trip, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't really know anything about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should grow a moustache. You're a real man now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't grow a moustache. It never comes in evenly.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VIJAY jogs off. Bleeker STOPS and wipes away his sweat.</context>
      <utterance>Me neither. But I'm going to stop wearing underpants in order to raise my sperm count. See you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Juno... A couple of us are going to the cineplex after school to donut that movie with the guy with eighteen kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Bleek... Going for my ultrasound. Gotta note and everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll try to drop by later.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>ULTRASOUND TECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the feet...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL THREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oooh...</utterance>
   <speaker>ULTRASOUND TECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The monitor reveals the baby's head.</context>
      <utterance>And there's a hand...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL THREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Check that out... No way...</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you look at that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Check out Baby Big-Head. That kid is scary!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I'm a sacred vessel. All you've got in your belly is Taco Bell!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Touche.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno and Leah look at BREN, who is dabbing her eyes discreetly.</context>
      <utterance>It is really weird looking. It's like it's not even real. I can't believe there are saps who actually cry at these things.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? I'm not made of stone.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULTRASOUND TECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, there we have it. Would you like to know the sex?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, please Junebug?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way. No, I definitely don't want to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULTRASOUND TECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Planning to be surprised when you deliver?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want Mark and Vanessa to be surprised, and if I know, I won't be able to keep myself from telling them and ruining the whole thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULTRASOUND TECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are Mark and Vanessa your friends at school?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, they're the people who are adopting the baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULTRASOUND TECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Well, thank goodness for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, what's that supposed to mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>ULTRASOUND TECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno, Leah and Bren become immediately defensive.</context>
      <utterance>I just see a lot of teenage mothers come through here. It's obviously a poisonous environment for a baby to be raised in.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know I'm so poisonous? Like, what if the adoptive parents turn out to be evil molesters?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or stage parents!</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They could be utterly negligent. Maybe they'll do a far shittier job of raising a kid than my dumbass stepdaughter ever would. Have you considered that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ULTRASOUND TECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... I guess not.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is your job title, exactly?</utterance>
   <speaker>ULTRASOUND TECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said, what-is-your-job-title, Missy?</utterance>
   <speaker>ULTRASOUND TECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm an ultrasound technician, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I'm a nail technician, and I think we both ought to stick to what we know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULTRASOUND TECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bren gestures to the ULTRASOUND MONITOR.</context>
      <utterance>You think you're special because you get to play Picture Pages up there?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ULTRASOUND TECH exits in a huff.</context>
      <utterance>My five year-old daughter could do that, and let me tell you, she is not the brightest bulb in the tanning bed. So why don't you go back to night school in Manteno and learn a real trade!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bren, you're a dick! I love it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Juno? Wow, I didn't expect to see you here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got something really cool to show you guys. Is Vanessa here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gestures awkwardly to Juno's belly.</context>
      <utterance>No, she's working late tonight. She's trying to accrue some extra time off for when, you know...</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. I hear they can be kind of a time-suck.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on in. You wanna Ginseng Cooler?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. What is it with you rich people and your herb-infused juices?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Something to do with the four-packs...  ...They're not bad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why aren't you at work?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mostly work from home. I'm a composer.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No shit. Like Johannes Brahms?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, more commercial stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Commercials.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you seen those ads for Titanium Power men's deodorant?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Titanium Power! Get more snatch by the batch!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wrote that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're kind of a sellout, aren't you? What would the Melvins say?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds up a manila envelope.</context>
      <utterance>They'd say you came a long way out here not knowing if anyone would be home.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, you're going to want to sit down for this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark sits down. With great fanfare, Juno retrieves a dark, glossy sheet from the envelope. It's her ULTRASOUND.</context>
      <utterance>Park it, dude.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Behold, good sir! The very first photo of your future child.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark EXAMINES the ultrasound, baffled.</context>
      <utterance>You're kidding!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it kind of looks like my friend, Paulie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, is he bald and amorphous?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark looks jolted, as if it's the first time he considered that her baby might have a father. He stands up and holds the photo up to the light critically.</context>
      <utterance>No, he's the dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you tell if it's a boy or a girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The doctor can tell, but I decided not to know. I want it to be a big surprise.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it can really only go two ways.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what you think. I drink tons of booze so you might get one of those scary neuter-babies that's born without junk.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Junk?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know... it's parts...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know what junk is.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We definitely want it to have junk.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark chuckles.</context>
      <utterance>Well don't worry about it. My stepmom is forcing me to eat really healthy. She won't even let me stand in front of the microwave or eat red M&amp;Ms. Hope you're ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A new SONG has begun. Mark closes his eyes in ecstasy and walks toward the stereo. Juno follows him toward the source of the music, looking perplexed by how happy he is.</context>
      <utterance>Wait...do you hear that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's only my favorite song. It's Sonic Youth doing "Superstar" by the Carpenters.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've heard the Carpenters before. Chick drummer and freaky dude. Not unlike the White Stripes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark grabs the STEREO REMOTE off the kitchen counter and turns up the volume to a roar. Mark and Juno stand in silence in the kitchen. Mark mouths along with the lyrics.</context>
      <utterance>You haven't heard the Carpenters like this. Listen.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you remember you told me you loved me, baby...</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This album is all Carpenters covers by alt-rock bands. It's called If I Were a Carpenter. It is God. I'll rip a copy for you before you leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the least I can do. What did you say your favorite band was?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't. But it's a three-way tie between the Stooges, Patti Smith and the Runaways.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark walks over to his music collections and starts pulling CD's. He's got a Carpenter's disc, the "No Alternative" charity compilation, and Mother Love Bone. Juno spots a VHS TAPE on the coffee table and picks it up.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I definitely need to make you some CDs. At least while my kid is hanging out in there. He gestures at Juno's burgeoning paunch.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Wizard of Gore?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah. It's Herschel Gordon Lewis. He's the ultimate master of horror.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark SWIVELS AROUND slowly on his desk chair, surprised.</context>
      <utterance>Please. Dario Argento is the ultimate master of horror.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Argento's good, but Lewis is completely demented. We're talking buckets of goo. Red corn syrup everywhere. And fake brains up the yin-yang.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark gives a look - "Oh, Really?"</context>
      <utterance>Frankly, this looks kind of stupid.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is even better than Suspiria. You've got decent taste in slasher movies, Mark.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He raises his mug in a toast and Juno clinks it awkwardly.</context>
      <utterance>Here's to dovetailing interests.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, have you and Vanessa thought of a name for the baby yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, sort of. Vanessa likes Madison for a girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madison? Isn't that kind of... I don't know, gay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, pretentious much? I guess everyone should have a mysterious name like Juno, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My dad went through this phase where he was obsessed with Greek and Roman mythology. He named me after Zeus's wife. I mean, Zeus had other lays, but I'm pretty sure Juno was his only wife. She was supposed to be really beautiful but really mean. Like Diana Ross.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That suits you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, not many teenage girls in your situation would actually go through with this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I weighed my options. But after all this, I'm glad I didn't, you know, get rid of it. I want to have it. For you guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A door suddenly slams upstairs. Vanessa's home.</context>
      <utterance>You're something else.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vanessa. Shit, you better get out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? What the big deal?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing. She just hates when I sit around watching movies and 'not contributing.'</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno jumps up and rushes out.</context>
      <utterance>I'll handle this. I'm really good at diffusing mom-type rage.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait... aww, crap!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno intercepts her breathlessly, clutching the ULTRASOUND photo. Mark trails behind her.</context>
      <utterance>Mark? Are you home? I want to show you some things I picked up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vanessa JUMPS and makes a strangled sound.</context>
      <utterance>Hi Vanessa!</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Juno! God, you startled me. What are you doing here? What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing...</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vanessa is obviously entertaining some worse-case scenarios. Her eyes are wide and she's uncharacteristically ruffled.</context>
      <utterance>I went to the doctor today.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is the baby okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds the ULTRASOUND up to show Vanessa and drapes her arm around her.</context>
      <utterance>Sure. It's the right size and everything. I even saw its phalanges today! Check this...</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What...</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vanessa drops the shopping bags, sick with relief.</context>
      <utterance>This is the baby. Your baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God...</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't it look like it's waving? It's kind of like it's saying "Hi, Vanessa. Will you be my mommy?"</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Yeah, it kind of does.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Juno was nice enough to bring this by for us.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I came over as soon as I got that cold ultrasound goo off my pelvis. My stepmom verbally abused the ultrasound tech so we were escorted off the premises.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She can't divert her gaze from the photo.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, that's great!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vanessa chuckles tightly, clearly embarrassed by her show of emotion.</context>
      <utterance>See? Nothing to worry about.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, what kind of swag did you score?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Mall madness, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh it's just some stuff I picked up. For, you know, the baby. Babies need a lot of things. I want everything to be just right.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought people got all that stuff at baby showers. When my stepmom had my sister I remember she got about a million presents. They were all lame though, so I wasn't jealous.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I doubt anyone's throwing us a shower.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um, I think people are kind of unsure about the situation because it's not, you know, set in stone.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean? You mean...  Do you think I'm going to flake out on you?</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno glances at Mark and again at Vanessa. Vanessa looks embarrassed.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, I don't think that, Juno. It's just that, we went through a situation before where it didn't work out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cold feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should have gone to China. I heard they give away babies like free iPods. They shoot 'em out of those T-shirt guns at sports events.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Well, Juno, your parents must be wondering where you are. You might want to head home.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She waves and heads for the door.</context>
      <utterance>Naah. I'm already pregnant, so they figure nothing worse could happen to me. I gotta bounce anyway. It was nice seeing you guys again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vanessa looks pain-stricken as Mark helps Juno with her bag.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, don't forget your bag.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where the hell have you been, Junebug?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I drove to St. Cloud to show Mark and Vanessa the ultrasound. And I wound up staying for a couple of hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A couple of hours? Why are you going up there in the first place?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They said they wanted to know about this stuff. They said to keep them updated, so I did!</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could have sent it to them. Why would you drive an hour out to East Jesus, Nowhere?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat as Bren absorbs this.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, I just did. And while we were waiting for Vanessa, Mark and I watched The Wizard of Gore and he burned me some CDs of weird music. He's kind of cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was a mistake, Juno. Mark is a married stranger. You overstepped a boundary.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Bren-duhhh, I think you're the one overstepping boundaries. You're acting like you're the one who has to go through this and get huge and push a baby out of your vag for someone else. Besides, who cares if he's married? I can have friends who are married.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't work that way, kiddo. You don't know squat about the dynamics of marriage.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know anything about me!</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bren rises to leave, clutching the Dog Fancy magazine.</context>
      <utterance>I know enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't even have a dog!</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, because you're allergic to their saliva. I've made a lot of sacrifices for you, Juno. And in a couple years you're going to move out -- and I'm getting Weimaraners.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow, dream big!</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bren STORMS out. Juno heads to the URN by the door and defiantly pours the remains of her blue slushie into it.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, go fly a kite.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bleeker's mom was possibly attractive once. But now she looks a hobbit. The fat one that was in The Goonies.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi Juno. What can I do for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I borrowed Paulie's physics notes in school today. I'm pretty sure he needs them back, or his grade could plummet to an A minus.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She steals another glance at Juno's belly.</context>
      <utterance>Fine. Come in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bleeker smiles faintly.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, don't concentrate so hard, man. I think I smell hair burning.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She closes the door halfway and leaves. Juno rolls her eyes and pulls the door shut entirely.</context>
      <utterance>Ten minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's up?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just wanted to come over. You know, say hi. I miss hanging out with you on school nights.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nervously cracks open a container of ORANGE TIC-TACS and pours them into his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>I miss it too.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Orange Tic-Tacs are Bleeker's one and only vice. When we made out, the day I got pregnant, his mouth tasted really tangy and delicious.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, it looks like you're getting pregnant-er these days.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bleeker is visibly relieved.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Um, I hooked up a whole private adoption thing. These married people in Saint Cloud are going to be the parents.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? What are they like?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The guy is super cool! His name is Mark and he's into old horror movies and he plays guitar. I actually hung out with him today.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that normal?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I asked my dad and Bren not to narc us out to your folks, so we should be safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno walks over to the bed and sits down next to Bleeker.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. That's a relief.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to really start looking like a dork soon. Will you still think I'm cute if I'm huge?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno is caught off guard by his sincerity.</context>
      <utterance>I always think you're cute. I think you're beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Bleek.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The song playing ends, and another one begins. It's "the song," the track that Bleeker and Juno both recognize from the infamous night in the basement.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Junebug, when all this is over we should get the band back together again.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Sure. Once Tino gets a new drumhead we should be good to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We could get back together too.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bleeker picks at the carpet, dejected.</context>
      <utterance>Were we together?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we were once. You know, that time.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Katrina De Voort? You could go out with Katrina De Voort.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't like Katrina.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I totally heard you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't. Katrina smells like soup. Her whole house smells of soup.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think? Custard or Cheesecake?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're yellow.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I wanted to pick something gender-neutral for now. Once we get the baby, God willing, we can create a more decisive palette.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do people think yellow is gender- neutral? I don't know one man with a yellow bedroom.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I'm leaning toward Custard in this light. I don't know. I should paint a small area...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or you could just wait a couple months. It's not like the baby's going to storm in here any second and demand dessert-colored walls.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What to Expect says that readying the baby's room is an important process for women. It's called "nesting."</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nesting, huh? Are you planning to build the crib out of twigs and saliva?</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should read the book. I even flagged the "daddy chapters" for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just think it's too early to paint. That's my opinion.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I disagree. Mark shrugs, resigned. Vanessa points to the nursery's largest wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That wall is going to need something. Maybe we could put our first family picture there.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hm.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark stares at the wall, looking lost.</context>
      <utterance>Can you see it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="39">
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yum. This pretzel tastes like a friggin' donut!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She wrestles Leah for the pretzel. Onlookers stare at them, appalled, as Leah puts Juno in a half-Nelson.</context>
      <utterance>Share the love, Tits!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leah claps a hand over Juno's mouth.</context>
      <utterance>She's assaulting me! She's denying me fresh-baked goodness!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hly shht!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno drags Leah behind a pillar and peers out from behind it. They're watching a group of well-heeled women and their children shopping en masse. One of the women is pushing a toddler in an ultramodern stroller. And one of the women is VANESSA, looking vaguely detached.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's her. That's Vanessa Loring.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno nods.</context>
      <utterance>Of the Penny Saver Lorings?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way! She's pretty.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sound shocked or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The women gather near a play area, sip Frapps and loudly discuss their outfits for an upcoming party.</context>
      <utterance>I just thought she'd look really old in real life.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I was like, "No offense, sweetie, but nobody looks good in gauchos."</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Especially not with her build.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of the little girls in the group tugs at Vanessa's sleeve. Vanessa happily follows the little girl over to their play area and begins to play energetically with her. Juno watches intently, but Leah just snickers.</context>
      <utterance>Wah-wah-waaah!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's gonna steal that kid for her collection.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They watch Vanessa for a few more moments. The other kids wander over toward the play area while their mothers ignore them. Vanessa continues to entertain the children.</context>
      <utterance>Right, seriously.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leah stands up. Juno lingers for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Bo-ring!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want a huge cookie. And like, a lamb kebob. Simultaneously.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The elevator door opens, revealing... Vanessa.</context>
      <utterance>God, Spermy. Must you always feed?</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno tries her best to look enthused.</context>
      <utterance>Juno?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well hi Vanessa! What brings you to the mall today?</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just, you know, shopping with my girlfriends.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno glares at Leah.</context>
      <utterance>You're gay?</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please excuse Leah. She's mentally challenged.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, okay. So... how are you feeling?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lifts her shirt and presses her popped-out NAVEL.</context>
      <utterance>Happy? Oh, you mean like, physically. I'm good. Look, I have a snooze button now!</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vanessa is admiring the belly, when Juno grimaces.</context>
      <utterance>That's great.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vanessa looks confused.</context>
      <utterance>Dude, it's moshing all over.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vanessa nods in understanding then begins summoning the courage for an unusual request.</context>
      <utterance>It's kicking.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um... Juno, can I -- Can I touch it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grabs Vanessa's hand and plants it on her stomach.</context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding? Everyone at school is always grabbing at my belly. I'm like a legend. They call me the Cautionary Whale.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vanessa moves her hand, wanting desperately to feel the baby.</context>
      <utterance>I can't feel anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She says this as though it's an admission of failure.</context>
      <utterance>It's not moving for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vanessa kneels down next to the swell of Juno's belly.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, you should try talking to it. They can apparently hear speech in there, even though it sounds all ten thousands leagues under the sea.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leah gives a look to Juno as if she's about to barf.</context>
      <utterance>Hi. Hi, baby. It's me. My name is Vanessa. I can't wait to meet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vanessa looks like she's giving up hope. Then suddenly,</context>
      <utterance>Can you hear me sweet angel?</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God -- It moved! I felt it!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elbow.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno smiles at Vanessa in awe of her genuine affection.</context>
      <utterance>Wow! It's magical.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark instantly smiles.</context>
      <utterance>So, I've been spending a lot of time listening to that weird CD you made me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh really? What's the verdict?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I sort of like it. I mean, it's cute.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cute?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, when you're used to the raw power of Iggy and the Stooges, everything else sounds kind of precious by comparison.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I imagine you have a collection of punk chestnuts to prove your point.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Consider it your musical education.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm dying to see what you've got to teach me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, stop surfing porn and get back to work. Just wanted to say hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark hangs up. Smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Go learn something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, you're getting huge. How many months has it been now?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Almost eight. You wouldn't believe how weird I look naked.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish my funbags would get bigger.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trust me, you don't. I actually have to wear a bra now. And I have to rub this nasty cocoa butter stuff all over myself or my skin could get stretched too far and explode.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hot!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, why is everyone always staring at me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She illustrates by making a rounded gesture near her stomach.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you are kind of... convex.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow, someone's been actually doing her geometry homework for once!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have a choice. Keith's been grading me really hard lately.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please do not refer to Mr. Conyers as "Keith," okay? My barf reflex is already heightened these days.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keith's hot.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see KEITH the teacher talking to some science kids in the background. He has a Wild America beard. He lifts a cup of coffee to his lips and slurps lustily.</context>
      <utterance>Eww, he's all beardy!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you hear Bleek is going to prom with Katrina De Voort?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Katrina? Pfft, no way. He doesn't like Katrina. It must be a pity date.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He asked her. I heard they were going to Benihana, then the prom, then to Vijay's parents' cabin.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bleeker told me Katrina's whole house reeks of soup!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, it totally does. I was there for her birthday about four years ago and it was like Lipton Landing. But you know, boys have endured worse things for nookie.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no way in hell they're having sex or even holding hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't be so sure about that. He did it with you. He's a man now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, Bleek trusted me. We're best friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you jealous? I thought you said you didn't care what he did.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not jealous, and I don't care. I just know he doesn't like Katrina and I don't think he should toy with her emotions like that. She seems so nice and all.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay Juno, I'm really convinced.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Prom is for wenises, anyway. Once you're old enough to go, it's not cool anymore.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you honestly and truly going to prom with Katrina De Voort?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um, hi?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leah just told me you were going with her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno is clearly AFFRONTED.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I did ask her if she wanted to go. A bunch of us from the team are going to Benihana, then the prom, then Vijay's parents' cabin.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're getting a stretch limo.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your mom must be really glad you're not taking me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're mad. Why are you mad?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not mad. I'm in a fucking great mood. Despite the fact that I'm trapped in a fat suit I can't take off, despite the fact that everyone is making fun of me behind my back, despite the fact that your little girlfriend gave me the stinkeye in art class yesterday...</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A GIRL strides past (obviously KATRINA) with a sour look aimed squarely at Juno.</context>
      <utterance>Katrina's not my girlfriend! And I doubt she was actually giving you the stinkeye. She just looks like that all the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bleeker takes a deep breath.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever. Have fun at the prom with Soupy Sales. I'm sure I can think of something way more cool to do that night. Like I could pumice my feet, or go to Bren's dumb Unitarian church, or get hit by a ten-ton truck full of hot garbage juice. All those things would be exponentially cooler than going to the prom with you. She starts to walk away.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're being really immature.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bleeker BRACES himself and pushes up his lab goggles.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not how our thing works! I hurl the accusations and you talk me down, remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not this time. You don't have any reason to be mad at me. You broke my heart. I should be royally ticked at you, man. I should be really cheesed off. I shouldn't want to talk to you anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? Because I got bored and had sex with you one day, and then I didn't, like, marry you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like I'd marry you! You would be the meanest wife of all time. And anyway, I know you weren't bored that day because there was a lot of stuff on TV. The Blair Witch Project was on Starz, and you were like, "Oh, I want to watch this, but we should make out instead. La la la."</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it, Bleek. Take Katrina the Douche Packer to the prom. I'm sure you guys will have a really bitchin' time!</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well... I still have your underwear.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still have your virginity!</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God, SHUT UP!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Are you ashamed that we did it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno picks up her BACKPACK dejectedly and slides it over her shoulder. She's about to walk away, when...</context>
      <utterance>Well at least you don't have to walk around with the evidence under your sweater. I'm a planet!</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, let me take that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shouldn't be carrying that heavy bag. I'll take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns around, wipes TEARS off her cheek (making sure no one sees) and continues down the hallway.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. It's fine. What's another ten pounds?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. That shirt is working hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is Vanessa here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He and Juno smile conspiratorially.</context>
      <utterance>Nope. We're safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gestures for Juno to follow him into the house.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, I have something for you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="48">
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Mark! Is this the baby's room? It's beautiful!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hilarious. No, I just keep all of my old comics down here, and I want to show you one of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God, you're one of those guys...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark RUMMAGES through a cardboard box in the corner.</context>
      <utterance>You're gonna like this, I promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shows the COMIC to Juno. It's called "Most Fruitful Yuki." It depicts a pregnant JAPANESE GIRL kicking ass and taking names.</context>
      <utterance>Here it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Most Fruitful Yuki"? What is... Oh my god, she's a pregnant superhero!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno examines the comic. "Most Fruitful Yuki" does resemble her.</context>
      <utterance>Isn't that great? I got it when I was in Japan with my band. She reminds me of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow, I actually feel like less of a fat dork now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She throws a KARATE KICK in Mark's direction with a KEE-YA! Juno is sincerely pleased.</context>
      <utterance>Most Fruitful Yuki is bad ass, man. You should be proud to be the same condition.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a battered portable CD player in the corner. Juno kneels down and pops in one of the discs.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, how about some tunes?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno puts in the CD and "All The Young Dudes" fills the room. Mark Laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Now this first one is kinda slow. But it's Mott the Hoople so it's still totally rad and hardcore.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I actually know this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, this song's older than me, if you can believe that. I danced to it at my senior prom.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's almost interesting, Mark. Who did you dance with?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her name was Cynthia Vogel and she was a good dance partner. Even let me put my hands on her butt.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She mockingly places her hands on Mark's waist and moves back and forth stiffly.</context>
      <utterance>Oh man, I can just picture you slow dancing like a dork!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark puts his hands on what remains of Juno's waist. She drapes her arms around his neck self-consciously.</context>
      <utterance>No, I put my hands on your waist. Then you put your arms around my neck. That's how we did it in '88.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, okay. Like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've never been to a dance, have you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only squares and nerds go to dances.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They SWAY slowly to the music. Juno's belly bumps up against Mark.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno rests her head on Mark's chest. They dance in silence for a few moments, then stop moving. Mark pulls Juno as close as he possibly can, given her expanding girth.</context>
      <utterance>I feel like there's something between us. They laugh.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm leaving Vanessa.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno backs away.</context>
      <utterance>It's just not working out, but I'm getting my own place in the city... and I've got it all planned out. It's something I've wanted to do for a long time...</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. No, you definitely cannot do that, Mark. That's a big, fat sack of no!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She GESTURES wildly to her belly. Suddenly, something matters to her far more than the approval of an older guy.</context>
      <utterance>This isn't what we agreed on. You guys have to take care of... this! You are the chosen custodians of the big-ass bump!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I thought you'd be cool if...</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you guys to adopt the Buglet. I wanted everything to be perfect. Not shitty and broken like everyone else's family. Listen, once I have the baby, Vanessa is going to finally be happy, and everything will be all right. Believe me on this one!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A baby is not going to fix everything. Besides, I don't know if I'm ready to be a father.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you're old!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... How do you think of me, Juno? Why are you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I just liked being your friend. I sort of liked becoming furniture in your weird life.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This...  ...this is what my life has become. Stuff in boxes. Stuff underground. Is that so appealing to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I guess... Is this my fault? Is Vanessa mad at you because of me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not the point. We're just not in love anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark suddenly sees Juno for what she is -- a teenage girl.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but didn't you love Vanessa when you married her? If you love someone once, you can love them again, I know it. My friend Leah has gone out with the same guy, like, four times. You're just not trying.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He paces over to the wall and KICKS it softly.</context>
      <utterance>I'm such an idiot. I can't believe what an idiot I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please don't get a divorce! God, Mark, just do me a solid and stay with your wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, you're so young.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno turns to leave, then shoots one furious look back at Mark.</context>
      <utterance>Not really. I'm sixteen. I'm old enough to tell when people are acting like total a-holes!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She bolts up the stairs, sobbing.</context>
      <utterance>Oh and by the way, I bought another Sonic Youth album and it's the worst thing I've ever heard! It's just noise, man!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Juno? What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's obvious from Juno's tears and flushed face that she's lying. Vanessa instantly goes pale with fear, but she tries her hardest to seem serene and "together" in front of Juno.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark? Why is Juno crying?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rushes toward the door.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not crying. I'm allergic to fine home furnishings. See you later.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno halts.</context>
      <utterance>Hold on.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Juno, what's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno looks totally betrayed. She doesn't respond. Vanessa looks at Juno's expression and knows Mark is lying.</context>
      <utterance>She's hormonal. Right, June? It's just part of the whole process.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't do anything... I just... I've just been thinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just thinking if this is really the right thing for us.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She knows exactly to what he's referring.</context>
      <utterance>What are you referring to?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been just wondering if we're, you know, ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course we're ready. We've taken all the classes. The nursery. The books --</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno's face continues to fall. Vanessa notices.</context>
      <utterance>I know we're prepared. I just don't know if... I'm ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno ain't buying it.</context>
      <utterance>Juno, don't worry about this. He just has cold feet. That's how boys are. The books all say the same thing. A woman becomes a mother when she gets pregnant. A man becomes a father when he sees his baby. He's going to get there. He'll get there.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't we let Juno go home and we can discuss this later on, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It all just happened so fast. We put that ad in the paper. I thought it would take months if, you know, ever and then -- boom -- Two weeks later, she's in our living room.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She answered our prayers.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This stops Vanessa. Juno looks offended.</context>
      <utterance>Ever since, it's just been like a ticking clock.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long hideous beat.</context>
      <utterance>What are you saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another hideous beat.</context>
      <utterance>It just feels a little like bad timing.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What would be a good time for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. There's just things I still want to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like what? Be a rock star?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vanessa sighs. It's done.</context>
      <utterance>Don't mock me.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vanessa looks defeated.</context>
      <utterance>You're trying to do something that's never going to happen. And you know what? Your shirt is stupid. Grow up. If I have to wait for you to become Kurt Cobain, I'm never going to be a mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear the front door closing. Vanessa and Mark look over and notice that Juno has escaped the conflict.</context>
      <utterance>I never said I'd be a great father.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I called Gerta Rauss. She says she can represent both of us. They call it "collaborative divorce." It's apparently all the rage right now. And it's easy because we don't have children.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark nods and sits down.</context>
      <utterance>No, it's fine. Thanks for making the call, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're actually, finally doing this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like it, yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you found a place to stay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, downtown.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A hotel?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a loft.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They STARE at the wall, speechless and defeated.</context>
      <utterance>Aren't you the cool guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She buries her head in her hands.</context>
      <utterance>I wanted a baby so bad. So bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a LOUD KNOCK on the front door.</context>
      <utterance>I know you did.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vanessa takes the note from his hand and turns it over, examining it.</context>
      <utterance>It looks like a bill from Jiffy-Lube.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's for me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, big puffy version of Junebug. Where have you been?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dealing with stuff way beyond my maturity level. Where is everyone?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bren took Liberty Bell to her tot ice skating class.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tot ice skating? Tots can't ice skate. Liberty Bell's still getting the hang of stairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, but you know Bren. She dreams big.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, she does.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look a little morose, honey. What's eating you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm losing my faith in humanity.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think you can narrow it down for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess I wonder sometimes if people ever stay together for good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean like couples?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, like people in love.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you having boy trouble? I gotta be honest; I don't much approve of you dating in your condition, 'cause... well, that's kind of messed up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, no!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's kind of skanky. Isn't that what you girls call it? Skanky? Skeevy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please stop now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tore up from the floor up?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, it's not about that. I just need to know that it's possible for two people to stay happy together forever. Or at least for a few years.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno nods in agreement.</context>
      <utterance>It's not easy, that's for sure. Now, I may not have the best track record in the world, but I have been with your stepmother for ten years now, and I'm proud to say that we're very happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A wave of REALIZATION crosses Juno's face.</context>
      <utterance>In my opinion, the best thing you can do is to find a person who loves you for exactly what you are. Good mood, bad mood, ugly, pretty, handsome, what have you, the right person will still think that the sun shines out your ass. That's the kind of person that's worth sticking with.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I sort of already have.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods toward her belly.</context>
      <utterance>Well, of course. Your old D-A-D! You know I'll always be there to love and support you, no matter what kind of pickle you're in.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno laughs and hugs her father, planting a smooch on his cheek.</context>
      <utterance>Obviously.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She salutes and dashes out of the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>I need to go out somewhere for just a little while. I don't have any homework, and I swear I'll be back by ten.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were talking about me, right?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you put like a hundred things of Tic Tacs in my mailbox?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. That was me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because they're your fave. And you can never have too much of your favorite one-calorie breath mint.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... thanks. I think I'm pretty much set until college on the Tic Tac front.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I've been thinking. I'm really sorry I was such a huge bitch to you. You didn't deserve that. You never deserve any of the poo I unload on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know it's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Also, I think I'm in love with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, you mean as friends?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, for real. I think you are the coolest person I've ever met. And you don't even have to try.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I try really hard, actually...</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you're naturally smart. You always think of the funniest things to do. Remember when you passed me that postcard during Spanish class, and it was addressed like, "Junebug MacGuff, Row 4, Third Seat From the Blackboard"? And it said, "I'm having fun in Barcelona -- wish you were here"? That was hilarious.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just bored. I only think school is awesome like, 80% of the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Plus, you're the only person who doesn't stare at my stomach all the fucking time. You actually look at my face. And every time I look at you, the baby starts kicking me super hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno presses Bleeker's hand against her belly.</context>
      <utterance>It does?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wizard!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it's because my heart starts pounding when I see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mine too.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Basically, I'm completely smitten with you, and I don't care if I'm making an ass out of myself right now, because you've seen me make an ass out of myself a million times, and you still want to be my friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, yeah. You're the best friend I've ever had, even when you're being kind of evil.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all I need from you. That's more than I could ever ask for. You're just golden, dude.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we make out now?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bleeker and Juno KISS, oblivious to the gawking track team guys in the background. In the distance, near the school entrance, we see STEVE RENDAZO (the kid who always TORMENTS Juno) regarding the makeout session with a sad, envious expression. LEAH passes by, does a double take, then hurries up to the fence, rolling her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Either I just pissed my pants or...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAC</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or...</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thundercats are go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ow, ow, fuckity-ow. Bren, when do I get that Spinal Tap thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's called a spinal block, and you can't have it yet, honey. The doctor said you're not dilated enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean I have to wait for it to get even worse? Why can't they just give it to me now?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno lets out a genuine shriek of pain.</context>
      <utterance>Well, honey, doctors are sadists who like to play God and watch lesser people scream.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit.  Hey, can we give my kid the damn spinal tap already?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We see Juno in the process of delivery, from her POV. Leah holds one of Juno's feet and Bren holds the other.</context>
      <utterance>It really didn't hurt that bad having him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We see Leah holding Juno's FOOT, which is shaking. Leah's shirt is soaked. She rolls her eyes and mouths "Fuck you" at Juno. Juno's raised MIDDLE FINGER enters the frame.</context>
      <utterance>The best part was when I peed on Leah during labor.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The doctor reveals JUNO'S BABY BOY above the sheet.</context>
      <utterance>And then, out of nowhere, there it was...</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Juno looks at the baby in awe, then her eyes begin to flutter... and she passes out.</context>
      <utterance>There he was.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Paulie breaks the tape, winning the race. The fifteen or so people in attendance cheer.</context>
      <utterance>I decided to not call Bleeker to tell him that I was having the baby. He had a big meet against Manteno and I didn't want him to get all worried about me and choke.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His legs are as swift as his seed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bleeker pants at the finish line, dripping with sweat.</context>
      <utterance>What did you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bleeker looks out at the BLEACHERS, scanning them for Juno. She's not there.</context>
      <utterance>P. Bleeker has just broken a district record in the 400.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Bleek takes off RUNNING toward the parking lot without stopping to explain. His mother stands up, confused.</context>
      <utterance>But he figured it out anyway.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pull back to reveal she's speaking to VANESSA, who stands, paralyzed, several feet away.</context>
      <utterance>Would you like to meet your son?</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a son?</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are the adoptive mother?</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a son.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vanessa reaches out for the baby and gingerly accepts him in her eyes. She spends a few moments just looking at him. She feels someone watching her, then looks up to see a Bren leaning against the doorway. Vanessa blinks away her tears self-consciously.</context>
      <utterance>Healthy kid, too. Didn't waste any time getting out.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do I look?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vanessa laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Like a mom. Scared shitless.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Juno begins strumming her guitar and playing "Anyone Else But You," by the Moldy Peaches. Bleeker joins in. At first their playing is discordant, but suddenly it works.</context>
      <utterance>Ready? Bleeker nods.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a part time lover and a fulltime friend. The monkey on your back is the latest trend. I don't see what anyone can see, in anyone else but you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here is the church and here is the steeple. We sure are cute for two ugly people. I don't see what anyone can see, in anyone else but you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We both have shiny happy fits of rage. You want more fans, I want more stage. I don't see what anyone can see, in anyone else but you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are always trying to keep it real. I'm in love with how you feel. I don't see what anyone can see, in anyone else but you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I kiss you on the brain in the shadow of a train. I kiss you all starryeyed, my body's swinging from side to side. I don't see what anyone can see, in anyone else but you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The pebbles forgive me, the trees forgive me. So why can't you forgive me? I don't see what anyone can see, in anyone else but you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNO AND BLEEKER TOGETHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She and Bleeker exchange glances as they play. They smile ambiguously. Juno leans over and kisses Bleeker on the cheek. Pull out to reveal the surrounding green suburb buzzing with life and summer activity.</context>
      <utterance>Du du du du du du dudu. Du du du du du du dudu. I don't see what anyone can see, in anyone else but you.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
