<movie id="324" title="Jurassic Park The Lost World">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JURASSIC PARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Screenplay by David Koepp</utterance>
   <speaker>JURASSIC PARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>based on the novel by Michael Crichton</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ISLA SORNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two SHIP HANDS, dressed in white uniforms, have set up a picnic table with three chairs on the sand and are carefully laying out luncheon service -- fine china, silver, crystal decanters with red and white wine. PAUL BOWMAN, fortyish, sits in a chair off to the side, reading. MRS. BOWMAN, painfully thin, with the perpetually surprised look of a woman who's had her eyes done more than once, supervises the settings of the table. She looks up and sees a little girl, CATHY, seven or eight years old, wandering off down the beach.</context>
      <utterance>87 miles southeast of Nublar</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BOWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cathy gestures, pretending she can't hear.</context>
      <utterance>Cathy! Don't wander off! Cathy keeps wandering. MRS. BOWMAN  Cathy, come back! You can look for shells right here!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave her alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BOWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about snakes?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no snakes on a beach. Let her have fun, for once.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rounding a curve in the beach, her parents disappear from view behind her. A RUSTLING sound draws her attention, and she turns, toward where the thick jungle foliage gives way to the sand. A large bush, maybe twelve feet tall, is moving, its branches swaying and shaking. Curious, Cathy walks up to the bush, which abruptly stops moving. A small, lizard-like animal, dark green with brown stripes along its back, steps out from the bush. Only about a foot tall, it stands on its hind legs, balancing on its thick tail. It walks upright, bobbing its head like a chicken.</context>
      <utterance>Please be quiet, please be quiet please be quiet...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The animal (a COMPSOGNATHUS) just stares at her. Cathy squats down on her haunches. CATHY (cont'd) What are you? A little bird or something? She opens her hand. She's got a handful of goldfish crackers. CATHY (cont'd) Are you hungry? You want a goldfish? The compy bobs forward a few steps, cautiously. CATHY (cont'd) Come on. I won't hurt you. The compy draws closer. Cathy holds the cracker in the palm of her hand. The compy gets closer still -- -- and hops numbly up onto Cathy's palm. Her arm dips a bit under the weight, but it's not that heavy, and she holds it up easily. It bobs its head, scarfs up the goldfish, and eats it. Enchanted, Cathy breaks into an enormous grin and returns her hand, calling back over her shoulder. CATHY (cont'd) Mom! Dad! You gotta come see this! I found something! She turns back. Thirty more compys have come out onto the sand. They're standing there, bobbing anxiously, staring at her from a few feet away. Cathy's smile fades. She turns her head slowly to the right. TWENTY MORE COMPYS have come in from that side, forming a semi-circle, bobbing and CHIPPING as they surround her. CATHY (cont'd) (terrified) What do you guys want?</context>
      <utterance>Well, hello there!</utterance>
   <speaker>BACK ON THE BEACH,</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>the table is set. Mrs. Bowman calls out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BOWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From around the curve of the beach, a flock of birds bolts from the jungle trees as Cathy's shrill SCREAMS suddenly pierce the air.</context>
      <utterance>Cathy, sweetheart! Lunch is ready!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The source of the voice is JOHN HAMMOND, the founder of InGen and creator of Jurassic Park. But he's not in the room. His image is on a closed circuit TV screen, which has been wheeled up to the end of the table. And he doesn't look good. He's terribly infirmed, propped up in bed, his face pale and drawn, medical equipment BEEPING around him. HAMMOND (cont'd) There are some corporate issues that are not about the bottom line. We have so much still to learn about those creatures. A whole world of intricate, interlocking behaviors, vanished everywhere -- except for Site B. Please. Let's not do what is good for more men at the expense at what is best for all mankind. The CHAIRMAN, seventyish, nods awkwardly to the television.</context>
      <utterance>The hurricane seemed like a disaster at the time, but now I think it was a blessing, nature's way of freeing those animals from their human confines. Of giving them another chance to survive, but this time as they were meant to, without man's interference.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAIRMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to PETER LUDLOW, late thirties, a man with the anxious look of someone who insists the buck stop on his desk. Ludlow flips open a file, pulls out a stack of black and white eight by tens, and tosses them on the table.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, John. Mr. Ludlow?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOARD MEMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CHAIRMAN signs heavily, feeling like a traitor. He can't bear to look at Hammond on the TV monitor.</context>
      <utterance>I second the motion, Mr. Chairman, Please poll the members by a show of hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAIRMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It starts slowly, guiltily, but every hand in the room goes up. Ludlow sits back, victorious. Hammond, furious, raises his right hand, which holds a remote control, and points it at the TV screen. It goes blank.</context>
      <utterance>All those in favor of InGen Corporate Resolution 213C, please signify your approval by raising your right hand.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Curious Man sits down next to Malcolm, grinning.</context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're him, aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No response from Malcolm. The guy leans in even closer. MAN (cont'd) Roooooarr.</context>
      <utterance>The guy. The scientist. I saw you on TV.  I believed you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets up and moves to another seat on the car, away from the Curious Man. As he sits down, he notices two other COMMUTERS across from him are staring at him. He looks at them. They looks away. He pulls the collar of his coat up tight around him. Nowhere to hide.</context>
      <utterance>I was misquoted. I was merely speculating on the evolutionary scenario of a Lost World. I never said I was in any such place.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MALCOLM stands in the foyer of an expensively decorated Park Avenue apartment.</context>
      <utterance>Whom shall I tell Mr. Hammond is calling?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A door opens and a little dog comes YAPPING out of the back. It bounds straight at Malcolm, GROWLING, jaws SNAPPING. It lunges -- -- and Malcolm BATS it away with one swift swing of his cane. The dog rolls across the floor and slinks away, WHINING. The Butler looks at Malcolm disapprovingly.</context>
      <utterance>Ian Malcolm</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BUTLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not an animal lover?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not really.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HAMMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>How's the leg?</context>
      <utterance>Ian! Don't linger in the doorway like an ingenue, come in, come in! Malcolm steps further into the room. HAMMOND  It's good to see you. It really is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Resentful.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When you have a lot of time to think, it's funny who you remember. It's the people who challenged you. It is the quality of our opponents that gives our accomplishments meaning. I never told you how sorry I was about what happened after we returned.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HAMMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were right -- and I was wrong. There! Did you ever think you'd hear me say that? Spectacularly wrong. Instead of observing those animals, I tried to control them. I squandered an opportunity and we still know next to nothing about their lives. Not their lives as man would have them, behind electric fences, but in the wild. Behavior in their natural habitat, the impossible dream of any paleontologist. I could have had it, but I let it slip away.  Thank God for Site B.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Malcolm just looks at him for a long moment.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>HAMMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hatchery, in particular? You know my initial yields had to be low, far less than one percent, that's a thousand embryos for every single live birth. Genetic engineering on that scale implies a giant operation, not the spotless little laboratory I showed you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isla Nublar was just a showroom, Ian, something for the tourists, Site B was the factory floor. We built it first, on Isla Sorna, eight-some miles from Nublar.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, no, no, no, no . . .</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After the accident at the park, a hurricane wiped out our facility on Site B. We had to evacuate and leave the animals to fend for themselves. And they did. For four years I've fought to keep them safe from human meddling, now I want you to go there and document them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you out of your mind? I still have nightmares, my reputation's a joke, my leg is shot -- you think I need more of that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It would be the most extraordinary living fossil record the world has ever seen.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hammonnd picks up a thick file folder from the night table near to him and open it on his lap. Inside, there are memos, charts, maps and photographs.</context>
      <utterance>So what?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been putting this together for over a year.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMOND</speaker>
      <mode>MORE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have personal suggestions for your entire team, phone numbers, contact people. They won't believe you about what they're going to see, so don't bother trying to convince them. Just use my checkbook to get them there. I'll fund your expedition through my personal accounts, as such money and equipment as you need, but only if you leave immediately. If we hesitate, all will be lost.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John . . .</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Malcolm just shakes his head, flipping through the file sadly.</context>
      <utterance>You'll need an animal behaviorist, someone with unimpeachable credentials. I believe you already know Sarah Harding. She's got theories about parenting and nurturing among hunter/scavengers I bet she'd be dying to prove on a scale like this. If you convince her to go, it'll be a major coup. When she publishes, the scientific community must take it seriously.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Malcolm gently closes the file and pushes it back to Hammond.</context>
      <utterance>Your documentation, you should use forensic photographic methods, Hasselbladt still cameras, high definition video. When the trick photography analysts take your evidence apart, make it impossible for them to say there was enhancement or computer graphic imaging. Oh, this is very important -- avoid the island interior at all costs. Stick to the outer rim. Everything you need to know can be found there. Vindication lies on the outer rim.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not going, John.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ian, you are my last chance to give something of real value to the world. I can't walk so far and leave no footprints; die and leave nothing with my name on it. I will not be known only for my failures. And you will not allow yourself to go down in history as a lunatic. You're too smart. You'e too proud. Dr. Malcolm. Please. This is a chance at redemption. For both of us. There's no time to equivocate, we must seize it now, before -- He stops, staring over Malcom's shoulder. Malcom turns. PETER LUDLOW, still in his overcoat, is standing in the doorway to the bedroom. He looks back and forth from Hammond to Malcolm suspiciously.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Malcolm doesn't answer. He seems to know Ludlow, and dislikes him. LUDLOW (cont'd) Did I interrupt something? Malcolm turns back to Hammond.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Uncle John. Dr. Malcolm.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Find someone else.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, you two were just, uh, telling old campfire stories, were you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do me a favor. Don't pretend for a second that you and I don't know the truth. You can convince Time magazine and the Skeptical Inquirer of whatever you want, but I was there.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You signed a non-disclosure agreement before you went to the island that expressly forbade you from discussing anything you saw. You violated that agreement.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You cost me my livelihood. That on which I relied to support my children.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If your university felt you were causing it embarrassment by selling wild stories to Hard Copy, I hardly see how I am to--</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't tell anything, I told the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You version of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are no versions of the truth! This isn't a corporate maneuver, it's my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We made a generous compensatory offer for your injuries.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was a payoff and an insult. InGen never--</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Malcolm, and I will jealously defend its interests. People will know what I want them to know when I want them to know it. Ludlow tosses something to Malcolm, hard. It sails across the foyer, upright, and Malcolm reaches out and catches it with one hand. It's his cane. LUDLOW (cont'd) Don't forget that. Malcolm stares at him for a long moment. Finally, he turns and walks away. But he does not out of the apartment. Instead, he walks directly past Ludlow, crosses the living room, and steps back into Hammond's bedroom, closing the door behind him with a determined CLICK.</context>
      <utterance>InGen is my livelihood, Dr.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns around. AJAY (AH-jay) SIDHU, a wiry East Indian in his late forties, is standing behind him, caught trying to sneak up.</context>
      <utterance>Ajay?</utterance>
   <speaker>AJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That cheap aftershave I send you every Christmas, you actually wear it. I'm touched. Sit down, sit down, what brings you to Mombassa?</utterance>
   <speaker>AJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You. Tell me, Roland, when was the last time you answered your phone?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind them, the group of TOURISTS, all men, laughs loudly. One of them, the MOST OBNOXIOUS TOURISTS, berates the WAITRESS.</context>
      <utterance>Last time I plugged it in, I suppose. Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>AJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got a call from a gentleman who's going to Costa Rica, or thereabouts. If he's to be believed, it's a most, uh, unique expedition. And very well-funded.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Most Obnoxious Tourist bellows for the Waitress. His buddies LAUGHS. Roland throws a glance, annoyed.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm a very well-funded old son of a bitch. You go.</utterance>
   <speaker>AJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But alone? We always had great success together, you and I.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a little bit too much, I think.</utterance>
   <speaker>AJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Waitress comes to the Tourists' table and the Most Obnoxious Tourist actually paws her ass. Roland is out of his chair in a second. ROLAND (cont'd) (to Ajay) Excuse me. Romand walks over to the Tourists' table, says something to the Waitress in the local dialect, and she walks away, behind him. He stares down at the Most Obnoxious Tourist. ROLAND (cont'd) You, sir -- are no gentleman.</context>
      <utterance>A true hunter doesn't mind if the animal wins. If it escapes. But there weren't enough escapes from you and me, Ajay. I've decided to spend a bit less time in the company of death. Maybe I just feel too close to it my--</utterance>
   <speaker>TOURIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that supposed to be an insult?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Tourist looks at his Buddies and laughs.</context>
      <utterance>I can think of none greater.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOURIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buzz off, you silly old bastard.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do I have to do to pick a fight with you, bring your mother into it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOURIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding? I could take you with one arm tied down.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. We were saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>AJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You broke that idiot's jaw for no reason other than your boredom. Tell the truth, Roland. Aren't you even interested in knowing this expedition's quarry?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ajay just smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Ajay. Go on up to my ranch, take a look around the trophy room, and tell me what kind of quarry you think could possibly be of any interest to me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah is thirty, with a compact, athletic body built for the outdoors. She loos through the goggles again, sweeping ahead of the hyenas to their prey. It's a herd of African buffalo, standing belly-deep in the grass, agitated, bellowing and stamping their feet. Sarah turns to MAKENA, her African assistant. SARAH (cont'd) They'll try to take down a calf. Come on.</context>
      <utterance>Hyenas. Ace Face is the striped snout.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAKENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah scurries up and over a rock face. Makena follows. Closer now, they watch as the hyenas rush the herd, running through it, trying to break it up. MAKENA (cont'd) You know, we could see everything from up on the edge of that cliff.</context>
      <utterance>Closer?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAKENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But the view would --</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(into a pocket recorder) F1 headed sough, F2 and F5 flanking, twenty yards. F3 center. F6 circling wide east. Can't see F7. While she talks, breathless, fascinated by the drama before her, Sarah continues to creep closer and closer to the action. Makena follows, with growing unease.</context>
      <utterance>No cliffs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAKENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sarah.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's practically on top of the animals now.</context>
      <utterance>F8 circling north. F1 straight through, disrupting. Herd moving, stamping. There's F7. Straight through. F8 angling through from the north.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAKENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Makena has a hold of Sarah's sweatshirt and is tugging her back, at least trying to slow down her progress as Sarah, wide-eyed with fascination, creeps even closer. Suddenly there is a tremendous BELLOWING and the grass right in front of them rips apart, trampled under the feet of the hyenas as they cluster around a fallen buffalo calf. They yelp and jump, their muzzles bloody. The adults move aside, making room as the hyena pups come forward, squealing to get at the kill. Sarah's eyes shine with excitement and she moves even closer, whispering into the tape recorder.</context>
      <utterance>Dr. Harding.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah stops in mid-sentence, unsure if she heard what she thought she heard. It rings again, the unmistakable CHIRPING of a cellular phone. Sarah and Makena both move at once, pawing at a backpack. SARAH (cont'd) (a frantic whisper) I thought you turned it off! Two hyenas look inquisitively in the direction of the phone. Sarah comes up with it and jabs at a button in irritation. SARAH (cont'd) Yes?! Someone speaks on the other end. Sarah rolls her eyes. SARAH (cont'd) Ian. This better be important. Sarah doesn't say anything for a long moment, just listens as the voice on the other end talks. And talks. SARAH (cont'd) When?</context>
      <utterance>Brooding behavior in evidence at the kill site, pups are ushered forward and adults help them eat, pulling flesh away from the carcass and-- A telephone rings.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind them, the SPARKS of a acetylene torch fly as WORKMEN make modifications on several vehicles, including a dark-green Mercedes Benz AAV (all-activity vehicle). The hood of the AAV is up and the V-6 engine has been pulled out; a new, smaller engine is lowered in its place. To one side are two long trailers, connected by an accordion-like passageway, like on a subway car, allowing one to be towed behind the other.</context>
      <utterance>We leave in twenty-four hours. Five member team.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>EDDIE CARR, fortyish, is barking out orders to the Workmen.</context>
      <utterance>Eddie Carr's handling all our equipment and he'll be there to maintain it. He's designing special field trailers now, top of the line mobile research units.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, look at the plans, Henry, you can't place that strut laterally, it has to be crosswise, LOOK AT THE</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>WORKMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eddie bends down to inspect the cage, which is rectangular, constructed of inch-thick titanium-alloy bars. Malcolm hangs up the phone and walks up, joining him.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Eddie! Specs say it can't deform at 12,000 PSI, we had to test it</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any damage?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Minimal.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Minimal" is too much. It has to be light, it has to be strong --</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>God save me from academics.</context>
      <utterance>Light and strong, light and strong, sure, why not, it's only impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are an academic.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Former academic. Now I actually make things. I don't just talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I'm all talk, Eddie?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't matter what I think.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind them, someone CLEARS THEIR THROAT. Eddie and Malcolm turn around. KELLY MALCOLM, an African-American girl around twelve years old, stands in the doorway to the garage, a duffel bag slung over one shoulder. She looks at Malcolm and breaks into a wide grin.</context>
      <utterance>Is there anything we've forgotten? Anything at all?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She drops the bag on the floor, and wraps her arms around him in a warm embrace. He responds stiffly.</context>
      <utterance>Kelly! What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vacation. I'm all yours. You didn't forget, did you? She pulls back and looks at him. KELLY  Did you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Karen is expecting you in half an hour. You only have to stay with her one night, she'll put you on a bus in the morning and your mother will be at the station when you get there.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't even know this woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I do, and she's fantastic. She'll take you to the museum, maybe to a movie if you play your cards right. You're going to have a fantastic time.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop saying fantastic. Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't tell you. But I'll be back within a week.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My vacation is over in a week.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I promise.</context>
      <utterance>I'll make it up to you this summer.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm your daughter all the time, you know. Not just when it's convenient.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very hurtful. Your mother tell you to say that?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the construction floor, EDDIE calls out. EDDIE (o.s.) Dr. Malcolm! Malcolm looks at her, trying to make peace. Quickly.</context>
      <utterance>No, Dad. I have thoughts of my own once in a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that kid still bothering you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which one?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, at the bus stop. With the hair?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was about a year ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Richard talked to his parents.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That Richard. EDDIE  Ian, come here a minute!</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could come with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out of the question. You'd miss the gymnastics trials. You've been training for that for a year.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care about the trials, I want to be with you. I could be your research assistant, like I was in Austin.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is nothing like Austin. Forget about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her, hurt. Eddie calls out a third time, impatient now. Grateful for the escape, Malcolm gets up and heads for the door. He pauses guiltily.</context>
      <utterance>You like to have kids, you just don't want to be with them, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaves.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not like you wan me to be. I've what I can be.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JUTTISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Couldn't -- we just -- airlift -- into the -- island?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Harding insisted we go by sea! Helicopters are too disruptive. These aren't piles of bones you'll be studying this time, Dr. Juttson, they live, they breathe, and they react! Juttson looks at him skeptically -- -- and throws up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's your story, Nick?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Do a lot of work for Greenpeace.</context>
      <utterance>I was a cameraman for Nightline for six years, been freelance since '91.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That must be interesting. What drew you there?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Women. 'Bout eighty percent female in Greenpeace.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick grins and shuts it off.</context>
      <utterance>Very noble of you.  You don't think you're bringing that thing onto the island, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I wouldn't want to spook the woolly mammoths.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think this is all a joke?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, please. How am I supposed to keep a straight face when --  -- Johnny Cash here tells me I'm going to Skull Island?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ian's a very good friend of mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He doesn't need a friend, he needs a shrink.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But her face says even she has her doubts.</context>
      <utterance>I believe in him.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, there's only one reason any of us are here. His check cleared.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boat's CAPTAIN, a Costa Rican, points ahead and SHOUTS to them.</context>
      <utterance>Drop the cynical pose. You can't pull it off while playing Donkey Kong.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all turn and look out over the bow. Up ahead, shear, reddish-gray cliffs of volcanic rock rise dramatically out of the fog-heavy ocean. CAPTAIN (cont'd) Isla Sorna! The boat ROARS ahead, plowing into a heavy wreath of fog. The mist swirls and encircles it.</context>
      <utterance>There it is!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be back in three days, but keep the satellite phone on and your radio tuned to the frequency I specified in case we need you sooner.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the distance, they hear the faint, strange ROAR of a very large animal. The Captain looks at Malcolm, eyes wide. CAPTAIN (cont'd) -- safe.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. I've lived around here all my life, these islands are completely --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>subsonic Fluger impact-delivery dart. He cracks open the cartridge bank, revealing a row of plastic containers filled with straw-colored liquid. Each is tipped with a three inch needle and carries a bright yellow warning tag -- "EXTREME DANGER! LETHAL TOXICITY!" EDDIE (cont'd) I loaded the enhanced venom of Conus purpurascens, the South Sea cone shell. Most powerful neurotoxin in the world. Acts within a two-thousandth of a second. Faster than the nerve-conduction velocity. The animal's down before it feels the prick of the dart. From their right, the shaking trees seen closer now. By walking down the stream bed, the humans are tracking right along with the animals as they move in the foliage.</context>
      <utterance>Lindstradt air rifle. Fires a</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there an antidote?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ahead of them, thick foliage blocks the path of the dried up stream bed to the height of about fifteen feet. But around them, the CRASHING sounds get louder and closer, the swaying trees shiver right beside them. Eddie raises the rifle in defense as the trees right at the edge of the stream bed sway and part. Above the foliage, they see the sudden movement -- -- of a row of STEGOSAUR fins. The spade-shaped fins run along a ridge down the middle of the animal's back, about three feet tall each. The group freezes, amazed, and as the stegosaur continues on, they get a good look at it through a break in the foliage. It's a large dinosaur with a small head, a thick neck, and a huge lumbering body. A double row of plates runs along the crest of its back, and it has a dragging trail with long spikes in it. The gum drops out of Nick's mouth, FLOPS onto his shirt, and sticks there.</context>
      <utterance>Like if you shoot yourself in the foot? Wouldn't matter. You'd be dead before you realized you'd accidentally pulled the trigger.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh --</utterance>
   <speaker>JUTTSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- my --</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- God!</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A second stegosaur, a baby about a quarter the size of the first animal, breaks through the foliage, following the adult. While the group is reaching to that, the earth vibrates and a third stego, by far the biggest of the three, walks out of the foliage right behind them, crossing within ten feet. Apparently unconcerned about these little creatures in their environment, the stegos continue on across the stream bed. Sarah raises a still camera and shoots pictures. Her shutter is muted, so that a muffled CLICK is all that's audible. Juttson raises a pocket recorder to his lips and whispers into it breathlessly.</context>
      <utterance>It's beautiful!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUTTSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His breathy words turn into almost helpless laughter, of all things, as he can't contain his astonishment. Eddie covers his mouth, trying to keep him quiet.</context>
      <utterance>Stegosaurus, family Stegosauridae, infraorder Stegosauria, suborder Thyreophora. Length, adult male, estimate twenty-five to thirty feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was a pair bond! A family group, even, long after that infant was nestbound!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUTTSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick turns to Malcolm, eyes like saucers, and makes a futile, wordless, boy-was-I-wrong-on-this-one gesture. Malcolm smiles, leans over, and TAPS softly on Nick's video camera. Nick raises it to his shoulder and flicks it on as the group continues on into the bush after the animals.</context>
      <utterance>I want to see the nesting ground!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gestures and Juttson peers through a pair of field glasses.</context>
      <utterance>Lone nest -- not colonial. I don't see an egg clutch...</utterance>
   <speaker>JUTTSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The empty shells are crushed and trampled. The young stay in the birth environment, that's conclusive!</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sees an opportunity. As the baby heads back to its parents, Sarah scoots right along with it, moving behind it, using its body as a shield to block her from the view of the other two. Nick and Eddie's faces whiten in alarm. Nick reaches out to stop her, but he barely gets hold of the sole of her boot before she pulls away from him and duckwalks out into the clearing.</context>
      <utterance>Not without a shot of the nest.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BACK AT THE HILL,</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>the others can only watch her, aghast.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's gutty.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's nuts.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ian, you're not insane! I'm so glad!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUTTSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Malcolm -- the world -- owes you an apology.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No more smoking. We leave no scent of any kind. No hair tonics, no cologne, seal all our food in plastic bags. We will observe and document, but we will not interact.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick ejects the used videotape from his camera and pulls out a sharpie, to label it.</context>
      <utterance>That's a scientific impossibility, you know. Heisenberg uncertainty principle. Whatever you study, you also change.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What should I call this? "Jurassic Pork?" Eddie, next to him, laughs.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And let's forget about the high hide. We can't do this kind of work up in a tower, we need to be out in the field, as close to the animals as possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUTTSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not surprised stegosaur lived in a family group, but there's never been anything in the fossil record to prove the carnivores did.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why wouldn't they? Look at hyenas, jackals, nearly all species of predator birds --</utterance>
   <speaker>JUTTSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That doesn't say a thing about T-rex, they could have been rogues. Robert Burke certainly thinks they were.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Is there any --</context>
      <utterance>We've got to see one to find out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, my God.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- way we could safely --</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes off, running as fast as he can, down the trail, toward base camp. They look ahead, in the direction Nick is running. A plume of black smoke is rising up over the trees.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fire!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick grabs a jug of water, but Sarah steps in.</context>
      <utterance>A campfire?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start to kick and rake dirt onto the fire with their hands and feet. Eddie and Dr. Juttson jump in and help out.</context>
      <utterance>No! Water mixes the smoke billow, use dirt!</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Malcolm turns toward the source of the voice. KELLY stands in the doorway of the trailer, sheepish. KELLY (cont'd) I wanted it ready when you got back. The whole group stares, stunned, none more so than Malcolm himself.</context>
      <utterance>Who the hell started a campfire?! VOICE  It was just to make lunch.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh ... man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know you were putting yourself in a potentially dangerous situation, but you didn't bother to find out how dangerous before you leapt in. You don't have the faintest idea what's going on on this island!</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want to do, Ian, lock her up for curiosity? Where do you think she gets it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUTTSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have chromium tapes? The others fog in high-</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-humidity, I know.  Highest lead density on the market.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've got a lot of heavy marching ahead of us. I'm not carrying anybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can keep up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going home. I'm sending a radio call for the boats. We'll all go down to the lagoon and wait for them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lighten up, Ian, you sound like a high school vice-principal.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm her father.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick leans over and whispers to Eddie, gesturing to Malcolm and Kelly.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, now.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you see any family resemblance here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's too dangerous.</context>
      <utterance>You can't stay, Kelly, that's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it's so dangerous, why'd you bring any of us?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're wrong, Dad. I do know what's going on on this island.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How could you possibly?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her, touched. Nick mutters to Eddie again.</context>
      <utterance>Because you said so. Maybe nobody else believed you, but I always did.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The kid scores with cheap sentiment.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A low sound has been rising while she speaks, and now it comes BOOMING over the jungle around them, a THUNDEROUS racket that shakes the very ground beneath them. Suddenly, three C-130 military cargo planes THUNDER overhead and ROAR toward the island interior, flying very low. The planes are enormous, fat-assed creatures, their rear cargo doors hanging open.</context>
      <utterance>Ian, if we recall the boat now, we've made two invasive landings in one day. That'll have to go in any paper I write, and it will leave room for people to say our findings were contaminated. You know the academic world as well as I do, once they smell blood in the water, you're dead. Our presence has got to be one hundred percent antiseptic. That means if we bend a blade of grass, we bend it right back the way it-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>UP ON THE RIDGE,</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick looks at Sarah.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were saying something about antiseptic?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burke has a detailed set of satellite recon photographs that he spreads out on the hood of a jeep.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome to your dream come true, Dr. Burke.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Right -- here.</context>
      <utterance>I believe the large herbivores forage in open plains, like bison, which would explain the great variety of heat dots we're reading in the flatlands around this waterhole.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burke flips open a manifest that he will carry with him at all times. Inside, there are dozens of sketches of various kinds underneath. As each vehicle ROARS out of the equipment container, Burke slips a waterproof eight by ten card with an icon of the various dinosaurs on the island into a slot in the dashboard.</context>
      <utterance>Then that's where we're going.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the procession goes on, Ludlow turns to DIETER STARK, the man we saw welding earlier.</context>
      <utterance>Hadrosaurus! Carinthosaurus! Maiasaurus!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dieter nods and turns to some of the HUNTERS, who number about twenty in all, that are working nearby. But someone steps in front of Dieter, cutting him off. It's ROLAND TEMBO, the hunter from the bar in Mombassa.</context>
      <utterance>This is as good a place as any for base camp. First priority is the laser barriers, I want them all up and running in thirty minutes. Half an hour, understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cancel that, Dieter.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roland points to a stream running nearby.</context>
      <utterance>What? Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carnivores hunt near stream beds. Do you want to set up base camp or an all-you-can-eat people bar?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You heard his, Dieter. Find a new spot. And remember, we're after herbivores only -- no unnecessary risks. Dieter SIGHS and goes to work. Roland puts an arm around Ludlow and pulls him aside.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peter, if you want me to run your little camping trip, there are two conditions. First -- I'm in charge, and when I'm not around, Dieter is. Your job is to sign the checks, tell us we're doing a good job, and open your case of scotch when we have a good day. Second condition -- my fee. You can keep it. All I want in exchange for my services is the right to hunt one of the tyrannosaurs. A male. Buck only. Why and how are my business. If you don't like either of those conditions, you're on your own. Go ahead and set up your camp right here, or in a swamp, or in the middle of a rex nest, for all I care. But I've been on too many safaris with rich dentists to listen to any more suicidal ideas. Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good lad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pachycephalosaurus!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carnivore?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh? No! No, herbivore, late Cretaceous. Very unusual plant eater, see that distinctive domed skull? That's nine inches of solid bone.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just get them out of the way, Dieter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dieter gestures to the speedbird to pull ahead, which it does, slowly, toward the animals. The pachys look up, alert, but do not move. Dieter walks toward them.</context>
      <utterance>Dieter. This is a round-up, not a war. Use your powers of persuasion.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, come on, don't have all day!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It matches the pictures.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roland gets up and goes back to his vehicle, ignoring the pachy demolition derby that continues up at the speedbird. Roland opens a case in the back of the jeep, revealing -- -- his gun. It's an antique elephant gun, a double barreled .600 Nitro Express. Nearly a hundred years old, it's still in immaculate condition, its rosewood stock buttery smooth, bisons delicately engraved along its silver breach. The barrels are twenty-four inches long, topped with an ivory bead foresight at the business end. Roland scoops up the gun, breaks the breach, and pulls two rounds of ammunition from his shirt pocket. Four inches long and three-quarters of an inch in diameter, these are the largest full metal jacket cartridges ever made. He slips one into each barrel and heads back into the bush. Roland pauses before he goes, as if noticing the animals trashing the speedbird for the first time.</context>
      <utterance>It certainly does.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do you think you're going?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that he disappears into the foliage. The Driver of the Speedbird drops it into gear and the battered car GROANS forward. As it moves ahead, it reveals DIETER, lying underneath it, ego bruised worse than body.</context>
      <utterance>To collect my fee.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ajay turns. Roland points in the direction in which the footprints lead. ROLAND (cont'd) I'm no tracker, but even I can read this spoor.</context>
      <utterance>Ajay.</utterance>
   <speaker>AJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roland smiles. Ajay sets off in his direction and Roland follows.</context>
      <utterance>Do you wish to go where the animal has been, or where the animal is?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you tell us about these guys, Ian?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I didn't know! I don't have the faintest idea what they're doing here.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ruining everything, that's what they're doing. You could choke on the diesel smoke already!</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly has a pair of binoculars and is studying the vehicles as they move below.</context>
      <utterance>Ian, nothing we observe will be valid if we're trailing along in the wake of an army.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"InGen." What's InGen?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where does it say that?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Malcolm takes the binoculars and stares down there himself.</context>
      <utterance>On the side of that one truck.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUTTSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>InGen is a genetics corporation, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that who we're really working for?! Gene splicers?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! We're an independently funded expedition.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Funded by whom?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John Hammond.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUTTSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But he's the head of InGen!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta be kidding.  You dragged me out of Greenpeace to be a corporate stooge? You couldn't get anybody else?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, what have you done, Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The group moves on ahead, but Malcolm lingers, angry, staring through the binoculars.</context>
      <utterance>We'd better keep moving, or we'll lose them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing to me, John?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ajay nods. The baby tyrannosaur hears the whisper and looks up, cocking its head in curiosity.</context>
      <utterance>It's the rex nest.</utterance>
   <speaker>AJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make a blind here? Wait for the buck to return?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DIETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Wranglers adjust their poles, extending them another three feet, which allows them to stay further from the reeling, ten foot tall animal. DIETER (cont'd) Now! Almost as one, the Wranglers flip their noose over the stunned animal's neck. It thrashes, but the Wranglers hold their poles tightly, surrounding and immobilizing it.</context>
      <utterance>Easy -- easy -- not too close! Full extension!</utterance>
   <speaker>UP ON THE RIDGE,</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick turns away. He can't watch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives the binoculars to Sarah, who moves forward gingerly. MALCOLM (cont'd) You okay?</context>
      <utterance>Ludlow. That's why Hammond was in such a hurry for me to get here. He knew they were coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUTTSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do they want?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They want their money back. To InGen, this island is nothing more than a bed investment.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUTTSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eddie's waiting for us.</context>
      <utterance>We should get back to base camp.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe Peter Ludlow's running all this.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands the binoculars to Malcolm.</context>
      <utterance>He isn't. Check out the guy walking past the fire.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BACK ON THE RIDGE,</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>SARAH  He's the one in charge.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick, who has been quietly fuming next to them, now steps forward.</context>
      <utterance>Well, if that's true -- the man in charge just left camp.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then this is our chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our chance to do what?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rummages through his pack, coming up with various tools. A hunting knife. A bolt cutter. NICK (cont'd) Nobody has to come with me. I've done this before.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know these guys, but I know 'em. I've seen 'em on Japanese whalers, French barges trying to dump barrels of nuclear waste in the North Atlantic. They're all the same. They spray us with water cannon when we try to stop 'em, sink our boats, and then call us crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her, hurt.</context>
      <utterance>Why, Nick. You are a tree-hugger.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There' no reason for name calling.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Juttson, please take Kelly back to camp right away. Leave the other car for us and we'll meet you there in an hour or so.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you guys gonna do?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly what John Hammond wanted us to do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ludlow laughs and shakes his head. He takes a drink and offers Roland one. Roland accepts. Ludlow notices Roland's gun leaning against a tree.</context>
      <utterance>Offering a little incentive.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of gun is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father's .600 Nitro Express. Made in 1904. Karimojo Bell gave it to him after he took down his last elephant. 8700 foot pound striking force.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How close do you have to be?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forty yards. Less, maybe. I assume it'll take a slug in the brain case to bring him down.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roland just looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Why not just use a scope and a poison dart and snipe him from a hill?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ludlow leans down, close to the baby rex, and examines it while it thrashes on its chain. Its mouth has been bound shut with a leather strap.</context>
      <utterance>Or a laser beam from a satellite?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You rally think this'll draw the parent?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I once saw a bull elephant die charging a jeep. All the jeep had done was startle the bull's calves. I saw a lioness carry wounded prey four and a half miles, all the way back to its den, just to teach its cubs how to finish off a kill.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Killing lessons? Heartwarming.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rex won't be any different. It'll come.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>growth inhibitors...</context>
      <utterance>You're kidding yourself. An adult T-rex cares about one thing -- filling its own belly. It acts the way people wish they could, that's why everyone's fascinated by it. If people had the chance to see one dinosaur and one only, ninety-nine percent would -- He stops, an idea on his face. LUDLOW  Wait. Why not? Sedatives...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CRACK! The tyrannosaur, even with its jaws clamped shut, lunges at Ludlow's face, head-butting him right across the bridge of the nose. Ludlow staggers back, WAITING in pain, clutching his bleeding face. Roland laughs. Ludlow, like an enraged child, snatches up Roland's gun and brings the butt down viciously on the rex's leg. The bone breaks with a dry SNAP and the animal HOWLS in pain. Roland lunges and throws Ludlow to the ground, but the damage is done.</context>
      <utterance>I hadn't planned on bringing carnivores back because of the liability risk, but I only thought of adults, it never occurred to me --  You are a billion dollar idea, my little f-</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As his pain eases, Ludlow feels a bit foolish, but he attempts to cover.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell you do that for?!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Had to. To keep him still for the trip.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've broken its leg!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets up, brushes himself off, and heads back to the camp, trying to salvage his dignity. Roland watches him go.</context>
      <utterance>We've got to transport it seven thousand miles. Would you prefer it bit off the leg of a crew member?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What in Christ's name is going on?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up the sniped padlock from one of the animal cages. NICK (cont'd) We're not alone on this island.</context>
      <utterance>Isn't it obvious?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick, thank God, we didn't know if -- Malcolm opens the rear door.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a piercing SHRIEK, the BABY TYRANNOSAUR, now in the back of the AAV, flings itself at the open doorway, jaws SNAPPING just short of Malcolm's nose.</context>
      <utterance>Wait, don't ---</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do we have anyone up there?</utterance>
   <speaker>BACK UP ON THE RIDGE,</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Malcolm is confronting Nick.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It has a broken leg!</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So do it a favor and put it out of its misery!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs around and leaps in the driver's seat. Sarah slips into the passenger seat, quickly, leaving Malcolm no choice but the rear.</context>
      <utterance>No! Get in the car before they hear us!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JUTTSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all turn and look, but Eddie furrows his brow, watching them pull the wounded animal from the back seat.</context>
      <utterance>There they are!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is that they have with them?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah turns away from a drawer of medical supplies, holding a small syringe. Her shirt is streaked with blood from the baby's injured leg.</context>
      <utterance>This is exceedingly unwise.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick tightens his grip on the animal and Sarah makes an injection into its thigh, over its loudly voiced objections.</context>
      <utterance>Too late to worry about that! Hold him together, Nick!</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah picks up a small ultrasound transducer and runs it over the animal's leg. A green and white skeletal image appears on a monitor next to the table.</context>
      <utterance>Just do whatever you have to do and get it out of here as quickly as possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They peer closely at the monitor.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, there's the metatarsals -- tibia, fibula -- there it is! See it? That's a fracture, just above the epiphysis.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That little black line?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That little black line means death for this infant. The fibula won't heal straight, so the ankle joint can't pivot when he stands on his hind feet. The baby won't be able to run, and probably can't even walk. It'll be crippled, and a predator will pick it off before it gets more than a few weeks old.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you set up?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It has to be temporary, something that'll break apart and fall off as the animal grows...</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The tyrannosaur, still in pain, SHRIEKS again.</context>
      <utterance>Think fast, Sarah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are they doing? Why don't they hurry?!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the trailer, the baby lets out a long, plaintive</context>
      <utterance>Give me the radio.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give it more morphine!</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes fall on Nick. She holds out her hand, urgently. SARAH (cont'd) Spit! He spits his bubblegum into the palm of her hand. The baby rex CRIES OUT again.</context>
      <utterance>We'll kill it with too much, we'll put it into respiratory arrest! I'm almost done. Damn it, I need another adhesive, something pliable I can --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Juttson puts an arm around Kelly, instinctively pulling her closer to him. Eddie WHISPERS urgently into the walkie-talkie.</context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sarah, come in!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUTTSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's moving. Fast.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold it down, Nick!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Malcolm moves to answer the radio, but Sarah SHOUTS to him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm trying! EDDIE   Is anybody there?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Forsaking the radio, Malcolm moves to the medicine drawer and comes up with what she wants. Working fast, he draws twenty cc's of the pink liquid. EDDIE (o.s.) (still from the radio, now desperate)</context>
      <utterance>Ian, get the bottle of amoxicillin and fill a syringe! Quick injection of antibiotics and I can get it out of here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do they want?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think they want?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's impossible, they can't have the sensory equipment to track it all the way here!</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Current evidence seems to be to the contrary, wouldn't you say?! GIVE IT</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Malcolm reaches for the door handle.</context>
      <utterance>Ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He dives down on the floor under them, pointing the video camera up at the door, getting the best shot. Malcolm takes a breath, turns the knob, and throws open the door. Outside, the enormous rex heads pause for a moment, staring, surprised. Although terrified, Sarah actually starts to sing.</context>
      <utterance>Wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As free as the grass grows --</context>
      <utterance>Born free, as free as the wind blows.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you insane?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The baby, excited, wriggles free of them and lands on the ground outside. Not wasting a second, Malcolm SLAMS the door shut. The three of them freeze, not daring to breath. Outside, they can hear the SNUFFLING and COOING of the animals as they inspect their young -- -- and then the soft THUD of their footsteps, growing fainter as they move away. From the wall, EDDIE'S VOICE comes over the radio, relieved.</context>
      <utterance>I swear to God, it works with lions sometimes! There we are -- your baby is free --</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're going back into the jungle.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes the radio, her voice shaky.</context>
      <utterance>Thank God. Thank God. MALCOLM'S VOICE comes over the radio. MALCOLM  Kelly? Are you all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh huh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Malcolm slump against the wall of the trailer. SARAH and NICK sit on the floor leaning against the opposite wall, completely drained. Sarah pulls out her pocket recorder and speaks shakily into it.</context>
      <utterance>Wait there. I'll come up in a minute. Don't move, understand? KELLY  I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They laugh weakly.</context>
      <utterance>Note to Dr. Juttson -- Tyrannosaurus rex does nurture its young.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Immediately:</context>
      <utterance>There's, uh -- there's an unwritten rule when a news crew is in a war zone. You stop the van every two miles and decide whether or not to go on. Whether or not you feel lucky. One "no" from anybody in the group and you turn around right there, no question asked, nobody embarrassed.  Well? Do we go on?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all laugh.</context>
      <utterance>No way.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. I'm satisfied with the evidence we have right now. I feel vindicated. John Hammond will too.  Do you have enough to publish?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They will come after me. But I can collect some stool samples, for DNA with that, Nick's tapes, and the rest of you to back me up, it should stand when we get back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A low RATTLE sneaks into the trailer. Malcolm, Sarah, and Nick takes a step forward from the walls, looking around. The RATTLE gets louder, the trailer shakes and vibrates, everything in it starts to BANG against the walls -- -- and something huge SMASHES into the side of the trailer. They're all thrown against the far wall, there is an earsplitting CRACK of electricity, the entire trailer rocks and sparks a brilliant blue, and then everything goes black. The satellite phone flies out of Malcolm's hands and SMACKS against the wall. It lands on the floor, its number pad still glowing green. Nick crawls over and looks out one of the windows. Outside, the flank of one of the tyrannosaurs wipes past the window, revealing the second tyrannosaur, charging straight at the trailer!</context>
      <utterance>What the hell is he sorry f-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Malcolm, frantic, crawls up to a window to get a look outside. He looks down and sees a T-rex footprint in the earth outside as they move past it. He cranks his head to get a look at the direction in which they are being pushed. His eyes widen at something he sees outside the window.</context>
      <utterance>They're pushing us!</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, God.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sure enough, out the back window, we see a few more feet of muddy earth, and then nothing but inky black. The three of them look at each other for a moment -- -- and then crawl like hell toward the other end of the trailer. The opposite end reaches the edge of the cliff and starts up to tip ever-so-slightly downward. They reach the accordion-like connector and Malcolm crawls into it.</context>
      <utterance>They're pushing us over the cliff.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The rope falls through the center of the trailer, its end dangling all the way out the smashed rear window. But the trailer SHUDDERS, starting to move again.</context>
      <utterance>Catch!</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're sliding!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Climbs up if you can!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at the other two. They glance around, then drop their heads. Sarah hears a SOUND in the distance.</context>
      <utterance>Eddie?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the edge of the jungle, a cris-cross of flashlight beams moves toward them. But rather than the three or four that would signify their own group, there are nearly twenty of them. The HUNTERS, PETER LUDLOW is in the lead, ROLAND and AJAY with him. DIETER is there too, shepherding KELLY and DR. JUTTSON along in front of him. Malcolm sees Kelly, they call out to each other, and race together. Malcolm falls to his knees and hugs her as tightly as he possibly can.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, God. Now what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you all right?! Anything broken?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm fine, I'm fine, I was scared, I thought you, are you okay?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roland looks around, at the mess that was their base camp.</context>
      <utterance>I'm fine... I'm fine...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what you think.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trespassing, sabotage -- you could go to jail just for being here, did you know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DR. JUTTSON has encountered DR. BURKE.</context>
      <utterance>Don't start a legal argument with me, this island isn't your property, and neither are these animals!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUTTSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here, Burke? There's no TV cameras, what's the point?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dieter continues to get in Nick's face.</context>
      <utterance>Dr. Juttson, you exist outside the classroom. I am amazed.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you looking for a problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUTTSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone, keep your voices down!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Back off, Dieter.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUTTSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to me, by moving the baby rex into our camp, we changed the adults' perceived territory!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Their what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, God.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUTTSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why they persisted in destroying the trailers, they now feel they have to defend this entire area! We're not safe here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks to you people.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, we came here to observe, you came here to strip-mine the place! It's a looter mentality, all you care about is what you can take.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points at Malcolm, who is still off to the side, sitting in stunned silence. Malcolm looks up and nods, slowly. The grimness of their situation sinks in. ROLAND (cont'd) We are stuck here, ladies and gentlemen. And we're stuck together.</context>
      <utterance>None of that matters. Our communications equipment's been destroyed. If your radio and satellite phone were in those trailers that went off the cliff, and I'm guessing by the look on his face --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we can't stay in the rex's territory, we have to move tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>photographs of the island, which are still mostly legible.</context>
      <utterance>Move where? Our boat's not coming for two days, your airlift is waiting for an order you have no way to send -- Ludlow refers to the charred and trampled satellite</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a communication center, here, in the old worker village. Hammond put in some kind of renewable power source replenishing. It may still work. If we could get there, we could send a radio call for the airlift.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How far is the village?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said if we could get there.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, how far is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A day's walk, maybe more. That's not the problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Malcolm shepherds Kelly away from the conversation and mutters something to her quietly in the background.</context>
      <utterance>The velociraptors. Malcolm looks up sharply. LUDLOW  Our infrareds show their nesting sites are concentrated in the island interior. That's why we planned on keeping to the outer rim.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are velociraptors?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUTTSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dieter brandishes his weapon.</context>
      <utterance>Carnivores. Pack hunters. About six feet long, three or four hundred pounds, and very, very fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Malcolm rejoins the conversation, alone. He keeps his voice low.</context>
      <utterance>I think we can handle ourselves against them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I'm quite certain you can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, we have two choices. We can hike back down to the lagoon, where we can sit for two days, in the open, next to a heavily used water source while we're waiting for your boat to arrive, or we can head for the village, where we might find some shelter and we can call for help.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roland looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>We'd never make it past the raptors. Trust me, I have some experience in this matter.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Malcolm just shakes his head, then turns and walks back to Kelly. Roland turns to the others. ROLAND (cont'd) Load up. Let's get this moveable feast underway.</context>
      <utterance>That may be. But you weren't with me at the time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks away as Kelly looks up at him, questioning. ROLAND falls into step with Malcolm and notices his limp.</context>
      <utterance>Damn it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Malcolm looks at him, then looks away without answering. ROLAND (cont'd) Wrong question?</context>
      <utterance>You all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever heard of Gambler's Ruin?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A statistical phenomenon. Says everything in the world goes in streaks. It's real, you see it everywhere -- in weather, in river flooding, in baseball, in blackjack, in stock markets. Once things go bad, they tend to stay bad. Bad things cluster. They go to hell together.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Malcolm glances at Kelly, who has taken a slightly faster pace and is a few steps ahead of them now.</context>
      <utterance>Feeling a bit blue, are we?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just -- flawed. Very deeply flawed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did you come here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So that others would know about this place?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why should they?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because it exists.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll still exit if they go on not knowing, won't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. And people will live in the absence of truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So the truth is more important to you than your life?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roland follows his gaze forward, to Kelly, who's about ten yards ahead now.</context>
      <utterance>I don't care about my life. But if I'd ever thought for a second that she would be in danger --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She yours?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somewhere on this island, there exits the greatest predator that ever lived. And the second greatest predator must take him down.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But why?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You remember that guy, about twenty years ago, I forget his name, but he climbed Everest without any oxygen, came down almost dead. And they asked him, "why did you go up there to die?" And he said "I didn't. I went up there to live."</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's called self-testing. But in your case, it sounds more like self-destruction. A uniquely human characteristic. In fact, human beings destroy things so well that I sometimes think that's our function. Maybe every few sons, some animal comes along that kills off the rest of the world, clears the decks, and lets evolution proceed to his next phase. Maybe death and destruction are our job, maybe we're supposed to destroy ourselves and every other living thing that- Every person on the trail within earshot has stopped and is staring at Malcolm, shaken by his words. Roland grabs Malcolm by the shirt collar and pulls him close, GROWLING in his ear.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Malcolm just blinks. This guy's in charge.</context>
      <utterance>Tell you what. You can see whatever you want to, to me, but you will not spew any more nihilist rants at anyone else in the group. I'm fighting panic, and you push the wrong buttons. Understand?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think -- my dad doesn't think we're going to make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts an arm around her. Kelly looks up at her, grateful. The long march continues.</context>
      <utterance>Your dad is wrong. About a lot more than he knows.</utterance>
   <speaker>UP AT THE FRONT,</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>NICK catches up to ROLAND.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you should call a break.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Another half hour.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roland looks at him, steely, then SHOUTS to the group.</context>
      <utterance>Some of them won't make another half hour. We didn't come this far to start dropping in the middle of the jungle. If you don't call it, I will.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JUTTSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe you're still angry about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, it's very easy to criticize the first person who studies something.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUTTSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's easy to criticize sloppy research and hasty conclusions.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, even if we do get those tapes back, people are going to say it's just another hoax. Ian Malcolm's alien autopsy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe. Maybe not.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't look at her. She sits down beside her. SARAH (cont'd) There's something more important that you should be thinking about instead.</context>
      <utterance>Ian, they will misplace our evidence, shoot holes in our testimony, and say some special effects genius created the animals. The only way people will ever believe that dinosaurs exist is if you dump a T-rex in the middle of times Square.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long ago was this?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roland looks at them, thinking. Finally:</context>
      <utterance>Seven, eight minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and heads back to the front of the column.</context>
      <utterance>Then he's dead. Nobody tells the little girl. Last thing we need is screaming hysterics.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to send someone to look for him!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at each other, appalled, but the column starts to move. Numbed, shocked, but left with no choice, they move on, one by one.</context>
      <utterance>You go if you like, but we're not waiting for you. MOVE IT OUT!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MALCOLM is next to him.</context>
      <utterance>Looks like the worker village is down in there, about a mile and a half northeast from the base of these cliffs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roland looks around at the exhausted MARCHERS.</context>
      <utterance>There must be a game trail, some kind of path that goes down there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then we hit it.</context>
      <utterance>They'll have to rest before we look for it. Eat. Sleep. Two hours.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There you are. Your dad's looking for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah takes off her outer shirt and hangs it over a bar to dry the broad red smear across its front.</context>
      <utterance>I doubt that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, come on. Go talk to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? He likes to be alone. I can stay with you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You hear something?</utterance>
   <speaker>AJAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roland looks at him. This isn't so good. He looks out at the shifting jungle. He notices a thin plume of smoke rising up over the trees just barely outside the edge of camp.</context>
      <utterance>No. I feel something.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, no.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>UP ON TH ROCK FACE,</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Malcolm is frantic.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta get down there!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With an enormous SPLASH, something bursts through the cascading water and crashes into them. Dr. Burke.</context>
      <utterance>Shhhh... shhhh...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls his way up against the far wall, as far away from the water as he can. FOOOOM! Now another shape bursts through the watery curtain. A Tyrannosaur head. Burke gave away the hiding spot. The four SCREAM as the rex's jaws SNAP left and right, searching for them, falling just inches short. They squeeze as far back against the wall as they can get. The rex can't quite get its head all the way through the opening -- -- so it uses its tongue. A long, dark blue shape slithers out of its mouth and touches the humans, trying to wrap around them, to pull them out of the cave. Burke, blind with panic, forces himself even further into the cave, which pushes Kelly further out.</context>
      <utterance>Get out of the way!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many rounds did you find for that weapon?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four, counting the one in the chamber.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't let it out of your hands again.  Can the kid walk?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ask her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can the kid walk?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>While he addresses the group, Roland straps on one of the servo-lights, the shoulder-mounted flashlights that follow your gaze.</context>
      <utterance>I can. I can walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to find a path down into the interior of the island. Load up whatever you think you need, and I mean need. If you can't carry it indefinitely, don't bring it. We'll hit the worker village in a couple hours and be out of here before dawn.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ludlow doesn't ask.</context>
      <utterance>Piss.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're standing in a flat, sandy area lined with boulders at the sides. The flat area stretches fifty yards from side to side and as far as they can see ahead. But that's not what amazes them so. Everywhere, the sand is dotted with dinosaur skeletons. Some are huge, apatosaurs, sixty feet from head to tail tip. Others are smaller, herbivores of many different kinds. The more intact skeletons lie on their sides, their ribcages arcs of pale bone. but just as many have been ripped apart, bits of carcass tossed in every direction.</context>
      <utterance>God help us.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do not feel lucky.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They march on, tiny figures moving among the mountainous skeletons by the light of the full moon. Roland notices one carcass in particular, a recent kill. It's an enormous HADROSAUR with fresh bites taken out of it. He bends down, studying the soft earth around it for footprints.</context>
      <utterance>Keep moving.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roland catches up and looks at Ludlow.</context>
      <utterance>The jungle. It's always ready to return.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's the power and radio setup?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A light rain falls as they start down the street, carefully, silently, Roland and Malcolm with their weapons at the ready. They pass the skeleton of a fallen water tower. An empty gas station, its vine-snarled pumps now useless. The only sound is the low mechanical HUM of the servo-lights as they follow the group's gazes obediently. Every few feet, the group encounters strange, grayish lumps that lies in random places in the middle of the street. Malcolm, curious, stops and taps one of them. It's a rock-hard. Nick looks over his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Operations building. Far end of the street.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lava?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finally, they reach the operation building, at the far end of the town.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The radio rig is inside. It runs directly from the geothermal generator, so power shouldn't be a problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls out his canteen. Ludlow watches as he screws the top off, moves toward the building, and starts splashing the contents on the outside of it. The rest of the group just stares at him.</context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he got in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Piss.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't ask me. The guy's completely out to lunch.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What in God's name would he want with- Roland rejoins them.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drops his pack, swings his gun off his shoulder, and checks the load. Dr. Juttson looks fearful.</context>
      <utterance>Tyrannosaur urine. I don't want anything to do with it, and neither does any other animal on this island. This building is now demarcated as the rex's territory. As long as you stay in that building, you'll all be safe until the helicopter comes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUTTSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After the rex. I saw a fresh kill back in the valley with tyrannosaur tracks all around it. If I'm not back in time, don't wait for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got to be kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Runs against my nature to hole up in a cave and wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think the rex might have the infant with it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ludlow takes off his hat and turns to Nick.</context>
      <utterance>Possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know how to work a radio, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going too?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a slip of paper from the brim of his hat and hands it to Nick. LUDLOW (cont'd) This is the broadcast frequency. ID yourself as "Harvest Leader." You know what to tell 'em.</context>
      <utterance>I lost everything I came after on this trip, but one T-rex in one theme park could single-handedly bail InGen out of Chapter 11.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gentlemen feel you have to do this now?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ludlow double checks the clip on his semi-automatic rifle --</context>
      <utterance>Now's the perfect time. The animal just fed, so it won't stalk us for food. Predators don't hurt when they're not hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- and SMACKS it back into the belly of the gun. NICK (cont'd) Only humans do.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We took to the rock.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In front of Roland, a palm frond sways gently in the night breeze. Roland's eyes widen. He pulls out another pinch of campfire ash and releases it on the wind. This time, the ash blows off, straight away from him.</context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They freeze, terrified. Behind them, the enormous green pebbled boulder -- -- opens an eye. That's no boulder, that's the MALE TYRANNOSAUR, standing rock-solid still, its natural camouflage blending into the surrounding foliage perfectly. Very slowly and almost silently, the rex brings its head all the way around until it is staring directly down at them from about ten feet away. Roland and Ludlow stand frozen, their back to the rex, unaware of its presence. Until it exhales. The soft SNORT of its breath isn't quite audible, but it brushes the hair on the backs of their necks ever so slightly. Their hearts drop into their stomachs. Ludlow speaks, his voice a queasy HISS.</context>
      <utterance>Wind shift.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's... behind... us.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUDLOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I don't move, I can't shoot it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind them, the rex appears satisfied. It starts to swing its massive head around, back toward the jungle. It lifts one great leg and takes a step into the trees. Roland signs and closes his eyes, relieved. But Ludlow seizes the opportunity. He whips his weapon around and drops to one knee. ROLAND (cont'd)</context>
      <utterance>Let it go, Peter. The animal won.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Co-Pilot scans the street below, but it's choked with overturned cars and fallen trees.</context>
      <utterance>There they are!</utterance>
   <speaker>CO-PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No LZ in the street, too much debris!</utterance>
   <speaker>PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Co-Pilot nods and they peel off, swooping over the rest of the village. At the far end of the street, the Co-Pilot brings the searchlight to bear on the large, flat roof of a three story building. The Pilot gives him a thumbs-up.</context>
      <utterance>Check the other buildings!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Happily, the group double-times it down the street, headed for the chopper. Again, those strange rock formations are everywhere. Some seem to be on the sides of buildings, as if they once dripped there and then turned to stone. This time Sarah pauses at one that is dripping over to the side of a car like solidified lava. Her face falls as a thought occurs to her.</context>
      <utterance>There it is!</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ian. It's guano.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These formations. They're dried --</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A VELOCIRAPTORS jumps onto a fallen tree trunk behind them. They don't see it.</context>
      <utterance>Birdshit?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Unaware of the raptor's presence, they resume their trot toward the helicopter. Behind them, the raptor crouches and SNARLS, but the sound is lost under the WHINE of the helicopter's engines. It springs, covering the distance between them quickly. The animal SLAMS into JUTTSON, the last person in the group, and takes him down. Juttson is thrown forward, into the others, who fall like dominoes. Juttson SCREAMS, his voice an unnatural, high-pitched SQUEAL, as the raptor flips him over and lowers its jaws into him. Sarah looks up, panicked. Her eyes widen at the sight of a SECOND RAPTOR, this one running straight at hr at top speed. She buries her face in the dirt, covering her head with her hands -- -- and the raptor's foot SLAMS into the ground between her legs as it bounds over her and dives onto Juttson, joining the first raptor in the kill. Panicked, the group scatters in all directions. Kelly jumps up and scrambles into the middle of the street, where she hits the dirt and crawls under a fallen shed in the middle of the road. Malcolm rolls over to the space where Kelly was, but she's gone now. He looks around frantically.</context>
      <utterance>Who cares? Let's go!</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah rolls onto her feet and sprints toward the building nearest her. Behind her, a THIRD RAPTOR gives chase, bounding after her with horrifying speed. Sarah runs flat-out, but her speed is nothing compared to the raptor's, and it gains on her rapidly. The walls of a structure of some kind close in around Sarah, and as she leaps across a leather seat and SLAMS a door behind her, we realize she's crawled into the back seat of an abandoned car. But the car door is thin protection against the charging raptor, which SLAMS into the window, head first. The window spinderwebs, but does not yield. The raptor crumples to the ground. Sarah looks up, through a three inch hole in the middle of the web. The raptor leaps back to its feet and plunges its nose into the tiny hole, thrashing, widening it. Sarah SCREAMS and the animal forces its entire head through the hole, SNAPPING its jaws just short of her face. She hurls herself over the seat and into the front as the animal penetrates even further into the car, but its torso will not fit through the window opening. It pulls away. In the front seat, Sarah gets some very bad news. There's no windshield. The raptor springs up onto the hood, its claws CLATTERING on the sheet metal, and tosses its body through the opening -- -- just as Sarah hurls herself out the door. While the raptor struggles to right itself in the front seat, Sarah runs to the nearest building, ducks inside, and SLAMS the heavy wooden door.</context>
      <utterance>Kelly?! KELLY?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Kelly?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They race off, down the street.</context>
      <utterance>She's with Sarah!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't stay in here!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're sure as hell not going back out there"</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's just a shack!</context>
      <utterance>This is single-wall construction!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll hold!</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a CRASH, the wood SPRINTERS around the lock and the door swings open violently. Malcolm is thrown aside, landing hard on the floor. A VELOCIRAPTOR stands HISSING in the doorway. Nick throws his weight against the door. SLAMMING it hard against the raptor. Malcolm rolls over and paws the gun off his back. SLAM! The raptor charges the door again, this time BLASTING it off its hinges, knocking Nick to the floor beneath it. The raptor turns and SNARLS at Malcolm. Malcolm swings the gun around -- -- the raptor lunges at him -- -- Malcolm's finger closes on the trigger -- -- and the raptor lands on top of him. The weight of the animal CRUSHES him into the floor, but the gun barrel now stands between them. The raptor CHOMPS down hard on the barrel, its teeth GRINDING on the metal, and SNAPS its head, to tear it from Malcolm's hands. Malcolm pulls the trigger. The raptor's eyes pop wide as the dart SLAMS into the back of its throat. It makes a GURGLING sound, then convulses violently and rolls off of Malcolm, yanking the gun from his hands as it falls and dies. Nick scrambles out from under the door. Malcolm tries to wrench the gun from the raptor's clenched jaws, but it won't budge.</context>
      <utterance>For sixty seconds, maybe! Look at this!  You could-</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Head for the roof!</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to find Kelly!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think she's with Sarah!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick looks around, desperate. A fallen power pole leans against the building they're standing on, its lines gone slack.</context>
      <utterance>It's too wide!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Malcolm understands. He and Nick throw a shoulder into the pole and give it a mighty push, tipping it over in the other direction. One good hard shove and it falls to the far building, THUDDING against it solidly. Its power lines are not taut, a lifeline from this rooftop to the next. Nick grabs hold and starts to pull himself across the gap, hand over hand. Behind them, the door of the building SPLINTERS and CRASHES open as a raptor throws all its weight into it. Malcolm leaps onto the power line without hesitation and starts pulling himself across. But even with the door wide open, the raptor on the other side hesitates. It SNARLS and backs away, refusing to come out onto the roof.</context>
      <utterance>Help me push this!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Malcolm looks around, at the rooftop. Strange bits of scrap and debris seem to have been arranged there, in an odd, concentric pattern.</context>
      <utterance>It's afraid to come onto the roof!</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something's wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to the roof of the kilm house, in the distance. Malcolm turns, and sees SARAH crawling across the tile. His face turns white.</context>
      <utterance>Look! Sarah!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad!</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs her by the hand and they take off down the street.</context>
      <utterance>Come on!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Kelly?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eyes wide with panic, they both turn and look down at the street below, where they see KELLY and MALCOLM, racing at top speed down the middle of the street --</context>
      <utterance>Where's Ian?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hang on! If I tip it hard, I can cut 'em with the rotors!</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look out the windows, where, indeed, the magnificent animals are merely accompanying them, flying escort as the chopper gains altitude. SARAH (cont'd) They're protecting their nest. That's all. That's all they're doing. Kelly, completely drained, sits between Sarah and Malcolm, each of whom has a protective arm around her. She sags against her father's chest, nothing left. He holds her tight and WHISPERS in her ear.</context>
      <utterance>NO! Don't! They're not attacking!</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Kelly, thank God. Thank God for you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LEX stands on her tiptoes and kisses Malcolm on the cheek. TIM extends a hand and Malcolm shakes it. MALCOLM (cont'd) This is Kelly. My daughter. They nod their hellos.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Lex. Tim.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm glad you came, Dr. Malcolm</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry about your grandfather.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were going to call you, in a few days. Tim and I have been thinking, and we've decided we want people to know about the island. About what we all saw.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We think it's something our grandfather would want us to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Malcolm looks at her for a long moment.</context>
      <utterance>Because it's true.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, Lex. But even if we're the only ones who ever know, it'll still be true. You see, I've decided that if the world found out about what your grandfather created, it wouldn't be around for very long.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But -- it was real. You can't let people go on saying it's not.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly smiles and takes his hand, her slender fingers interlocking with his.</context>
      <utterance>That's the thing about reality. He looks down at Kelly. MALCOLM  Even when people stop believing in it, it doesn't go away.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We sweep low, landing on the roof the helicopter took off from, the nest below now careful rebuilt with straw and scrap, a dozen unblemished eggs in the middle of it.</context>
      <utterance>Do you feel the cold wind blowing on your face? That's real.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A PTERANODON land gently on the nest. Ever so carefully, it positions itself over the eggs, lowers itself to roosting position, and folds its giant wings around its body.</context>
      <utterance>Do you see the four of us, standing here together, alive? That's real.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALCOLM</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The animal raises its head, opens its beak, and SQUAWKS approvingly up at the heavens.</context>
      <utterance>And maybe that's still that matters.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
