<movie id="323" title="Jurassic Park III">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You make sure to get us as close as you can, okay? If it's a good trip, I'll give you a little extra.</utterance>
   <speaker>ENRIQUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Enrique heads toward the driver's seat and a large SECOND-HAND WINCH bolted to the deck.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. I take you close. But not too close.  You don't want them to eat you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ENRIQUE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ben and Eric nod excitedly and give the thumbs up. Ben lifts the camcorder to the record the action. Enrique jams the down the throttle down, and with a loud RAOR, the speedboat shoots forward. Soon the boat is whipping across the rolling ocean. Strapped together, Ben and Eric lean back over the passing water, intently watching for Enrique's signal. As the boat picks up speed, Enrique eyes the speedometer. Ben grabs the end of the RIPCORD attached to the harness. He and Eric braces themselves. Enrique finally signals with a pulling motion. He pulls the winch, Ben yanks the cord and - WOOOSH! A brightly colored PARASAIL blossoms behind the boat, hoisting Ben and Eric aloft. In a big BLOCK LETTERS on the parasail is stitched "DINO-SOAR." THE TOWNLINE unsold rapidly from its enormous reel. BEN AND ERIC climb higher and higher. ENRIQUE keeps an eye on the clients. When they reach a certain height, he LOCKS OFF the reel. High overhead, Ben and Eric are floating in wonderful, quiet splendor. The motor of the boat now sounds strangely distant. Down below, the boat enters a think blanket of FOG. Eric points excitedly at the islands as Ben films him with the camera. Then, a sudden TUG on the thing line cause Ben to drop the camera, which now dangles from his neck.</context>
      <utterance>Ready, amigos?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A second tug...and now the faintest of screams. Ben and Eric look down to find that the boat has disappeared into the low bank of FOG. By the time the boat emerges on the far side of the mist...THEIR IS NO SIGN OF ENRIQUE. The deck is splattered with blood. As Ben considers the driverless boat...</context>
      <utterance>What was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ben glances over at Eric, staring in horror at something below. Following his gaze, Ben finds that their boat is only moments away from crashing into A LARGE REEF. Sticking out of the water, the imposing reef is being battered by waves. AS THE BOAT SMASHES INTO THE REEF, it splinters into a number of pieces. A panicked Ben turns to Eric.</context>
      <utterance>Ben!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eric and Ben frantically unclip their lines. Catching an updraft, the parasailers float upward. A strong wind sends them wafting over the daunting cliffs of ISLA SORNA...</context>
      <utterance>Unclip your line!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Grant demonstrates with some GRUNT and GROANS of his own, he only succeeds in frightening the boy.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, actually, Charlie, those two are herbivores. They wouldn't be interested in fighting each other. But these...  See, these are carnivores. And this one here -- see its claws -- this one here uses its claws to gouge at the throat of its opponent</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, Alan?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmm?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's three. Why don't you wait till he's a little older?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bounces them along the sandbox edge. Then, the sound of a CAR ENGINE turning off and a door SLAMMING is heard.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, right.  Happy dinosaurs.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARK DEGLER coming through the gate carrying a briefcase. He's their age, handsome but not annoyingly so, with a friendly, balance demeanor. He and Ellie kiss tenderly on the lips.</context>
      <utterance>That must be Mark.  Mark, we’re back here! Ellie and Grant turn to see --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good day?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellie hands off the baby.</context>
      <utterance>Keeping the world safe.  Here, let me take her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark, this is Alan Grant.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men shake hands, and we now realize it is Grant who is the stranger in this household. Little Charlie runs to his father, showing his dinosaur.</context>
      <utterance>Nice to meet you, Alan. I've heard a lot about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grant smiles uncomfortably, a third wheel.</context>
      <utterance>Daddy, this is a herbabore.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's my name? Come on, Jack, say it. Is my name Alan? Say my name. The bird doesn't respond.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He used to know me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grant shrugs, gives Jack the cookie, and heads towards the table. The three adults are finishing their dessert and coffee. The The children have been out to bed. An awkward moment of silence. Uncomfortable smiles. Then --</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Alan it's been six years.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark stands and collects their cups.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Great.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, Mark's working at the State Department now.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?  What do you do there?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark smiles, nodding. Then he goes into the kitchen. Another uncomfortable silence.</context>
      <utterance>Indeed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what are you working on now?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have a new site in Montana. At least until the money runs out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything good?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Raptors, mostly.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grant leans forward, realizing Ellie's one of the few people he can talk to about this.</context>
      <utterance>My favorite.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You remember the sounds they made?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I try not to.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've done cranial scans, and raptors actually had a quite sophisticated resonating chamber. I have a theory that their ability to vocalize is the key to their social intelligence. The way they can work together as a team.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think they could talk to each other?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And from the cage in the corner of the room...</context>
      <utterance>To a degree we never imagined.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both look back at the parrot. ELLIE smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Bullshit!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You taught him that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good luck with the fund raising.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was never easy, but before Jurassic Park, you could find money. Somewhere. Now fossils are out. Everyone wants to see a real live dinosaur.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Times change Alan. But you're the still the best. I mean that.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long moment passes between them as both consider where they've ended up.</context>
      <utterance>The last of my breed.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd better get going.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me know if I can help, Alan. You’re bad about asking for help, but please ask me. Anything, anytime.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Goodbye, Ellie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not sure what the right thing to do is, they finally end up with a friendly hug. They keep it short. Grant gets in his car. Starts the ENGINE. He's about to pull off when Ellie knocks on the window. He rolls it down.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Alan.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>They evolved.</context>
      <utterance>When I met you, I thought that one day millions of years ago, all the dinosaurs became extinct. Wiped out. But you told me otherwise. When conditions changed, dinosaurs changed. They became other things.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A well-accepted theory.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SYMPOSTIUM LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nearly every hand goes up. Grant doesn't seem surprised.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you very much Dr. Grant. Now does anyone have a question?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now most of the hands are down. Picking one of the few remaining...</context>
      <utterance>Does anyone have a question that doesn't relate to Jurassic Park? Quite a few hands go down. GRANT  Or the incident in San Diego, which I'll remind you, I did not witness.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TOO-CLEVER SCIENCE REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Recognizing those as fighting words, the symposium leader is about to step in. But Grant will take this himself.</context>
      <utterance>Isn't paleontology itself in danger of extinction?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, and let me be perfectly clear on this point. Dinosaurs lived 65 million years ago. What's left of them is fossilized in stone the actual scientists spend years to undercover.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CHERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He scoots over, lying down beside her. Checks her work.</context>
      <utterance>Billy? I don't think I'm doing this right.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need to go slowly. See, just take it little at a time. She's not listening, just watching his eyelashes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can never tell what's bone and what's rock.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs her bare fingers over the two different patches, showing her. After a pause, she runs her finger along his stubbly chin...</context>
      <utterance>Technically, it's all rock. The calcium in the bones is replaced during fossilization. But you can feel the difference. See? Rough, smooth. Rough, smooth.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billy may not have started this flirtation, but he's not ending it either. It's then that a</context>
      <utterance>Rough. ...and along his lips. CHERYL  Smooth.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>falls across them. Billy looks up to see...</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grant has just returned, a bag over his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Dr. Grant!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Brennan.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How was your trip? Profitable?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll be broke in four weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cross into one of the tents, which only has two "walls". On a dust-taped table, a dusty Macintosh is feeing data into a strange machine the size of a dorm refrigerator. A mechanical arm sweeps back and forth across a tray of fine sand.</context>
      <utterance>Three weeks. I had to rent some equipment.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You rented an automated litter box.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a rapid prototyper. I feed in the scan data from the raptor skull, than the computer breaks it into thousands of slices which this thing prints, one layer on top of the other. It's the future of paleontology.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The arm stops and suddenly the tray of sand shakes, dropping through holes in the bottom to reveal an object the size of a person's fist.</context>
      <utterance>Not if it can't dig.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grant hates technology, but he can't help but be amazed by the result. He lifts the strange object up, shaking out the remaining sand. Billy puts it to his lips and blows through it like a conch shell. The resulting SOUND is unique and piercing, the cry of an non-existent animal. Grant is speechless with excitement. And so he uses it again and again, producing different SOUNDS and variations. In the distance, flocks of birds rise to the sky and fly off. Billy looks up to see a MAN and a WOMAN getting out of a Cadillac. Cheryl is pointing them in the direction of the tent. BILLY (cont'd) (falsely casual) Oh, I forgot to tell you. Some visitors wanted to come by and talk to you. I told them you'd be happy to see them. maybe even have dinner with them.</context>
      <utterance>I give you a raptor's resonating chamber.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely not.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Only now does Grant realize these two people Who were walking up to them. Putting on a friendly smile, Billy goes up to them.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Grant?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul Kirby. Kirby Enterprises  My card. PAUL KIRBY is a talkative optimist with no "off" switch. His wife AMANDA KIRBY, just as friendly, is harder to read. There seems to be exhaustion behind her eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can I do for you, Mr. Kirby?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>of yours, and I have an extremely interesting proposition to discuss. Would you let my wife and I take you to have dinner tonight? Our treat.</context>
      <utterance>Well sir, I am a great admirer</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I've been traveling and I'm very tired. Maybe some other time.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind Kirby, Bill furtively rubs his thumb and fingers together, indicating the guy is loaded. Grant musters a weak smile.</context>
      <utterance>I guarantee it'll be worth your while.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's be my pleasure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First off let me say as a dinosaur enthusiasts, Amanda and I have admired your work for years.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is truly, what’s the word? Inspiring.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's everything Grant can do just to be polite. He desperately wants to leave and get back to his dig.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amanda and I, well, we just love the outdoors. Heck we've been on pretty much any adventure tour they can come up with: Galapagos, K2, the Nile...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We even have two seats reserved aboard the first commercial moon flight. Billy nudges Grant.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmmm.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, for our wedding anniversary this year we wanted to do something really special, something... He places his hand on his wife's.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...once-in-a-lifetime.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kirby's look to Grant as if they've offered him an amazing gift. But Grant just sighs and smooths the tablecloth.</context>
      <utterance>We've arranged for a private airplane to take us flying over Isla Sorna. And we want you to be our guide.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a very nice offer, Mr. Kirby, but I'm afraid I'm much to busy. If you like I can refer you to a number of highly qualified...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, see Dr. Grant, you're the best. You've seen these animals in the flesh. No one else has come close to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul is momentarily stymied, but Amanda rallies.</context>
      <utterance>I'm flattered, but I've taken this little adventure tour. And with the air restrictions they've imposed after the incident in San Diego, you can’t fly low enough to see anything of interest.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see, that's just the thing. Paul and I have special permission to fly low.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How low?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm no aviation specialist. But I do know it's hell of a lot lower than anyone else.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From what I understand, it's pretty much whatever we want.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's hard to believe.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's just say that through my business -- imports/exports, emerging markets -- I've made some friends in high places. In this case, the Costa Rican government.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grant is trying to find another way to say no, when Paul pulls out his checkbook.</context>
      <utterance>Dr. Grant, you don't know how important it is for us to have you come along. It would make all the difference.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even with what I pay you, you could get a better bag.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way. This is lucky. Couple years ago some buddies and I went hang gliding off these cliffs in New Zealand. Updraft sent me right into the side. BOOM!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That does sound lucky.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was this strap alone that saved my life. Got caught on a rock as I was falling.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Because he hasn't really said it...</context>
      <utterance>Reverse-Darwinism. Survival of the most idiotic.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen Alan, I really appreciate you bringing me along.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The bones will be there when we get back. That's the nice thing about them. They never run away.  And besides, you got me into this. I don't intend to be alone with these people.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mercenary Cooper, the weapons specialist we met earlier. He's wearing sunglasses so dark you can't tell whether he's staring at you or fast asleep. He doesn't answer. Did he even hear? And then --</context>
      <utterance>So how do you know the Kirby's? and we reveal...</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Through our church.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What Religion?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh the one that worships God and believes in being Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>16 	EXT. SKY - DAY 							16</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The plane continues onward.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The adrenaline still surging through him, Grant turns and looks</context>
      <utterance>Alan. We're almost there.</utterance>
   <speaker>THROUGH THE WINDOW.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clouds obscure the view, than parts reveal</utterance>
   <speaker>ISLA SORNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>rising majestically out of the water.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Calling back from the cockpit...</context>
      <utterance>Admit it. You're excited. Grant will admit nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>UDESKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cooper! Yell up if you see anything!</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Grant spots...</context>
      <utterance>No, I thought I'd keep it to myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There. There! An Apatosaur. Look at the coloration.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Paul just waves him away with a hand, staring intently out his window. We HOLD ON Grant a moment, thinking that odd.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. and Mrs. Kirby! If you look out the right you can see...</utterance>
   <speaker>UDESKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>South shore is clear. The rest is rock.</utterance>
   <speaker>NASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we on?</utterance>
   <speaker>UDESKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul, Amanda and Cooper don't respond.</context>
      <utterance>That's not the landing gear?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Paul turns back to him.</context>
      <utterance>What you're...  You can't land.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Grant if you'd just sit tight, we'll explain this all in a jiffy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This plane can not land!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grant is out of his seat, heading for the cockpit. He'll wrestle the controls if he has to. Cooper grabs him, pulling him back. Grant starts to struggle, but he's certainly no match. A well-practiced fist hits him dead on.</context>
      <utterance>It's going to be all right. Just...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>By his expression, we see Billy would have to lie.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me we didn't land.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think they're looking for someone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three mercenaries are now walking into the jungle with their guns.</context>
      <utterance>Dr. Grant, are you alright? I'm sorry we had to be so...</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is going on? What are they doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Establishing a perimeter. Making it safe. These guys are really good. One of them was a Green...</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grant looks to Amanda, who shouts through a bull horn.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Kirby, trust me, on this island, there is no such thing as safe. We have to get back in this plane...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And tell your wife to stop making so much noise! We're food to these damn animals.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amanda, Honey! Dr. Grant says it's a bad idea!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He says it's a bad idea!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As in on cue, there is a DEAFENING ROAR from the jungle. Everyone turns toward the sound and freezes.</context>
      <utterance>What's a bad idea?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grant doesn't answer, still listening to the reverberations. Then a couple shots are heard.</context>
      <utterance>What was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it a rex?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billy and Paul breathe a small sign of relief.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Nash and Udesky come RUNNING out of the jungle, headed for the plane.</context>
      <utterance>Sounds bigger.</utterance>
   <speaker>UDESKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We gotta go, now!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Udesky and Nash sprint past Paul in interrupted by a second, closer, DEAFENING ROAR. He pales.</context>
      <utterance>What's the problem? Can't you guys...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't just...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, honey. We'll circle around and come back. Udesky closes the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the other guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>UDESKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A blood-curdling SCREAM echoes through the jungle followed by</context>
      <utterance>Coop's a professional. He can handle himself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Udesky climbs into the copilot's seat, and Nash revs the engine.</context>
      <utterance>We're going!</utterance>
   <speaker>30	EXT. RUNAWAY - DAY						30</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The plane starts down the runway.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slams down full throttle in an attempt to reach flying speed. Seeing that Nash has no intention of stopping, Paul shouts from the cabin.</context>
      <utterance>Coop, you know I can't do it pal.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing? That's Mr. Cooper!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Checking themselves, everyone seems pretty much intact. Still thinking of himself as in charge...</context>
      <utterance>Is anyone hurt?</utterance>
   <speaker>UDESKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He attempts to turn on the cockpit radio, but it's dead.</context>
      <utterance>Quiet! We're okay. Let's everybody just stay put.</utterance>
   <speaker>NASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's got the sat-phone?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul hands the bulky phone up to Nash, who dials out. Grant unstraps himself, climbs to the back to the side door and shoves. The door opens a few inches before hitting a branch. He looks out the and lets out a quiet gasp as the ground reels</context>
      <utterance>Right here!</utterance>
   <speaker>THIRTY FEET BELOW.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE ON the sat-phone. pressed against Nash's ear.</context>
      <utterance>He quickly shuts and latches the door.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A huge reptilian face appears in the cockpit window. Everyone else SCREAMS now.</context>
      <utterance>What is it? What's the matter? Amanda SCREAMS.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The plane LURCHES - and we hear a deep GROWL.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul is too startled to speak. Udesky tires to step in, but Grant gives him back a look.</context>
      <utterance>Why did you bring us here?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Still crunched against the tree, Paul pulls out a photo from his shirt pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Our son is on this island. We need your help to find him.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Letting go of Paul, Grant takes the photo, a Sears-style portrait of the boy we saw Parasailing at the beginning. He shakes his head, disbelieving. He hands the photo to Billy. The group splits into two sides -- Paul and Amanda, Grant and Billy -- with Udesky stuck between. Dialogue overlaps in places.</context>
      <utterance>This is him. Eric. He’s thirteen now. He's just about the greatest kid in the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's with a man named Ben Hildebrand.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her new boyfriend.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A friend. We were vacationing. Eric wanted to see the island and the dinosaurs, so Ben found a guy who would take them parasailing. They never came back.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We called everyone, did everything we could. Because of all the controversy over this island, no one will step in. Costa Rica says it's a no-fly zone, it's their own damn fault. Guys at the U.S Embassy -- our U.S. Embassy -- said we should "accept the inevitable." You believe that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you hired these mercenaries.</utterance>
   <speaker>UDESKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We prefer "recovery specialists." We do overseas custody issues and...</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you duped us into coming here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>land. Somebody who'd been to this island before.</context>
      <utterance>We needed somebody who knew the lay of the</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have never been on this island!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure you have. You wrote that book...</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was Isla Nublar. This is Isla Sorna. The second island.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know, there were two islands.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still, you have survived the dinosaurs before. You saved those kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A few of us survived. A lot more died. And we were better prepared and better armed.  How many days have they been missing? A look between Amanda and Paul.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grand and Billy are speechless. It might as well be eight years.</context>
      <utterance>Eight weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After what you've seen today, you really think your son could be alive?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before anyone else can talk, Grant puts his hand out. He wants everyone to shut up while he plans their next move.</context>
      <utterance>He's smart, Dr. Grant. And he knows so much about dinosaurs.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm sorry, but no. We'll savage what we can from the plane. Then we head for the coast. There may be a boat left, something to get us off this island.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Grant, we're not leaving without our son.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that he leaves, A beat later, Billy follows. He has genuine sympathy for the Kirby's, but he's logical enough to know Grant is right.</context>
      <utterance>You can stick with us, or you can go and look for him. Either way you're probably not getting out of here alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>BACK WITH PAUL AND AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They look to Udesky.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Udesky is clearly at a loss, but for everyone's reassurance he tries to mutter some brio.</context>
      <utterance>What do we do?</utterance>
   <speaker>UDESKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I think we should start searching for your son. In the direction they're going.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They follow after Grant and Billy.</context>
      <utterance>Excellent.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Amanda looks over as they get dressed.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing you haven't seen before.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much weight have you lost?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty, twenty-fire pounds. I've been swimming at the Y.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You hate to swim.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A nod to mean, that's the truth.</context>
      <utterance>People change.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look good.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They make brief eye contact, which Amanda breaks. Around the side, Billy is taking photos of a giant footprint the dinosaur left in the mud during its attack on the plane. Grant looks over.</context>
      <utterance>So do you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How would you classify it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Obviously a superpredator.  Suchimimus. that snout.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They never got that big.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Baryonyx?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not with that sail.  Spinosaurus Aegypticus.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't remember that on InGen's list.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billy looks past Grant to see Paul approaching. He's struggling with the straps on his backpack. turning in circles. Billy regards him with suspicion.</context>
      <utterance>That's because it wasn't on their list. Who knows what else they were up to?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So Mr. Kirby, tell me, when you climbed K2, did you base camp at 25- or 30,000 feet?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirty-thousand, I think. Closer to the top.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About a thousand feet above it, actually.  Most mountain-climbers remember how tall that mountains were. Paul knows he's caught.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is no Kirby Enterprises, is there?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is. I own a place called Kirby Paint and Title Plus. We're out in the Westgate Shopping Center in Enid, Oklahoma. The "plus" is for bathroom fixtures, fireplaces accessories, patio furniture. Stuff like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't suppose that check you wrote us is any good.</utterance>
   <speaker>UDESKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He paid us half up front. Cash.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mortgaged everything we had to do it. Even the store. and if we make it off this island with my son, I swear, I'll make good on the money I owe you. I don't care if it takes me the rest of my life. Grant and Udesky exchange a dubious glance.</utterance>
   <speaker>UDESKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>However long that is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eric!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quiet!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop that. Dr. Grant says this is dangerous territory.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well we should split up or something. We can cover twice the area.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Dr. Grant says...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Grant says this, Dr. Grant says that...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well what's the use of hiring an expert if your not going to listen to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because "Dr. Grant" isn't looking for Eric. Dr. Grant is looking for the coast.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine...and when the Tricyclatops comes after you, don't come crying to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, don't worry about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you say!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kirby's conversation trails off into the jungle. Udesky moves up next to Grant and Billy.</context>
      <utterance>Just drop it Paul!</utterance>
   <speaker>UDESKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And as they continue forward, Billy spots something in the trees ahead.</context>
      <utterance>If they split up, I'm going with you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Young adult.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eric...</utterance>
   <speaker>UDESKY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S</mode>
      <context>All turn to see Udesky holding up a camcorder encased in a waterproof shell.</context>
      <utterance>Hey. Got something here.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grabs it from Udesky and pops open the housing. She tries the power switch on the camcorder, but the battery's dead. Udesky pull out a flashlight from his pack and looks to Amanda.</context>
      <utterance>That's Ben's!</utterance>
   <speaker>UDESKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And as Udesky fiddles with the flashlight, Grant and Billy consider the parasail.</context>
      <utterance>Here, give that to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It looks intact.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should take it with us to signal any planes.</utterance>
   <speaker>UDESKY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S</mode>
      <context>Udesky has rigged the wires on the flashlight so that the batteries can be used to power the camcorder. He brings a live wire to back of the camcorder. A red power light comes on.</context>
      <utterance>I think I've got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It works!</utterance>
   <speaker>UDESKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Udesky swings the tiny screen out and pushes play. The others crowd around.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know for how long.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's him. That’s Eric!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Ben catches the frisbee, checks his watch and motions to Eric. Eric runs over, and Ben puts his arm around him as they run to the camera. Paul reacts to this image but holds his tongue.</context>
      <utterance>I filmed this the morning they left.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unclip the line!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Now the camera penetrates the jungle canopy and the picture and sound become complete chaos: SCREAMS from the both, branches BREAKING, flashes of Ben and Eric's frightened faces as the camera is buffeted in all directions. With a lurch the terrifying descent in finally over, and the jungle floor is just ten feet away, swaying back and forth beneath Ben and Eric's feet.</context>
      <utterance>Hand on! Hang on buddy!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>There's GURGLING to his voice. Ben may be more hurt than he's letting on.</context>
      <utterance>Are you ok, buddy?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sound of PUMPLING is followed by the sight of Eric DROPPING into the frame, landing on the ground rolling. He stands and looks back up at Ben.</context>
      <utterance>We're okay. It's going to be okay. Here, get ready. I'm going to unhook you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm all right</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S</mode>
      <context>BACK ON PAUL AND AMANDA - overjoyed.</context>
      <utterance>We're going to get out of this, pal. And on that, the power and picture fade away.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amanda brings a hand to her mouth, silently nodding her head. Grant and Billy exchange a dubious look, than begin pulling the parasail out of the tree. As they do so, the sail gets caught on a branch. They pull harder. The branch bends, but the sail won't come loose. One last tug and than, SNAP. The branch breaks, the chute falls away to reveal</context>
      <utterance>See? He's okay. He's alive! Everything's going to be all right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>A SKELETON.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finally, the others are able to pull her away. As they untangle the lines, the men are able to get the first view of the remains of Ben Hillenbrand, still caught in his harness. Amanda's knees buckle. Regaining her balance, she runs off into the jungle. Paul quickly follows.</context>
      <utterance>It swings down directly at Amanda. She SCREAMS.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amanda!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry Amanda. I am. And I'm sorry for the things I said about him.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you liked Ben. I had no right to...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Checking in on clients, Udesky stops at the edge of the thicket. Something raises the hairs on the back of his neck.</context>
      <utterance>I guess I was hoping that with Ben around, there'd be someone to keep him safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>UDESKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods for the others to take a look at this. They head over, Grant at the rear. As he approaches, Billy is packing up the rest of the chute in a backpack. He stops short from what he sees. Looking down, we CIRCLE across the jungle floor. Here we find a strange, hollowed-out construction made of sod and branches. Maybe six feet around. Just now noticing the others' stare, Paul looks down into one of the bowls at his feet, a half-buried nest. It's filled with football-sized eggs, laid in a spiral. And this isn't the only nest. Amanda counts twelve in all, laid out in an oddly symmetrical pattern. The last to arrive, Grant identifies the species in a horrified instant.</context>
      <utterance>Dr. Grant!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And as he says the words, off in the distance, we hear the cry of some herbivores, around by the chorus of snarls.</context>
      <utterance>Raptors.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul has no idea.</context>
      <utterance>What’s a raptor?</utterance>
   <speaker>UDESKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't look that big. I mean, comparatively.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we came across one, we might live.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well that's good.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the back --</context>
      <utterance>But you never came across just one.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait! Where's Billy? They all stop. The only one not there is -- Grant Billy! Billy!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought we weren't suppose to yell.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S</mode>
      <context>He comes in from the left. Excited, he explains to Grant --</context>
      <utterance>Here!</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Furious with his student. Grant just keeps moving. There's no time to stand around and argue.</context>
      <utterance>I got some great pictures of the nest. You know this proves raptors raised their young in colonies.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This speaks to a larger social structure, the possibility of Darwinian altruism. It changes everything. A beat. Trying not to sound presumptuous --</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We could co-write a paper.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah yes, the first rule of academics. Publish or perish.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eric! Are you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All listen for a response. Nothing. Paul and Amanda exchange a despondent look. Sitting on the reception counter is an official-looking telephone. Everyone has the same thought, but no one dares. Finally -</context>
      <utterance>Eric!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Amanda puts the receiver to her ear. Nada. With Grant in the lead, they head deeper into the building. Unseen by the group, a fleeting SHADOW flits across the lobby's dirty windows with terrifying speed.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is how you make dinosaurs?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billy looks around the lab. He can't help but be impressed.</context>
      <utterance>This is how you play God.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billy sets his lucky camera back down on the worktable. Two years from now, astute observers of the DVD will not that Billy doesn't actually take his camera from the bag; he was carrying it because there wasn't any room inside. Billy pulls a new roll of film from the bag and zips it shut.</context>
      <utterance>Okay if I take pictures? Grant nods.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>A GIGANTIC MANIFIED RAPTOR HEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Something about this specimen catches Amanda’s attention. She bends forward, getting very close to the glass. She peers right into the eyes of the nightmarish creature. Then --</context>
      <utterance>floating in the one tank.</utterance>
   <speaker>AN ACTUAL RAPTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fortunately the raptor can't get between the closely spaced tanks. Amanda runs.</context>
      <utterance>lunges at her form behind the tank. She SCREAMS.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amanda!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And as the group races through the lab the Raptors find a larger gap between the tanks.</context>
      <utterance>Back out! Move!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They push hard on the cage door, swinging it and the raptor right through the opening of the cage. Now the raptor is trapped in a small triangular space, the door going right to the ceiling. Amanda slides the door's bolt through the chain like wall, temporarily trapping the dinosaur. The raptor struggles desperately, GRAWLING AND SNARLING, but the cage door seems to be holding. As everyone rushes back to the door. The raptor begins to make a LOW, HAUNTING MOAN. As the others head for the door, Grant lingers a step, listening to the beast's simple melodic cry. It has the same tones as came from the model resonating chamber.</context>
      <utterance>Push!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's calling for help.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>A PACK OF RAPTORS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>emerges from the jungles, coming their way.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the lab building, the raptor we left imprisoned now BURSTS out one of the doors and HOWLS to the pack -- the same cry we heard in the lab. The raptor pack moves into the hunting formation. One ALPHA-MALE RAPTOR. slightly larger than the others, leads the charge up the middle. Grant risks a looks back. But doesn't stop running. GRANT (cont'd)</context>
      <utterance>Head for the trees!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Udesky.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From here, the thick branches overlap, forming a kind of "second floor" above the ground. It's not easy, but you can move from branch to branch, tree to tree.</context>
      <utterance>He's this way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to help him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's right. A predator wouldn't leave a kill wounded.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She breaks from Paul's grip and drops to the ground. She's only a foot away from the tree when</context>
      <utterance>He's not a kill, he's still alive.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They couldn’t climb up, so they were trying to get us to come down.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bored with waiting, the raptors go back to finish off Udesky, making a meal out of it. Up in the branches, the survivors are horrified and sickened. Then, from the deep in the forest, a new RAPTOR CRY. The feasting raptors look up, listening, then suddenly run off into the dark jungle.</context>
      <utterance>They set a trap  They actually set a trap.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Grant?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ever the scientist, Dr. Grant tests a theory even in the face of danger: he holds up the intact egg so that the raptors can see it. They suddenly go crazy, howling the same phrase but LOUDER.</context>
      <utterance>God damn you, Billy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He gently drops the bag to the ground. Although the raptors are interested, pulling out the unbroken egg, they're still by no means placated. The song may have changed, but they still want Grant dead. They begin to jump at him, eventually, hopping up on each other’s backs. It's only a matter of time till they reach him. Grant moves to climb higher, but sees no branches he can reach. And than he hears the low CREAKING. A CRACK. The branch he's on is starting to give in. He looks down at the face of his enemies, knowing he'll be their next meal. And then,</context>
      <utterance>It means, "Give us the egg," doesn't it? "We want the egg."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>A HUMAN SHAPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>at the edge of the smoke</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grant half-climbs, half-falls out of the tree, rushing to get through the heaviest of the smoke.</context>
      <utterance>Come on! They'll be back!</utterance>
   <speaker>A SMALL DIRTY HAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>grabs his, pulling him along.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy holds up a hand. He listens for a moment. He doesn't hear anything outside.</context>
      <utterance>Eric...</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eric, your parents are both here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In Costa Rica?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eric truly can't believe it. He hoped to be rescued but...</context>
      <utterance>On the island.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll never make it. I mean, they can't manage when the cable goes out.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eric studies his guest, finally certain he recognizes him.</context>
      <utterance>You'd be surprised what people can do when they have too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're Alan Grant, aren't you?  I read both of your books.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which one do you prefer?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The first one. Before you where on the island. You liked dinosaurs back then.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grant takes a better look around Eric's tiny hideaway, impressed with what he's been able to scavenge. Among the many items we see another smoke canister, some battery-powered lanterns and lots of candy wrappers. This kid's been living on chocolate for weeks.</context>
      <utterance>Back then, they hadn't tried to eat me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When InGen cleared out, they left a lot of stuff behind.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eric pulls up a long cattle prod to show Grant.</context>
      <utterance>Any weapons, radios?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Found this, but the battery's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The line catches Eric strangely. It's the first moment of true emotion we've seen him in.</context>
      <utterance>It's a wonder you aren't. I'm amazed, Eric. I barely lasted 30 hours. You lasted eight weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that all it's been? I thought it was longer.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you read Malcolm's book?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dunno. I mean, it was kind of preachy. Chaos-this, chaos-that. And like, to me, the guy seemed kind of high on himself. Grant smiles.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's two things we have in common.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't just stop looking. Eric and Dr. Grant are out there somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to find them too, but we can't do a bit of good right now. For every scary thing we saw in the daylight, I'll bet there ten times more of 'em at night.  Am I right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don’t know.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you were an expert.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Grant was.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amanda is impressed by her own determinations. A long beat. AMANDA (cont'd) So what do we do? No one has the faintest clue.</context>
      <utterance>Well Dr. Grant isn't here, so we're going to have to figure out what to do ourselves.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amanda looks over, not sure what his absolution. PAUL (cont'd) Eric has always been headstrong, and you throw Ben Hildebrand into the mix and well...</context>
      <utterance>I just want you know, Amanda. It's not your fault what happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well what?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Realizing he's trying his best, Amanda can’t stay angry with him.</context>
      <utterance>Well damn it. I don't speak ill of the dead. What I'm trying to say is, it’s was just a crazy accident. The exact same thing could have happened if he was with me. You can't go beating yourself up about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This wouldn't happen if he was with you. I mean, you drive five miles below the speed limit. I totaled three cars in fives years.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That one time was just the bumper.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I would have him to see more of the world than Enid, Oklahoma. I wanted to see more of the world than Enid, Oklahoma. And so yes, it's my fault that this happened. I'm sorry that you have to be here. Really looking at her...</context>
      <utterance>He would have been, safe. Completely, entirely, suffocatingly safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sorry at all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Know what this is?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A raptor claw. I use to have one. A fossil.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eric is becoming more and more a normal thirteen-year old boy. There's an innocence to him that's coming back.</context>
      <utterance>Mine's new. Grant hands it back.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much of this island have you explored?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Figured if anyone came to look for me, that's where they'd start.</context>
      <utterance>I stayed pretty close to the compound,</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need to head for the coast.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Closer you get to the water, the bigger things get.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need to stick to the plan. Head for the coast.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Eric and Dr. Grant?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Going to the coast was Alan's idea. If he's alive, that’s where he's headed.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billy represses his instinct to say Eric's dead.</context>
      <utterance>What about Eric?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, Paul frantically searches his pockets as the others anxiously watch.</context>
      <utterance>My phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You had the phone the whole time?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I don't have it with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When did you have it last?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't remember</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Paul wracks his memory...</context>
      <utterance>Think.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bust suddenly, he stops, his face is lighting with an awful realization. Amanda couldn’t bear the wait...</context>
      <utterance>The plane. I got a call on the plane, put it in my coat pocket, and...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?...WHAT!?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The hideous implication of his words slowly sink in.</context>
      <utterance>I loaned it to Nash. He must have had it on him when he...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grant immediately covers the boy’s mouth. But it's to late. The dinosaur has stopped. We still can't see it. We don't know how close it is. Paul and Amanda spot Eric with Grant. They're a thousand emotions at once: relieved, disbelieving, terrified, overjoyed. They want to run to him, to yell out to him, but the monster is close. Grant takes his hand off Eric's mouth. They both stay completely silent. All this time, the sat-phone is RINGING. Than it stops. And after an agonizing beat, the beast moves. At first we're not sure which direction it's headed, but finally we can tell its moving away. Once the sail is finally out of sight, Eric breaks from Grant's hold and dashes to his parents' arms. They coop him up. Hug him, kiss him, their affection unquenchable. He's crying.</context>
      <utterance>Mon! Dad!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sweetheart, you're okay.  You're okay.  You're okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never had a doubt. Never did. Us Kirby men, we stick around, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looking at her grubby son, Amanda licks her shirttail, trying to rub his face clean.</context>
      <utterance>We do.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She LAUGHS. It's the first times she's laughed in two months. Billy crosses the distance to Grant.</context>
      <utterance>Honey, there's not enough spit in the world for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need to keep moving.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alan, I want to tell you that I'm so sorry about the...</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks off. Billy follows him.</context>
      <utterance>Billy, I can't talk to you now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, okay? Just yell at me. Call me an idiot. An asshole. Stupid. Tell me I screwed up because I know I did. Grant doesn't respond.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Grant shakes his head, disgusted, But doesn't stop.</context>
      <utterance>I thought if we could get a raptor back to the mainland, we could get serious money for it. Enough to fund the digging for 10 years. More. Whatever it took.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to believe me. I did it with the best intentions.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grant keeps walking, leaving Billy with his guilt.</context>
      <utterance>Some of the worst things imaginable have been done with the best intentions. You rushed in with no thought to the consequences, to yourself or anyone else.  You're no better than the people who built this place.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We climb down to the barge and follow the river out to the ocean. With any luck, the Costa Rican coast guard will pick us up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then we go home?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grant leads everyone down a RAMP to --</context>
      <utterance>Then we go home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grant nods and looks in the other direction.</context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their only other option is a precarious catwalk that disappears into the mist.</context>
      <utterance>How about if we try this way?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think it goes all the way across?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The only way to get his-near-fall is to push ahead. But his stomach turns at being so high. Amanda follows. The catwalk creaks and groans, listing slightly. She freezes mid-stride.</context>
      <utterance>One way to find out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More silence. Then, out of the fog, a distant voice call out --</context>
      <utterance>Dr. Grant?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Amanda steps tentatively forwards. Eric is clinging to her.</context>
      <utterance>Come on over. One at a time.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eric, its okay. You'll be right behind me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eric reluctantly releases her mother. Amanda starts to cross.</context>
      <utterance>We're not going anywhere, I promise. As Paul holds Eric, and Amanda shares a look. Amanda We're all together now, Eric.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay! Come on, Eric!</utterance>
   <speaker>74	EXT. LANDING - DAY							74</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eric is next to go across. He's still tentative.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How 'bout if I...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billy and Paul look on as Eric disappears into the vapor.</context>
      <utterance>No, I can do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it Eric. Nice and easy...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, my God.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then, the sound of Eric SCREAMING.</context>
      <utterance>A bird cage.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eric!</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly,</context>
      <utterance>It won't hold!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul! Where is he? Can you see him?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm trying! That thing took him down this way!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Split up!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Billy glances behind him. He races forward, motioning fro his companions to turn around.</context>
      <utterance>Billy, look out!</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then Billy is knocked down by the lead pteranodon. It strikes from behind with a brutal, calculated beak to the head. Billy stumbles and falls to the ground. Grant rushes forward with Paul right after him. Amanda takes Eric to safety down river. Billy SCREAMS as the ENTIRE FLOCK of pteranodons now swarms around him, picking him apart with their beaks and claws.</context>
      <utterance>Get back! Get back!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Billy!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grant can't take his eyes off Billy, whose BLOOD stains the water rushing by. And now several pteranodons are heading their way. Difficult as it is to leave Billy behind, Grant and Paul make a run for it. Just as the pteranodons are about to swoop in for the kill, Alan and Paul dive back into the river...</context>
      <utterance>It's no use, Dr. Grant. No use.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My own kid was right in front of me and I didn't do a damn thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You couldn't have made that jump.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should have tried. It should have been me on that beach back there, not Billy.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How would you have helped Eric?  He needs you, Paul. He needs us.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He could have died.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But he didn't. And neither did you. And I'm glad about that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have any kids?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Although I've studied them in the wild. Eric looks over, not sure what that means.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to be an astronaut.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, I was the opposite. I never understood why anyone would want to go into space. It's so dangerous. You do one thing wrong and you're dead. The astronomer -- or the paleontologist -- get to study these amazing things from a place of complete safety. And truthfully, everything you really need to learn, you can learn it from the ground.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But then you never get to go in space.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The barge starts to round a bend. On the bow, Grant and Eric are the fist to see something remarkable. Eric GASPS, unprepared. We don't know yet what they see. GRANT (cont'd) I can blame the people who made this island. But I can't blame the people who want to see it. To study it. At the rear of the barge, Paul just now sees what's ahead. Awe- struck, he slows the motor and motions for Amanda to take a look. And so do we.</context>
      <utterance>Exactly. The difference between imagining how things might be and seeing how they really are. To be able to touch them. That's what Billy wanted to do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And bracing themselves and hocking their breath, they PLUNGE their arms into their respective dung-heaps. After a few moments of this disgusting search...</context>
      <utterance>Find it before it stops ringing!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All turn to Paul. Clearing away the clinging defecation, he holds up to a beeper. And still the phone RINGS. Returning to their bleak task, they shovel the excrement with their arms. Finally:</context>
      <utterance>I've got something. I think I've got something!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grant snatches the RINGING SAT-PHONE from Amanda's hands, presses a button, and puts it to his ear.</context>
      <utterance>I've got it! I've got it!</utterance>
   <speaker>RECORDED VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>ON PHONE</mode>
      <context>The Kirby’s hear the recorded voice and let out a collective, heavy sigh. Grant shuts off the phone. In all the excitement, none of them notice a fierce horned CARNOTAUR right behind them. The giant creature ROARS, ready to eat them. But as it gets in close, it smells them. Even a dinosaur won't eat something that is covered in shit. After a beat, the Carnotaur turns and walks away, back into the jungle.</context>
      <utterance>You too can own a time share in beautiful Guadalajara. Enjoy a meal in one of our four star restaurants, explore our coral reefs, or just walk on the beach...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't help but be a little offended.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever you do, don't call the U.S. Embassy. They won't do a God Damn thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we don't exactly have a Costa Rican phone book here, so it will have to be somebody we know in the states. Someone we can absolutely count on to send help.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stan.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul glares at her. Now Eric notices something odd in the river.</context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't trust Stan with a snowball in a blizzard.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others look down in the murky water. Just below the surface,</context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>A SHIMMERING WAVE OF SILVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then a SINGLE FISH jumps from the water. And another. And another.</context>
      <utterance>passes beneath the boat.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bonitas.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another roll of THUNDER, this time much closer.</context>
      <utterance>Something must've scared them.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul moves the motor and pulls the start cord. The engine sputters but won't come to life. And now the phone BEEPS. The battery is getting even weaker. Grant makes a quick decision and DIALS.</context>
      <utterance>Get the motor going.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Grant ignores the question. RING. RING.</context>
      <utterance>Who are you calling?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pick up! Pick up!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hewwo?</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERCUT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Recognizing who it must be...</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long silence. Charlie bites his lip, looks around.</context>
      <utterance>Charlie? Charlie. Get your mother. Right away!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charlie? Are you there?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sat-phone BEEPS again, this time much LOUDER. Amanda and Eric watch Grant, realizing their fate may hang on this single call. Paul struggles without success to start the motor. Then, unseen by the group, a</context>
      <utterance>Hewwo?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charlie! It's the dinosaur man! Go get mommy, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not sure what to do with the phone, Charlie makes a logical choice and hangs it back up. He walks away to his mom.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was somebody on the phone?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellie looks at him with confusion, then quickly checks the Caller ID box besides the phone. It's international, and not a number she recognizes.</context>
      <utterance>Dinosaur man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She can hear the Spinosaurus ROAR.</context>
      <utterance>Alan?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>But he's cut off by a SECOND ROAR, the sound of someone</context>
      <utterance>Alan? Alan!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCREAMING.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellie pales. Charlie looks at her with a smile.</context>
      <utterance>And then the line goes dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Raaaar!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to a heavy crane assembly, designed for lifting cages off the large boats. Now well accustomed to fleeing on command, Amanda sends Eric up first, climbing the scaffolding like a jungle gym. All the while, they're trying to spot Paul. Grant is the last to climb, reaching the first section as Spinosaurus returns from the water, SLAMMING into the base of the crane. The whole assembly SHUDDERS, threatening to rip into the water.</context>
      <utterance>Up! Up!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Try as it might, the beast can't climb the crane. So instead it RAMS it, SHAKES it, trying to knock them off. Eric slips, but Amanda catches him. About to shed his bag to climb higher, Grant finds one last hope. It's the resonation chamber model. A beat before he decides: It may not be the best choice, but it's the only choice. He blows through it, the same EERIE PITCH we heard before. On the third try, he's able to approximate the "egg" cry he heard the raptors give. He keeps it up, repeating over and over. Spinosaurus stops for a beat, confused How this sound could be coming from a non-raptor. But then keeps SMASHING. We can hear the mounting bolts STRAIN. Soon the whole crane will tip. But not before a MATCHING CRY is heard in the jungle. Grant stops, not certain he heard it. But there it is AGAIN. He keeps blowing. The crane is close to tipping when a single RAPTOR appears from the darkness, CHIRP-BARKING at the Spinosaur, who simply bats away. But then MORE RAPTORS come. And even MORE. Soon there are dozens gathering, circling. Grant stops signaling. All three survivors watch with horrified fascination, knowing their fate is perilous no matter which side wins. Looking at his adversaries, Spinosaurus ROARS. And suddenly the raptors attack. Spinosaurus easily handles the first few, but like ants they just keep coming. They climb up his back, slicing, into him with their razor-sharp claws.</context>
      <utterance>Just hold on.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All three drop from the crane arm into the water. Meanwhile, the fight continues. Spinosaurus rallies, shaking off many of the raptors, but they just keep coming. Their hooked claws dig in, scraping the meat to the bone. Spinosaurus puts up a brave fight to the end, but finally collapses, dead. The raptors continue to shred it to ribbons. Then one of the raptors looks over to see the survivors swimming away. But a bird in the hand is worth two in the bush. It goes back to its meal.</context>
      <utterance>Jump! Swim for the far shore!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to keep looking for Dad. We have to.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. I know. I want to look for him too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kneels down, facing him. She's just as upset as he is, but motherhood carries the burden of remaining calm.</context>
      <utterance>then we should...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>okay? He's very very very clever, very very brave, and he loves you ever very much.</context>
      <utterance>Let me tell you a few things about you Dad,</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He loves you too.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. He loves us very very much. And I know that right now more than anything, your Dad would want to know that we're safe. Okay? Eric nods.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>everything's going to be all right, I promise.</context>
      <utterance>We're going to get out of this, and</utterance>
   <speaker>A VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Out of the darkness steps Paul Kirby. Amanda is knocked over with surprise. Eric runs to him, nearly tackling him.</context>
      <utterance>Listen to your mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amanda hugs him and Eric so tightly they can't breath.</context>
      <utterance>Good thing I've been swimming, huh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eric really smiles, remembering the day.</context>
      <utterance>You remember when we went fishing last summer? And I was trying to put the boat in and the trailer sank? And then the tow truck came and tried to pull it out, but it got dragged in? And the truck driver threatened to knock your Dad's lights out? So I said I was the governor and he believed me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amanda is smiling too. She had completely forgotten the incident.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>To Paul, after some consideration....</context>
      <utterance>That was a fun day.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should try fishing again.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean it?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her hand takes his, gently brushing off the wet sand, fingertips touching. It's a small thing, but it's a start. Sensing his cue to leave, Grant gets up and starts walking down the beach. Eric hurries to follow him. He speaks conspiratorially, not wanting to alarm his parents.</context>
      <utterance>I do. It's worth another shot. And who knows? Things might turn out differently.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The lady you called, how do you know she can help us?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's the one person I could always count on. And she's saved me more times than she realizes. I owe her everything. A long beat as they walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's strikes me now I never told her that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they keep walking, Grant notices something rammed against the rocks ahead. It's a speedboat, its hull ripped open from the impact. And it's not just any boat either -- it's the same Dino-Soar boat that was pulling the parasail. Eric hasn’t seen it yet, so Grant stops him.</context>
      <utterance>You're right.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eric, do you know what happened to the boat? that brought you here? Why did it crash?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I couldn't see.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eric nods and heads back to Paul and Amanda. Grant forges on, approaching the speedboat wreckage. He doesn't know what he'll find, but he needs to look. Almost reaching his parents, Eric stops. Looks out over the ocean, where he sees</context>
      <utterance>Do me a favor. Go back to your parents for a minute, would you?  They look worried.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look up to see the distant lights, just now making out full forms...</context>
      <utterance>Mom! Dad!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He SHOUTS with joy. Paul, Amanda and Eric wave their arms, making as much motion as possible. The helicopters -- big military choppers -- change direction, heading straight for them. Paul and Amanda embrace, then kiss, the moment getting the best of them</context>
      <utterance>Helicopters. Helicopters!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're safe!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No we're not.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think is going to happen with the dinosaurs?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The population will Stabilize eventually. They'll adapt to fit different roles.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Either that, or the government will firebomb it back to the Stone Age.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would completely support that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Dr. Grant realizes...</context>
      <utterance>I hope they don't. I want to come back someday.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So do I.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
