<movie id="327" title="Kalifornia">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The flashlight finds the corner in question. Flash!! The warehouse lights up again, revealing a huge machine room.</context>
      <utterance>This is it. This is the where he'd take her whenever he had the urge to molest her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course! Nobody would have heard her cries over the noise of the machines.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The driver fidgets blindly with the various levers and knobs. He finally manages to get the defroster and heater to work. The girl leans forward into the stream of warm air.</context>
      <utterance>Damn! This defroster never works...</utterance>
   <speaker>PRETTY TEENAGE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She closes her eyes, lets it blow across her face. He watches her. His eyes linger on her body.</context>
      <utterance>...Mmm... feels good.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls her wet hair off her bruised face and gives him a nervous smile.</context>
      <utterance>Have a problem with your car?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRETTY TEENAGE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He throws a curious look at her, then back to the highway.</context>
      <utterance>No.  My problem's with men.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The flashlight continues to search through the darkness.</context>
      <utterance>This is where she murdered her first victim. They found his body over in the corner, shot through the head.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another flash!!!!!</context>
      <utterance>They found her second victim over there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PRETTY TEENAGE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay if I smoke?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The driver watches as she reaches into the purse... out a soggy pack of matches. She looks at them... I look to the driver.</context>
      <utterance>...sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRETTY TEENAGE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My matches are all wet. You got a lighter?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>illuminates the night rain streaming in through the fractured remains of the ceiling.</context>
      <utterance>She lured them here with the promise of sex.  Imagine the anger and hatred she must have felt returning to this place. Did she use that to help her pull the trigger? Carrie snaps another shot. Flash!! The blinding flash</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian stops talking. Carrie scans the darkness. From the quiet... A Thunderous Roar!!</context>
      <utterance>Shhhhhhhhh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PRETTY TEENAGE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girl reaches out, steadies his trembling hand... and pulls the red hot coil to the cigarette between her lips. When... in a THUNDEROUS CRASH!! The glistening wet rock comes smashing through their windshield!!!!</context>
      <utterance>...nothing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FROM SOMEWHERE IN THE BLACKNESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The distant echo of a Woman's voice.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIM</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you dead or alive?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KIM</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Brian is distracted, distant, not paying attention to the game of "Twenty Questions" that he is playing.</context>
      <utterance>Brian?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIM</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Obviously!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man or woman?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie tunes in and pays attention to the game.</context>
      <utterance>Man.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Real or fictional.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Real.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian's eyes dart to Carrie. The look on his face tells everyone she nailed it. Brian gets up to get another drink. Several people laugh, amazed that Carrie knows Brian so well.</context>
      <utterance>Ted Bundy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a guess!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't count, she's disqualified.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because you've been living with him, and his thesis for the last year and a half.  He's probably been researching Ted Bundy all week.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carl looks over to Carrie. She gives him the finger and a cheeky smile. CAROL, sitting next to Carrie, asks...</context>
      <utterance>Carl, you are the world's worst loser!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any word from that gallery?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nervous?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Apprehensive. Let's not forget these are the people who banned the Mapplethorpe show. Anyway, California's loaded with galleries.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie watches Brian disappear into another room.</context>
      <utterance>You mean 'Ted Bundy's' finally agreed to leave?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Soon as he finishes his thesis.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie lights a cigarette. Her frustration is showing.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, Eric's been "finishing" his for over three years now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets up and begins weaving her way through the crowded room. Carol follows.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well Brian's got 'til the end of the summer, then I'm outta here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, but I just can't see you veggin' out in LA-LA LAND.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie and Carol share a strained laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I don't know... I think that once I dye my hair blonde, buy a string bikini and cultivate that tan... I could be veggin' out with the best of 'em...  Like fer shurr!</utterance>
   <speaker>OMITTED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eric dumps in a handful of ice cubes as Brian pours in the booze.</context>
      <utterance>I'm talking about the mind and culpability of a serial killer. Someone who has no ability to distinguish between right and wrong should not be imprisoned, let alone executed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, here we go again. Let's just lay it all at the altar of misfiring synapses, amok biochemicals and horrendous childhoods.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, it's a fact, most of these people suffer from a severe chemical brain imbalance.  That enough Tequila?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian pours in the rest of the bottle.</context>
      <utterance>Probably not...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls open the refrigerator door and grabs two beers. Carrie steps up behind Brian.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, until it's your mother's head they find in the refrigerator.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Executing the killer wouldn't bring my mother back.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian turns to see Carrie now behind him. She wraps her arms around his neck.</context>
      <utterance>Thank god!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ha, ha.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but it'd sure make you feel better, wouldn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Peter finds triple sec in the refrigerator.</context>
      <utterance>No, it wouldn't make me feel better.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eric takes the triple sec from Peter and pours some in the blender. He turns it on. It whines.</context>
      <utterance>...Looking for this?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I have to listen to one more "tweed" talk about his dissertation, I'm going to throw up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Label it anyway you want, the bottom line is these people are evil, plain and simple.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, now you want to talk about good versus evil? Well then let's start with Adam and Eve and the snake.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who do I have to blow to get out of here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A... I gotta go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coffee and a bowl of chili, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The only other customer is an OLD MAN, sitting at the counter nearby nursing a cup of coffee. His face half hidden under a rain soaked hat. Early selects a tune from the countertop juke box.</context>
      <utterance>...Be right there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OLD MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early gazes at the Old Man curiously, then calls out to the waitress...</context>
      <utterance>The Antichrist'll be a woman, in a man's body. Seven heads and seven tails.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early notices the small bug crawling across the counter. He leans closer to it and watches it. After a moment, he THWACKS it off the counter with his thumb and finger. The bug lands on the hot iron griddle with a SIZZLE! EARLY glances at the Old Man again... then scoots over one stool closer to him. Early seems curious to want to get a glimpse under the brim of the Old Man's hat.</context>
      <utterance>Make that to go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Waitress spins a startled look to the booth beyond hers! Early leans out from behind the highback partition.</context>
      <utterance>...Size 6.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Waitress... smiles, nods shyly.</context>
      <utterance>That's right ain't it, size 6?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Happy birthday Adele.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is ADELE CORNERS. She's 17, pretty, uneducated and Early's girlfriend. She steps over to him, gives him a kiss, then sits down on the seat across from him. She starts to try on her new shoes.</context>
      <utterance>Early, you are so sweet.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel kind of like the wizard of oz, you know when she gets the red shoes.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She passes the bag to Early. He digs in. Between bites, he glances over to Adele who's enthusiastically pulling on the new shoes.</context>
      <utterance>Well Dorothy, why don't you hand me that chili there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tonight turned out to be pretty interesting.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The party? She grabs a leather cap that sits on a chair.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The warehouse. I'm not that drunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie's dress falls to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>It was definitely the high point of the evening.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just being there where it really happened. It was different... more visceral.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian is at the foot of the bed, he turns to see... Carrie has transformed. She has stripped down to her black bra and panties, fishnet stockings, a nightporter style leather cap. A surprised Brian stands there a moment. Looking at Carrie. She looks great.</context>
      <utterance>Mmm... I love it when you talk like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>OMITTED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carrie pushes Brian back onto the bed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You thirsty Lucy?</utterance>
   <speaker>OMITTED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She waters her small cactus .</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bet that feels good, don't it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances around to make certain that no one's looking, then 'flashes' her body to Early with a giggle.</context>
      <utterance>Early...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early smiles. Adele turns back into the trailer then, remembers...</context>
      <utterance>Have a good one.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early looks at the run down house next door where Diebold lives. A beat up red pick-up is parked in front.</context>
      <utterance>Oh... I forgot to tell you, Mr. Diebold was by again yesterday.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said, if he ain't got the rest of his money by the end of the month, he's gonna "kick us the...  F-U-C-K outta here." Early works his jaw, thinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele nods.</context>
      <utterance>He said that, huh? Cursed in front of you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early gets in his car.</context>
      <utterance>You gonna talk to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early revs the raspy engine.</context>
      <utterance>If he comes back, don't answer the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele's words are unheard as Early pulls away flinging his beer bottle at a couple of chained PITBULLS in Diebold's front yard.</context>
      <utterance>Suppose he hears me inside?</utterance>
   <speaker>OMITTED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian turns the corner, he's immediately greeted by a series of erotic images being projected on the far wall. They are slides of Carrie's photographic work. In regard to the nature and content of Carrie's photographic work, her photographs address the sexual collision of opposites. "What if's." The subjects of her photographs are hypothetical and highly unlikely partners. Studies in contract. Moments of passion.</context>
      <utterance>I picked up some Chinese. Did you hear from the gallery?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From across the room, he hears Carrie's disembodied voice. He drifts toward the couch.</context>
      <utterance>You got your slides back.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian finds her slumped down on the couch. He sits down. She's got a drink in her hand. A bottle on her lap. She continues to click through the slides. As she rambles on, it's obvious that she's definitely under the influence of something 90 proof.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, same old shit. Too graphic... not suitable for mass consumption... one of those... I forget. Who cares.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian can see she's upset. Drowsy from the booze. He just watches her. Listens. Her words linger in his head.</context>
      <utterance>Christ Brian I'm dying here... you are too, you just don't know it yet. You're too busy working on that damned thesis... And, thing is... when you finally do finish it, it's just gonna get filed away on some shelf at the University Library... then what?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you wanted to be a writer.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you can write anywhere. Let's get out of here, while we still can.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carrie, come on... we can leave anytime we...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No we can't. We can never leave once you start talking about tenure... and vacation pay... and parking privileges and... oh shit! let's just go to California now, right now, before it's too late.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...just like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The bold graphic sexual photographs of Carrie's continue to accentuate her comments.</context>
      <utterance>Just like that. Load up the Lincoln... point it West... stop when we hit the fucking ocean.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian notices an envelope on the floor nearby. He picks it up. Opens it. Inside, he finds the photographs Carrie took at the warehouse. Interested, he shuffles through them. He becomes more and more intrigued with what he sees.</context>
      <utterance>That's half the kick anyway. Doing something you've never done before. Experiencing something... different. Something... unpredictable.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances over to Carrie... she's fallen asleep. He reaches over and quietly pulls the drink glass from her hand.</context>
      <utterance>...These are great.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early spots his PAROLE OFFICER standing in the bedroom area snooping around. He has a prosthetic hand which he uses to search through Early's things.</context>
      <utterance>Adele, who's car's that out...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAROLE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Parole Officer hiccups throughout the scene.</context>
      <utterance>She's not here.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early notices the man looking through some of his letters and papers.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doin' here? I ain't supposed to be at the Parole Office 'til tomorrow, two o'clock.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAROLE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Parole Officer opens one of the closet doors, pilfers through things inside, as if searching for something. Early is getting pissed off but says nothing.</context>
      <utterance>Social call.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAROLE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're supposed to call me when you lose your job Early. I stopped by the mirror factory today, you left quite a mess behind there.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lifts his crudely bandaged middle finger.</context>
      <utterance>Wasn't my fault...</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parole Officer steps over to the refrigerator, opens it, snoops around inside.</context>
      <utterance>...It was dangerous there and they treated me like shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAROLE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He finishes with the refrigerator and continues his search through the drawers and cabinets of the trailer.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah... Well you never have been 'treated right'... Have you?  Your father was pickin' on you when he threw you out of the house for stealing the tires off his truck. The Marines misunderstood you when they gave you that dishonorable discharge.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAROLE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...The police were way out of line when they stopped you from beating that bartender half to death. And no doubt God'll be pickin' on you on Judgement Day...</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Parole Officer ignores the question. He steps up to a sink overflowing with dirty dishes.</context>
      <utterance>I ain't got nothing against God. It's the people he let come into the world... lot of them should have been stopped at the door. What are you looking for?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAROLE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early dismisses the place with a glance.</context>
      <utterance>That girlfriend of yours ain't much for housekeeping, is she.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early opens the refrigerator, grabs a bottle of beer.</context>
      <utterance>I'm thinking about moving...</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early sits down at the table. The Parole Officer steps over to him.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe down to Texas... Probably get some work on them offshore oil rigs. Hear the pay's good... hell, the weather's got to be better'n here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAROLE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Parole Officer pulls a slip of paper from his shirt pocket, sets it on the table.</context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about? You know you can't leave the state.  What you can do is get a job.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAROLE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You be at this personnel office, Friday, three o'clock sharp.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAROLE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Janitor's job.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early lifts his beer for another drink. The Parole Officer's prosthetic hand snaps tight around the neck of the beer bottle, just inches from Early's lips.</context>
      <utterance>Oh man... come on, I don't want no janitor job.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAROLE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that Early looks up at the man, almost defiantly, then stands up. The Parole Officer hiccups again. Early stares at him for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, I don't give two shits about what you want or don't want... I'm telling you to be there Friday, three o'clock sharp or the sheriff will be here for dinner. You understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Parole Officer shakes his head in disgust and walks out of the trailer to his car.</context>
      <utterance>You oughta think about putting a bag over your head... Might cure them hiccups.</utterance>
   <speaker>OMITTED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. I didn't have the heart to wake you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie grabs his container of Chinese and takes a few bites. Listens.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I sat down with my tapes and your photographs, which are great by the way... and I started writing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how's it going?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie glances over his shoulder at his writing.</context>
      <utterance>...I think it's the best stuff I've done.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and I think I know why.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I was there. And for a moment that night I understood how she came to pull the trigger.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This mean your finally going to finish your thesis?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, fuck the thesis. I think there's a book here. Your photographs and my research, together.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A book on the warehouse murders?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian reaches down to the floor and pulls a large map of the United States up and lays it out on his desk. He traces a route West. Along the way, specific locations have been circled.</context>
      <utterance>A book on some of the most infamous murderers in America. I want to go to where they lived and where they killed and I want you to photograph it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I'm thinking is, we can drop down through Tennessee, across Arkansas and into Texas, from there it's a straight shot into California.  "We don't stop... until we hit the fucking ocean."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's about fucking time, Kessler! I'd just about given up on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie steps up to Brian.</context>
      <utterance>We don't have enough money, but we'll figure something out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian looks at the container of Chinese in his hand. Carrie takes it from him, sets it down on the road map. Kisses him.</context>
      <utterance>...It's either the best idea I've had in a long time... or there's way too much MSG in this stuff.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DIEBOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold on a minute there boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early tries the engine again. Still won't start. Diebold, getting closer. The dogs are barking.</context>
      <utterance>Shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>DIEBOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hurriedly, Early tries the engine one more time. It starts. Grinning from ear to ear, Early pulls away before Diebold and his dogs reach him. Pissed, Diebold grabs a rock and hurls it, hitting Early's car. The car stops, dead in its tracks.</context>
      <utterance>Goddamit, you're gonna settle up that rent here and now.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIEBOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've had it with your bullshit boy. I want my money.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NEW ANGLE - DIEBOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As soon as the Grand Prix is out of sight...</utterance>
   <speaker>DIEBOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele starts laughing, she tries to hide it with her hand.</context>
      <utterance>That's it! You tell him... I want you both the fuck out of here by Sunday or I'm gonna call the Police.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIEBOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Muttering to himself, he turns back toward his house. He then notices what Adele is laughing at. One pitbull is trying to hump the other.</context>
      <utterance>...You won't be laughing come Sunday little girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIEBOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elvis! Get the fuck off him!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>CAROL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian glances over his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>You know, they say one of these days...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carol peers over Brian's shoulder and reads the note.</context>
      <utterance>...the whole thing's going to slide into the ocean... Yeah, I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Looking for someone to take turns at the wheel and share expenses... on a week long cross country blue- highways tour of historic murder sites..."  You gotta be kidding. Who in their right mind would want to do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian smiles at her and walks away.</context>
      <utterance>...I would.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>Like I said...</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carol turns to see Early.</context>
      <utterance>Where's the personnel office at?</utterance>
   <speaker>RITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks away. Early's eye catches the bulletin board, he sees in bold red marker - "CALIFORNIA."</context>
      <utterance>First door on the left.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks carefully around the junk piles. It's dark; hard to see. She comes to the edge of a deep dark hole and peers in... She can't see anything but hears the rustling of a shovel digging.</context>
      <utterance>Early?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sound of digging stops.</context>
      <utterance>Early? You down there?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's up Adele? Dinner ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a moment's hesitation, Early resumes his digging.</context>
      <utterance>Almost.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The digging stops again.</context>
      <utterance>Early...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The moonlight illuminates his face when he looks up at her.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me more about California.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... for one thing... They think faster out there, on account of all that warm weather they got; cold weather makes people stupid, that's a fact.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess that'd explain why there's so many stupid people around here.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, and in California you never have to buy fruit 'cause it's all on the trees everywhere you turn...  ...and, 'course there ain't no speed limit out there, and all drugs are legal... And I heard your first month's rent is free; state law. I figure 'til we get settled we can just move around month to month...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'll we do out there?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early lets out a playful howl, as Adele looks up over her shoulder at the moon.</context>
      <utterance>Well... the very first thing we're gonna do... is get us a couple of six packs of Lucky Lager and climb up on toppa' that famous Hollywood sign and howl at the moon...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know... I read once... Ain't nothin' on that big old moon 'cept some old golf balls those astronauts left behind.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele smiles and begins walking back to the trailer.</context>
      <utterance>Bull. That ain't right... Government sends people there all the time, just don't want us to know about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be long now, dinner's 'bout ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a moment, Early climbs out of the hole and stands in the moonlight for a moment. We see that he's completely naked except for a pair of high top steel toed work boots. Early gazes up into the night sky, looking at the cold white moon.</context>
      <utterance>I heard that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian throws the bags in the open trunk with the other bags.</context>
      <utterance>Real polite. Kept calling me 'sir.'</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still think we should have met them first.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie bows her head and folds her hands in mock prayer.</context>
      <utterance>Beggars can't be choosers. They were the only ones who answered the ride share note, remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian throws a needling glance to Carrie and slams the car hood shut. They both get into the car, Brian behind the wheel.</context>
      <utterance>Please God, we're gonna be stuck with these people for a week, don't let them be as boring as Brian's friends. Anything... but that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah... He had a real thick accent right outta "Deliverance."  "Still? Who said anything about a still? Get ya ass up in them woods!"</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian starts the car. It backfires loudly startling Carrie. Brian laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Funny, very funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Aintry? This river don't go to Aintry."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera slowly reveals Adele... and the fact that she is alone as she voices her concerns. Then from behind her Early approaches. Just in time to hear...</context>
      <utterance>We shouldn't be doin' this, Early. You leavin' the state, ridin' around with strangers... besides, what kinda people would want to stop at places where other people was murdered.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if they're dangerous?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Startled, Adele drops her shoulder bag. It lands on top of a couple of cardboard boxes and a beat up old duffle bag -- all their possessions. A few personal items spill out of it.</context>
      <utterance>They ain't dangerous Adele. They're writers.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kneels down to pick things up.</context>
      <utterance>Early Grayce!</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you settle things with Mr. Diebold?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah I left him with the car... We're all squared up now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He angrily reaches in and grabs it.</context>
      <utterance>What's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches for the cactus but misses.</context>
      <utterance>Early!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele bites her lip almost crying. Suddenly, Early looks past Adele to see something, Adele turns too.</context>
      <utterance>What kind of a person would carry a cactus in her purse!</utterance>
   <speaker>NEW ANGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Lincoln comes gliding into view.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian honks the horn, Early waves back.</context>
      <utterance>You've got to be kidding me, they look like Okies!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus... They've probably got five bucks between them. Turn around.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lighten up...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Geez, they look kinda weird.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just smile, let me do all the talking.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many times you gonna tell me that?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As many times as it takes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An awkward moment as everyone just stands there... until Brian reaches for Adele's bag.</context>
      <utterance>Hi I'm Brian... Early, and you must be Adele.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian picks up her bag and carries it to the Lincoln. Adele is instantly won over by the gesture -- Early leery of it.</context>
      <utterance>Let me help you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, I'm Adele.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns away from the window...</context>
      <utterance>Carrie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie turns back, rolls down window...</context>
      <utterance>I like your hair.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Pardon?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I said, I like your hair.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns and sees Early reflected in the side mirror watching her. He grins at her, Carrie looks away.</context>
      <utterance>...Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tight fit.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian looks to him, Early grins and winks. Brian slams the Lincoln trunk lid shut.</context>
      <utterance>Best kind.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, we can stop somewhere if you and Adele haven't had time for breakfast, Early.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's like this, Mr. Kessler.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brian.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian raises his eyebrow a tad, but is not really curious about it.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it's like this, Bri'. I don't eat much in the mornin', never have. Maybe a beer once in a while; Lucky Lager's my favorite.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A glance passes between Brian and Carrie. Is she for real?</context>
      <utterance>It's because of what he read in a book once... That folks needin' breakfast is a myth, or whatever, put out by those cereal people.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE'S POV - IN VANITY MIRROR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Early motions Adele not to talk so much.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what do you do Early?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh... I do some work up at the Merrick Mirror factory, or I used to...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One night we figured out how much bad luck he must have comin' from all them mirrors he broke...  Four hundred and ninety four years to work it all off... After he dies, he'll have to keep coming back to earth over and over and over...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele and early show no sign of understanding the word.</context>
      <utterance>Karma.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Karma...  You know, if you do something bad to somebody fate will pay you back by something bad happening to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie glances at the odometer on the dash... THE FIRST MILE clicks over.</context>
      <utterance>That French ain't it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON ADELE'S REFLECTION IN MIRROR... then Early leans in front of her.</context>
      <utterance>So Adele, did Early happen to mention the places we'll be stopping at?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele leans against Carrie's front seat.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah Bri' I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you takin' the pictures?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it hard to learn?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early pulls Adele back toward the back seat.</context>
      <utterance>Not really.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gonna talk to the people who did those murders?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a good idea. Unfortunately most of them have been executed.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Too bad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>PAROLE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAROLE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His Parole Officer.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right, I talked to you on the phone. They say it's a torch job, that sound like your boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAROLE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could be.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where would we find him?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAROLE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell if I know, crazy son of a bitch said he was thinking of moving to Texas.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see the smoldering remains of Early's Grand Prix. In the background Diebold's pitbulls are being dragged away by a Dog Wrangler.</context>
      <utterance>Without his car?</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the owner of the house...  ...this John Diebold, any idea where he might be?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAROLE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From inside Early's hole we hear a voice call out.</context>
      <utterance>No, but I can tell you he's not gonna be too happy about this.</utterance>
   <speaker>LABORER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Parole Officer and Police Officer turn back toward the trailer, as people rush to the site.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PAROLE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Diebold?</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...That'd be my guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAROLE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like somebody cut off his ring finger.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men look to one another... as others begin to unearth the body.</context>
      <utterance>Well now I'd say that's the least of Mr. Diebold's problems.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early reaches in the bag and pulls out a small plastic bottle of mineral water and an orange juice.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie turns around, Early hands her the water. Early leans forward and hands Brian the orange juice.</context>
      <utterance>All right, who gets the...  ...water.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then Early reaches past Brian to the rear-view mirror and hangs a plastic St. Christopher statue around it.</context>
      <utterance>Here you go Bri'. Got a couple a bags of chips and some jerky, just holler if you want some.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much do I owe you?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele struggles to understand the camera instructions on the side of the box. She leans forward and shows Carrie her camera.</context>
      <utterance>Forget it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie deliberates her response for a moment, then...</context>
      <utterance>Guess I don't know the first thing about cameras.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie pulls a roll of film out of her bag and takes Adele's camera to load.</context>
      <utterance>Well, the first thing... is you need film. Preferably black and white.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wouldn't have any color film, would ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls a roll of color film out of her camera bag and quickly snaps it into the camera.</context>
      <utterance>...Yeah, sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie points the camera at a smiling Adele and snaps the first picture.</context>
      <utterance>I like things in color, pink, purple, and red. I dunno, black and white is kinda... boring.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele takes the camera.</context>
      <utterance>You just aim and press the button.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Pigeon Forge!</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE'S POV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Road sign to Pigeon Forge.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shush, Adele.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Early, can we stop there... just for a little while.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances to Carrie, who fires off several photos of the fence and yard. The Lincoln continues slowly down the long drive... Up ahead through the windshield Brian sees a beautiful old farm house.</context>
      <utterance>The Novaks are all gone but the fence that Michael Zaruba was hired to put up is still here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Novaks embraced the young drifter as one of their own.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian and Carrie turn to see... Adele training a camera on them.</context>
      <utterance>Hey you two.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian and Carrie look to one another then force a weak smile. Early jumps in and throws a pair of devil's horns up behind Brian's unsuspecting head as... the shutter clicks. Brian and Carrie quickly turn their attention back on the house.</context>
      <utterance>Give me a smile now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An unusual bird house and a tricycle sit in the front yard. To the side of the house are the remains of an old swing set. Carrie finds an interesting angle on the swing set, with the house in the background, SNAP! She fires off a shot.</context>
      <utterance>Neighbors said he was a quiet young man, who was often seen pushing the children on the swing set.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early is surprised that they don't want him in the photograph. He wanders away from the front of the house. Meanwhile, Adele photographs the moment.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Early... Could you step out the way, for a second?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then... A NINE YEAR OLD GIRL comes running from around the side of the house. She stops dead when she sees all of them. Carrie snaps a final photo.</context>
      <utterance>The first one to die was the nine year old daughter...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The little girl scans all their faces.</context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The little girl remains silent. Brian rolls a look to Carrie then back to the little girl.</context>
      <utterance>...My name's Brian, what's yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After an awkward pause, the little girl silently crosses the yard to the porch and opens the front door.</context>
      <utterance>...Could I speak to your parents?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pa! There's more of them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The father says nothing and does not respond to the extended hand. Brian retracts his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, my name is Brian Kessler.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a writer, I'm working on a book about famous murderers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Brian can finish, the man slams the door in his face.</context>
      <utterance>...I mean, this was the Novak house...  With your permission I'd like to come in and photograph...</utterance>
   <speaker>FARMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamned ghouls...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We could have been in and out of there in less than ten minutes...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian continues on in a huff until Carrie breaks stride and stops. She pulls him next to her.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, I got some great stuff... it's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian glances back at the house. She interrupts his glance, kisses him.</context>
      <utterance>It's okay... okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They enter the car.</context>
      <utterance>...That house is part of American history now, whether he likes it or not.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie, surprised at Early's new found philosophical belief. She looks into her side view mirror... And sees Early smiling back at her. Carrie looks away...</context>
      <utterance>Forget about it Bri'. I wouldn't be surprised if that Karma thing don't come back and get him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early doesn't bother to respond. He keeps eating.</context>
      <utterance>Well we've come three hundred miles so far. Not a bad day's haul.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got any family or friends in California, Early?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me neither. How 'bout you Carrie?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early winks at Brian, Carrie catches the wink. Early and Adele get up and head for the door. Adele waves goodnight.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks Bri', I'll get the next one.  Think it's time we hit the sack.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sweet dreams.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He can't help the way he was raised. I kinda feel sorry for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Feel sorry for him? Obviously you didn't get a whiff of that sock?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bitch, bitch, bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Up yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you believe thirty bucks for this room... for what? A lumpy mattress, that crummy TV and a crapper.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Early continues to sift through all the items from the purse.</context>
      <utterance>Early, sing me a song.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which one.</utterance>
   <speaker>OMITTED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Early start sing with her... As the song ends.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey can we go to that Chinese restaurant when we get to Los Angeles? You know, to see all them famous footprints?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...And all I'm saying is I think we ought to try and get along with them. That's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You try, I'm gonna pretend they're with somebody else.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carrie.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian turns the light off. From the blackness...</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to talk about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian switches the light back on.</context>
      <utterance>Pretty smooth how he stiffed us on dinner?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence... Brian reaches out for the light... when</context>
      <utterance>He didn't stiff us. He paid for the gas remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian decides to leave the light on. He moves closer to Carrie. He slides up against her backside. He reaches for her under the sheets. Kisses her neck.</context>
      <utterance>I'm telling you he's nearly broke and we're going to end up paying for those two.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie pushes her body up against his in response.</context>
      <utterance>You finished?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian's mouth moves down along her back. He slips beneath the sheets. From the expression on her face, she obviously approves... Yet she can't resist slipping in another remark...</context>
      <utterance>...Um, maybe... maybe not.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie rolls over on her back. Brian moves on top of her. Kisses her stomach.</context>
      <utterance>...Um... Funky fucking sock.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie reaches down and grabs two fists full of Brian's hair. She pulls him to her. He slides up along her chest, kissing her. Things heat up. She reaches out, grasps his arms. Pulls him closer.</context>
      <utterance>...and what's with that hair? Is that grease or motor oil or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian bites at her neck. She stops talking. His sweating shoulder presses against her face. She turns her head to encourage him. In the dresser mirror... she sees their shadowy reflections. Their bodies atangle under the sheets.</context>
      <utterance>...you believe that tattoo? Looks like he had another girls name there and carved it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their reflection in the mirror intrigues her. Intoxicates her. His aggression excites her. She pulls him into her. The metal bedframe bangs against the motel wall repeatedly as they make love. Then slowly, the camera bisects the plaster and lumber divider and emerges in the next room...</context>
      <utterance>...and that body odor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early lifts his beer bottle in salute.</context>
      <utterance>Morning...</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bri'.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Adele?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The WAITRESS arrives with a menu, offers it to Early.</context>
      <utterance>She wasn't feeling so good.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Breakfast?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Waitress notices Early's bottle of beer.</context>
      <utterance>Nah... Don't eat breakfast. Never have.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets Early's attention.</context>
      <utterance>Ah sir... sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We ah... don't have a liquor license here. So I'm afraid...</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Waitress gives him a curious look and walks away. Just then, Brian look past Early... A surprised expression crosses Brian's face. Early turns to see... Adele approaching the table. Her hair has been crudely chopped to resemble Carrie's. It looks like shit.</context>
      <utterance>Well don't be, I got plenty more where this one came from.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele smiles, pleased with Carrie for noticing. She sits down next to Brian.</context>
      <utterance>You cut your hair.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...Once he gets an idea in his head there's no holding him back. Carrie looks to Brian curiously. Adele is distracted by a small cactus on the window near the table.</context>
      <utterance>Early cut it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie notices Adele's 'new' (stolen) purse... We see the wheels turning in Carrie's head. How? Where?</context>
      <utterance>Nice job Early.</utterance>
   <speaker>OMITTED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Need a hand with those bags?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, thanks, I can manage.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up her bags and walks out of the room. Carrie watches him, then she steps to the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>I got 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All set?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take your time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This the book your writing?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just a work in progress, kinda rough.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This guy killed a mess of people.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Henry Lucas.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Henry Lee Lucas. Well he was only convicted of killing eleven but he claimed to have killed over three hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wonder what all them people done made him so mad? Brian looks to Early in his rear-view mirror.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early takes over. He pulls off his shirt, jacks the car up and begins replacing the wheel with ease.</context>
      <utterance>Here Bri' let me do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did he get away with it for so long anyhow?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie scans the landscape with her camera. She sees Adele walking around a small roadside graveyard. She is reading the epitaphs on the headstones. Carrie fires off a few shots. Then she sees Early, she can't help but notice Early's lean body. She zooms in on his muscles and prison tattoo. Click!! Early completes the task. Together he and Brian begin putting everything back in the trunk. Suddenly, from behind, Adele jumps onto Early's back, surprising him. He gives her a "horsey ride" around the Lincoln.</context>
      <utterance>He almost always killed strangers. Spent years moving on from one place to another. That made it real hard to track him down.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENEATH THE LINCOLN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Early's feet galloping.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You dropped this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands the wallet back to him. Something between them goes unspoken.</context>
      <utterance>Early Grayce if this ain't your lucky day.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her remark gets Carrie's attention.</context>
      <utterance>I used to smoke before I met Early. But he broke me of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Broke you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Early don't think women should smoke or curse or drink liquor.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie takes a quick look to the mini-market. She's lost sight of Early.</context>
      <utterance>So you don't do any of those things.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better not, or Early'd whip me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He whips you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early puts his arm around Brian and turns him back toward the car.</context>
      <utterance>...Then some.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Comes to twenty eight dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie points to Early. As Brian and Early approach the car, Early pulls out the money clip.</context>
      <utterance>Talk to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early peels off thirty bucks from the money clip. He sees Carrie watching him, Early smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Call it an even thirty.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hearing that, Carrie climbs into the back seat. Adele climbs over the backrest into the frontseat.</context>
      <utterance>I'll drive Bri'.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She climbs again into the backseat.</context>
      <utterance>Adele, get in the back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Hey you're good. Thought you said you never played before?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't... I'm a fast learner.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...They never caught that Black Dolya Killer, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dahlia, no.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now why is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some people think it's because he never killed again. He just disappeared back into society.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't sound too convinced 'bout that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I always thought it was the work of a serial killer. Anyone who took that much time and care bisecting another human being must have been enjoying it and would have done it again. And again. Until someone stopped him.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That your... "theory", ain't that what they call it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie listens in as she continues to play cards with Adele.</context>
      <utterance>You wanna hear mine?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian picks up his tape recorder.</context>
      <utterance>Ain't you goin' to record it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian hands Early the hand held tape recorder.</context>
      <utterance>Early Grayce, June twenty third.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You lose!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Carrie appears at the door holding her camera.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Minnesota Fats!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands Brian the key.</context>
      <utterance>Don't forget your key.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian takes the key and walks to the car. Carrie sees Adele standing outside her door. Brian enters the Lincoln.</context>
      <utterance>Why'd I open my big mouth?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Lincoln pulls away.</context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you go with them?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you how Early feels 'bout a woman drinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie swings the camera around to Adele, and snaps off a shot.</context>
      <utterance>How'd you meet Early?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know I can fix that haircut for you, if you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian exits the Lincoln and looks at Early questioning.</context>
      <utterance>I wonder if there's any "doors" out here?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian looks at him blankly. He can't think of a thing to say in response. Early walks toward the entrance of the bar. Brian joins him.</context>
      <utterance>You know... "openings" to other dimensions.  I read there are a lot of them out West, mostly in the desert. They say if you know what you're doing, you can travel anywhere in the Universe in a matter of seconds. Wouldn't that come in handy?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By the way, I'm not much of a pool player.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit, it ain't hard to play pool. I can teach you everything ya need ta know.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell yeah! I'll even spot ya a few points first game.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute. You're gonna hustle me?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both laugh and enter the bar.</context>
      <utterance>Nah... how much money have you got?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie looks in the mirror.</context>
      <utterance>How do you get your cigarette to stay there like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie takes out a fresh cigarette and hands it to Adele. Together they stare into the mirror with their dangling cigarettes. Adele drops her cigarette, as she reaches down for it she notices Carrie's portfolio.</context>
      <utterance>Could I try that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a portfolio of my work.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your pictures. Can I see 'em?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele grabs the black leather binder and sets it in her lap. Carrie continues to cut Adele's hair. Adele opens the binder and takes a look at the first erotic image and slaps the cover back down. She's embarrassed.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie watches her in amusement. After a moment, Adele reconsiders, and opens the book. She gazes at the shocking photograph.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus!</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You took this picture?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie resumes cutting Adele's hair. Adele thumbs through several photographs.</context>
      <utterance>Took 'em all.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No it is not!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold still.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele notices Carrie's scowl in the dresser mirror. Carrie stops cutting.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry. Boy I'll tell ya, if Early found a picture of me like that I'd be black and blue for a week.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shouldn't let him do that to you...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do what?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Adele... are you serious?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think Early's bad to me, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie starts cutting Adele's hair again.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When Carrie doesn't respond, Adele grabs Carrie's scissor hand and stops her from continuing. Carrie looks at Adele's reflection in the dresser mirror.</context>
      <utterance>Well... You're wrong. I ain't saying Early ain't never hit me... but he never hurt me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...When I was fourteen years old three boys raped me in the back of a truck, and beat me so bad I was in bed for almost four months...  ...I feel safe with Early, most the time he treats me pretty good. And I know he wouldn't let nothin' like that ever happen to me again... Carrie is speechless, Adele looks in the mirror at her new haircut.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, that ain't so bad now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LARGE YOUNG CRACKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She spins safely out of his reach.</context>
      <utterance>When you gonna give me so o' that!</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some guys, close enough to hear her over the noise, laugh at her put down. She moves on until she reaches... Brian standing near a small high table. Early's not with him. She sets four beers down on the table. Brian tries to talk to her over the music. He leans in close. His mouth to her ear.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe when you grow up a little sonny.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These aren't Lucky Lager, I ordered Lucky Lager.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waitress laughs. Brian smiles and glances around the room. He notices the Large Young Cracker staring at him.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry honey, 'ain't nothin Lucky around here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>YOUNG CRACKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Young Cracker is obviously very drunk.</context>
      <utterance>What did you say to her city boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing, I jus...</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With his eyes on Brian, Early grabs a beer. Brian is scared, and confused, with one ear and one eye on the Young Cracker, the other on Early.</context>
      <utterance>You'd better hit him first Bri', 'cos it's comin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG CRACKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This yur' boyfriend?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early looks at the beer.</context>
      <utterance>Hit him.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG CRACKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian is frozen, confused, doesn't know who to address. Early continues to ignore the Young Cracker.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Asshole!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't stock it here Early.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG CRACKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Young Cracker moves to hit Early. Early swiftly smashes his beer bottle into the oncoming face. The Young Cracker doubles over clutching his face in agony. Early kicks him in the face, sending the Young Cracker to the ground. Early finishes him off with several more kicks from his heavy work boots. Two large tough guys approach Early and Brian. Brian's heart racing, Early cool as a cucumber. Instead of taking on Early, they stop, reach down and drag the unconscious man away. The waitress returns to their table.</context>
      <utterance>Why you fuckin'...</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sets down two beers and two shots, doubles.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry about that, he's always causing trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are on the house.</utterance>
   <speaker>OMITTED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My momma's a beautician. Guess that's where I get it from. She wouldn't hear of my moving in with Early... on account of his just getting out of jail and all. Ain't seen her in nearly a year now. I wish she'd call me, just once.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's Early been in jail for?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carryin' a gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Anything else?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An' resistin' arrest... At least that's what the Police said.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele realizes she has said too much, looks at her watch.</context>
      <utterance>Jeez... Adele!</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele hastily weaves her way out the door.</context>
      <utterance>I'd better be goin'. It's late.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie stares down at her feet. Red toenails. Cottonballs between the toes.</context>
      <utterance>Great.</utterance>
   <speaker>OMITTED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian looks at Early, doesn't understand.</context>
      <utterance>Got to see a man about a mule.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early branches off behind the car.</context>
      <utterance>Gotta take a piss.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early starts to take a leak.</context>
      <utterance>Any reebs left in the back seat?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's what we used to call a beer when we was kids... Beer spelled backwards. Brian reaches in the back seat and grabs the last Lucky Lager. He crosses to the other side of the car and hands Early the beer.</context>
      <utterance>Aaahhhhh...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last one. Early stares at the last of the Lucky Lagers.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Well I probably drunk more than my share, anyway... you go on an' have it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early takes the beer.</context>
      <utterance>No, it's all yours. It's on me... for saving my ass back there.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early polishes off the rest of the bottle and heaves it into the woods.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, that's what buddies are for, right...?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When Early opens his eyes, he sees a concerned look on Brian's face.</context>
      <utterance>You know those doors I was talking about? Found two of them back in Kentucky. Shit, I wasn't even looking for one the first time. Me and the boys are just swingin' our sickles by the side of the road, and I turned around and there it was... this door with this bright blinding white light all around it... course I'm thinkin' I must be sunstroked or somethin'... so I close my eyes figurin' I'll count ten and it'll be gone right... so I'm countin'...  ...1-2-3-4-5... an' I'm 'bout ta piss myself right... -6-7-8-9... 10. An' I open my eyes slow, spectin' it won't be there right...</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then Early starts laughing. Brian follows suit. They both climb back in the car. Their forced laughter trails off. Brian shifts the Lincoln back into gear and segues awkwardly...</context>
      <utterance>...and it wasn't. An awkward silence.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early stares at Brian. For a moment Brian is unsure what Early will say, or do? Then Early grins...</context>
      <utterance>What were you "swinging a sickle" for?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian brakes their eye contact, looks back out onto the highway and just drives off.</context>
      <utterance>For... 'bout three years.</utterance>
   <speaker>OMITTED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A few seconds pass.</context>
      <utterance>Gotta see a man about a mule... What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie, in bed, switches on the side table light. Reveals Brian leaning on the wall trying to get his shoes off without falling over.</context>
      <utterance>The same thing that's been "wrong" the whole trip. Your good buddy Early.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who said he's my good buddy?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian points to the empty beer bottles on the table.</context>
      <utterance>You sure been acting like you were...  ...Out whoopin' it up, a drankin' and ever' thang.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian throws his shoes somewhere and heads toward the bathroom.</context>
      <utterance>Hey come on, you two were drinking too... so what's the big deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, and you should've seen how terrified she was that he'd find out. He beats her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She told me...  ...but only when she "deserves" it. Did you know he was in jail?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, from right behind him:</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, for stealing a car. Aaahhhh.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Startled, Brian turns to see Carrie.</context>
      <utterance>Bullshit!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No response from Brian. Carrie walks away.</context>
      <utterance>...He told her it was for carrying a gun, but the truth could be murder for all we know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop being so fucking melodramatic! If it was murder he'd still be locked up or on parole, in which case he wouldn't be allowed to leave the state.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian smacks himself on the forehead (a sarcastic "how stupid of me!") He pulls his shirt off over his head, and admits...</context>
      <utterance>Maybe he wasn't allowed to leave! Geezus Brian!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course! The accent, the clothes, and those table manners!... He's got to be a mass murderer!  What else could he be? He switches off the bathroom light, steps out of the doorway, and begins to pull his jeans off. Carrie climbs into bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian tosses his jeans and moves toward the bed. Carrie switches off the the only light in the room. In the dark, we hear a thud as Brian trips over a chair.</context>
      <utterance>You know, it wouldn't even surprise me if he turned out to be... a Republican!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamnit!... my fucking toe!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't you done enough drinking for tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early reaches past her into the ice machine and grabs a solitary cube. He puts it in his mouth, sucks on it. His torso is drenched in sweat. He catches Carrie staring at him.</context>
      <utterance>...Brian hurt his foot.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes... Don't know why it is... I get so hot I can't stand it. I just start sweating like a dog. You ever get like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early spits the ice cube back into his hand. He presses it against the back of his neck.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie follows a bead of ice water as it slides down between his shoulder blades and along his back.</context>
      <utterance>I can feel it start to run down my neck...  ...and down my back... right into my pants.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He snaps a look back to Carrie and finds her looking at his ass. She diverts her glance.</context>
      <utterance>...and everything starts stickin' together... keeps running down the back of my legs like two rivers racin' for my boots, see who gets there first.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie shakes her head no. Early looks in his hand to see that his ice cube has melted.</context>
      <utterance>You never get that hot, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie tries to slip past him. He reaches back into the machine, momentarily blocking her exit. He grabs another ice cube. His face only inches from hers.</context>
      <utterance>I gotta get back before this ice melts.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...never?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pops the ice cube in his mouth and lets her pass.</context>
      <utterance>No, never. Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No response, Early chews up the ice cube.</context>
      <utterance>You like Skynard?</utterance>
   <speaker>OMITTED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the front seat, Brian's hand springs up in a desperate plea for an end to Adele's colorful description.</context>
      <utterance>My daddy always took sauerkraut juice and tobasco sauce for a hangover, mixed in one egg not two, and some tomato juice...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian rolls down his window for some fresh air, as the car pulls away.</context>
      <utterance>I'm okay, thanks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie nods toward the back seat. Brian turns and sees Adele looking back at them questioningly. Beside her, Early rustles.</context>
      <utterance>What! What!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian notices that Adele's rummaging has revealed an automatic pistol in the open canvas bag. Brian stares at it. Early's eyes open.</context>
      <utterance>Look again!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian fires off another shot, misses again.</context>
      <utterance>Only thing my old man ever gave me is that goddamn .45.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nearby stands an unhappy Carrie. Adele pulls her yoyo out of her pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Bri', you're jerkin' it when you pull the trigger, hold it real steady.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie doesn't respond. Adele offers the yoyo to Carrie.</context>
      <utterance>Boys'll be boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie shakes her head no. Adele withdraws her offer.</context>
      <utterance>You know any tricks?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again Carrie declines. Her steely gaze returns to Brian.</context>
      <utterance>You wanna learn some?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BANG!! The can flies off the tree stump. Brian turns to Carrie to see her reaction... but she's already on her way back to the car, and she's furious. Concerned, Brian starts to follow after her... But Early grabs his attention.</context>
      <utterance>Steady... Breath in... now let half of it out, and... fire.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian gazes at the gun resting in the palm of his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Bri, I want you to keep this gun... consider it a present. Never know, California could turn out to be a dangerous place.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell ya Bri., I'm still a little sleepy,... think Adele and me are gonna take us a fiesta.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie reaches over and takes the keys from the ignition, locks the glove compartment and pockets the key. Both she and Brian exit the car. As they start to walk toward the structure Brian hears a sound, he turns back to see. Adele leaning forward into the frontseat as the lincoln's big white top starts to come up.</context>
      <utterance>Siesta.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Camera in hand, Carrie begins to move about, despite the fact that this place repels her. Brian presses a button on the audio cassette player. The small tinny speaker plays a bad recording of something we slowly come to realize is the unmistakable sounds of a woman being tortured and pleading for her life.</context>
      <utterance>A copy of a tape they found. He recorded everything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian and Carrie walk through the remains of a doorway into another room.</context>
      <utterance>His mother had him working in here before he was eight years old... killing animals with a sledgehammer that was bigger than he was.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pleas for help and screams on the tape subside to a steady whimpering.</context>
      <utterance>When she was pissed at him, she'd beat the shit out of him and lock him in here overnight...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Eventually the boy wakes up one morning, picks up that sledgehammer and starts hurting back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's more...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm finished. Carrie stops to pick up the rest of her gear.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie wheels around to face him.</context>
      <utterance>Look... I know you're pissed off about the gun, and I don't blame you...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She switches off the cassette player.</context>
      <utterance>Brian, I'm not pissed off. God damm it, turn that thing off.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm scared. A week ago you would never have even thought to pick up that gun. This afternoon you're out there wielding it around like Clyde fucking Barrow, for Christ's sake! What's with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, it was a cheap thrill, it was stupid, I admit it, alright?  But let's not blow this. Not now... Let's just get the photos.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe I agreed to do this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh come on, don't give me that shit... you wanted to take these photos as much as I wanted you too.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie storms out of the place. She exits the tunnel, and makes her way toward...</context>
      <utterance>Wrong! I was willing to do whatever it took to get you up off your ass and on the way to California... There's a big difference.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brian I want him out of our car!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, what did he do?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brian get him out of the car. Next gas station either he leaves or I do!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In fact, each time the lightning flashes occur all of the electrical power at the station is affected. The fluorescent lights outside and inside begin to flicker and falter sporadically.</context>
      <utterance>Twenty dollars in the tank and a carton of cigarettes.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie looks at the TV, watches for a moment. It doesn't hold her attention. She looks away and notices Adele leaving the car. Adele walks toward a Coke machine at the other end of the gas station.</context>
      <utterance>...the ex-mental patient with a history of arrests is still at large... Static.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie turns back toward him.</context>
      <utterance>Here's your cigarettes...</utterance>
   <speaker>ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...And change. Better be careful, looks like a bad one coming. Where you headin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>California.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He buttons up his rain coat and goes out into the night to gas up the Lincoln. Carrie pulls a pack of cigarettes from the carton, nervously lights one up. She looks out the window toward the Lincoln.</context>
      <utterance>Hear it never rains there. Must be nice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NEWSCASTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Static.</context>
      <utterance>...we would like to repeat...</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWSCASTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Static.</context>
      <utterance>...there is a nationwide manhunt for...</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWSCASTER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Static.</context>
      <utterance>...is believed responsible for the murders of his landlord John Diebold...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>NEWSCASTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie panics, turns toward the door and runs smack into the arms of a dripping wet Early Grayce! Early stares at her and drops his bag to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>If you see this man...</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then... Early notices himself on the TV.</context>
      <utterance>I ain't ridin' in no bus... bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWSCASTER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Early grabs Carrie around the neck and yanks her into the back office. He pushes her down onto a chair.</context>
      <utterance>...call your local police or FBI... Static.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He searches behind the cash register and finds a sawed-off shotgun. He shuts the TV off.</context>
      <utterance>You just sit there and keep your mouth shut.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Attendant rushes back in from the pouring rain. Early points the sawed-off shotgun at him.</context>
      <utterance>I knew that boy'd have a hogleg here somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early forces him into the office.</context>
      <utterance>Get over here.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele enters the adjacent room. She checks out the various vending machines in search of candy. Early taps on the window and motions her into the office. She sees Carrie in the chair, scared to death, and Early aiming the gun at the Attendant.</context>
      <utterance>Sit your ass down in that corner.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Early, what're you doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele looks back at Carrie, then hurries out. Early empties the cash register.</context>
      <utterance>Go back to the car and keep Brian there. I don't want him in here...  Do it Adele... Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your name, boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Walter Livesy.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think. I might just have to kill you Walter. How do you feel about that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not so good. You sure you have to?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Wish I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Early, just think...</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut your mouth.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele gets in and starts looking under the seats.</context>
      <utterance>Adele, what are you doing back here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Lost my purse... Could you help me look for it? It's probably under the seat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you from Walter?</utterance>
   <speaker>ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vernon, Florida.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never heard of it, any huntin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turkey mostly.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early rips the phone out of the wall.</context>
      <utterance>Turkey's are real smart. Smarter than most people think...</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The attendant nods yes.</context>
      <utterance>Tell you what Walter, you lie down there now... You make sure you stay put for a while after we leave... Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Mind if I hold that Bible?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The attendant has no response.</context>
      <utterance>What do you need a Bible for?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I'm goin' to kill you. Well that'd make me a liar then wouldn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early takes the Bible off the desk and hands it down to the Attendant.</context>
      <utterance>No sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The frightened young man lies face down on his stomach clutching the Bible and starts to pray. On the counter next to him Early notices a large stuffed "happy face" display. "Free with every 20 gallon purchase." He grabs one, stares at its face curiously.</context>
      <utterance>Here you go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the back seat Early wipes some more feathers from his face, then points the Attendant's gun at Brian's head.</context>
      <utterance>Carrie, what's wrong?  Early, we went through this already, you have to leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele starts the car. She pulls out of the station and into the rainstorm.</context>
      <utterance>'Fraid not Bri'... Drive Adele.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian reaches in the glove compartment. He removes the gun and hands it to Early.</context>
      <utterance>Hate to be an Indian-giver but I'm gonna have to ask for my gun back.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie sits in the corner of the back seat, covered in feathers but not even noticing them.</context>
      <utterance>What happened back there?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele turns to the back of the car to face Carrie.</context>
      <utterance>He shot him in the head... oh God!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a killer, Brian... He's fucking insane.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early picks some more feathers off himself.</context>
      <utterance>Everybody just shut up!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You two just cooperate and do what I say, and we'll all arrive safe and sound in California, as planned... unless, of course, Adele don't kill us first with her driving.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is this stuff?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early opens another container. Stares curiously at the contents.</context>
      <utterance>It's Chinese food. It was the only place open. You said you was starving, you'd eat anyth...</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah but, what is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early sets the container down.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, they didn't speak too good English.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele somewhat reluctantly hands Early a bottle of beer from a second bag.</context>
      <utterance>And just what exactly are the Chinese doing here in the middle of the American desert anyway?... Didja get the beer?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early notices that Brian is watching him intently. He mistakes Brian's interest for hunger.</context>
      <utterance>..."Chink" beer!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early pulls out his gun, puts it on the table next to him. Brian sits across from Early. He watches as Early rummages impatiently through the carry out paraphernalia.</context>
      <utterance>Oh hell, I'm sorry Bri. Adele, honey, untie Brian, he's starving over there.  Carrie, you want some? Carrie doesn't respond at all. Adele unties Brian.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frustrated, Early finally takes a gulp of Chinese food right out of the container. It goes down rough.</context>
      <utterance>Where's the damn forks and spoons at!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian picks up a pair of chopsticks, then reconsiders, puts them back down and, like Early, gulps from the container. NEARBY, Carrie sits quietly. As she listens to the two men talk... she notices something on her arm. She lifts her arm up to get a closer look.</context>
      <utterance>...Is it just me, or has this whole trip been goin' downhill ever since we ran outta Lucky Lager?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Well now, how many people d'you see me kill?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>None.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Well then, that's how many I killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you say so.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn right I do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian shakes his head no.</context>
      <utterance>You never killed anyone have you Bri'?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian stops eating and looks at Early.</context>
      <utterance>You never even seen anybody killed, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early leans closer to him.</context>
      <utterance>What are you getting at?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eye to eye, the two men stare at one another. Brian has no answer.</context>
      <utterance>You wanna tell me how'n the hell you gonna write a book 'bout somethin' you don't know nothin' 'bout?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya see what I'm sayin'?  Ha!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early goes back to gulping down his dinner. This time he gets a spicy one.</context>
      <utterance>...Ha.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...way too much MSG.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neither makes any attempt at smiling. Adele snaps their photo anyway. In the front seat, she sits quietly for a moment then leans over to Early and whispers something to him.</context>
      <utterance>Smile.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele sits back quietly. Carrie wants to speak but doesn't.</context>
      <utterance>No way. I guarantee you he was breathing when I walked outta there.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey... Ain't we getting near the next murder site... Bri?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget about it, doesn't matter.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell it don't...  ...Hand me Brian's map there Adele. One day I'm gonna pass some store and see your book in the window. Me and Adele gonna buy a copy for our coffee table.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early looks down the hill to the old mine building.</context>
      <utterance>Figured your hands might be starting to hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie's steely gaze answers Early's question.</context>
      <utterance>Let's have a look. You girls coming?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early leans into the car and picks up Adele's camera.</context>
      <utterance>Can I just wait here?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pistol in hand, Early follows Brian down the hill. Adele begins nervously playing with her yoyo. Carrie watches as Brian and Early disappear around a bend in the dirt road. Out of the corner of her eye, she hones in on Adele's yoyo. Adele becomes increasingly intense about manipulating the yoyo, controlling it. Until she's lost in it. A momentary refuge.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry Bri', I'll take the pictures.  ...you stay here with Carrie.  You run off... Bri' pays the price. Karma, remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is called walk the dog.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So tell me... what happened here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flash! -- Early takes a photo with the Instamatic.</context>
      <utterance>Two brothers, prospectors, lived here. Up until a few years back.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early scans the grounds.</context>
      <utterance>They picked up hitchhikers... young men... and brought them back here.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reluctantly Brian leads Early toward the old mine building. At the opening, Early hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>Where'd they do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian stops in his tracks.</context>
      <utterance>Bri.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARRIE'S POV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A distant empty ribbon of road.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is one of my favorites... rock the cradle.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flash!! Early takes a flash photo of Brian, momentarily blinding him.</context>
      <utterance>...They asked them just before they were executed why they did it. They said "to be famous."  Why do you do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early moves slowly toward Brian.</context>
      <utterance>Do what Bri?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian's eyes dart nervously to the gun dangling in Early's palm. Flash!</context>
      <utterance>We both know you didn't have to kill that gas station attendant.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flash! Brian flinches. Early remains silent as he closes in on Brian.</context>
      <utterance>You wanted to.  Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early's boot lands toe to toe with Brian's shoe.</context>
      <utterance>It make you feel good? Powerful?  Superior, what? Come on Early, tell me something.  Were you angry?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eye to eye, the two men stand there.</context>
      <utterance>Who are you angry with Early... your mother, your father?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to know about my daddy, I'll tell you about my daddy, Bri...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele screws up the trick. She pulls the yoyo off her finger and throws it in the back seat. She leans into the front seat and cranks the radio up to the max. Closing her eyes, she begins moving to the music, and tries to ignore Carrie.</context>
      <utterance>Adele, listen to me... Early's sick; he should be in a hospital.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The police are after him, he's a murderer!</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...That's not true.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not true!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MALE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's take a look.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Male Officer exits, unlocking his holster. The Female Officer picks up the police radio and calls in the license plate number.</context>
      <utterance>I'll call in the plate.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I wouldn't lie to you, Adele. . . I saw him kill that man.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Early didn't kill nobody, he wouldn't do that. I don't know why you're saying those things. You ain't my friend. With that, Adele stops her dancing and turns away from Carrie... To see the Male Officer walking toward them.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Male Officer continues toward them. It looks like he's talking to them... but his voice is inaudible under the deafening radio.</context>
      <utterance>Please don't say anything Carrie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>POLICE RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian is not sure what to do. He looks around... sees the Officer's handgun lying in the dirt. He takes a step toward it, when... another gunshot rings out! Brian stops. Looks to the police car. He sees Early standing there, smoke belching from the dashboard... the police radio is dead. Early walks back toward Brian and the others. He steps over to the injured Male Officer on the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Officer needs help, shots fired, six Adam five, one eighty-seven, suspects wanted in multiple murders. Location unknown, last seen...</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early picks up the wounded cop's gun. He hands it to Brian as he trains the .45 automatic at Brian's chest.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me that don't hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian looks to Early in disbelief.</context>
      <utterance>Shoot him. You'll be doing him a favor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early cocks the pistol and pushes the barrel to Brian's head. Brian looks down at the wounded cop who is writhing in pain.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian won't do it. He drops the gun to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>It's the answer to all them questions of yers.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early cocks his pistol.</context>
      <utterance>Now you'll never know.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early stares at the wounded cop's face.</context>
      <utterance>...Don't do it. Early, look at him, look at his face. That's not your father.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early reaches down and takes the dead cop's handcuffs. He casually points the little camera at the dead cop. Flash!!</context>
      <utterance>I know that. That there is a policeman in a world of pain. And this is what you call a mercy killin'. Early shoots the cop again. The cop lays still.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele looks across the seat to Early. Her face drained of all expression.</context>
      <utterance>I'm still waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not so much as a simple "thank you." Adele at a loss. Finally... confused...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you for what?  What are you thanking me for Adele?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shrinks away from him.</context>
      <utterance>Well Adele... it was for...  ...saving your fucking life back there!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Darlin' you were 'bout that far from spendin' the night at the morgue. You understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early looks into the rear-view mirror. Brian tries to defuse the situation.</context>
      <utterance>He wasn't going to shoot her, you murdering son of a bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carrie... stop it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck is wrong with you Brian!? If you'll stop taking notes for once and open your eyes... you'll see that he is a homicidal fucking killer. He is... for real!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up Carrie, please... just shut up!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EARLY'S POV - NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Off in the distance... an oasis of greenery.</utterance>
   <speaker>OMITTED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...You can forget about 'em forever and then look at 'em and they're doin' even better than before.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Adele... we gotta do something before Early kills someone else.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...There ain't nothin' can kill 'em. They can live for two even three hundred years.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Adele for god sake please lis...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele drifts back to the cacti.</context>
      <utterance>There ain't nothing we could do. Once Early sets his mind on somethin', well thats the end of that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Musgrave downs most of her drink with the first try. Distressed, her head slumps down.</context>
      <utterance>You've got beautiful cactuses here, I just love 'em. My momma used to keep a garden.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with her?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sets the glass down next to a recent picture of Mrs. Musgrave and an ELDERLY MAN with silver hair.</context>
      <utterance>I'll bet she did.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's your husband?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. MUSGRAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early looks at her, he doesn't believe her.</context>
      <utterance>...I'm a widow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MR. MUSGRAVE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Early's eyes drift over to a set of golf clubs that sit in the corner of the room.</context>
      <utterance>My oh my, this is quite rare, quite rare indeed. Come have a look...</utterance>
   <speaker>MR MUSGRAVE'S POV - THROUGH TELESCOPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The planet Saturn and its glorious rings.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. MUSGRAVE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peaches?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta talk to her. She looks up to you, she'll listen to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tried talking to her at the mine. It didn't work.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then try again,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>He pulls his eye away as Adele arrives.</context>
      <utterance>Early?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Musgrave collapses to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Well 'Peaches'... you're a widow now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie doesn't answer him. Then, in the background directly behind Early... Adele and Mrs. Musgrave quietly appear. Carrie notices them as they start to cross the hallway to the kitchen. Early sees Carrie's eyes glance past him. He turns to see why... when...</context>
      <utterance>That's you ain't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Early stops. Looks back to Carrie. Brian also turns to her curiously.</context>
      <utterance>You're right Early...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early looks at the photo again. Adele and Mrs. Musgrave now cross safely to the kitchen. Carrie eyes meet Early's. He smiles, pulls the nude photo of her close to his face... and licks it.</context>
      <utterance>...It is me. Do you like it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Musgrave is confused, is it a trick? She looks into Adele's eyes... and knows it's not. The old lady turns and walks out into the dark desert. Adele stands at the open door, watching Mrs Musgrave escape.</context>
      <utterance>Go on now... please.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Call me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Early enters, and sees Adele standing at the back door. Adele turns to face him. Early looks past her into the night and realizes what she's done. He strides across the room pulling the pistol from his waistband.</context>
      <utterance>Adele?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peaches! Come on back here. There ain't nothin' for you to be afraid of.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody wants to hurt you Peaches!</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Desperate, Adele grabs a large potted cactus. She rushes toward Early. Swinging the cactus like an unwieldy bat, she pummels the side of his head. He stumbles forward, disappearing into the darkness. Adele stands outside the kitchen door, bewildered. Then...</context>
      <utterance>Early! Stop!!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Early re-emerges from the shadows. Adele's eyes widen when she sees him. His cheek has long bloody gashes where the cactus ripped the flesh.</context>
      <utterance>Oww! Oww!! -- FUCK!!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele starts to cry.</context>
      <utterance>Honey... What do you think you're doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, n'jus what in hell you crying 'bout? I'm the one got hit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A look comes over Early's face that we've never seen before. That he's never felt before. Hurt. He doesn't know how to deal with it. And he definitely doesn't like it.</context>
      <utterance>I changed my mind, Early. I'm not gonna climb up that Hollywood sign with you... I decided. I think your mean, and you hurt people.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carrie, watch for Early.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you going to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie glues her eyes to the kitchen doorway. Brian presses his back up under the belly of the piano and using all his strength manages to lift the piano an inch off the floor. Carrie slides her cuffs out from under the leg.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to try and lift the end of the piano. If I can... slide your cuffs free.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie's eyes dart back toward the kitchen. Then she notices a chair nearby.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie grabs the chair. As Brian lifts the piano, she pushes the chair beneath the underside of it. It holds the piano suspended an inch off the floor. Brian drops to the floor and slips the cuffs free. When... a solitary gunshot rings out from the cactus garden. A moment later, Early steps quietly into the room. He's pulling the last few cactus needles from his face. He sees Brian and Carrie standing.</context>
      <utterance>Can you lift it again? Just lift it, hurry.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You two been busy in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to Adele?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A shocked silence. Brian and Carrie look to one another. Carrie moves toward the kitchen but Early stops her! Brian rushes at him. Early sticks the .45 automatic in his face!</context>
      <utterance>Well, let's put it this way.  I need me a new woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to squeeze the trigger.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry about this Bri...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early stops. He looks to Carrie.</context>
      <utterance>Early, don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early deliberates the situation, then eases up off the trigger... and smiles to Brian. Then, without warning, he hits Brian over the head with the butt of the .45 automatic. Brian falls to the floor unconscious.</context>
      <utterance>I'll do whatever you want. You want me to go with you, I'll go with you. Just don't kill him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie quietly responds. She kneels on the front seat and reaches into the back. She grabs a bottle by its neck, and pulls it from the six pack of beer. Bottle in hand, she hesitates a moment...</context>
      <utterance>Pass me a beer hon'.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna hit me with that, huh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands the bottle to him. Early reaches out for the beer, but instead of taking it, he clasps his hand over hers. He looks at her and begins to squeeze...</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early squeezes even harder -- Carrie begins to wince with pain. She waits for the glass bottle to shatter in her hand.</context>
      <utterance>Stop lyin'... I can see right through you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who d'ya think you're foolin'?  I know you better than you think...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early hits the brakes. The car screeches to a halt in a cloud of dust. Early squeezes on her hand even harder and begins to drag her toward him.</context>
      <utterance>...You're hurting me...</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie turns her head away. Early pulls her closer.</context>
      <utterance>I seen the way you been lookin' at me since we met... Snappin' my photo when you thought I wasn't lookin'. Wanting me...</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs her hair with his other hand... Pulls her head around -- forcing her to look at him. Early has Carrie right up against him, looking right into her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I saw you when I killed that boy...</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were plenty hot.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrie struggles even harder, but Early tightens his hold.</context>
      <utterance>Sick... some people might say takin' photos of me and Adele humpin' in the back of the car is sick.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...You know what I mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly... Early releases Carrie, taking the beer from her. Carrie retreats back into the corner of the passenger side.</context>
      <utterance>...I know I'd love to smash this bottle right in your fucking face.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives her a grin, then opens the bottle.</context>
      <utterance>That's better... Honesty... I like that in a woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early takes a gulp of beer.</context>
      <utterance>But I'll tell ya... when we get to California, we're gonna have to do something 'bout that gutter mouth of yours.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which way did they go?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. MUSGRAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He took the fire road.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian starts the pickup and drives off.</context>
      <utterance>Take your car and get to that phone. Call the police.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A violent gust of wind sends several of the erotic photos swirling through the air. One of the photos whips across Early's chest. The wind holds it there momentarily.</context>
      <utterance>You'll like it...</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early peels Carrie's photo off him, the blood from his wound covers the back of it. He slaps it against the nearest wall. It sticks. He walks toward her.</context>
      <utterance>Not a lot, but you'll like it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian searches for Carrie.</context>
      <utterance>That was damn tricky of you Bri.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carrie... Carrie... it's over.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On all fours, Brian reaches out for the gun, but Early kicks it across the room.</context>
      <utterance>Go ahead Bri, ask me something.  You wanna know how I'm feeling'? Well I'd say I'm feelin' pretty damn good.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another kick to Brian's chest. The wind rushes out of him.</context>
      <utterance>How 'bout you? You feelin' good?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Early unloads a ferocious kick to the side of Brian's face! His head snaps back, his handcuffed arms buckle and he falls flat to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>...'Cause you sure don't look so good.  Or maybe you're feelin'... powerful. That it, you feeling powerful? Superior? I know I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With one last effort, Brian manages to pull himself back up to his knees. He focuses on the gun ahead of him and tries to crawl toward it. But Early's foot shoves Brian. He flips over onto his back, landing in front of the bedroom doorway. Early moves toward him, knife in hand. As Early moves toward Brian, unexpectedly from inside the doorway, the torso of the female child mannequin whips past. Her hardened molten face slams into Early's bloodied face. Early stumbles backward. Brian crawls for the gun and grabs it. From his knees he turns, steadies the weapon, takes a quick breath... and fires. Hitting Early square in the chest! Early falls to the ground on his back. Brian lifts himself to his feet. He sees that Carrie has dragged the bedframe to the doorway, and in her free hand she holds the child mannequin by the leg. Gun in hand, Brian steps over to Early. Early's body is still. Blood oozes from the hole in his chest. On a silver chain around his neck is the key to Brian and Carrie's handcuffs. Brian reaches down and grabs the keys... when suddenly Early's arm springs up from his side. His hand grabs Brian's shirt collar. Brian is startled by the move, then realizes that Early's hold is weak. His fingers tremble. Finally his arm drops back down to his side.</context>
      <utterance>What? Am I angry with my daddy? Now why would I be angry with my daddy... you're the one hit me with the shovel. And you're the one's gonna wish you hadn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men stare at one another for a moment... then Brian, with one hand still on the handcuff keys, shoves the .45 automatic firmly under Early's chin.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Bri... I think I need a doctor. What d'ya say?</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
