<movie id="329" title="Kill Bill Volume 1 and 2">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>1.   "2"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>2. The Comatose Bride 3. The Man From Okinawa 4. Showdown at House of Blue Leaves 5. Yuki's Revenge 6. "Can She Backe A Cherry Pie..." 7. The Lonely Grave of Paula Schultz 8. The Cruel Tutelage Of Pai Mei 9. Elle and I 10. The Blood-Splattered Bride</utterance>
   <speaker>OVER BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We hear labored breathing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WE STAY ON BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then a MAN'S VOICE talks over the breathing;</context>
      <utterance>...breathing continues...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you find me sadistic?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>He continues wiping away the blood.</context>
      <utterance>I bet I could fry an egg on your head about now, if I wanted to.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No kiddo, I'd like to believe, even now, you're aware enough to know there isn't a trace of sadism in my actions... Okay - Maybe towards these other jokers - bot not your.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BILL'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>While still in her CU The Bride speaks for the first time in the picture. She looks up at the man standing over her and says;</context>
      <utterance>No Kiddo at this moment, this is me at my most masochistic.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After saying the "y" in "baby", we hear a BANG and The Bride receives a bullet in the side of her head.</context>
      <utterance>Bill, I'm pregnant. It's your baby.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>CU A PRETTY YOUNG WOMAN in a frilly pink dress with two bullet holes in her.</context>
      <utterance>That's Tim, Arthur's best friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>CU A PLUMP YOUNG WOMAN, shot to death, wedding bouquet still clutched in her dead fist.</context>
      <utterance>That's his girlfriend Janeen.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>AN OLDER MAN IN A BLACK SUIT shot fulla holes.</context>
      <utterance>That's my best friend from work Erica.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A DEAD OLDER WOMAN by his side in an old-fashioned flower print dress.</context>
      <utterance>That's the minister. I think his name was Reverend Hillhouse.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A DEAD OLDER WOMAN slumped over an organ.</context>
      <utterance>That's his wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Organ player, don't know her name.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Arthur. Arthur Plympton. The</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then finally, The Bride.</context>
      <utterance>name on his driver's license was Charles Arthur Plympton, but for some reason he preferred Arthur. Maybe if he went by Carles people would have called him Charlie. If that was his reason for going by Arthur I can understand it. Nothing wrong with the name Charlie, except he didn't look like a Charlie, he looked like an Arthur. Obviously you'll have to take my word on this. Speaking of names, I was about two seconds away from becoming Mrs. Charles Arthur Plympton.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We do a DISSOLVE from the Bride looking dead in the bridal gown To The Bride, still in B/W, still in a bridal gown, but the asswippin she took in the scene before must have been in the past, because she looks like a million dollars now.......three million even.</context>
      <utterance>And that, that's me. I'm the Bride.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The last one.</context>
      <utterance>Looked dead, didn't I? Well I wasn't, but it wasn'T for lack fo trying, I can tell you that. Actually Bill's last bullet put me in a coma. A coma I was to lie in for five years. When I woke up, ...I went on what the movie advertisements refer to as a Roaring Rampage of Revenge. I roarded and I rampaged and I got bloody satisfaction. In all, I've killed 33 people to get to this piont right now. I have only one more.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>.... I'm gonna Kill Bill.</context>
      <utterance>The one I'M driving to right now. The only one left. And when I arrive at my destination.....</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FOUR-YEAR-OLD GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two warrior women whose eyes reflect only combat concentration, suddenly switch upon hearing the four-year old's voice. The Housewife's eyes flash a look of pleading to the eyes of The Bride. The Bride seems to answer back; "Okay." The Black woman and the white woman hide their edged weapons behind their backs, as the Four-Year-Old Little Girl walks into the newly destroyed living room. The Housewife switches to her mommy voice.</context>
      <utterance>Mommy, I'm home!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE HOUSEWIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Little Girl is flabbergasted at the mess, and the condition of her mother, who looks like she's just been in a bar room brawl.</context>
      <utterance>Hey baby, how was school?</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mommy, what happened to you and the T.V. Room?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>THE HOUSEWIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, that good for nothin dog of yours, got his little ass in the living room and acted a damn fool, that's what happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She says it with the slightest hint of skepticism, then tries to enter the living room.</context>
      <utterance>Barney did this?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE    HOUSEWIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The little girl's eyes go to the blonde lady in the living room who she ain't never seen before, who also looks like she's been fighting. The Bride smiles at the confused Little Girl.</context>
      <utterance>Now baby, you can't come in here, there's broken glass all over the floor, and you gonna cut yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE HOUSEWIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a old friend of mommy's I ain't seen in a long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whenever during the picture somebody says The Bride's real name, it will be BLEEPED OUT ON THE SOUNDTRACK, ...that is, till I want you to know. The shy, suspicious little girl doesn't say anything, she just stares at the blond lady.</context>
      <utterance>Hello sweety, I'm  , what's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE HOUSEWIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her name is Nikki.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nikki still says nothing, only stares.</context>
      <utterance>Nikki. What a pretty name for such a pretty little girl. How old are you Nikki?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>THE HOUSEWIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nikki,  aked you a question.</utterance>
   <speaker>NIKKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm four.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four years old, aye. You know I once had a little girl. She'd be five right now. Maybe you two could of played with each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE HOUSEWIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The child doesn't move, so the mother repeats herself.</context>
      <utterance>Now baby, me an  have some grown-up talk to talk about, so you go in your room now and leave us alone till I tell you to come out.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE HOUSEWIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The little girl slowly walks away and disappears behind the door of her bedroom. The two women turn to face each other, masquerade and combat both finished.</context>
      <utterance>Nikkia - in your room - now.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE HOUSEWIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want some coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two women move into the kitchen. The Bride re-sheaths her SOG, and The Housewife puts the butcher knife back in the drawer. The Bride sits down at the kitchen table, while The Housewife pours both of them coffee.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, sure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE HOUSEWIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cream and sugar?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As The Housewife fixes the coffee, we hear The Bride's</context>
      <utterance>Both, please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The two combat artists sit at the kitchen table, drinking coffee out of Vernita's coffee mugs.</context>
      <utterance>This Pasadena homemaker's name is Jeanne Bell. Her husband is Dr. Lawrence Bell. But back when we were acquainted, five years ago, her name was VERNITA GREEN. Her code name, was "COBRA"..... Mine was BLACK MAMBA.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were you expecting me?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERNITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes and no. Bill got in touch with me right after you woke up, and then again a little later after your episode in Japan.  So I suppose it's a little late for a apology, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You suppose correctly.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERNITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even if I was sincere?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vernita says to the Bride across the table furiously but with low volume;</context>
      <utterance>Oh. I'm quite positive you're sorry, now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VERNITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look bitch, I need to know if you're gonna start anymore shit around my baby girl!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can relax for now. I'm not going to murder you in front of your daughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERNITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's being more rational than Bill led me to believe you were capable of.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pauses for effect -- the ham.</context>
      <utterance>Well that's a demonstration of Bill's complete ignorance when it comes to the subject of me, and what I'm thinking, and what I might do. It's mercy, compassion, and forgiveness I lack, not rationality.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vernita says her name;</context>
      <utterance>I'll wait for now, but I won't wait for long. I'll allow you to choose a time and place for us to meet again, preferably as far away from Nikki as possible. I could have just HIT you, I didn't, I demand respect for that. Since this is not a HIT, consider it a DUEL. And as two former Deadly Vipers, we will observe Viper rules of honor. One on one - no help - no bushwhackin - no treacherous weapons - on weapon of choice - our skill and our bodies.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- I'm not through telling you. Failure to keep our date, or duplicity of any kind, will result in me putting a xoxo hollow point bullet into the back of your skull from a window of a building across the street from Nikki's elementary school. Now, feel free to respond.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERNITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The blonde listens to the black woman with a poker face.</context>
      <utterance>Look...I know I fucked you over. I fucked you over bad. I wish to God I hadn't, but I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERNITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I could go back in a machine I would, but I can't. All I can tell you is I'm a different person now.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERNITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be that as it may, I know I do not deserve mercy or forgiveness. However, I beseech you for both on behalf of my daughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The B-word stops Vernita short, almost like a cold-handed slap in the face (it should affect the audience that way as well).</context>
      <utterance>-- Bitch, you can stop right there.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just because I have no wish to murder you before the eyes of your daughter, does not mean parading her around in front of me is going to inspire sympathy. You and I have unfinished business.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And not a goddamn fuckin thing you've done in the subsequent five years - including getting knocked up - is going to change that.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERNITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have every right to wanna get even --</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vernita knows no matter what else is said, blood will spill.</context>
      <utterance>-- But that's where you're wrong, Vernita. I don't want to get even. To get even, even Steven. I would have to kill you, go into Nikki's room, kill her, then wait for your old man, Dr. Bell, to come home and kill him. That would make us even. No, my unborn daughter will just hafta be satisfied with your death at her mother's hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERNITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When do we do this?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It all depends... When do you want to die? Tomorrow? The day after tomorrow? That's about as long as I'll wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERNITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How bout tonight, bitch?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spendid. Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERNITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a baseball diamond where our little league has its games, about a mile from here. We meet there around two-thirty in the morning, dressed all in black, your hair in a black stocking, and we have us a knife fight, we won't be</utterance>
   <speaker>VERNITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they continue to talk, Vernita pulls down a cereal bowl for her daughter and lays it on the kitchen counter.</context>
      <utterance>bothered. I have to fix Nikki's cereal.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vernita moves to another kitchen cabinet, and pulls down a box of the sugar cereal, "Kaboom."</context>
      <utterance>Bill said you were one of the best ladies he'd ever seen with an edged weapon.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERNITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the two females continue to talk, Vernita reaches her hand inside the cereal box.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you, bitch, I know he didn't qualify it, so you can just kiss my motherfuckin ass, Black Mamba.  Black Mamba, I shoulda been motherfuckin Black Mamba.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Weapon of choice? And if you want to stick with your butcher knife, I'm cool with that.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERNITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vernita FIRES A GUN from inside the cereal box at The Bride.... .... The bullet explodes out of the cardboard box, and HITS the coffee mugh directly in front of The Bride, BLOWING IT TO</context>
      <utterance>Very funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITHEREENS.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vernita pulls the gun out of the cereal box and FIREES again... ...The bullet HITS THE FLOOR of the tiny kitchen... ...The Bride moves under the kitchen table, then using her back, LIFTS THE TABLE OFF THE GROUND, RAMMING IT STRAIGHT INTO Vernita, pinning her flat up against the table top, and the kitchen counter.</context>
      <utterance>The Bride THROWS HERSELF ON THE FLOOR....</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VERNITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, bout the bushwhack. Please don't...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bride removes her Sog, looks up and sees little Nikki standing in the doorway of her room. The little girl sees her mother dead on the floor, lying in her own blood. And she sees the blonde lady standing over her mother, bloody knife still in her hand. But oddly enough, Nikki doesn't cry. The little girl locks eyes with the big girl, and holds her stare. As she talks to the little girl, she removes an already stained with blood white handkerchief with the name "BILL" sewn on it. And the blonde wipes the girl's mother's blood off her blade.</context>
      <utterance>Do to your daughter, what you did to mine...  ...I won't. Vernita dies.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that apology, statement, and invitation, The Bride walks out the kitchen side door, leaving the little girl to her mourning.</context>
      <utterance>It was not my intention to do this in front of you. For that I'm sorry. But you can take my word for it, your mother had it coming. When you grow up, if you still feel raw about it, I'll be waiting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>OVERHEAD SHOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CU the back of a head wearing a yellow rainslicker hood, framed by the red umbrella above it, which water cascades down and beats a rhythm against. The figure in the yellow rainslicker with the red umbrella (who we can guess is female) starts walking towards the hospital.</context>
      <utterance>A red umbrella opens as rain falls down.</utterance>
   <speaker>WE GO TO SPLIT SCREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CU The Bride's unblinking The back of the yellow comatose sleep. slicker - walking in the rain towards the hospital's entrance. CU her yellow galoshes slapping against the wet asphalt, and splashing through puddles. CU The Bride in her coma CU the hospital's electrical doors -</context>
      <utterance>Left Side Right Side</utterance>
   <speaker>WOOSH - OPEN.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We follow behind the woman in the raincoat as she walks from outside into the hospital down the hall, and into the ladies room door. CU The BRIDE EX CU OF A WHITE in her coma WOMAN'S SHAPELY</utterance>
   <speaker>BAREFOOT ANKLE AND LEG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>stepping into a sheer, white stocking.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She curses to herself...there can be only one person on the other end....she answers it.</context>
      <utterance>I might never of liked you. Point in fact I despise you. But that doesn't suggest I don't respect you. You were a master of a profession that's most difficult to master. Dying in our sleep is a luxury our kind is rarely afforded. My gift to you. As she lifts the syringe off the tray.... Her cell phone RINGS....</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The female assassin turns away from the wide-eyed stare of The Bride, and paces the hospital room talking in the cell phone.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Bill.  Affirmative.  Comatose.  I'm standing over her right now.  What!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't fuckin ssshhh me! If you think I came all the way down to Texas - in a dog and cat rainstorm no less - just to tuck sleeping beauty in bed - you got another fuckin thing comin -  You don't owe her Shit!!  You don't owe her shit.  Man, fuck that bitch!  Oh you're not are you? Well Bill, you never leave a job half done. A great teacher taught me that once, he looked a whole lot like</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elle pauses as Bill on the other line has his say. We don't hear his side, we stay with Elle as he talks. We can tell by her face, he's making some sense. After awhile she answers back;</context>
      <utterance>you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess.  No, I don't need to guess, I know.  Affirmative.  I love you too, bye bye. The female assassin puts the phone away and looks down at The comatose Bride with the open eyes. Even though her face is expressionless, she almost seems to be smiling.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elle leans closer to the Bride's face.</context>
      <utterance>Thought that was pretty funny didn't ya? Word of advice shithead, don't you ever wake up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bride does one of her motor reflex functions...She SPITS in Elle's face. Elle springs up, wipes the spit off her cheek and looks down at The comatose Bride in her bed.</context>
      <utterance>Ya know now I get a better look at you, you're not so damn pretty. Yeah, you go that Venus thing going for you but...ya know, now I get a closer look at you you're kinda weird looking. You got this big nose that doesn't fit with the rest of your face, your eyes are two different sizes. And look at your skin...My complexion is way better than yours --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grabs The Bride by the front of her hospital gown... ....Yanks Her up to a sitting position...</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no you didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...And PUNCHES her hard in the face three times.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you ever take your ass out of this Goddamn bed for as long as you fuckin live, I will beat you into the ground, bitch!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elle doesn't even look back.</context>
      <utterance>Nurse come here quick, we're losing this man!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks out of the SHOT.</context>
      <utterance>Tough titty, I quit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>THE ORDERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trucker 2 (Gerald) would tend to agree, Trucker 1 (Warren) fronts.</context>
      <utterance>Now is that the cutest little blonde pussy you ever saw, or is that the cutest little blonde pussy, YOU-EVEA-SAW?</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>EYES WIDE OPEN PLAYING POSSUM. She can't believe she's being exhibited in this manner. A look of chagrin crosses her trying-to-be expressionless face, "I've seen a fuck load better than you, fatass."</context>
      <utterance>I seen better. CU The BRIDE</utterance>
   <speaker>THE ORDERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As The Orderly counts The Truckers' money, he lays out the rules;</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, in a movie - maybe. But I know damn well this is the best pussy you ever saw you had touchin rights to. The price is seventy five dollars a fuck gentlemen, you gittin your freak on or what? The Truckers pay the bill of fare.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE ORDERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's the rules; Rule number one; no punchin 'er. Nurse comes in tomorrow an she got 'er a shiner - or less some teeth, jig's up. So no knuckle sandwiches under no circumstances. And by the</utterance>
   <speaker>THE ORDERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>way, this little cunt's a spitter - it's a motor reflex thing but spit or no, no punchin. Now are we absolutely positively clear about rule number one?</utterance>
   <speaker>TWO TRUCKERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE ORDERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rule number two; No monkey bites, no hickeys - in fact no leavin no marks of no kind. But after that, it's allll goooood. Her plummin down there don't work no more, so feel free to cum in 'er all ya wont. Keep the noise down - try not to make a mess, and I'll be back in twenty. The Orderly turns to leave, then remembers something, and turns back. He takes out the most disgusting jar of vaseline in the history of cinema, and hands it to Warren.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE ORDERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As soon as he leaves the Two Truckers start giggling. Warren begins to unbuckle the belt that lies beneath his belly. While he looks down to accomplish this, The BRIDE'S POV</context>
      <utterance>Oh by the way, not all the time, but sometimes this cunt's cunt can get drier than a bucket of sand. If she dry, lube up with this and you'll be goo to go. BON-APPETIT, gentlemen. And with that, The Orderly's gone. The BRIDE'S POV:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>GERALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Warren, she just blinked.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said she can't blink.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know what he said, I'm tellin ya</utterance>
   <speaker>GERALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Warren drops his Levi's to his ankles.</context>
      <utterance>she just did.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Warren begins to climb up on the bed and mount The Bride. Before he does he stops, and looks back to Gerald.</context>
      <utterance>Just wait, when I get through with this little dumbbell, she gonna stand up and recite the Gettysburg Ad-dress.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Gerald.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This shit ain't no peep show. Go out in the hall and I'll let ya know when it's your turn.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awww c'mon, I gotta leave the room?</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't get no errection wit you lookin at me, so go on.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gerald leaves the room; we go out with him in the hallway.</context>
      <utterance>Well, just hurry up then.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FRAME.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>lies on the floor in a stange state of consciousness. He's in both excruciating pain, and quite sure he's lost his mind, since at this moment he's lying on the floor, looking up at The comatose Bride asking him questions.</context>
      <utterance>The ORDERLY</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Bill?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE ORDERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bill! Where is Bill!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE ORDERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dunno no Bill.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE ORDERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please please stop, don't hit me again!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is Bill?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did you get this from?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE ORDERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's mine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WE ZOOM OUT OF HER EYES INTO A CU. The REMEMBERING THEME CUTS OFF. She looks down at Buck and says;</context>
      <utterance>Well, ain't you the slice of cutie pie they all said you wuz. Well Ma'am, I'm from Longview Texas, my name's Buck, and I'm here to fuck. He starts to unbuckle his belt.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A "how the fuck does she know look," crosses his face. The Bride looks down at him....The VENGEANCE THEME BEGINS PLAYING LOUDLY ON The SOUNDTRACK, and the VEIN IN HER FOREHEAD BECOMES PRONOUNCED and begins to PULSATE IN TIME WITH The MUSIC. Every time The Bride comes face to face with a tormenter, this Theme will play on the soundtrack. By mid movie this music should drive the audience wild with orgasmic anticipation of the carnage to come... ...and With the door in her hand and one mighty slam, this Longview Texas boy is sent to the Promised Land. She searches the dead man's pockets, coming up with a brown wallet that says on it, "BIG EL PASO PIMPIN," loaded with lettuce. She also pulls out a set of car keys on a pickup truck key chain that has the words, "Pussy Wagon" on it written in a pimpy font. She gathers up all these items, and Gerald's knife, then begins to strip Buck of his orderly uniform.</context>
      <utterance>Your name's Buck, right? And you came to fuck, right?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toe doesn't move an inch.</context>
      <utterance>Wiggle your big toe.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It doesn't move.</context>
      <utterance>Wiggle your big toe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wiggle your big toe.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>VOICE OVER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As I lay in the back of Buck's pickup truck, trying to will my limbs out of entropy, I could see the faces of the cunts who did this to me, and the dick responsible. Members all of Bill's brainchild; "The Deadly Viper Assassination Squad."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ASSASSINATINO SQUAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SHOW CAST CREDITS START: WE SEE The BRIDE doing something cool...FREEZE SCREEN GOES ORANGE except for a SCOPE-SIGHT RIFLE GRAPHIC WITH CROSSHAIRS over The Bride's face. OFF TO THE SIDE IS HER</context>
      <utterance>the D.iV.A.S."</utterance>
   <speaker>IDENTIFYING CREDIT;</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(The Bride's real name is covered by a stamp that reads)</context>
      <utterance>"Starring</utterance>
   <speaker>CLASSIFIED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>as</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ORANGE B.G. SCOPE-SIGHT GRAPHIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Starring</utterance>
   <speaker>O-REN ISHII</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>as</utterance>
   <speaker>COTTONMOUTH"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>VERNITA GREEN doing something cool - FREEZE</utterance>
   <speaker>SAME GRAPHIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Starring</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>VERNITA GREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>as</utterance>
   <speaker>COBRA"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The older, male doing something cool - FREEZE</utterance>
   <speaker>SAME GRAPHIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Starring</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>as</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDEWINDER"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>ELLE DRIVER doing something cool - FREEZE</utterance>
   <speaker>ORANGE B.G. SCOPE-SIGHT GRAPHIC;</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Starring</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>as</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>WE MOVE FAST TO O-REN ISHII'S SILHOUETTE, The SILHOUETTE BECOMES A POSED PICTURE OF O-REN in all her Deadly Viper glory.</context>
      <utterance>Now after five years of beauty sleep I knew absolutely nothing about my enemies' strengths weakness or whereabouts. But as fated by God vengeance would have it, I who knew nothing - knew one thing. As sure as God made little green apples...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>....if O-Ren Ishii, the first name on my Death List, was still alive... she'd live in Japan. O-Ren Ishii, made her first acquaintance with death at the age of eleven.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The Boss's screams cause TWO OF BOSS'S MEN to run into the room, only to be SHOT DOWN by O-Ren, as she removes a gun from a holster strapped to her thigh. The 20-YEAR OLD O-REN ISHII on a rooftop with a high-powered, scope-sight rifle up to her eye. Her EYE is HUGELY MAGNIFIED in the SCOPE.</context>
      <utterance>At thirteen, she got her revenge.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She fires.</context>
      <utterance>By twenty, she was one of the tip top of female assassins in the world.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BLOWN OFF.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>stands before Bill and The Bride. (Bill is not clearly viewed.)</context>
      <utterance>The 23-YEAR OLD O-REN ISHII</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>BEATING UP the pregnant Bride with the other Vipers...</context>
      <utterance>At twenty-three she joined Bill's Deadly Vipers... The 25-YEAR-OLD O-REN ISHII</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>POSED FIGURE of the BRIDE in all her pre-beating bridal gown glory.</context>
      <utterance>At twenty five she did her part in the killing of eight innocent people, including my unborn daughter, in a small wedding chapel in El Paso Texas. But on that day, five years ago, she made one big mistake...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>An hour and a half later from the last time we saw her.</context>
      <utterance>...she Should of killed nine. However, before statisfaction would be mine, first things first... CU The BRIDE IN BUCK'S TRUCK</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wiggel your big toe. CU The BRIDE'S BIG TOE wiggles - slightly.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hart part's over. Now let's get these other piggies wiggling.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SUSHI CHEF</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>English?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Almost -- American.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>The Sushi Chef gives an exaggerated look of surprise, and says;</context>
      <utterance>Domo.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSHI CHEF</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, "Domo", Very good -- very good, you speak Japanese?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nooo, just a few words I learned since yesterday. - May I sit at the bar?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSHI CHEF</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>The Sushi Chef YELLS IN JAPANESE, to someone OFFSCREEN. The Bride thinks the restaurant so small it's almost hard to imagine there could be a back room to it. Before getting a response from whoever it was he was yelling to a moment ago, The Sushi Chef turns back to The Bride.</context>
      <utterance>Sure sure sure - sit. What other words did you learn - excuse me --</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSHI CHEF</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>The Bride puts on a thinking face.</context>
      <utterance>-- What other Japanese you learn?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh...let's see..."Arigato."</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSHI CHEF</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Arigato"...Very good.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSHI CHEF</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>..."Ah-So"...</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSHI CHEF</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Ah-So!" You know what "Ah-So" meansŸ</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"I See."</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSHI CHEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see - Very good.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I already said "Domo", right?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSHI CHEF</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>The Sushi Chef goes "Oooh" like he's just discovered the answer to a mystery.</context>
      <utterance>"Kon-netie-wa."</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSHI CHEF</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>..."Kon-nichi-wa"...repeat please.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Kon-nichi-wa?" Saying with surprise and admiration;</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSHI CHEF</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>The Bride smiles and lets loose with a girlish giggle.</context>
      <utterance>Most impressive...you say Japanese words, like you Japanese.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you're making fun of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSHI CHEF</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No no no - serious business. Pronunciation - very good. You say "Arigato" ...like we say "Arigato."</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, thank you - I mean...arigato.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSHI CHEF</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should learn Japanese - very easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>Whenever the Sushi Chef doesn't either hear your or understand you, he yells the word;</context>
      <utterance>No kidding, I heard it's kinda hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSHI CHEF</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>And everybody always speaks LOUDER and CLEARER immediately afterwards.</context>
      <utterance>What!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I always heard it was difficult.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSHI CHEF</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes yes yes - most difficult. But you have Japanese tongue.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>The Sushi Chef proclaims as if he should know;</context>
      <utterance>Maybe I was Japanese in another life.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>He sets an order of colorful, raw fish in front of the young blonde woman, that not only looks good, it looks beautiful.</context>
      <utterance>Most definitely, most definitely Japanese in another life.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you know tuna's my favorite?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSHI CHEF</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tuna's my favorite.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSHI CHEF</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>He YELLS OFFSCREEN in Japanese agai. A little BALD JAPANESE MAN with a shitty attitude, comes out from the back room. He heads for the tall blonde asking in a grumbly voice in Japanese, "What she wants to drink?"</context>
      <utterance>Ah, thank you very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>The Sushi Chef pantomimes drinking.</context>
      <utterance>I beg your pardon?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSHI CHEF</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- Drink -</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yes, a bottle of warm sake.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSHI CHEF</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>In Japanese he YELLS/ORDERS the warm sake, the little Bald Man disappears. The Bride takes a bite out of her fish.</context>
      <utterance>Ahhh sake,  Very good.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSHI CHEF</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First time in Japan?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSHI CHEF</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>As the chef slices the next portion with a large knife, he asks;</context>
      <utterance>Yes, this is my first time.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSHI CHEF</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What brings you to Okinawa?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I came to see a man.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSHI CHEF</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aaahh, you have friend live in Okinawa?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not quite.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSHI CHEF</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>The Sushi Chef continues slicing.....</context>
      <utterance>I've never met him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a break in the Sushi Chef's slicing. After a beat, he brings a bloody finger INTO FRAME and sticks it in his mouth. The little Bald man appears with a bottle of warm sake, he pours one for The Bride, then disappears again. As The Bride sips the sake, she looks at the chef. As The Sushi Chef sucks his finger, he looks at The Bride. The Sushi Chef drops the voice he had been using up to that point...and IN JAPANESE SUBTITLED IN ENGLISH asks;</context>
      <utterance>Hattori Hanzo.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSHI CHEF</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>The Bride answers in Japanese;</context>
      <utterance>What do you want with Hattori Hanzo?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need Japanese steel.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSHI CHEF</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you need Japanese steel?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have vermin to kill.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSHI CHEF</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must have big rats you need Hattori Hanzo steel.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huge.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>The Sushi Chef answers in ENGLISH;</context>
      <utterance>May I?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANZO</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>She starts reaching for one...</context>
      <utterance>Yes you may.....</utterance>
   <speaker>HANZO</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>She finds it lying sleeping in its shiny, black sheath. Her hand lifts it from the rack. She UNSHEATHS the steel, partially....then with GREAT FLOURISH....completely. Hanzo's mouth froms a smile.</context>
      <utterance>...try the second one down in the sixth row on your left.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANZO</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>He pulls a baseball out of his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Funny, you like samurai swords...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANZO</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>THEN SUDDENLY - HE THROWS THE BASEBALL HARD, right at The Bride's head....</context>
      <utterance>...I like baseball.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then give me one of these.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANZO</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are not for sale.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't say, sell me. I said, give me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANZO</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And why should I be obliged to assist you in the extermination of your vermin?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>Hattori Hanzo goes to a dusty window, and writes the name, "BILL" on it with his finger. The blonde girl nods her head yes. The proud warrior moves over to the door in the floor, throwing it open. He points into a corner...</context>
      <utterance>Because my vermin, is a former student of yours. And considering the student, I'd say you had a rather large obligation.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>.....starts to descend....</context>
      <utterance>...You can sleep there...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANZO</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>.....before his head disappears, he says;</context>
      <utterance>...it will take me a week to make the sword...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANZO</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>She smiles slightly...then moves over to the window, takes out a handkerchief, and wipes Bill's name off.</context>
      <utterance>...I suggest you spend it practicing. ...he closes the door behind him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HANZO</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>We go back and forth between CU of HANZO reciting the doctrine like a samurai drill instructor and the Bride repeating it.</context>
      <utterance>Revenge is never a straight line. It's a forest. And like a forest it's easy to lose your way...to get lost... to forget where you came in. To serve as a compass, a combat philosophy must be adopted that can be found in the secret doctrine of the Yagu Ninja. And now my yellow haired warrior, repeat after me;</utterance>
   <speaker>HANZO</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>The Bride repeats this...</context>
      <utterance>"When engaged in combat, the vanquishing of thine enemy can be the warrior's only concern...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANZO</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>The Bride repeats this...</context>
      <utterance>...This is the first and cardinal rule of combat...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANZO</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>The Bride repeats this...</context>
      <utterance>...Suppress all human emotion and compassion...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HANZO</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>The Bride repeats this... Her eyes look at the greatest maker of swords on this earth and says;</context>
      <utterance>This truth lies at the heart of the art of combat. Once it is mastered... Thou shall fear no one... Though the devil himself may bar thy way...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>her white hand with her long fingers COMES INTO FRAME and removes the beautiful, artful instrument of vengeance.</context>
      <utterance>Domo. EX CU The Hanzo Sword,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When fortune smiles on something as violent and ugly as revenge, at the time it seems proof like no other, that not only does God exist, you're doing his will. At a time when I knew the last about my enemies, the first name on my death list, was the easiest to find. But</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The charcoal drawing gets color and becomes ANIMATED, turning into a JAPAMATION O-REN...</context>
      <utterance>of course, when one manages the difficult task of becoming queen of the Tokyo underworld, one doesn't keep it a secret, does one?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Japamation images of O-Ren and her Army, taking on ANOTHER YAKUZA ARMY, among falling cherry blossoms. WE CUT BACK AND FORTH between cartoon images of this and the real life real McCoy samurai sword battle. O-Ren's ability is simply amazing.</context>
      <utterance>At the age of twenty, Bill backed his Nippon progeny financially and philosophically in her Shakespearian-in-magnitude power struggle with the other Yakuza clans, over who would rule vice in the city of Tokyo.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When it was all over, it was the geisha-regaled O-Ren Ishii that proved the victor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Boss Tanaka brings his fist down on the table, smashing the plate in front of him into itty bitty pieces. The party comes to a halt as all eyes go to the leader of the Tanaka Crime Family.</context>
      <utterance>The man who seems bound and determined to break the mood is Boss Tanaka. And what Boss Tanaka thinks is...</utterance>
   <speaker>CRIME FAMILY LEADER #2</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tanaka? What's the meaning of this outburst? This is a time for celebration.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOSS TANAKA</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>The Bosses all react with shock and outrage...O-Ren remains cool. She raises her voice for the first word, but lowers it for the rest of the sentence.</context>
      <utterance>And what exactly should I be celebrating? The perversion of our illustrious council?</utterance>
   <speaker>O-REN</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen...Boss Tanaka obviously has something on his mind. Allow him to express it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOSS TANAKA</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>The BOSSES react again...O-Ren;</context>
      <utterance>My father...  ...along with yours and...  ...along With yours, started this council. And while you drink like fish and laugh like donkeys, they weep in the afterlife over the perversion committed today.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BOSS TANAKA</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>Faster than you can say Jimminy Cricket,... O-Ren's samurai sword is unsheathed... Boss Tanaka's head is liberated from its body... The head hits the floor... And from the spot between its shoulder blades, a geyser of blood shoots up in the air. The BOSSES who were shocked at Tanaka's words are even more flabbergasted at O-Ren's resonse. The two bodyguard's, standing behind Boss Tanaka, hands go to their swords and draw them. O-Ren turns her blade in their direction. The Bosses and their bodyguards say nothing,...only watch. The lady looks across at the two men and says in and authoritative voice;</context>
      <utterance>I speak, Mistress Ishii,....of the perversion done to this council, which I love more than my own children,...by making a half Chinese American its leader. Then...</utterance>
   <speaker>O-REN</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>They look at her for a moment, then they lower their swords.</context>
      <utterance>Fight me or work for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>O-REN</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>They do.</context>
      <utterance>Drop them on the ground.</utterance>
   <speaker>O-REN</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get behind me.</utterance>
   <speaker>O-REN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They do.</utterance>
   <speaker>O-REN</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>They do.</context>
      <utterance>Get on your knees.</utterance>
   <speaker>O-REN</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>They do.</context>
      <utterance>Put your foreheads on the floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>O-REN</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>The mistress' eyes got to the other bosses looking at her. As she speaks English, bodyguard translators translate for their bosses.</context>
      <utterance>Keep your mouths shut. You better believe they do.</utterance>
   <speaker>O-REN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to say this in English so you know how serious I am. As your leader, I encourage you to -- from time to time and always in a respectful manner, and with the complete knowledge that my decision is final -- to question my logic. If you're unconvinced a particular plan of action I've decided is the wisest, tell me so. But allow me to convince you. And I will promise you, right here and now, no subject will be taboo...except the subject that was just under discussion.</utterance>
   <speaker>O-REN</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>He picks it off the floor and meekly offers it to the Queen. She takes it by the hair and holds it up as she speaks.</context>
      <utterance>Hand me that head.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BACK AND FORTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>between CU's of the two women, face to face.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I am looking for the attorney of O-Ren Ishii, Sofie Fatale. Would that be you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>The Bride PUNCHES her in the face.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Mistress Ishii's attorney. How can I help you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>O-REN</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>The Staff and The Customers Stampede the exits. The Bride, The Crazy 88, and O-Ren hold their ground without moving a muscle, till the dining room, as well as the entire restaurant known as "The House of Blue Leaves," is deserted of every human not engaged in the face- off that precedes combat. O-Ren gives a simple order;</context>
      <utterance>Sorry everybody, but I'm afraid we're going to have to close the place. There's some private business that we must attend to now.</utterance>
   <speaker>O-REN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MIKI, one of The Crazy 88 (The little one), steps forward, unsheaths his sword, and yells at the yellow clad blonde.</context>
      <utterance>Miki.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKI</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>Raising his samurai sword high, he Charges, Screaming A Banzai Scream... The Bride turns to face him. Miki Charging and Screaming... The Bride slowly raises the Hanzo Sword into Striking Position.</context>
      <utterance>You had it coming bastard!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>O-REN</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>The six remaining Crazy 88 unsheath their swords at the same time with a GREAT SOUND EFFECT. They circle the Bride.</context>
      <utterance>Tear the bitch apart!</utterance>
   <speaker>O-REN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inside the circle of Combatants who surrounded her. She Whips the sword out of the floor and raises her blade diagonally in front of her. Her eyes are reflected in the shiny steel. Holding her sword in the diagonal position, The Bride can see reflected in the shiny blade, whoever stands behind her. The six Crazy 88 Attack... The BRIDE does a Zatoichi-like SWISH-SLASH-SWISH with her steel blade. Four boys die an immediate samurai blade-inflicted death,</context>
      <utterance>The BRIDE</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>O-REN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>smiles.</utterance>
   <speaker>O   -REN</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't think it was going to be that easy, did you?</utterance>
   <speaker>O   -REN</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>O-Ren smiles...</context>
      <utterance>You know, for a second there, yeah I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>O-REN</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>Both O-Ren and the Bride finish the phrase together,...</context>
      <utterance>Silly rabbit...</utterance>
   <speaker>O-REN/THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is something they used to say back when they fought alongside of each other as "Vipers." The seventeen Crazy 88 reinforcements come running into the restaurant and with drawn swords surround The Bride. As a HEAVY METAL COMBAT BEAT begins to PULSATE ON THE SOUNDTRACK, The Boys and The Bride have a Spaghetti Western Stand-off. We do a 360 INSIDE the CIRCLE of The Crazy 88, who surround the yellow-haired warrior. Not all have Samurai swords; one JUGGLES TWO HATCHETS, another TWIRLS A THREE-STAFF TRIPLE IRON over his head. As the Heavy Metal music builds...We Cut to various Shots of The Two Opposing Forces Preparing to Strike....Hands on Sword Handles...Feet finding Combat Stance...etc... ....Until Heavy Metal reaches its Breaking Point... ...At that point, the Metal EXPLODES OVER THE SOUNDTRACK...IN TIME WITH The BRIDE EXPLODING INTO A VIOLENT KILLING MACHINE</context>
      <utterance>...Trix Are for kids.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>Mr. Barrel says;</context>
      <utterance>Any more subordinates for me to kill, O-Ren?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BARREL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One last one.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're Mr. Barrel, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BARREL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you're Black Mamba.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our reputations precede us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BARREL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Apparently.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Barrel takes out a kato mask on a stick, like from a 17th Century costume ball, and holds it over his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me Mr. Barrel, why don't you wear your Kato mask? Are you and iconoclast?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BARREL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't like that rubber band. It fucks up my hair.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shouldn't work for her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BARREL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too late.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not too late to quit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BARREL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have choices?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BARREL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know exactly how you feel.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This has nothing to do with You and I, and everything to do with me taking satisfaction from that bitch behind you. And there's absolutely positively no way I'M going to leave here without taking that satisfaction. So Mr. Barrel, you have to stand aside. And that means you must quit, right now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MR. BARREL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes you can.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BARREL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't say "Can't", there are no "Cant's." Yes - You - Can.....</utterance>
   <speaker>O-REN ISHII</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Screams at her "...last line of defense;"</utterance>
   <speaker>O-REN</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you waiting for? Are you on a date? Attack her you fool!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God...  ...She just called you a fool. She just called you a fool in front of me. Not only am I your opponent. I'm a female fellow countryman. And you're going to risk your life - to say nothing of harming me - for a woman who refers to you as a fool?</utterance>
   <speaker>O-REN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>is furious, and slaps Mr. Barrel on the shoulder.</utterance>
   <speaker>O-REN</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>The Bride acts like she's embarrassed to witness what she just saw. Mr. Barrel spins in O-Ren's direction shooting her a look she's never seen from him before. He then looks back to the Bride.</context>
      <utterance>Attack, Goddamn you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her a BEAT longer...then says as he resheaths his sword;</context>
      <utterance>I'll owe ya one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BARREL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INSERT: The Blade sliding back down into the Sheath, The Handle locks into place with a Click. He looks back over his shoulder at his former Mistress, and says;</context>
      <utterance>The things I do for a pretty face.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BARREL</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>O-Ren fries and egg on her head. Then with his sheathed Sword in his right hand, and his left hand in his pants pocket, he walks across the carnage-strewn room and out the front door. As he walks, when he's parallel with the Bride, He stops and says;</context>
      <utterance>I quit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BARREL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About that one you owe me.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BARREL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna collect someday, you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He continues walking without a look back. Before he Exits the restaurant, he throws a look in Sofie's direction, Who's lying minus her arm in a pool of her own blood, and says;</context>
      <utterance>I'll be disappointed if you don't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MR. BARREL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tough luck bout that arm Sofe. He exits the Movie. O-REN and The BRIDE match eyes. The Japanese gal says;</utterance>
   <speaker>O-REN</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very funny.  Your instrument is quite impressive.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Domo.</utterance>
   <speaker>O-REN</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where was it made?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okinawa.</utterance>
   <speaker>O-REN</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whom in Okinawa made you this steel?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Hattori Hanzo steel.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>O-REN</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>(pause)</context>
      <utterance>Swords however never get tired. I hope you've saved your energy. If you haven't, you might not last five minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>O-REN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you seen the garden in this establishment?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>O-REN</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>O-Ren moves out of the position she's stood in for the entire battle. She steps on the doormat of a corpse, that serves the same purpose of a bottom step, and moves over to the white paper wall and slides it open....REVEALING.... .....A WHITE WINTER WONDERLAND, set against a Jet Black sky. A Snow-covered Japanese Garden awaits right outside. Snow falls from the sky (Slightly artificial, not phony - but Operatic/Theatrical). O-Ren stands next to the Bride in the doorway looking out into the white night.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, you really should. It's quite beautiful. Allow me.</utterance>
   <speaker>O-REN</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>The Queen of the Tokyo Underworld steps outside... The Bride follows her...</context>
      <utterance>As last looks go, you could do worse.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CLASH - DANCE - SEPARATE...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>does a Somersault over the Bride's head, landing behind her opponent. She brings her Sword down in a Slashing Swing... SLASHING The BRIDE across her back - Spinning her around... O-Ren goes in for the kill...The Bride meets her blade... The Blades Clash and Lock...The Two Women's faces come together as the Blades become entangled... O-Ren moves her arm in a counter-clockwise motion that loosens the grip enough to bring her sword handle hard into The Bride's mouth... Knocking her backwards over a small, stone bench - Flat on her ass in a koi pond. - The Combat Guitar Stops - O-Ren doesn't charge the fallen blonde, She laughs;</context>
      <utterance>O-REN LEAPS in the air</utterance>
   <speaker>O-REN</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>The Combat Guitar starts again...As The Bride slowly rises out of the koi pond. She brings up her sword and Says Calmly to O-Ren in Japanese;</context>
      <utterance>Silly Caucasian girl likes to play with samurai swords. Bill might of humored you, but you will find neither humor nor mercy at my blade. Now unless you intend to commit sepeku among the koi, stand up and fight. You may not be able to fight like a samurai, but you can at least die like a samurai.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>The Two Women Clash Swords furiously, their attack ends with</context>
      <utterance>Attack me. With everything you have.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>O-REN</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I apologize for ridiculing you earlier.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>They continue breathing...</context>
      <utterance>Accepted.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>O-REN</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>The Flamenco Guitar begins again, as The Two Women Circle each other for their final attack. With all the quickness and skill at their command, they clash in a superb display of Samurai Swordplay...TILL...They Find themselves on opposite sides of a garden wall... ...The Bride and O-Ren both begin Running diagonally through the snow, Swords held up high, Facing each other, Continuing to run even after they passed the wall, Screaming their Samurai hearts out...</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>O-REN</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>Her sword FALLS from her grip...in the snow by her feet.</context>
      <utterance>That really was a Hattori Hanzo sword...</utterance>
   <speaker>O-REN</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>O-Ren FALLS to her knees, toppling forward. Left Cheek in the snow, just barely alive, She says;</context>
      <utterance>I always dreamed of owning one...</utterance>
   <speaker>O-REN</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did he make it for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>The Last thing she says before she dies;</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>O-REN</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>With her cheek resting against the snow, her eyes close and she's gone. The BRIDE removes a white handkerchief (The One we saw her sewing earlier with "Bill" in the corner), and uses it to wipe the blood, once belonging to the first name on her death list, off her Hanzo Steel.</context>
      <utterance>...He must of liked you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've kept you alive for one reason. Information. Being O-Ren's lawyer, I take it you're familiar with Bill?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In fact, I'd guesstimate, you worked for Bill before O-Ren, and that's how it is you came to work for O-Ren. Am I correct?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought so. Give me the arm you have left.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>She injects Sofie with the gold syringe.</context>
      <utterance>I want information. Now gimme your arm. Sofie offers up her remaining arm.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The cocktail racing through your bloodstream at this moment is Bill's own recipe. He calls it "The Undisputed Truth." Sofie is injected.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, first things first. Where was the other Yubari sister? Yuki?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yuki's sick. She went home early.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do tell? What's wrong with her?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She has a cold.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awwww poor baby. What do you think she'll do when she finds out what happened?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BUSINESS SUIT</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>Yuki staring out into space, says with a drunken voice;</context>
      <utterance>Do you like Ferraris?</utterance>
   <speaker>YUKI</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>She slowly turns to face the older Japanese man in the business suit.</context>
      <utterance>Ferrari...Italian trash.</utterance>
   <speaker>YUKI</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>The man in the business suit giggles at her boldness; she gets annoyed;</context>
      <utterance>Do you find me hot?</utterance>
   <speaker>YUKI</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't laugh! Do you want to fuck me, yes or no?</utterance>
   <speaker>YUKI</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>THEN...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see she has stabbed him in the belly with a samurai short sword, and is slowly dragging the blade across his abdomen, creating a big red grin across his mid-section.</context>
      <utterance>He lets out a GRUNT coming from below.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>YUKI</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>Blade cuts deeper...</context>
      <utterance>How bout now, big boy, do you still wish to penetrate me...</utterance>
   <speaker>YUKI</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>And with her last line, does the final disemboweling slice that sends his insides spilling out onto the barroom floor.</context>
      <utterance>Or is it I who has penetrated you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When she stops shedding tears, she'll start shedding blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Best guess, what will she do?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't hafta guess, she'll come after you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will she ever give up?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She won't have to. When she finds</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>you, I don't know who will win. But what I do know is, she will find you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is she more skilled than I?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Skilled won't be the word.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be coy with me, bitch. What would be the word?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bride takes this in...then moves on.</context>
      <utterance>Crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, now I want all the information on the Deadly Vipers,... What they've been doing and where I can find them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.; ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sofie, Sofie, my Sofie, I'm so sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please forgive my betrayal -- He shhhh's her off screen;</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.; ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- no more of that. I invented that truth serum. Once it entered your bloodstream, you no longer had a choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, still --</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.; ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- But still -- nothing, except my aching heart over what she's done to my beautiful and brilliant Sofie.  If you had to guess why she left you alive, what would be your guess?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guessing won't be necessary. She informed me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>Then with SUPERMAN X-RAY VISION we see through the helmet to the Bride's face inside as she says the last line.</context>
      <utterance>I'm allowing you to keep your wicked life for one reason and one reason only. So you can tell him, in person, everything that happened here tonight. I want him to witness the extent of my mercy..., by witnessing your deformed body. I want you to tell him, all the information you just told me. I want him to know what I know. I want him to know I want him to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I want them all to know, they'll all soon be as dead as O</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WE CUT TO A</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>CU of SOFIE WE PAN to a CU of YUKI Bill says off screen;</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.; JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If O-Ren was number one, unless she's being tricky, Vernita Green will be number two.</utterance>
   <speaker>YUKI</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is Vernita Green?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S., JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>Yuki blows a pink bubble gum bubble, it pops and she says in English;</context>
      <utterance>Los Angeles. Vernita's in Pasadena. But the woman you want will hold up in a low budget motel, fifteen of twenty minutes away from stepping on board a plane departing LAX. If I had to bet...I'd say Hawthorne.</utterance>
   <speaker>YUKI</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>California, here I come.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CU Yuki's face as she watches The Bride driving away the Bride drive away. from the scene of her latest victory. CU Yuki, smiles. Now's the YUKI'S POV: The yellow time. pussy wagon drives away.</context>
      <utterance>Two down, and three to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>the surveillance seat of her exterior of the motel, sports car. Her hands are the Bride is staying in. busy below frame. The motel is located on a Hawthorne residential street. Her yellow pickup truck is parked on the street.</context>
      <utterance>Yuki, at night, sitting in YUKI'S POV: The</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>WHEN...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yuki yells to the figure across the street.</utterance>
   <speaker>YUKI</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>We see the back-turned figure of the Bride slightly freeze upon hearing the Japanese greeting. Without turning around she says;</context>
      <utterance>Conigute wa!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Conigute wa.  Yuki?</utterance>
   <speaker>YUKI</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>The Bride turns around to face the young avenger.</context>
      <utterance>Bingo! THRILLER MUSIC begins on the soundtrack.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>YUKI</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>Yuki giggles.</context>
      <utterance>You can kill yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>YUKI</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Taking a trip?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was.</utterance>
   <speaker>YUKI</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You still are. One way.</utterance>
   <speaker>YUKI</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>Yuki giggles.</context>
      <utterance>I know you feel you must avenge your sister. But I beg you...walk away.</utterance>
   <speaker>YUKI</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>Yuki giggles. Then she takes out a flashlight, and switches on the beam.</context>
      <utterance>You call that begging? You can beg better than that.</utterance>
   <speaker>YUKI</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I see your face? I've heard your beauty is exquisite. I would like to see for myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>Yuki shines the flashlight beam in the Bride's face.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>YUKI</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ohhhh,...look how pretty your face is. Oooohhh,... I want to touch it.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Domo.</utterance>
   <speaker>YUKI</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>Yuki then shines the flashlight up into her own face.</context>
      <utterance>Your face is so pretty, I just want to put both of my palms against your cheeks and give you little tiny kisses.</utterance>
   <speaker>YUKI</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do I look?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>YUKI</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're just saying that 'cause I told you how pretty you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yuki, you're gorgeous.</utterance>
   <speaker>YUKI</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>Yuki's gorgeous?</context>
      <utterance>Really? Is that how you'd describe me to somebody if I wasn't here?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>Yuki giggles.</context>
      <utterance>You bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't make me kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>YUKI</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>Yuki removes the Israel sub-machine gun from behind her back and FIRES A LOUD INTENSE VOLUME of firepower at The Bride. The Bride dives out of her way, just as her yellow pussy wagon is demolished by the ammo. The Bride, with her samurai sword in her hand, and her backpack full of money, takes off running across a couple of front lawns... Yuki chases her with machine gun fire... The Bride LEAPS over a long hedge...disappearing Behind it. Yuki runs after her, firing all the way, destroying the hedge... The Bride darts across the street, she hits the ground and rolls under a Volkswagen van. Bullet FIRE EXPLODES all around the Bride as she rolls out on the other side. She removes her 9mm automatic and returns fire from behind the van.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>YUKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yuki yells to her in English;</utterance>
   <speaker>YUKI</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>She takes out a hand grenade, removes the pin with her teeth, and slides it towards the Bride. The Bride sees the live hand grenade skidding and sliding on the asphalt towards her... She takes off running...as the Volkswagen van EXPLODES BEHIND</context>
      <utterance>You think you're safe! I say; Ha!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuki speeds after her, but this time she pops the curb and drives across the front lawns on the street heading right for her. The Bride runs into the house she's in front of. She runs through the living room, to the kitchen and the back door, but the kitchen's where the family that lives here is hiding and they block the door. Yuki's sports car pulls up in front of the house. She stands up in the convertible. Takes out a grenade, pulls the pin and says;</context>
      <utterance>Stay in your house and stay down on the floor!</utterance>
   <speaker>YUKI</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>She lobs the grenade up on the porch, then throws herself face down on the lawn. The porch and the front of the house explodes into splinters. Everybody in the kitchen is blown back. Realizing there's no getting out of the back door, the Bride runs back into the living room that's now missing a wall, and runs up the home's staircase leading to the bedrooms. Yuki steps into the house, sub-machine gun in hand... The Bride makes it to the top of the stairs, and is just about to disappear behind the upstairs hallway wall...</context>
      <utterance>Time for the rabbit to come out of her hole!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuki screams like a little girl at the pain. She yells from the doorway into the hallway;</context>
      <utterance>Gotcha!</utterance>
   <speaker>YUKI</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>The Bride answers Yuki back with an imitation of Yuki's giggle, which makes the youngin blow her top.</context>
      <utterance>You fucking bitch! You shot me in my breast! They're not fully developed yet, you fucking asshole! Now I'm always gonna have a dimple!</utterance>
   <speaker>YUKI</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>She fires her machine gun around the corner, tearing up everything around the Bride. When the young girl stops firing, the Bride yells;</context>
      <utterance>Piss me off!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>From her hiding place, Yuki snorts a line of baby blue powder. It gives her energy.</context>
      <utterance>Yuki, in about two minutes there's going to be an army of police here. So if you're gonna kill me, now's the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S., ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>Slapping a new clip in her machine gun.</context>
      <utterance>So what's it gonna be bitch?</utterance>
   <speaker>YUKI</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>Yuki comes around the corner FIRING her machine gun in the</context>
      <utterance>That fucking does it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>NURSE OWENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>on her cell phone, a business card in her hand, with a number written on the back that says, "B. Owens," and her phone number. She's bleeding from her five bullet holes. Sitting in a pool of her own blood. She's starting to tremble. We can't see where she's at, but it's somewhere surrounded by wood planks. The moon shines into the structure.</context>
      <utterance>Hello. CU The Bride</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, I'm calling Nurse Owens --</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE OWENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is this.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know me, but --</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE OWENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- And I don't want to neither. Now</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE OWENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know how you got my number, but you can just rip that shit up, because --</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- I've been shot five times --</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE OWENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Stop, I don't wanna hear no more. I got problems of my own.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm dying.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE OWENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then bitch, you better call yourself a ambulance, cause I don't do this shit no more.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't call an ambulance.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE OWENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- No, you can call a ambulance, you just don't want to. But if your ass is really dying, you ain't got no motherfuckin choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do have a choice, and I'm choosing to call you. If you refuse to help me, I'll die. And that will be your choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE OWENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bitch, I don't even know you!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you need to know? I'm from Earth, I'm a woman, I'm dying, and only you can help me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>NURSE OWENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, where you at?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm in Hawthorne. I'm hiding in a kids treehouse. It's a street called, "Dimmick". 1-7-3-6 Dimmick Avenue. There's a bunch of police cars and firetrucks, about two blocks away.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE OWENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatcha do, crawl two blocks?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nurse Owens likes that last line.</context>
      <utterance>If you can't walk, you better crawl.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE OWENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got you some money dontcha, or am I doin this out of the goodness of my heart?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You come and get me, today's pay day.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE OWENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ain't too far away. You gonna bleed to death I get there in a half a hour?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE OWENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, I'll be there in fifteen minutes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NURSE OWENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just you better be there when I get there, and you better be shot five times, and your bony ass better be on your last motherfuckin legs.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know I have a bony ass?</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE OWENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Nurse hangs up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>You sound like you have a bony ass.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Glad you made it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE OWENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The nurse hands the Bride a big bottle of Wild Turkey.</context>
      <utterance>There's cops all over here, I had to be cool. They tend to notice things like Negroes sneaking around people's backyards.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE OWENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This shit's gonna hurt, and I ain't got no anesthetic.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE OWENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So git busy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smoking her menthol Kool, Nurse Owens says;</context>
      <utterance>That fuckin smarts.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE OWENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, bullets are bad news. In the future, you should avoid them if you can.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll keep that in mind. So, do I have a future?</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE OWENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll live to kill again.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She passes out.</context>
      <utterance>Splendid.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DOORMAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>TWO EYES</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard you had a game?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORMAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TWO EYES</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They call me Bill.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORMAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bill what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>A FEMALE VOICE FROM OFF SCREEN says to the Doorman;</context>
      <utterance>That, no one ever calls me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The door opens revealing BILL to the other side of the door, and for the first time, to the audience. He looks cool.</context>
      <utterance>Open the door Alburt, let's see what this Bill looks like.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>L.F. O'BOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you a policeman, Bill?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>L.F. laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Not anymore?</utterance>
   <speaker>L.F.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bill steps inside and the game continues in earnest.</context>
      <utterance>Let him play, Alburt.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men stare...</context>
      <utterance>You'll have to.</utterance>
   <speaker>L.F.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now now boys...Mr. Bill, do you intend to start any shit with that sword?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I give you my word of honor, I will start nothing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>L.F.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(back to game)</context>
      <utterance>Good enough for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miss O'Boyle required a two-hundred dollar membership fee.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's rather pricey.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bill takes out a roll of bills that would choke a rodeo bull to death. He peels off two hundred.</context>
      <utterance>You wanna play for free, go to Vegas. You start now you'll be there by sundown.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I'll stay here. I'm thirsty.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bill walks over to the suite's bar, a YOUNG WOMAN tends it.</context>
      <utterance>That way.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beer.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty dollars for a beer?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>High cost of living shooter. You don't like it, go to Vegas. You can</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>get a prime rib dinner there for</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bartender produces a dixie cup, and a can of Budweiser. She pops the top and fills the cup, leaving half of the beer inside the can. She then offers only the cup to Bill.</context>
      <utterance>What am I going to do, I'm thirsty.  Pour the beer.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lifts the dixie cup to his lips, and says;</context>
      <utterance>I don't get that? The Bartender slowly shakes her head, no.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bill approaches the table with his dixie cup of beer.</context>
      <utterance>Cheers.</utterance>
   <speaker>L.F.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dropping his money roll on the table...</context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen, let's see if the new kid in school wants to play right away.  How bout it new kid, you wanna handle my bones, or do you just like to watch?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Color L.F. impressed.</context>
      <utterance>I came to play.</utterance>
   <speaker>L.F.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With her table stick, she pushes the dice to Bill. He takes them and inspects them.</context>
      <utterance>Boys take a look at this man, he's what Webster's calls, a gambler. The dice belong to you , sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>L.F.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope you're not implying anything, friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alburt starts to move from his position by the door.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not implying anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The players watch L.F. And Bill, an opposite ends of the table, trade quips. Bill looks from the dice to L.F.</context>
      <utterance>That did it fuckhead, you're out the door -- L.F. motions him back to his position.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You looked me over when I stood in your doorway. I'm looking you over as I step up to your table. If I don't know, I don't throw.</utterance>
   <speaker>L.F.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you satisfied?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More or less.</utterance>
   <speaker>L.F.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we're getting into a antagonistic relationship.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm sorry, I thought you were trying to take my money, and I was trying to take yours.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>L.F.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bill throws ten thousand dollars on the table, the room reacts.</context>
      <utterance>It's just a game.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're game, take my bet sportsman.</utterance>
   <speaker>L.F.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bill smiles as he rolls the dice in his hand, then throws...7...The room reacts...L.F. smiles and pushes the money and the dice back to Bill with her stick. He picks up his winnings, tosses them back on the table, and says;</context>
      <utterance>Covered.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The room reacts.</context>
      <utterance>Shoot it all.</utterance>
   <speaker>L.F.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds the dice in his fist...and throws...5...</context>
      <utterance>Covered.</utterance>
   <speaker>L.F.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bill throws...5...more reaction...more money...</context>
      <utterance>The point is five, gentlemen, five is the point.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shoot it all.</utterance>
   <speaker>L.F.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shoots again, he wins again... L.F. MOVES THE MONEY in front of him. Bill picks up the stack of moola...L.F. Stands behind her table, stick in her hand, eyes on her opponent.</context>
      <utterance>Covered.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shoot it all.</utterance>
   <speaker>L.F.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretty lucky tonight, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Play a game of luck long enough you're bound to meet some lucky people.</utterance>
   <speaker>L.F.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know we've never been properly introduced, I'm L.F. O'Boyle.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I'm not interested.</utterance>
   <speaker>L.F.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you're rude. Why so rude rude boy, I'm only trying to be friendly.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't come here to make friends. I came here to shoot a little crap. But then your boy over there hits me up for a two hundred dollar privilege to play fee --</utterance>
   <speaker>L.F.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- That's a membership fee, good for --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>L.F.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So that's your game, you want to teach me a lesson?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanna burn you down. When I'm through with you, you won't have a pot to piss, or a window to throw it out of. You'll thumb a ride out of L.A. wearing a barrel.</utterance>
   <speaker>L.F.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could always save myself this horrible fate by not taking your bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To be replaced by a different fate. The embarrassing truth that you run a gutless game. I won't forget it. I'm sure these gentlemen won't forget it. I'm sure they'll tell people who won't forget it. And we won't come back. If we don't come back, you won't get our money. Couple of weeks, you won't have a game.</utterance>
   <speaker>L.F.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a big mouth, lucky boy. And the idea of taking everything you've won away, and sending you out the door with nothing but a red face, is so appealing to me, that I will take your bet. But.....not with those dice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>L.F.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds out her palm and two new pair of dice (black) are placed in her hand by one of her bodyguards. She sets the dice on the table, and moves them in front of Bill with her stick. Bill looks down at them.</context>
      <utterance>The house's perogative and you know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>L.F.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you would like to change your bet?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He catches the young lady by surprise.</context>
      <utterance>Yes I would.....Shoot it all.....Against myself. His hand scoops the dice off the table.</utterance>
   <speaker>L.F.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the door Alburt says;</context>
      <utterance>Did I stutter, I'm changing my bet. I'm betting I don't make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALBURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yes I can. It's the shooter's perogative, and she knows it.</utterance>
   <speaker>L.F.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Covered.</utterance>
   <speaker>L.F.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He throws....</utterance>
   <speaker>....................BOXCARS.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bill scoops up his money and looks to the lady who's game he just busted.</context>
      <utterance>The spectators go apeshit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I use your phone?</utterance>
   <speaker>L.F.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure it's next to the bed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>L.F.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Game's over, get out! Get the fuck out! No more tonight, go home....</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks over and L.F. is sitting on the floor of the bed. All the players have left, only L.F. and her five tuxedo boys remain.</context>
      <utterance>Vernita's dead? When?  What about her family?  Nice to see Kiddo hasn't gone completely apeshit. No idea where she is?  Okay that did it, we're going to Texas and talk sense into Budd before  makes him number three.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(pause)</context>
      <utterance>We're going to have a talk about this later.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm not exactly among friends at the moment.  I'll keep that in mind, bye bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got a nose problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>L.F.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said you could use my phone. I didn't say I wouldn't listen.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is true.</utterance>
   <speaker>L.F.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't burn me down you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Course not. First rule of any house, ya gotta have LUCKY GUY comes in and wipes the place out insurance.</utterance>
   <speaker>L.F.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Standing up, folding his winnings into his inside jacket pocket, looking at L.F. and her boys, he says;</context>
      <utterance>If there weren't losers it wouldn't be a game.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without another word he exits the hotel room. Nobody makes a move to stop him. L.F. O'Boyle and her henchmen stand still as they wait for the sound of the elevator in the hall. The Bride's Voice comes on the soundtrack;</context>
      <utterance>I sincerely hope you mean that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>L.F. O'Boyle tells her men;</context>
      <utterance>What L.F. O'Boyle didn't know was, the real game was just beginning. Bill was on the job, and she was the target. Now Bill was the greatest assassin of the 20th century. In fact the term HITMAN was coined for him. And he rarely performs actual assassinations anymore. However every once in awhile - to keep his hand in - he does. Only he plays a game. He doesn't start big trouble...he lets them start it. If they do, they're dead. If they don't, not only won't he perform, he'll take the hit off the market. It's kind of fun watching people gamble when they don't know they're gambling, isn't it? They hear the elevator in the hall.</utterance>
   <speaker>L.F.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Five men go out the door.</context>
      <utterance>Get my money back. Don't kill him. Chop off all his fingers. Alburt smiles.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>L.F. Is too hysterical to answer.</context>
      <utterance>Do you know a Jessica?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drops her......</context>
      <utterance>Well, she knows you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great day in the morning. Brother Bill livin up to his familia obligation.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How ya doin' Budd?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Budd squints into the sun at the woman in Bill's ear.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, you know my life, Bill, just a mad rush of wild parties and wealthy women.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that that tall blonde one-eyed Viking bitch in the passenger seat?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Elle. Want to say hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never said "bye," can't seem to think of a reason to say, "hi."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd ya wanna talk about?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you not going to invite me in?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I ask why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It stinks in there, that's why. Now what's so important it requires a reunion?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You tryin to tell me she cut her way through eighty-eight bodyguards 'fore she got to O-Ren?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. There wasn't really eighty eight of them, they just called themselves The Crazy 88.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bill nods his head, "yes."</context>
      <utterance>She got 'er a Hattori Hanzo sword?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She has a Hanzo Jingi sword.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He made her one? Didn't he swear a blood oath never to make another sword?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Budd doesn't say anything at first...THEN;</context>
      <utterance>It would appear he's broken it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Them Japs know how to carry a grudge don't they? Or is it just you tend to bring that out in people?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know this is a ridiculous question before I ask, but you by any chance haven't kept up with your swordplay?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell, I pawned that years ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You pawned a Hattori Hanzo sword?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The disrespect is pain.</context>
      <utterance>Yep.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was priceless.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not in El Paso it ain't. In El Pso I got me 250 Dollars for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since it was a gift from me, why didn't you offer me the chance to buy it back?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because that would've required me to acknowledge your existence. Drunken bum though I may be, I don't need booze that bad. But who the hell gives a crap anyway. That bitch ain't gittin no Bushido points for killin a white trash piece of shit like me with a samurai sword. I'm a bouncer in a titty bar, Bill. If she wants to fight me, all she gotta do is come down to the Club, start some shit, and we'll be in a a fight.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Budd sees Bill's true concern for his welfare. Bill tries to charm his brother.</context>
      <utterance>-- Budd, you need to listen to me. I know we haven't spoken for quite some time, and the last time we spoke wasn't the most pleasant. But you need to get over being mad at me, and start becoming afraid of Bea. Because she is coming, and she's coming to kill you. And unless you accept my assistance, I have no doubt she will succeed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Budd chuckles.</context>
      <utterance>Can't we forget the past, and look at the happy side of all this?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what would that happy side be?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Budd is touched by Bill's concern and chuckles to himself.</context>
      <utterance>She's brought "the boys" back together.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I appreciate the concern on your face, but there's a difference 'tween "the boys", time can't erase. I don't dodge guilt. And I don't Jew outta payin my comeuppance. That woman deserves her revenge. And we deserve to die. But then again, so does she. So I guess we'll just see now, won't we.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Budd doesn't say anything, he just moves towards the back,</context>
      <utterance>You're late, Budd, this shit ain't school, ya know.</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>passing by a STRIPPER serving drinks.</utterance>
   <speaker>STRIPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Budd.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANOTHER STRIPPER walks out of the ladies' room and says to him;</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Lucky.</utterance>
   <speaker>STRIPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Budd, honey, the toilet's at it again. There's shitty water all over the floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take care of it, Suzie Pie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The BARTENDER gives her a beer bottle of Shiner Bock. As she drinks the Texas brew...SHE....</context>
      <utterance>Shiner.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...Looking for Budd among the crowd... ...She sees him... ...He's the bouncer... ...She observes him... ...he's sitting on a stool, observing the crowd, moving his head to the music... SHAW BROTHERS ZOOM into her eyes; VENGEANCE THEME plays on the soundtrack. Her hand removes her sog from its sheath. She moves through the crowd of Texas two-steppers, sog in hand, towards Budd sitting oblivious on his stool....</context>
      <utterance>...Watches the BAND.... ...The crowd...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bride, hurting and incapacitated from the shotgun blast, still nevertheless defiant, SPITS a gob of bloody saliva, right in ole Budd's face. Budd, gob of spit running down on his cheek and nose. The cowboy removes a red bandana from his back pocket, and wipes away the goo. Then his eyeballs go down to the spitter.</context>
      <utterance>...But I don't wont to neather.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With the help of his cowboy boot he rolls The Bride over onto her stomach, exposing her butt. SNAPPING the barrel closed, he takes aim and FIRES both barrels -- EXECUTION STYLE -- right into her keister. The Bride does the one thing she has yet to do with any opponent during the movie up till now. Her head rears back and she lets out a SCREAM!</context>
      <utterance>Now I know when it comes to a rock salt burn, you're feelin pretty much like a expert bout now. But truth be told, you ain't felt all rock salt's got to offer till you took a double dose in your backside.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That gentled ya down, didn't it? Yep...ain't nobody a badass with two barrels of rock salt dug deep in their backyard.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bill?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wrong brother, you hateful bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>....Budd?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bingo.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what do I owe this dubious pleasure?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This gets Elle's attention.</context>
      <utterance>I just caught me the cowgirl, ain't never been caught.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you mean what I think you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you think I mean I got 'er, you thought right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you kill her?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet I ain't. But I can sure do it easy enough. She's so gentle right now, I could preform her coup de grace with a rock.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you waiting for, run outta liquid courage.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We stay on Elle's side for the following exchange.</context>
      <utterance>No. It's just...I ain't killed nobody in a long Goddamn time. And just 'tween you, me, and Jesus Christ, kinda made me a promise I wasn't gonna. Be that however it is. Back when I did kill people...I got paid for it. Just don't seem right...turn amateur this time of life.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>We cut back to Budd's side. And what he's holding is The Bride's Hattori Hanzo sword.</context>
      <utterance>Anywho, guess what I'm holdin in my hand right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A brand spankin new Hattori Hanzo sword. And I'm here to tell ya Elle, that's what I call sharp.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, that's hard to say. Seein it's priceless and all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll give you a hundred thousand dollars for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure you would. But I'll take, one million.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeez Budd, who'd ever guess you were such a capitalist. I thought drunks like yourself were beyond such monetary concerns?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well Elle, a million dollars buys a whole lotta Jack.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why then are you selling it to a hateful bitch like me, when you know Bill would pay more?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's gonna be on yours.</context>
      <utterance>If I'm gonna drink myself to death, ...it won't be on Bill's dollar.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the terms?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You buy a ticket to Texas, and I'll see you here tomorrow mornin. You give me a million in foldin cash, I'll give you the greatest sword ever made by a man. How's that sound?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds like we got a deal. One</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>condition.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You kill her tonight.  And one more thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said one condition.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a caveat to the same condition.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She must suffer to her last breath.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That Elle darlin, I can pretty damwell guarantee.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I'll see you in the morning millionaire.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>"PAULA SCHULTZ."</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bride just GLARES up at the two tormentors, with the only weapon she has left, the contempt in her stare. Budd turns to Ernie and says in SPANISH, subtitled in English;</context>
      <utterance>Budd and Ernie stand over her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode>SPANISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at those eyes. This bitch is furious. You grab her feet, I'll get her head.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>The Bride knows how these fiends derive satisfaction, and she won't give it to them.</context>
      <utterance>Got anything to say?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode>SPANISH</mode>
      <context>The two fiends laugh, then bend down to lift The Bride and carry her over to the pine box. She struggles with her bound legs and arms...Both men DROP her to the ground. Budd whips out a can of mace from his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>In America white women call this the silent treatment.  And we let 'em think, we don't like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds the can of mace spray by her eyes. She stops. Her eyes go to the nozzle of the spray can, then to Budd.</context>
      <utterance>Hey hey hey, wiggle worm, look at this.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He removes a flashlight from behind his back and turns on the beam.</context>
      <utterance>Looky here bitch, this is a can of mace. Now you're goin underground tonight, and that's all there is to it. But, when I bury ya, I was gonna bury you with this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes move to the right, indicating the flashlight.</context>
      <utterance>But if you're gonna act like a horse's ass, I'll spray this whole Goddamn can in your eyeballs. Then you'll be blind, burnin, and buried alive. So what's it gonna be sister?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men lift up The Bride, and carry her over to the pine box and place her in. Budd puts the flashlight inside. He picks up the pine lid, and is just about to place it over the coffin...</context>
      <utterance>You may be stupid, but at least you ain't bloody stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHEN...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...her eyes hold his for as long as she can,</context>
      <utterance>...He locks eyeballs with The Bride...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She does. The Bride continues in VO;</context>
      <utterance>Well, now that you've had a nice, good cry, let's figure out how to get out of here? You're breathing like you just been fuckin. Calm down...close your mouth, and start breathing short breaths, through your nose.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Fear comes into her voice as she combats herself.</context>
      <utterance>That's a lot better. But you're still too agitated. Can you hear your heart? It's like I'm buried alive with Buddy Rich. Turn off that flashlight.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>She does. The screen goes Jet Black</context>
      <utterance>No! I can't turn off the light. Yes you can. The darkness will have a calming effect. Now turn off that fucking light.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didja do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A smile spreads across Elle's face. She rests her head back against the seat's headrest. Her eyelids close. She slightly parts her lips...and lets out a; "Ahhhhhhhhhhhhhhh" This is the face of satisfaction.</context>
      <utterance>Elle darlin, she's sufferin as we speak.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>As Bill tells this story, it will be illustrated On Screen by footage from Old Shaw Brothers Martial arts flicks of the 70's. Especially Films that feature Chinese Actor LO LIEH as the old, white-haired, white-eyebrowed Villian "PAI MEI."</context>
      <utterance>Once upon a time in China, some believe around the year, one-double knot-three.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.; CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...head priest of The White Lotus Clan, Pai Mei, was walking down the road, contemplating whatever a man with Pai Mei's infinite power would contemplate -- Which is another way of saying, who knows. When, a Shaolin monk appeared on the road traveling in the opposite direction. As the monk and the priest crossed paths...Pai Mei -- in a practically unfathomable display of generosity, gave the monk the slightest of nods. The nod, was not returned. Was it the intention of the Shaolin monk to insult Pai Mei? Or, did he just fail to see the generous social gesture? The motives of the monk, remain, unknown. What is known, were the consequences. The next morning Pai Mei appeared at the Shaolin Temple, and demanded that the temple's head Abbot offer Pai Mei his neck, to repay the insult. The Abbot, at first, tried to console Pai Mei, only to find, Pai Mei was inconsolable. So began, the massacre of the Shaolin Temple, and all sixty of the monks inside, at the fists of the White Lotus. And so began, the legend of Pai Mei's Ten-Point Palm - Exploding Heart Technique.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What praytell, is a ten-point palm - exploding heart technique?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We see on screen Pai Mei demonstrate this technique on five shaolin monks. Who after being hit...take five steps...then</context>
      <utterance>Quite simply, the deadliest blow in all of the martial arts. He hits you with his fingertips, at ten different pressure points on your body. And then, he lets you walk away. But once you've taken five steps, your heart explodes inside your body, and you fall to the floor dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>fall to the floor dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did he teach you that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. He teaches no one the ten-point palm - exploding heart technique. But he is Nietzsche's psalm personified. If Pai Mei doesn't kill you, he will make you stronger. Now one of the things I always liked about you, Kiddo, is you appear wise beyond your years. Then allow me to impart, a word to the wise. Whatever - WHAT - EVER - Pai Mei says, Obey. If you flash him - even for an instant - a defiant eye, he'll pluck it out. And if you throw any American sass his way, he will snap your back and your neck like they were twigs, and that will be the story of you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Caught him in a good mood, aye?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She climbs out, and gets her bag out of the back. Bill casts a glance at the stone steps he just decended.</context>
      <utterance>More like a sadistic one.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just seeing those steps again makes me ache. You're gonna have plenty of fun carrying buckets of water up and down that fucker.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did he accept me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because he's a very very very old man. And like all rotten bastards, when they get old, they become lonely. Not that that has any effect on their disposition. But they do learn the value of company.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When will I see you again?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the title of my favorite soul song of the Seventies.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing. When he tells me you're done.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When do you think that might be?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That my dearest, all depends on you. Now remember, no backtalk, no sarcasm. Least not for the first year. You're going to have to let him warm up for you. He hates Caucasians, despises Americans, and has nothing but contempt for women, so in your case, that may take a little while. Adios.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PAI MEI's VOICE ECHOES back;</context>
      <utterance>Hello! Her Voice ECHOES in the cavernous temple.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>A beautiful (but dusty) Mahagony staircase leads to Pai Mei's private chamber.</context>
      <utterance>Up the stairs, yankee woman!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The still unseen Man's voice BOOMS back;</context>
      <utterance>More stairs, Jesus Christ.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She climbs the wooden staircase.</context>
      <utterance>If it is Christ you seek, turn back now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Teacher, I am unworthy to be your student -- Pai Mei is still unseen.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your Mandarin is lousy. I can't understand a single word you say. It causes my ears discomfort. You are not to speak unless spoken to. Do you understand Mandarin any better than you speak it?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I speak Japanese very well --</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI    MEI'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't ask if you speak Japanese, or Mongolian, for that matter. I asked if you understand Mandarin?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bill is your master, is he not?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your master tells me you're not entirely unschooled. What training do you possess?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am proficient in a combination of Tiger and Crane style. And I am more than proficient in the exquisite art of the Samurai Sword.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>he makes a SNORTING</utterance>
   <speaker>SOUND)</speaker>
      <mode> SOUND)</mode>
      <context>This brings up The Bride's eye...She GLARES at the old man.</context>
      <utterance>The exquisite art of the samurai sword. Don't make me laugh. Your so called exquisite art, is only fit for Japanese fat heads. You really are a silly ass.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lowers her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Impudent dog! You dare glare at me!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry master --</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause...</context>
      <utterance>-- Silence! I do not wish to hear your unintelligible excuses.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your anger amuses me. Do you believe you are my match?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you aware I kill at will?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it your wish to die?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you must be stupid. Rise stupid, and let me get a better</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pai Mei laughs to himself again;</context>
      <utterance>look at your ridiculous face. She rises. CU The BRIDE through the scrim, eyes down.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The blonde woman goes to a large wooden drawer. She opens the drawer; it's filled with just about every type of edged weapon.</context>
      <utterance>You breathe hard. The one hundred steps robbed you of your wind. So your stupidity is matched only by your weakness. Is there anything you do well? -- Oh yes, you speak Japanese. I despise the Goddamn Japs. I would of thought an American would be immune to their pompous posturing. Apparently I was wrong. Go to that drawer.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bride removes a large heavy steel Chinese Sword. Pai Mei rises from his sitting position, for the first time, parts the scrim, and approaches the Bride.</context>
      <utterance>Remove the sword.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI    MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bride doesn't need a second invitation, she ATTACKS with the sword. He deftly moves out of the way. The fighting style is now like an old Shaw Brothers film, with Pai Mei dodging at will all of her rapid sword slashes. Quick and skillful as her moves are, they're also full of Effort and Frustration. While Pai Mei effortlessly moves out of the sword's path. He's amused, and Speaks while they fight;</context>
      <utterance>Let's see how good you really are. Try and land a blow. If you land a single blow, I'll bow down and call you master.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tries more...</context>
      <utterance>Come now woman, can't you even hit an old man?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He STRIKES her with a blow to her chest, delivered with an open palm, that sends her flying back hard against the wall. She clutches her chest, and coughs up some blood. Pai Mei laughs as he strokes his long white beard.</context>
      <utterance>Your ability really is quite poor.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He HOPS and DUCKS and DODGES her sword easily. He LEAPS HIGH UP IN THE AIR, and LANDS STANDING on the Blade of her Sword. The Bride looks down the blade of her sword and can't believe it. Pai Mei smiles at her and says;</context>
      <utterance>Ha ha ha ha ha! I've fought cripples who posed more of a challenge. Now fight, goddamn you! She ATTACKS with a wild cat's fury.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He does a BACKFLIP off the sword, kicking the Bride in the face in mid-somersault sending her CRASHING THROUGH A WOOD</context>
      <utterance>From here you can get an excellent view of my foot.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALL.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pai Mei stands waiting for her, TWIRLING THE SWORD in his hand like a cheerleader twirling a baton, till the twirling STOPS. The sword's handle is pointed towards the Bride.</context>
      <utterance>The Bride emerges from the hole in the wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>shows determination. Not to win, not even to land a blow,</context>
      <utterance>Give up? Or care to try again? The BRIDE'S FACE</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...Then he TWISTS her arm, till the blade's against her own throat.... ...Then TWISTS again till it's against her hip... ...Then TWISTS again while KICKING her leg, till the blade's edge is against her thigh...</context>
      <utterance>That blade's sharp. Careful not to cut off your own arm.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lets go of her arms, she swings furiously at him... ...he calmly SPINS out of the way. Then, he KICKS her in the stomach, doubling her over, then he brings the Sword between her legs, Blade Edge against her Crotch.</context>
      <utterance>If you can't fight any better than that, what use do you have for a leg?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The BLADE's against the nipple of her right breast.</context>
      <utterance>Now that really would be a shame. He takes the sword from her grasp... SWINGS once... The BLADES's against her jugular. He SWINGS twice... The BLADE's against the pocket of her throat. He SWINGS a third time...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tosses the sword in the air, catching it by the tip of the blade. Then like a mallet, brings the handle end down hard on the top of The Bride's head. She lets out a howl, and falls to the floor, holding the lump on her noggin.</context>
      <utterance>Your swordsmanship is amateur at best.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He CHOPS the sword in half with his hand.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a hundred and fifty years old, and you can't even make me break a sweat.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Like a Gordon Liu and Lo Lieh film, they do their animal style martial arts dance. As she STRIKES and he BLOCKS...he yells out;</context>
      <utterance>Let's see your Tiger and Crane style match my Eagles's Claw. Again she ATTACKS...again he eludes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With little effort on his part, he reaches out and GRABS her wrist, TWISTS...She's on the floor, with her arm stuck out in the air behind her, her wrist still between his fingers. He could literally break her arm in half.</context>
      <utterance>...pathetic.....terrible...you idiot, you should've landed that blow...you call that crane?... Enough, I grow bored.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...The pain is excruciating.....</context>
      <utterance>I asked you to show me what you know, and you did. Not a goddamn thing. He TWISTS her wrist...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like all yankee women, the only thing you know how to do is order</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She CRIES OUT.</context>
      <utterance>in restaurants and spend a man's money. He TWISTS more...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Through gritted teeth, she answers;</context>
      <utterance>Excruciating isn't it? I asked you a question!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could chop off your arm at will. I think I shall. He raises his other hand to chop off her arm. The Bride SCREAMS in ENGLISH;</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No please don't!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you wish to speak romantic languages, you've come to the wrong place.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please don't cut my arm off!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's my arm now. I can do with it what I please. If you can stop me, I suggest you try.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because you're helpless?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you ever felt this before?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Compared to me you're as helpless as a worm fighting an eagle, aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes!!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it your wish to learn how to make others as helpless as you were?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you cook?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since your arm now belongs to me, I want it strong. Can you do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can, but not that close.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you can't do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can put my hand through that at six inches.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He HITS the wall again leaving another hole.</context>
      <utterance>And you could shoot a man from a rooftop with a scope-sight rifle, if you so desired, but this is not what I asked. What if your enemy is three inches in front of you, what do you do then? Curl into a ball? Or do you put your fist through him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She does.</context>
      <utterance>If you want to eat like a dog, I will make you live and sleep like a dog. Outside. If you want to live and sleep like a human being, pick up those sticks.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOOD WALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at her fucked-up hand, then to the wall, hesitating....Then Pai Mei's behind her.</context>
      <utterance>The Bride HITTING it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks off in a huff.</context>
      <utterance>It's the wood that should fear your hand, not the other way around. No wonder you can't do it, you acquiesce to defeat before you even begin.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see one lone rat in the huge pit.</context>
      <utterance>In that pit, is a rat.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pai Mei brings a golden bow and arrow into Frame, and SHOOTS up in the sky. A BIRD FALLS to the earth with a golden arrow stuck through it.</context>
      <utterance>In the sky, is a bird.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hops into the pit, gets down on the ground, lock eyes with her rodent opponent, and goes after it. The BRIDE Practicing her Tiger/Crane combo Kung Fu. MORE wall.... At NIGHT punching the wall in front of her in her sleep. Trying to catch the rat to no avail.</context>
      <utterance>You are to go into that pit, and catch that rat, with your bare hands. If you catch the rat, I will deem you the victor, and tonight you will dine on bird. But, if you can't catch the rat by sundown, I'll deem the victor the rat. And because of the disgrace to my student, I will be forced to kill it. And then I will force you, to consume his body. Because to be my student, you must develop a taste for victory.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHEN...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks up and sees Pai Mei, golden bow in his hand, looking down on her. It's sundown. She stands, dusting herself off (she's dirty from the chase) and looks at her teacher. She picks her dead foe up from the earth, and removes the golden arrow. Then with the rat in her hand, she looks up to her teacher.</context>
      <utterance>A golden arrow kills the rat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She POPS the tiny rat heart in her mouth, and begins to chew. Pai Mei looking down on her, says;</context>
      <utterance>I acknowledge defeat at the paws of this rat. However, I will not eat this filthy vermin. What I will do...  ...is consume his victorious heart.  But tomorrow, you kill a big bird.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How does victory taste?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We do a Shaw Brothers ZOOM into a CU on Pai Mei, he gives an affirmative NOD and GRUNT. The BRIDE'S FIST goes through the wall.</context>
      <utterance>Bitter.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She answers from outside the door;</context>
      <utterance>Woman, is that you who disturbs my meditation?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, teacher.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She does, bowing to one knee.</context>
      <utterance>Enter.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What news do you find so worthy, as to disrupt my bath?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did it teacher. I put my fist through the wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIME CUT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>PAI MEI and the BRIDE looking at the hole in the wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves in front of the wall.....Takes her position...Her right hand in a fist -- Locked and loaded into position.... With Her left hand she reaches out and touches the wall where she'll strike....Like she's transferring her energy into the wood...She removes her left hand...and...STRIKES! She hits it HARD, but her fist doesn't go through. Her eyes sneak a look at the old man, who wears no expression.</context>
      <utterance>Very good. Would you care to demonstrate?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you watching is making me nervous.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And when she does, she DOES it.</context>
      <utterance>Not only that, it has you speaking before you were spoken to. Try again. She does.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CU PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>he says in ENGLISH;</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She immediately goes down to her knees;</context>
      <utterance>Impressive.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you teacher -- He just as immediately, lifts her back up.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You still fight better than you speak. Finally, a woman who understands what's important.</utterance>
   <speaker>THEN...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He MOVES the wall one inch in front of her.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAI MEI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then the old man leaves to finish his bath. The blonde gal begins again....Fist against wood...no effect....starting all over.</context>
      <utterance>Begin again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AGAIN...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her FIST SMASHES into the wood, leaving BLOOD on the lid...</context>
      <utterance>And AGAIN...</utterance>
   <speaker>AGAIN...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A crack in the lid...</context>
      <utterance>And AGAIN...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AGAIN...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More dirt...</utterance>
   <speaker>AGAIN...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even more dirt...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...So that's called a Texas funeral?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got to give it to ya Budd, that's a pretty fucked up way to die. What's the name on the grave she's buried under?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Budd turns on the NOISY blender, as Elle writes down the name Paula Schultz on a small notepad, placing it back inside her pocket. As the blender MASHES ICE, Elle looks around and sees the Bride's Hanzo sword in its sheath, leaning up against the T.V. In the front room. Budd shuts the blender off.</context>
      <utterance>Paula Schultz.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's my money in that black case, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure is.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The tall blonde girl steps into the living room, takes the Hanzo sword, and sits back down on the kitchen chair. She slowly removes the Japanese steel from its wood sheath.</context>
      <utterance>Well then, it's your sword now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Budd answers as he fills up two former peanut butter jars with breakfast margaritas.</context>
      <utterance>So this, is a Hattori Hanzo sword.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a Hanzo sword alright.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>Bill tells me you once had one of your own.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Once.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How does this one compare to that one?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're gonna compare a Hanzo sword, you compare it to every</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands her her margarita, she takes a sip. He takes a gulp.</context>
      <utterance>sword ever made -- wasn't made by Hattori Hanzo. Here, wrap your lips around this.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, which "R" you filled with?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They say the number one killer of old people is retirement. People got'em a job to do, they tend to live a little longer so they can do it. I've always figured warriors and their enemies share the same relationship. So now you ain't gonna hafta face your enemy on the battlefield no more, which "R" are you filled with, Relief or Regret?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little bit of both.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elle looks right at him with her eye, and says;</context>
      <utterance>Bullshit. I'm sure you do feel a little bit of both. But I know damn well you feel one more than you feel the other. The question was which one?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Regret.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah you gotta hand it to the ol' girl. I never saw nobody buffalo Bill the way she buffaloed Bill. Bill useta think she was so damn smart. I tried to tell him... Bill, she's just smart for a blonde.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elle looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>He looks over at Elle and grins.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gestures to the black suitcase by her feet. He smiles and lifts it up on the table, unzipping it open. Lying inside is a cool million, the thousand dollar bills are inside stacks of a hundred thousand each. At the sight of all this lettuce, Budd lets out a whistle.</context>
      <utterance>Want your money?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lifts a stack out of the bag, then another, then another...and when he lifts the third stack out, he looks down and sees a BLACK MAMBA SNAKE coiled underneath. The Black Mamba opens its WIDE JAWS...and LEAPS RIGHT AT</context>
      <utterance>Great day in the morning.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm sorry Budd, that was rude of me wasn't it? Budd -- I'd like to introduce my friend, The Black Mamba.  Black Mamba -- this is Budd. You know before I picked up that little fella, I looked him up on the internet.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elle finishes reading and puts the paper away. She looks down at Budd at her feet, going through all the symptoms she just described.</context>
      <utterance>Fascinating creature the Black Mamba. Listen to this,  "...In Africa, the saying goes, in the bush, an elephant can kill you. A leopard can kill you. And a Black Mamba can kill you. But only with the Mamba, and this has been true in Africa since the dawn of time, is death sure. Hence its handle; Death Incarnate."  Pretty cool, huh?  "...Its neurotoxic venom is one of nature's most effective poisons, acting on the nervous system causing paralysis. The venom of a Black Mamba can kill a human in four hours, if say bitten on the ankle or the thumb. However, a bite to the face or torso can bring death from paralysis within twenty minutes.  Now you should listen to this cause this concerns you.  The amount of venom that can be delivered from a single bit can be gargantuan.  -- You know I've always liked that word Gargantuan, and I so rarely have an opportunity to use it in a sentence.  "If not treated quickly with anti venom, 10 to 15 milligrams can be fatal to human beings. However, the Black Mamba can deliver as much as 100 to 400 milligrams of venom from a single bite."</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now in these last agonizing minutes of life you have left, let me answer the question you asked earlier, more thoroughly. When it comes to that bitch, I gotta lotta "R's" in me. Revenge is one. Retribution is another. Rivalry is definitely one. But I got another</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Budd, dying, watches from the floor as Elle takes out her cell phone and presses one button. The other party comes on the line, but we never hear their side.</context>
      <utterance>"R" for that bitch you might be surprised to find out. Respect. But right at this moment, the biggest "R" I feel, is Regret. Regret that maybe the greatest warrior I have ever met, met her end at the hands of a bushwhackin, scrub, alacky piece of shit like you. The woman deserved better.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Budd tries to make a sound from the floor, Elle calmly places her foot over his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Bill...Elle. I have some tragic news.  Your brother's dead.  I'm sorry baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She put a Black Mamba in his camper.  I got her, sweety.  She's dead.  Let me put it this way. If you ever start feeling sentimental, go to Austin, Texas. When you get here, walk into a florist and buy a bunch of flowers. Then you take those flowers to Huntington cemetery on Fuller and Guadalupe, look for the headstone marked "Paula Schultz", then lay them on the grave. Because you will be standing at the final resting place of BEATRIX KIDDO.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MELANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST GRADE TEACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WHIP PAN TO AN EX CU OF The grown-up BRIDE,</context>
      <utterance>Beatrix Kiddo.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hangs up the cell phone, and looks down at the dead man under her shoe. Picking up the Hanzo sword, she climbs down on the floor on her hands and knees to pick up the fallen money. CU The BLACK MAMBA out from under the refrigerator, behind Elle... Elle senses it. And slowly turns her head to look back.. Both Black Mamba and Elle Driver LOCK EYES... ZOOM INTO BOTH CU's tighter and tighter, till Elle says;</context>
      <utterance>I'm so sorry baby. --Look, I can get there in about four hours, should I come over?  No no no no no, you need me baby. I'm there.  Okay, I'm leaving now, go smoke some pot or something. I'll be there soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bring it on, bitch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FLASH ON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Budd's camper, seen from up high looking down. The BRIDE searching the camper.</context>
      <utterance>EX CU The BRIDE'S EYE - Watching. The BRIDE'S POV:</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH ON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>EX CU Her EYE. The BRIDE'S POV: Budd's camper, Budd exits by himself. The BRIDE searching the camper.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH ON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She watches from a high perch, Budd practicing with a ...</context>
      <utterance>EX CU The BRIDE'S EYE. The BRIDE'S POV:</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMURAI SWORD.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>searching under his bed, she sees a sword on the floor, resting in a shiny, black wood mahagony sheath. She removes it from its hiding place.</context>
      <utterance>The BRIDE</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bravo, Bea. I actually thought that alacky had got the best of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bride unsheaths her sword with great flourish. Elle does the same.</context>
      <utterance>You thought wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Budd's Hanzo sword.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said he pawned it.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without raising their swords into position, the two blonde warriors circle each other.</context>
      <utterance>Guess that makes him a liar, don't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elle?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bea.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was wondering, just 'tween us girls, what did you say to Pai Mei for him to snatch out your eye?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I called him a bastard.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oooh, not so good.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were I to do it over again, I'd bite my tongue.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One more question?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shoot.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Bill?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Villa Quatro.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elle nods her head 'yes.'</context>
      <utterance>Gulf of Mexico?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wouldn't lie to me now?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elle raises up The Bride's Hanzo sword into position. The Bride raises up her sword.</context>
      <utterance>Why lie?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw what you did to that little Mamba in there. Want to try that on somebody your own size?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bride completely drops her sword stance and her samurai bearing.</context>
      <utterance>I intend to.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Elle, I should warn you before we get started. Hattori Hanzo swords are extremely sharp. They can take a little getting used to. Careful not to cut your own arm off.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bride brings her sword back into combat position.</context>
      <utterance>I don't rattle, bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gonna bleed though, you're gonna bleed a lot.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JOSEPHINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Bill, you wanted me to tell you to leave now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I got to go and meet the Duchess.  Do you like it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yes Mr. Bill, it's very pretty.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you put it on the dinner table, so we can enjoy it tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he heads out the patio, he tells her;</context>
      <utterance>Good idea, she'll love it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh and Josephina, take the remaining flowers and spread them around the house, if you would.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JOSEPHINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He exits the patio, then turns around and pops his head back in.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Mr. Bill.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know I just had a great idea. Take the roses, and spread the petals on the bed I just got for her. That'd be a nice thing to come home to, wouldn't it, a bed of roses.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, she'll love that Mr. Bill.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wouldn't mind doing that for me, would you Josephina?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH ON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We follow behind Bill as he moves through his house...He slips on his jacket...Grabs his keys...TWO energetic GERMAN SHEPHERDS follow him out the front door onto his driveway. On his way to his silver Porsche, he roughhouse plays with the dogs, speaking to them in Spanish. When he gets to the sports-car, the dogs won't leave him alone, and one jumps on the Porsche. He yells at it in Spanish;</context>
      <utterance>EX CU The BRIDE'S EYE ....watching....</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode>SPANISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get the fuck off the car, Lucy, Lucy, down!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH ON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The gates in front of Bill's Hacienda home open, and his silver Porsche hits the streets running.</context>
      <utterance>EX CU The BRIDE'S EYE ...watching...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE    BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The Bride's POV: The Glass-enclosed Institution, and Bill standing by himself in the empty lobby.</context>
      <utterance>The attentive audience members among you will have probably noticed, that all my kills have been straight up fights.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'all figured I'd face him with my</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the Bride has said these things, WE'VE seen INSERTS of her putting together her high-powered scope rifle. Snapping on the scope sight. Setting the FOCUS through the CROSSHAIRS. Loading the heavy-duty AMMO. Curling her long white finger around the rifle's TRIGGER. SCOPE SIGHT POV: Bill's head in between the Crosshairs. SUSPENSE THEME is STRETCHED TIGHTER STILL...it will soon break.</context>
      <utterance>Hanzo sword, aye? Well, I figured Bill figured the same thing. I am the product of three godfathers. Bill, Pai Mei, and Hattori Hanzo. Different teachers teach you different things. But one thing I learned from all three, was "in combat, the opponent that does the unexpected, can usually expect to be the victor." Bill would never see this coming. Not from me. And least any of you judge me a bushwhacker, remember...It was Bill who taught me how to shoot.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello Bill.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kiddo, is that really you?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, it's me all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hear you were driving a truck?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My pussy wagon died on me. Who's your little friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He glances down at the sleeping child.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you mean the little tow head next to me, who looks extraordinarily like you?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bride gets choked up again, emotion betrays her voice.</context>
      <utterance>Her name is B.B.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She wipes her eyes. Her hand moves under her shirt, fingertips rest on scar.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Do you approve?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Can she hear us?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not now, she's in dream land.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How old is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean by that?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many years has she been alive?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't ask how old she is, ask, if she's five.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is she five?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't mothers like God, aren't you supposed to automatically know?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did and I do.  I want to meet her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have dinner with us at my hacienda tonight. She's expecting you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew you were on your way, so I told B.B. Her mommy was coming to see her.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What have you told her about me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That you were sick, that you were asleep, but one day you'd wake up and come back to her. And she asked me, "If Mommy's been asleep since I was born, how will she know what I look like?" To which I replied, "Because Mommy's been dreaming of you." And she said, "Then I'm gonna start dreaming of her." So I gave her a</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>picture of you --</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- which one?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The EXACT PHOTO DISSOLVES OVER The Bride's face, then</context>
      <utterance>The one I took of you in Paris, sitting on the steps with the baguette in your hand. Since she was one and a half years old, she's slept with that picture of you next to her bed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, prettier photos of me do exist.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And she's seen them. But the one she wants looking after her while she sleeps is the one of you holding bread.  We normally have dinner around seven, is that convenient?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause....The cars get closer...</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When do we cross swords?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it just so happens, my hacienda comes with its very own private beach. And my private beach, just so happens to look particularly beautiful bathed in moonlight. And there just so happens to be a full moon out tonight. So, swordfighter, if you</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cars will soon pass...</context>
      <utterance>want to sword fight, that's where I suggest. But if you wanna be old school about it - then we can wait till dawn, and slice each other up at sunrise, like a couple real life honest to goodness samurais. As per usual Kiddo, I'll leave the big decisions up to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do me a courtesy?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Slow down as we pass...I want another look at her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wear something nice tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a dress all picked out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will I like it?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said I looked beautiful last time you saw me in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His foot moves off the gas, slowing the car; her foot does the same. The cars in SLOW MOTION start to pass. The Bride looks into the other car.</context>
      <utterance>I'll dress up too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bill on his cell, eyes on rearview.</context>
      <utterance>You fucking maricone!</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you just wait one second there little missy. Unless I'm confused, we are trying to kill each other aren't we? Now I wasn't planning on taking a shot at you in front of the squirt, but, she is asleep. And if you're gonna forget everything I ever taught you, and gawk like you ain't got good sense, I'm gonna take a shot, am I not?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did she wake up?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up.</context>
      <utterance>Of course not. She's like you that way. I look forward to this evening. It was great speaking with you, Bea.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hattori!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANZO</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beatrix, what's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's alive! My baby girl's alive!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="143" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She FIRES...Then moves further into the house. Apparently, this is the do-the-unexpected part of her plan. Fuck the charade, storm the camp, kill everyone she comes across, send Bill to hell, scoop up her daughter, and head for parts unknown. So far, so good. She enters the butcher block kitchen, and finds Bill's cook and housekeeper, Josephina. Josephina stares at the shotgun barrel pointed at her.</context>
      <utterance>Hello Manny.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello Josephina.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello Miss Beatrix.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="144" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay in here and don't come out. If you leave this room I'll shoot you, comprende?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She closes the pantry door, and moves into the hallway leading to the living room. With her back against the wall, holding her weapon tight, she moves down the hall. As she creeps, an unseen Bill yells to her from around the corner.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Back against the wall she creeps down the hall to the end. She pumps the slide, and TURNS THE CORNER - SHOTGUN RAISED -</context>
      <utterance>Kiddo! If you're through shooting the servants, I'm in the living room. You remember how to get to the living room, don'tcha? Go down to the end of the hall, and make a left.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="145" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WHEN...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What the Bride sees in front of her is, Bill in a tuxedo, holding a small, orange squirt gun pointed at her. Standing next to him is five-year-old little B.B., dressed up in a very pretty party dress, arm outstretched holding a orange squirt gun, aimed at The Bride. The three look at each other for a moment, then Bill says;</context>
      <utterance>EX CU The BRIDE'S EYES - blink once. EX CU HER FINGER comes off the trigger.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then he suddenly clutches his abdomen like he's just been shot.</context>
      <utterance>Bang Bang!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="146" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>B.B. lowers her gun and plays out a big dying scene alongside her dad...Bill falls to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Oh B.B., Mommy got us.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>B.B. parrots this.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm dying...I'm dying...</utterance>
   <speaker>B.B.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bill on the floor, says up to his little girl;</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm dying...I'm dying...</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bride, still absentmindedly pointing her weapon at them, is truly thrown. Bill delivers his lines from the floor, spoken like a dying breath;</context>
      <utterance>Fall down sweetheart, Mommy shot you. The little girl falls down pretend dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But then while pretending to be dead, he speaks in a dramatic narrator's voice.</context>
      <utterance>You did it Quick Draw Kiddo. You are-the fastest. And with these last words, pretends to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>B.B. raises her head off the floor and says;</context>
      <utterance>But...little did Quick Draw Kiddo know,...that five-year-old B.B. Gunn was only playing possum, due to the fact she was impervious to bullets.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="147" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bill continues his dramatic narration;</context>
      <utterance>Hey, get back down there, you're playing possum. The little girl's head drops back down.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>B.B. springs up holding her tiny orange squirt gun and says;</context>
      <utterance>So, as the smirking killer approached, what she thought, was a bullet-ridden corpse,...that's when the little B.B. Gunn fired.</utterance>
   <speaker>B.B.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bride continues watching in gobsmackery. Bill raises his head off the floor, and says to her in his normal voice;</context>
      <utterance>Bang bang!</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bride shakes off her confusion, and acts out a big death scene fo her little girl.</context>
      <utterance>Mommy, you're dead - so die.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The little girl in her party dress, runs over to the big girl in her wedding dress, and kneels over her mommy. Mommy opens her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, B.B., you got me. I should have known, you are the best. She falls to the floor and pretends to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>B.B.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't die Mommy, I was just playing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="148" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They embrace each other.</context>
      <utterance>I know baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>B.B.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The female killer says to her daughter as mommieness begins to creep into her voice;</context>
      <utterance>I waited a long time for you to wake up, Mommy. Did you dream of me - I dreamed of you?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds her daughter out at arm's length to get a better look at her.</context>
      <utterance>Every single night, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What a pretty girl you are.</context>
      <utterance>Now let me look at you. My my my...</utterance>
   <speaker>B.B.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>B.B. starts stroking her mother's long blonde hair.</context>
      <utterance>You're pretty too, Mommy.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All of a sudden, Bill has joined them on the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The little girl gets shy.</context>
      <utterance>When I showed you Mommy's picture, tell Mommy what you said.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="149" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>B.B.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said - I said - You're the most beautiful woman I ever saw in the whole white world.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>B.B. points to Manny's blood, which splashed a little on the Bride's wedding gown.</context>
      <utterance>That's the truth. That's what she said.</utterance>
   <speaker>B.B.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Mommy spilled something on her dress.</utterance>
   <speaker>B.B.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blood?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Kool-Aid. Do you like Kool-Aid?</utterance>
   <speaker>B.B.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parroting Bill;</context>
      <utterance>Do you not like it, or do you not know what it is?</utterance>
   <speaker>B.B.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do not know what it is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="150" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The little girl gives a big nod, yes.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it's a very tasty beverage that I used to drink, when I was a little girl. It comes in a lot of different flavors and colors, and it's really good. Maybe we should fix some sometime. Want to do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>B.B. does an exaggerated nod, yes.</context>
      <utterance>Speaking of fixing and drinking and eating, I think it's dinner time don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When you were doin all that fancy shootin, you didn't happen to shoot a nice Mexican woman about forty five years old, did ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whew, then dinner should be done.  Josephina! You can come out now, we're ready for dinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSEPHINA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>He offers his hand to Mommy, and helps her to her feet. Then says to B.B.;</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Mr. Bill.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want to go on top of the world?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She says excitedly;</utterance>
   <speaker>B.B.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He scoops the little girl up, puts her on his shoulders, and as the mommy and the daddy and their little girl walk through the house towards the dinner table, Bill and B.B. Sing The Carpenter's song, "Top Of The World." It's obviously one of their songs.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="151" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>B.B., don't you think Mommy has the prettiest hair in the whole wide world?</utterance>
   <speaker>B.B.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What's better than pretty?</context>
      <utterance>In fact it's better than pretty.</utterance>
   <speaker>B.B.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gorgeous.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bride shows no sign of thawing around Bill.</context>
      <utterance>Very good, gorgeous. Mommy is gorgeous.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know baby, Mommy's kinda mad at Daddy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="152" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid I was. I was a real bad daddy.  Our little girl learned about life and death the other day.  You want to tell Mommy about what happened to Emilio?</utterance>
   <speaker>B.B.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I killed him. I didn't mean to, but I stepped on him and he stopped moving.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Emilio was her goldfish. She came running into my room holding the fish in her hand, crying, "Daddy daddy, Emilio's dead." And I said, "Really, that's so sad. How did he die?" And what did you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>B.B.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I stepped on him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually young lady, the words you so strategically used were, "I accidentally stepped on him." Right?</utterance>
   <speaker>B.B.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To which I queried, "And just how did your foot accidentally find its way into Emilio's fishbowl?" And she told me no no no, Emilio was on the carpet when she stepped on him.  Hummmmmm, the plot thickens. And just how did Emilio get on the</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>carpet? And Mommy, you would have been real proud of her, because she didn't lie. She said she took Emilio out of his bowl, and put him on the carpet. And what was Emilio doing on the carpet, baby?</utterance>
   <speaker>B.B.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was -- flapping.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then you stomped on him?</utterance>
   <speaker>B.B.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And when you lifted your foot up, what was Emilio doing then?</utterance>
   <speaker>B.B.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He stopped flapping, didn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>B.B.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you knew what that meant, didn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>B.B.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did that mean?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="153" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>B.B.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She told me later, that the second she lifted up her foot and saw him not flapping, she knew he was dead. Is that not the perfect visual image of life and death? A fish flapping on the carpet, and a fish not flapping on the carpet. So powerful even a five-year old child with no concept of life and death knew what it meant. Not only did she know Emilio was dead, she knew she had killed him. So she comes running into my room, holding Emilio in both of her little hands - it was so cute - and she wanted me to make Emilio better. And I asked her, why did she step on Emilio? And she said, she didn't know. But I knew why. You didn't mean to hurt Emilio, you just wanted to see what would happen if you stepped on him, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>B.B.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what happens when you stomp on Emilio, is you kill him. And you discovered that, didn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>B.B.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So we drove down to the beach, had a little funeral, and gave Emilio a burial at sea. And right now I'm sure he's happy as can be, swimmin around in fish heaven. But the point being, our child learned two very important lessons. One, about life and death. The other, somethings once you do, they</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>can't be undone. I knew just how she felt  You loved Emilio, didn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>B.B.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well sweety, I love Mommy, but I did to Mommy what you did to Emilio.</utterance>
   <speaker>B.B.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You stomped on Mommy?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Worse.  I shot Mommy. Not pretend shoot, like we were just doing. I shot her for real.</utterance>
   <speaker>B.B.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>B.B.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you want to see what would happen?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I knew what would happen to Mommy if I shot her. What I didn't know, is when I shot Mommy, what would happen to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>B.B.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="154" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was very sad. And that was when I learned, somethings once you do, they can never be undone.</utterance>
   <speaker>B.B.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to Mommy?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you ask Mommy.</utterance>
   <speaker>B.B.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you okay Mommy. Does it hurt?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No sweety, it doesn't hurt anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>B.B.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did it make you sick?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It put me to sleep. That's why I haven't been with you B.B., I've been asleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>B.B.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you're awake now, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm wide awake, pretty girl.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="155" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did she go to sleep easy?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It took her a little bit. She was excited. She's quite the little chatterbox.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up the bottle of vino.</context>
      <utterance>Well, if she doesn't like you, you got to kill her to say hello. But if she likes you, you can't shut her up. She's a chip off the ole blonde in that regards.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes her blonde head, no.</context>
      <utterance>Red wine?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives him a look.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Bea, you're a whole lot more fun with a couple glasses of wine in ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes her blonde head, yes.</context>
      <utterance>We're going to go out there and have at it, aren't we?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I've already had a glass. So unless you want to win by an unfair advantage, you should have a glass of wine. So we're both on the same footing wine wise.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="156" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, there's an old man down here, his name is Esteban Viharo. He was a pimp. I knew him when I was a child. He was a friend of my mother's. I told him about you. When I showed him your picture he smiles and said;  "Yesss, I see the attraction." He told me a story about taking me to the movies when I was five. It was a movie which had Lana Turner in it. And whenever she would appear on screen, he said I would stick my thumb in my mouth and suck it, to an obscure amount. And he knew right then, this boy will be a fool for blondes.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who would of ever thought you'd be such a good father?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives him another look.</context>
      <utterance>Well not you, that's for damn sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Must we have to endure your little zingers?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No we mustn't. But if you're going to say sentences like that, in the future, I will resist the temptation.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bill drinks some wine.</context>
      <utterance>Baby, you don't have a future.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="157" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I sent you to L.A. and you never came back. I thought you'd been killed. Do you know how cruel it is to make someone think someone they love is dead? I mourned you. Then in the third month of my mourning, I track you down. I wasn't trying to track you down, I was trying to track down - the fucking assholes - who I thought killed you. And when I find you, what to I find? Not only are you not dead, you're getting married - to some fuckin jerk - and you're pregnant? How do you expect me to react?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you think I hid?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did you leave in the first place? You have cold eyes towards me now. I understand their temperature, but they were warm the second to the last time I saw them, or was that just my imagination?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bride decides to tell all. As she tells this story, parts will be shown on the screen. To give herself a running start with the story she starts it off in Japanese;</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>Bill interrupts her.</context>
      <utterance>You sent me to L.A. to kill that lady scoundrel, Lisa Wong.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context>The Bride explodes;</context>
      <utterance>You are you talking in Japanese?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode>ENGLISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell do you care what I talk in? Don't you know when to keep your mouth shut? I'm trying to tell you what you want to know, if you'll just shut up and listen and stop talking! Now may I continue?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right, I'm wrong, continue.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The morning I left, I threw up. I don't feel like speaking in Japanese anymore - on the plane, I threw up. When I got to my hotel, I threw up. So naturally I started thinking, maybe I might be pregnant. So I bought one of those home pregnancy kits. Went back to my room and took the test. The little strip said blue. I was going to have a baby. I tried to call you, but you weren't there, so I just thought I'd call back later.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you never did.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- Would you shut up, I'm trying to tell you how I feel.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My apologies, please continue.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I just figured I'd call you back later. I was just so happy, I put on music and danced by myself in the hotel suite, holding my little blue strip. What I didn't know, was at some leg of my journey, I was spotted. With me in Los Angeles it didn't take Lisa Wong long to figure out someone put a hit out on her. So she sent an assassin of her own to</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bride stops dancing and goes to the door's peephole. PEEPHOLE POV: A pretty KOREAN WOMAN in the blazer and skirt outfit of a hotel manager. She's holding a basket of flowers. The Bride says through the door;</context>
      <utterance>kill me in my hotel room. As I was dancing in euphoria, the killer came down the hall. There's a knock on the hotel room door.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOTEL WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seeing it through the peephole.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, I'm Karen Kim, I'm the hospitality manager of the hotel. I have a welcome gift from the management.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she talks, she accidentally drops the blue strip, she bends down to pick it up...</context>
      <utterance>Oh, it's beautiful. But I'm kinda busy at this second, could you possibly come back later?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="158" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She raises the shotgun, and takes aim at The Bride...</context>
      <utterance>So you came here to kill Lisa Wong, huh? Well that's my sister, bitch. I'm Karen Wong, and I've come here to kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karen stops.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a second!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I'm an assassin. Yes I did come here to kill your sister. But I'm not gonna do that now.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I know you're not --</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karen looks at her, "what?".</context>
      <utterance>- listen to me! I just found out, right now - not two minutes before you blew a hole in the door, I'm pregnant.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On that table is the home pregnancy kit. On the floor by the door is the strip that says I'm pregnant. I'm telling you the truth, I don't want to and I won't kill your sister. I just want to go home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="159" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this, bullshit story number twelve in the female assassin's handbook?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karen looks over to the door, and sees the tiny strip on the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Any other time you'd be a hundred percent right. But this time you're a hundred percent wrong. I'm the deadliest woman in the world, but right now I'm scared shitless for my baby. Please, you hafta believe me. Look at the strip, it's on the floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bride complies. Karen bends down and picks the strip off the floor. Then takes the package it came in and reads the directions on the box.</context>
      <utterance>Sit down on that bed and put your hands behind your head.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blue means pregnant.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is blue, Karen's starting to believe her.</context>
      <utterance>I'll read it myself, thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, say I were to believe you, what then?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karen does...She starts backing out of the room...before she leaves, she says;</context>
      <utterance>Just go home. I'll do the same.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="160" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Facing Karen Wong, was the most frightening moment I have ever experienced. And that includes three years with that evil bastard Pai Mei. Before that strip turned blue, I was a woman, I was your woman. I was a killer, who killed for you. Before that strip turned blue, I would have jumped a motorcycle on to a speeding train ...for you. But once that strip turned blue, I could no longer do any of those things. Not anymore. Because now I was a mother. A mother who only had one thought on her mind. Please don't harm my baby. Can you understand that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. But why tell me now, and not then?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Starting to get mad.</context>
      <utterance>You wouldn't have let me go. Specially once you found out I was pregnant. You would've tried to talk me out of it. It would have been a big scene. I just said fuck it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck who?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bill, you couldn't know I was pregnant, once you knew, you'd claim it, and I didn't want that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="161" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not your decision to make.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes a sip of wine. It's morning now. And now it's her turn.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, but it's the right decision. And I made it for my daughter. Everybody on this earth deserves to start with a clean slate. But with us - my daughter would be born into a world she shouldn't be. Robbing her of the one thing everybody deserves. She would be born with blood stains. I had to choose. I chose her.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bill listens stoney, then;</context>
      <utterance>You know five years ago, if I had to make a list of impossible things that could never happen. You performing a coup de grace on me by bustin a cap in my crown, would be right at the top of the list.  I'd've been wrong, wouldn't I?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bride listens stoney, then;</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry was that a question? Of impossible things that could never happen - yes in this instance you would have been wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well what?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Explain yourself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="162" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I already have. When I told you the story of when I thought you were dead. Didn't you get how badly I felt?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You call that an explanation?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both understand one another.</context>
      <utterance>Well if that's too cryptic let's get literal.  There are consequences to breaking the heart of a murdering bastard. You experienced some of them. That's his explanation. She hears it.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You and I have unfinished business.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Baby, you ain't kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know how proud I am of you, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know I was rooting for you, don't you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="163" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I figured.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods her head, yes.</context>
      <utterance>You know on that beach out there I want you to be the victor?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You also know you're going to have to defeat me. I can't just give it to you, even though I want to.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It won't be necessary for you to give me anything. I've surpassed you. I'll take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, as they say in Missouri, show me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="164" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode>JAPANESE</mode>
      <context>She's facing him, sword in sheath, hand far from handle, in a standing still position, not moving a muscle of blinking an eye, staring her laser beams in Bill's direction waiting for his attack. He stands in a combat position, sword raises in a combat grip, to charge her.</context>
      <utterance>Attack me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He screams a samurai scream...and charges her... She stands motionless... Unblinking... Watching him coming... No fear.... No expression... We go back and forth, close, wide, low.</context>
      <utterance>That's my girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>TILL...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Using only her left arm, with the sheathed Hanzo sword in its grip, she blocks all of his blows, right arm unmoving down at her side...sort of like Pai Mei did to her earlier...his sword and her sheath lock together...they're close to each other, she brings up her right arm, sticks out two fingers, and hits Bill on ten different pressure points on his body. Then hits him straight on in the heart with her palm. His body jolts, like he's just had a heart attack...he coughs up a little blood...he looks at her. Their faces are very close... The face of the cold ice woman Ninja, melts away before our eyes, and the face of Beatrix Kiddo is filled once again with compassion.</context>
      <utterance>They meet...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="165" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course he did.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him apologetically;</context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you tell me? She doesn't have an answer.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles at her duplicitly, and says with blood on his lips;</context>
      <utterance>I don't know...Because...I'm a...bad person.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And walks five steps in the opposite direction...with each step his heart swells, on the fifth... It BURSTS...WE HEAR A SOUND, like of a tire blowout... He falls to the beach...dead. The Bride walks over to his body. She unsheaths her Hanzo sword. Blood lies in a pool, by Bill's mouth. She dips the tip of the blade in the blood, leaving the tiniest of crimson smudges. She then removes the Bill handkerchief, and wipes Bill's blood from off the blade onto the white cloth. She lets the Bill handkerchief drop onto his body.</context>
      <utterance>No. You're not a bad person. You're a terrific person. You're my favorite person. But every once in awhile...you can be a real cunt. They smile at each other. Then... Bill turns his back to her...</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
