<movie id="334" title="Klute">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Klute. With a K. K - L - U -</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you with plant security, Sergeant?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Town Police.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then how are you involved?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know Tom Grunemann.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You knew the subject Thomas Grunemann. How well?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We grew up together. Kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you account for his disappearance in any way?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did he recently appear to you agitated or depressed?  -- indicates no -- Did he voice to you grievance or discontent with his research work here? Indicates no. Moral or sexual problems or peculiarities? --</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marital problems in general? Indicates possibly -- am I right Sergeant?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody's got some, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did he ever mention specifically a girl or woman in New York?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Examine this letter please.  We recovered that from the shredder -- the plant disposal and incinerator system. Grunemann apparently typed it Friday, before he left, decided not to send it, tossed it away. We've already contacted the New York Police; they think they know the girl in question.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My husband was not like that! My God, Klute.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It looks like he sent her quite a few of those Holly -- the girl -- she recalls six or seven letters like --</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- No. I mean sure a little rough stuff, but just what people usually -- No, I would've said we were pretty good.  Johnnie I don't understand. I just don't understand. Klute nods. She is talking for both of them. Klute looks out the window to the children playing outside. CAMERA PANS out window to Klute's POV of children playing on a cold winter day. The trees are stripped bare.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- has disclosed no evidence of crime or criminal intent within the jurisdiction of this bureau, and since subject Thom --</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's been almost a year! Tom Grunemann's been missing for a year. And all the FBI has to offer is a report that must bore even you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>STREIGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you closing the case?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No sir, we don't state that. We're countin --</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you don't find it worth much effort.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well Mr. Cable, you've got me here from the Bureau. You got Lieutenant Trask here from New York representing his department and I don't frankly consider --</utterance>
   <speaker>STREIGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why couldn't you ever find out anything from the girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trask --</utterance>
   <speaker>TRASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We first hold her under surveillance expectin your boy Grunemann to show up there. Didn't. Then we bagged -- we arrested her on a CP charge, convicted, two month's women's city prison, offer to reduce sentence, she cooperated.  Four interrogations. She thought she remembered Grunemann -- from those letters from before, she made that connection -- but she hadn't seen him since and couldn't identify his photograph and she --</utterance>
   <speaker>STREIGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shakes his head, gestures doubtingly. Ross caps it.</context>
      <utterance>Oh a good call girl, she'll turn six-seven hundred tricks a year. The faces get blurred.  And since then, recent months, she's reported several, you know, incidents: like breather calls, anonymous phone calls, also somebody maybe following her, watching her, things like that. So it's I guess you could say, conceivable Grunemann's still around there, just hangin around her, spooking her. But you know, that --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's thousands.</context>
      <utterance>The subject got emotionallv disturbed; he just dropped out.</utterance>
   <speaker>STREIGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Inspector we understand your position; ours is a little different. We have an investment in Tom Grunemann. The Company has an investment, and we feel entitled to investigate for ourselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Private investigation, you mean. Yes sir, of course you're entitled, and there's some very competent --</utterance>
   <speaker>STREIGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. Ross and Trask look at Klute - more than a bit startled - then at each other. Klute just looks uneasy.</context>
      <utterance>Klute offered us his services; we've accepted.</utterance>
   <speaker>STREIGER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Klute knew Tom. He has a great many ideas about the case --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir, we know he --</utterance>
   <speaker>STREIGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'd expect him to work in cooperation with you. He'd report to each of you and to our Company's New York office, to Pete -- Pete goes there on a regular schedule back and forth, and --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Streiger, speaking frankly -- we've appreciated the Sergeant's interest you know, all along. Here, locally. But New York, that's - well --</utterance>
   <speaker>TRASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ever done any missing person's work?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spent much time in the city?  You see, I have to wonder -- speaking frankly; the Sergeant knows I'm only speaking frankly -</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frankly? He's interested.</context>
      <utterance>You wonder why we thought of Klute?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>(beat)</context>
      <utterance>-- Honey you make it look a little real. It should have, you know, that fun to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Strangle him to death funny?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- but then he glances at his watch, and at the others waiting their turn.</context>
      <utterance>Well we go from this into stomach diagrams. It can't be too -- look let's try it again from -</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Bree and the Male Actor set their cheeks together, beaming half-moon smiles to camera, hold it for a moment, as the Director reads again -</context>
      <utterance>No -- just give us the faces at the end, would you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- And another family saved by Elso tablets. OK --  Thank you very much. -- and holds out his hands for their scripts, at the same time as he summons from a list in his other hand --</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>BREE passes a new group of beautiful girls sitting in line waiting their turn as she exits as brightly as possible.</context>
      <utterance>Pierce -- Danner -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She waits for a moment. Then makes a curious, small gesture of her hand -- deposits another dime, dials again, is answered.</context>
      <utterance>Bree Daniel, any messages?  OK, thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>As she prepares to write it down, we CUT BACK TO -</context>
      <utterance>Trina? Bree. Do I? Oh no, just a commercial I thought I might get, that's all.  Well I'd take a quick thirty, hon. Do you have a commuter for me? Wait.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He mumbles some kind of greeting, steps back. She pauses a moment in the door (casing, instantly) -- then quite confident, friendly, provocative all at once --</context>
      <utterance>Hullo.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>-- and CUT TO --</context>
      <utterance>Ooh, I knew I'd like you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>1ST ANNC'R</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--R - W - M, radio's voice is the Shippensburg Valley, on a beautiful clear warm Thurs -- -- to --</utterance>
   <speaker>2ND ANNC'R</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Tucky Wonder Beans picking up a half cent over yesterday's price at- -- and CUT TO --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She turns the door handle , parts the door about three inches, looks through at him. He starts to enter.</context>
      <utterance>Miss Daniel? My name is Klute -- John Klute --</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>-- and the door crunches against its chain-lock. He stops perforce, a bit startled. A pause. A slice of Bree's face looks coldly out at him. He summons a smile.</context>
      <utterance>Can I talk to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name's John Klute.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tightens again.</context>
      <utterance>I'm an investigator. I'd like to ask you some questions about Tom Grunemann.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tom Grunemann. He wrote you some letters.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gee.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was a research engineer at the Tuscarora Laboratories in Pennsylvania. He disappeared from there last April. I've been hired to look for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miss Daniel.</context>
      <utterance>You know what I'm talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honest?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you let me ask you some questions?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dew yew hayuv ah-dentifikyshun? He takes out a folded letter and a wallet and passes them both through to her. Silence. She examines them with care, then appears to soften a little; even smiles slightly.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not police or FBI; you're just a private investigator?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mm.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you just want to ask me a few questions?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles again, hands the letter and wallet back out, closes the door (doesn't slam, just closes). Klute looks at it blankly for a time, starts to knock again, decides not to -- turns and descends the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Mm.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- and I take acting classes with Lee Tainter --</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Lee, yes --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- and I was in two of his workshop type productions, Uncle Vanya and the girl in Five Characters --  -- here -- and then of course I have the modeling and the demonstrator work, the trade-fair work -- but naturally I feel ready for something more, well you know, sustain --</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts for the door -- he's already turning away -- then ducks back, hands him one of her Glossies, laughing prettily at her own forgetfulness.</context>
      <utterance>Well, thanks very much for coming in.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you very much.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TRASK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>KLUTE closes the file.</context>
      <utterance>What you lookin' to get from her? You think she's got Grunemann hid somewhere, the attic, feedin him soup? Or maybe he's hidin in a dark alley and he'll jump on her and you jump on him. And third place, even if she does know somethin' she's right, she don't have to talk to you. You don't have police power, you can't make her.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a lot of people to die unknown.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As KLUTE slowly walks away we bring in TELEPHONE RING and BREE VOICE, OVER answering.</context>
      <utterance>Unknown, unidentified and unwanted. And there's more every day man, there's more everyday.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bree Daniel.  Yeah, hi hon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GIRL'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- comes in with these other yulds maybe two or three times a year, and five big ones baby, just one evening.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Klute sets down the headset (we drop the VOICES far under, INDISTINGUISHABLE), makes a note, and thumbs open the box of a fresh reel; the present reel is near the end. We establish a pile of ALREADY RECORDED TAPES. We CUT BACK TO --</context>
      <utterance>Marta, thanks, and I'd love to party with you hon, but --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BREE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bree Daniel --</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God baby, oh God I really love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's nice; who is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A CLICK, and the MAN'S VOICE CONTINUING, trailing into helpless sobs --</context>
      <utterance>I really love you baby, you know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello? Hello? Oh my God, hello?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BREE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bree Daniel.</utterance>
   <speaker>2ND MAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bree -- Frank Hanley, you remember, Fayetterville?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah, hi Frank, sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>2ND MAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I'm in town, like to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We FADE THIS CONVERSATION UNDER BUT HOLD, CONTINUING, as -- BREE PASSES CAMERA -- and we PAN TO SHOT OF KLUTE, at corner, unseen by her and apparently in surveillance of her. Then he too turns out of frame, and we CUT TO --</context>
      <utterance>Well Frank that's awful nice but I'm out of action, sort of, you know --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SPANGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Usual case history -- this isn't a medical confidence, it's all of them -- broken family, lonely, confused, crummy childhood, early promiscuity, formal prostitution beginning in her teens, income twenty-five to thirty thousand a year.  Oh they don't keep the money: they get rid of it, they get pimps. Why?  Why do you want to know all this?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to know how Tom Grunemann got mixed up in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPANGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not unusual.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did she talk about him to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPANGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About his letters -- that's all she remembered. Quite violent material, I'd say, obsessive, a quite sick man. But that's not unusual either.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Has she talked with you since prison?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPANGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. She had every good intention of it -- coming to me as a private patient, getting out of the life, devoting herself to an acting career.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think she's trying that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPANGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh sure they try. The idea of a better life. But they don't really know much about life: They get confused -- or scared or frustrated or bored -- they pop back to the one thing they can handle. The trick. The trick. Men in bed. Not men in general, not life, not love, not even real sex -- it avoids all that. Just the trick, the transaction.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He smiles, kisses her cheek, tests the fabric of her evening dress -- (in passing, as a matter of expertise).</context>
      <utterance>You scared me, Mr. Faber.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. FABER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then he turns, lifts down a WOMAN'S DRESS CAPE, carrying it -- graciously gestures her to precede him --</context>
      <utterance>Good material, not too good cut. I'd do better for you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh thank you. He sits in the chair opposite, sips his wine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. FABER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enjoy.  Well --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's good to see you. Well -- could we do it first and then just talk?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. FABER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure dear, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well -- well I'm just back. And -- I must tell you -- something quite wonderful.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. FABER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Cannes was quite fun, quite; and we played baccarat and chemindefer and there was a nice little Italian marquis quite enthusiastic for me -- but a young man can be so silly --</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. FABER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mm.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hesitates strangely, her fingers at the neck of the cape. Faintly --</context>
      <utterance>And then one night -- at the gaming tables -- well I just saw him. A stranger -- looking at me -- and I knew suddenly that all my life I'd been --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- May I? It's so --</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. FABER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stands, unloosing the cloak, letting it fall on the couch. But she doesn't sit again -- begins to move here and there about the enclosure, her hands wandering about her dress and body -- an erotic restlessness.</context>
      <utterance>Please --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not young; he wasn't young -- gray at the temples, he -- well actually he looked like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. FABER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And nobody could tell me who he was -- an exiled prince or a mercenary or a bullfighter or -- but I felt it stirring inside me, this -- this wild, pagan feeling --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But then she adjusts -- a frightened but matter-of fact hooker --</context>
      <utterance>Oh you bastard.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it the shakedown hon? You picked a loser, I just don't have it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm look --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I was taking calls full time would I be living in this kip? I'd be back on Park Avenue; I could support the whole National Guard!</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could I ask some questions?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She seems to have expressed it; the balance of power. She turns, goes out, heads upstairs. Klute unhurriedly takes up his folder of notes, then follows.</context>
      <utterance>Or you'll get me shoved back in the brig you mean; another month with the bull-dykes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Klute tosses down a second photograph.</context>
      <utterance>They showed me that one. I understand it's Grunemann, but I told them, I just don't remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSERT: SECOND PHOTOGRAPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tom Grunemann, Elaine Grunemann, two daughters.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Company outing or picnic or something like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't that sweet.  Well it could be any one of them bubi; I get to see them all. She separates from Klute, around the table . Klute puts photo aside, prepares to take notes, as she pleads --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>permissively on his pad of paper -- she goes on.</context>
      <utterance>Look -- please -- will you just try to get it from my side? A year ago. I was in the life fulltime. I was living on Park with leather furniture and a million dresses. Then they dropped on me, the fuzz, they caged me -- they started asking me about a man, some man, I'm supposed to have seen a year before that. Two years ago, two. He could be in Yemen! She waits for Klute to respond -- he doodles</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A name. Grunemann. Nothing. And they showed me pictures like this and they meant nothing. Then they asked me, well had I been getting letters, from someone out there in Cabbageville --</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Tuscarora --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without warning she wheels to the open windows, and shouts out full-voiced -- both startling and somewhat intriguing Klute --</context>
      <utterance>All right, yes, I had been. Those sick, wild letters -- I'm watching you, gonna follow you, gonna punish you, kill you et cetera. Well, they said, all right that's Grunemann. So try to remember when you and he - when -- well I don't know, there was that dumper once, he sounded like that dumper --  Dumpers; they get their kicks beating you up. A man hired me once, then tried to really kill me - that'd be about two years ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Turns around again, to Klute. Cheerfully --</context>
      <utterance>OK Tommy-baby, Allie-Allie-in-free kid, I got the gumdrops.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You remind me of my uncle.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?  What do you remember about that -- dumper?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing. Except he wasn't kidding. Usually it's a fakeout, you probably know. They pretend to tie you up, and you wear a dress with a cloth belt and they pretend to whip you or you --  Hell it's their money. I'll hang from the shower rod and whistle Maytime. Except this guy was really tripped out on it; he --</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you can't say that Dumper was Tom Grunemann.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A brief pause. Klute sorts his notes. She may take it that he's packing to leave -- hopes so anyhow. For an instant we see the undefended girl underneath --</context>
      <utterance>I can't say he was anybody!</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Then again she changes manner -- remembering a practical problem, approaching it as a matter-of fact hooker.</context>
      <utterance>So -- OK -- that's all?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well could I have them back now hon? -- those tape recordings you've got downstairs -- OK? -- and if you want you can have a good time and I'll have a good time and--</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She draws back again. Up to now she's been reasonably on top of things. Starting now we see her driven toward the things she'd really rather not talk about -- and increasingly more shaken.</context>
      <utterance>What about everything since?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything that's happened since Tom Grunemann disappeared. The phone calls and the --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just phone calls, right? They ring, you answer, they don't say anything, just blank. Kids getting kicks. Burglars looking for an empty apartment. I mean there is nothing that proves --</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the other things you've reported? --  -- being followed on the --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The PHONE RINGS. She startles. Then approaches with some difficulty -- but then answers with complete calm in her Smith-girl voice.</context>
      <utterance>Look -- I'm sorry -- I've led everybody wrong. I mean yes, I get those feelings, but that's just me, that's just feelings.  I'm sure this will amuse you; I'm scared of the dark. And sometimes I get shook up, I hear people or -- well, I'll come out in the morning and think someone's been prying at my mailbox, or there's a little -- trash outside my door and I wonder if someone left it there for -- do you see? -- things other people wouldn't even notice. Well that's not real, it's just nerves; it's got nothing to do with --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bree Daniel.  Oh yes, Ted Carlin, how is Ted?  Oh, well, thank you very much but maybe the next time you're in town?  Well I just love Ted and I'd love to meet you -- you have a very nice voice -- but I just --  Well I'm having a chat with a very nice cop. Actually not a real cop; he's a private inves -- A BUZZING from the phone; the connection abruptly broken. She hangs up, recites.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that how you get most of your dates? Someone gives your name to someone else?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Most of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that how you met the Dumper? -- Someone else gave --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How would I remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(a beat)</context>
      <utterance>How else do you meet them? Pimps?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're very square. Pimps don't get you dates, cookie; they just take the money. Klute takes up the slip of paper previously given him by Trask. In the same manner as before --</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have some names the police gave me. Frank Ligourin. Will you tell me what --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I'm sure this'll amuse you too. Ilia trying to get away from all that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She freezes again, looking at him. Then savagely --</context>
      <utterance>What about the old gentleman the other night, Mr. Faber?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You saw that, goddamn you? You saw it? He's seventy. His wife's dead. He started cutting garments at fourteen. His whole life, he's maybe had a week's vacation, I'm all he has and he never, never touches me, and what harm in it, what -- She chokes -- then goes on --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Klute, tell me, what's your bag? Are you a talker, or a button man or a doubler, or maybe you like them very young -- children -- or get your chest walked around with high-heeled shoes, or have us watch you tinkle? Or --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grabs up the company picture, raging on --</context>
      <utterance>-- You want to wear women's clothes, or you get off ripping things --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- you perverted hypocrite square bastards.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gee I hope this doesn't make my cold any worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me about Frank Ligourin.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mm? Oh, he was my old man. We broke up. She wanders away toward a bureau. Her shirt seems to itch her; she scratches her ribs. Then opens drawer, takes out a different shirt as --</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When did you and Ligourin break up? She pulls off her shirt, unhooks her brassiere and discards it, apparently quite unselfconscious. Klute reacts; then, carefully maintaining his cool</context>
      <utterance>When?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She turns to him in total innocence, holding the shirt rather carelessly in front of her -- a new attack.</context>
      <utterance>Mind not doing that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? This?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you could trick me for those tapes. Don't you get lonely in that little green room? Or let me get you someone; I have terrific friends, wild.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At this point -- or about this point -- Klute takes note of something. A little above her. He grows more watchful, but containing it carefully. We don't understand the change in his manner -- or even notice; she doesn't. In mock dismay --</context>
      <utterance>No thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has risen, is approaching her slowly -- carrying his notes as if to check something. She is hopeful again --</context>
      <utterance>Gee. I've had men pay two hundred dollars for me -- here, you're turning down a freebie.  You can get a perfectly good dishwasher for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've changed your mind? You do want to play?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want you to look up. There's someone on the skylight. She gasps, terrified -- immediately -- almost beyond control. He taps the pencil on his notes.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She manages to take hold of a corner of the notes, trembling. He goes on --</context>
      <utterance>Easy -- pretend you're looking here-  -- here.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He strolls away from her. His destination is the area of the door -- out of view from the skylight -- from where he can head for the roof. But he doesn't head that way directly -- first takes a turn in another direction, his bearing casual. Prompting --</context>
      <utterance>Now I'm going to walk around -- you just keep talking, straight through, straight through.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me about acting -- what are you doing tomorrow -- where do you go?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I go on rounds.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rounds, what are they? -- don't watch me, keep talking.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Klute has strolled out of view from above -- instantly flattens himself against the wall, eases the door open, about to slip and charge. As Bree labors on --</context>
      <utterance>You go see agents -- or Equity calls, open casting calls. And ad agencies -- commercials -- you don't get work, you just go around.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And they're always polite -- show people -- they say thank you very much. You lie there covered with blood, smiling, they say --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sees her condition. Gently --</context>
      <utterance>I couldn't get him.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He reaches to touch her -- she quails away from him.</context>
      <utterance>It's all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well do you think it was him?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't you get him?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe, if you tell me the things you haven't.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You asked me where I got that date with the dumper -- Frank sent me on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know where he got the dumper?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He never told me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, let's go down and ask him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you expect? Frankie still has a good string, three girls. Figure three hundred a week from each.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>Is that what you gave him?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank -- Klute.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. Come in.  I was just catching up some work -- mocking up the photographs.  I used to be a photographer myself - Bree tell you? -- Before I got in the publishing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Short silence. Then with the tact of a gentleman dealing with rude, difficult woman --</context>
      <utterance>Frank, he knows you're a pimp. He knows you were my pimp.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gestures gently to indicate outside. She nods once. He escorts her in that direction, OUT the door, closing it behind them.</context>
      <utterance>Well Bree, maybe you'd rather --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shrugs a shoulder at him, looks away. He goes on in the same quiet voice.</context>
      <utterance>How's it been?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With me Bree it's eternally the same. Toward you. I guess you know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She yanks at the elevator doors. But the elevator's not here yet. She turns away sharply into the door marked "Stairway". He turns back to his apartment.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah Frank, I know that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've always respected Bree.  I'd like to make something clear.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've just got a few --</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gestures Klute to one chair, sits in another, waits calmly, attentively.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like to make something clear. I don't go after a girl; a girl comes to me. Her choice. Right?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm looking for a man. Tom Grunemann.  Bree thinks he may have been the dumper -- that call she had two years ago. She says you sent her on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two years ago? Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They tell me you use narcotics. Could I bring someone around to look at your arms?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Klute waits.</context>
      <utterance>Look -- dad -- I may stand better with the cops than you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OK, a family matter. Between the girls. I had two other cows --  -- two other girls besides Bree.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She told me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OK and one of them Jane McKenna -- she blows a little jealous of Bree - you know? -- Bree comes first? And evidently she knew the freak --- that he was a dumper -- she conned me into passing him to Bree, you know, so Bree'd get hurt. I didn't know. Till afterwards.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you tell Bree, afterwards?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't tell them. That one of their own in-laws laid a dumper on them?  Peace in the family.  Beyond that, I don't know. All she wrote.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to talk with Jane McKenna.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would I be telling you all this? She copped out long ago. She committed suicide Baxter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you like my friend Frankie?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't he tell you what you wanted?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It didn't go anywhere.  But that's not why --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About the dumper, didn't he tell you that?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was Jane McKenna who sent you the dumper.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well -- she's dead. At the corner he slows, starts unzipping his bookcase as if indicating a change of route.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you were going back to the apartment.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands over the TAPE-REELS.</context>
      <utterance>You said you wanted these.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh golly, oh just what I've always dreamed of, dirty phone calls.  How come?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You told me what you could. I guess I'm through with your part of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there anything more I could --</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't see anything, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you gonna do next?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(starts off)</context>
      <utterance>Try some other ways.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do I do meanwhile? -- wait for that clown to fall through the skylight on me?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I don't think that was Tom.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said it was!</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I said what did you think.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh -- wait -- oh I get it. You said that just to keep me scared. So I'd tell you everything I -- oh clever; oh you smart, tricky hick.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A little?</context>
      <utterance>Hey, but did we get to you, Klute?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you got to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Us city folks? The sin, the glitter, the wickedness?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. No. Not that way. I'd say it was more -- I don't know --  -- too bad? Pathetic?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns smartly away, deposits the tapes in passing in a litter box, departs. Klute looks after her for a moment, then turns on his way. Then --</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks in past him, sits down on the edge of his bed.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell do you mean, pathetic?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's kind of late.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes her seriously, starts to move.</context>
      <utterance>It got lonely upstairs. There's someone on the roof.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, don't be a doo-doo.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not much point to this, is there?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ezra, I'm lots better than you're used to. Tell me -- the other night, watching me with Mr. Faber -- wasn't your tongue a little bit hanging out?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mm.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts for the bed, as if to lift her onto her feet. She takes off her robe and swings her legs up, and under the sheet.</context>
      <utterance>So you're not too different from him, or the chap on the roof, or Tommy-baby --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Under the sheet she unlooses her pajama bottoms, kicks them away, starts unbuttoning the shirt.</context>
      <utterance>Look, if you don't use it somebody else just will. And you've done your whole bit with me, your entire duty, and so now this is my thing. So enjoy, Mr. Faber would say, enjoy.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bree -- thanks -- I don't want to.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tries to rebutton the pajama shirt. She catches his hand, thrusts it underneath. In grief and anger</context>
      <utterance>Oh don't be all hypocrite. Or do you really like other kicks? Is it more just having power over someone? -- so you don't really need to --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>C.U., HER FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- triumphantly, contemptuously, orgiastically --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh lover -- oh you thrill me -- oh, it's beautiful -- oh yes, yes -- oh like that, like that, yes --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter hon? You were great. Terrific. A tiger.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sits up, gropes her pajamas from the floor, puts them on. In the same fond tone --</context>
      <utterance>Well what're you down about? You mean because you didn't get me there?  You can't expect that. I mean Frank, yes, he'd get me there all the time -- but never with a John.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She has the pajamas and robe on, pauses near the door --</context>
      <utterance>And I'm sorry I can't stay and learn your special little games. And I certainly don't want you to feel bad about this -- losing your virtue all of a sudden -- because I sort of knew you would. As I said, like everyone, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Besides - you can always tell yourself you made me come downstairs. Ta, luv.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Why?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why -- please, why? -- Why lose, why look? Why hate and give and want and love? Why get, grieve, g --</utterance>
   <speaker>JANG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All break posture, start offstage, while Bree, caught in mid-stride, clowns it a little.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- then toward Jang, a bit succinctly, indicating script --</context>
      <utterance>-- gug -- gug --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? -- I want to know what.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Do we have all your resumes?</context>
      <utterance>No, that was very good everybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRODUCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looks up.</context>
      <utterance>Booth -- Osman -- Zuff -- Anjeris Chaka. WIDER, near stage front. Bree shrugs, steps down off stage with the others. Bree finds Jang's hand out for her script, smiles wanly, turns it over, continues on out of scene. She finds something - someone -- impeding her way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You asked if there was anything more you could help me with.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. Impasse.</context>
      <utterance>When?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've checked the records of Jane McKenna's death -- I can't get anything special. But Frank Ligourin had another girl you said, besides McKenna and you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arlyn Page.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did she and Jane McKenna know each other?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frankie kept them in the same apartment: it cut his travel-time.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then maybe Arlyn Page knew the Dumper too.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arlyn had a very big habit - heroin - she's the one who started Frank. She's strung out now; you won't find her.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could help me find her. You know the people.  I'll pay you a hundred dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can make that in a lunch break!  Look, Hiram, you're sure it isn't just me? -- you decided you liked it, after all, the other night; you'll hang around for seconds?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She examines him -- shrugs -- turns, proceeds along the sidewalk, Klute accompanying --</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Joanie -- Mike, hi --  Hi Pat.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Bree honey, who you got?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bree leads on to where --</context>
      <utterance>A new daddy. I'n he cute?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trina this is Klute. I told you about him.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yes Mr. Klute -- won't you both join me?  And how do you like our fair city? There's so much here don't you think? The museums and the books and the foreign films -- Bree, have you seen the Godard film?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh uh.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh you've got to. He does such fun things with imagery. And I've been reading The Fall --  -- The Fall by Ahlbair Camoo -- it's the same thing, you know the imagery --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trina undergoes a change of demeanor. Flatly --</context>
      <utterance>Trina honey, he just wants to find Arlyn Page.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? She's a junkie.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was with you after she left Frank.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well she's not now.  I did everything for Arlyn. I loved Arlyn I took her right into my apartment, my own sweet apartment on First. But she wouldn't stay off it -- the junk -- and I wept and I pleaded and I held her in my arms - and she started taking things, my things, and selling them for horse. My clothes. We could've had everything together, everything -- and then the bitch sold my mink!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FIRST GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arlyn Page?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll never catch up; she's grooved out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pimp looks distrustfully at Klute who reassures</context>
      <utterance>Gil?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not looking for her personally - someone she might know about.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try Janie Dale.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JANIE DALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>GIRL on couch rises.</context>
      <utterance>It's old Mr. Clean from Cleveland. He wants to know when he can fly in and clean up the apartment and see you. I told him I have all the cleaning equipment and that he can come anytime, but it's up to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know he wants us to be dominant.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANIE DALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shrugs and turns to KLUTE &amp; BREE.</context>
      <utterance>Tell him that he'd better have his ass in here by one o'clock on Monday afternoon or you won't let him clean the bathroom floor, and tell him the price has gone up twenty bucks -- Old Dutcn Cleanser's not as cheap as it used to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANIE DALE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanted to know about Arlyn, honey? I had to let her go dear. Arlyn stopped being reliable.  I deal with a high type client, business people, you understand? I can't send them someone that's all the time half zonked out.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know where she went?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANIE DALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try Momma Reese.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>AZURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- a couple weeks then she'd drift off a couple of weeks, you know what I mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you heard from her recently?</utterance>
   <speaker>AZURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We START FADE SOUND as Klute repeats --</context>
      <utterance>She liked me all right but she had what she liked better, you know what I mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- and CUT TO --</context>
      <utterance>Have you heard from her recently?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MRS. VASEK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The whore, yeah. I threw out.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know where she went from here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. VASEK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Out.</context>
      <utterance>Live like animals. Her and the man.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see Klute persisting - DISSOLVE</context>
      <utterance>Was she living with a man?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell do you think's the matter.  I could wait for you someplace.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If Arlyn Page is living with Tom Grunemann --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Then you don't need me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts on, simply assuming that she'll follow. (There is a degree of acquaintanceship in their manners now - a reluctant collaboration.)</context>
      <utterance>But if it's someone else I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- and follows on. He checks numbers, then crosses street diagonally toward a half-framed house.</context>
      <utterance>You sure pull a lot of mileage out of a hundred dollars.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>ARLYN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>ARLYN enters rather eagerly. She sees Klute first, then Bree -- recognizes her -- retires flat against a wall, holding one palm outwards to shield her face. She is unbelievably gaunt. Inside one elbow, looking rather like a birthmark, we see a lacework of purple where her veins have pulped together.</context>
      <utterance>Cappy?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the connecting room a MAN'S VOICE (Berger's) calling out hoarsely.</context>
      <utterance>Arlyn? Honey?  Look, it's all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERGER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it Cappy? Cappy? --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BERGER hastens, stumbles, into the doorframe carrying a CAR-RADIO with wires dangling, speaks before he sees them.</context>
      <utterance>Arlyn, it's all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops for an instant face-to-face with Klute. Then turns, plunges out of view again. Arlyn breaks after.</context>
      <utterance>Cappy, I got a radio!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARLYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear the MUMBLE and WHISPER of their voices from the connecting room (as she reassures him). Bree looks inquiringly at Klute (is that Grunemann?): he shakes his head. Pause, then ARLYN reenters, wrapping her fingers together timidly -- wanting them out -- her only purpose.</context>
      <utterance>No --</utterance>
   <speaker>ARLYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bree -- honey - please, we're waiting for someone.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arlyn, he just wanted to ask some questions -- something you could help us about.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARLYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't you see I'm strung out?  Please, we're waiting for it -- he's got to have it!</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arlyn seems to accept the bargain. He indicates to Bree to proceed, stands away a little. Arlyn covers her elbow with one hand. Bree manages as best she can.</context>
      <utterance>We'll go. Just something you could tell us, first.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey, a couple of years ago, with Jane and Frankie? -- Jane sent me a Dumper --</utterance>
   <speaker>ARLYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, if he sees you, he won't come!</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arlyn, just tell me, did Jane have a dumper, one of her regular Johns?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARLYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about him? Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Klute hands Grunemann's picture to Bree: Bree shows it to Arlyn. Arlyn inspects it, then uncertainly, weakly --</context>
      <utterance>Did he come around often?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARLYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. He was an older man hon. The dumper was older.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear FOOTSTEPS - UNDER, DIMLY - mounting the stairs. Bree notices them first, Klute persisting with Arlyn --</context>
      <utterance>Do you remember his name? What can you tell me about him?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERGER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arlyn, get them out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARLYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, I am begging you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's important.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARLYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He was an older man!</context>
      <utterance>That's not the Dumper, that's all!</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arlyn catches the footsteps, dodges past him toward the door, intending to reassure --</context>
      <utterance>Can you give me any more description than that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARLYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- as the pusher, CAPPY, steps in. All of this is very quick, simultaneous, a confusion of voices. CAPPY takes one look at Klute --</context>
      <utterance>Cappy? --</utterance>
   <speaker>ARLYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all right, they're all right -- -- turns and runs.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERGER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Cappy's FOOTSTEPS race away down the stairs. BERGER plunges out from the connecting room, still carrying the car radio, shouting, pursuing --</context>
      <utterance>Cappy? -- Cappy?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERGER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>We hear him STUMBLE AND FALL on the stairs outside, the sound of body reeling down. Arlyn shrieks and races after: Klute and Bree follow.</context>
      <utterance>Cappy it's all right! I got a radio -- don't run, don't --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ARLYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Klute and Bree are only a half-step behind. Klute offers to assist: Arlyn puts him away ferociously.</context>
      <utterance>Oh baby -- no it's all right -- oh my baby baby baby --</utterance>
   <speaker>ARLYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get out!  Don't cry my baby; I'll find him, I'll get it. Baby, baby, don't cry.  Leave us alone! Get out and get out and leave us alone!  My honey, my baby, my baby -- We DISSOLVE TO --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She wouldn't be reliable anyhow -- a narcotics addict.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I believed her, Pete.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's right you know. Waiting for the pusher, she'd tell you anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I believed her: the Dumper was not Tom Grunemann.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, suppose it wasn't Tom Grunemann; where does that get you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's where it doesn't get me. I've got nothing left that connects to anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then, close the case.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I better keep looking.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where, how?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could try Arlyn Page again. She saw much more of the Dumper than Bree Daniel.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just finished telling me she had nothing to offer. Not Tom, you said, the Dumper was clearly not Tom.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CABLE'S SECRETARY appears for a moment tapping her watch significantly.</context>
      <utterance>It's got to make sense some way.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Cable -- they are meeting in Mr. Camara's office.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They rise, dismissed. He sorts a paper or two, continues to Klute.</context>
      <utterance>Yes Evvie, thanks. Gentlemen, I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm flying back out to Pennsylvania Friday; I'll fill them in on things.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is it back there?</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you're homesick.  I'll be out at my camp over the weekend. Nice right now, that touch of fall in the air, that skim of frost in the early mornings, very peaceful.  John, I'll be back here again Thursday; I'll be in touch. Lieutenant, thank you. KLUTE and TRASK depart. CABLE closes the door and returns to his desk. He pulls out a tape recorder from a drawer in his desk, rewinds it and turns it on. We hear a playback of the previous scene with KLUTE and TRASK. He stands at the window listening with some satisfaction; as if listening to what KLUTE revealed keeps him in control of the situation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TRASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were bringing a freighter down through Kill Van Kull; propellers washed it up on top. SUGARMAN brings into view a METAL BASKET attached with short ropes. He complains --</utterance>
   <speaker>SUGARMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you bring it up on deck?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKHAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They slip the basket downward, out of frame (into the water).</context>
      <utterance>Would you bring it up on deck?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECKHAND</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mickey, get something. Get the eels off.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We CUT TO -</context>
      <utterance>They'll drop off theirselves when she comes out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>TRASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We MOVE WITH KLUTE as he turns and moves away a few feet along deck. Here he stands. Then SUGARMAN moves into view holding a clipboard. Routinely --</context>
      <utterance>It'll go to the Examiner. But I don't see nothin that means nothin.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUGARMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You help us with ID? We can't get nothin from him. He indicates the direction of Berger. Klute examines the clipboard data.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arlyn Page was probably an alias. She went by the names Terry Arlyn and June Price. She may have been from Pittsburgh, someone told me. I can give you a list of people who knew her, if that would help to --</utterance>
   <speaker>SUGARMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No point, thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he claiming the body?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUGARMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He spits, moves back in the direction of the group; Klute continues to stand. BERGER moves in his direction. Brokenly --</context>
      <utterance>Uh uh, that'd mean funeral expenses.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man could you help me? Klute doesn't understand his purport, reacts instantly, sympathetically --</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Klute stares at him -- a quiet horror -- as Berger insists --</context>
      <utterance>You know, help me out. That's my baby there, dead. I got to get up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERGER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man you don't know what that does to me, my baby dead --</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- You've got to get up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Klute shoves a bill in his hand, turns away very sharply, off the tugboat.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TRASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's how the other one died, you know. In the water.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then -- (we are assuming a complete understanding here between Klute and Trask, non-verbal. What Trask is asking, in effect, is: is this meaningful? Do we both suspect the same man?)</context>
      <utterance>I looked it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He barely enters the room. His manner is cool and remote.</context>
      <utterance>Well hello -- come on in.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you ought to know, Arlyn Page is dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The same as Jane McKenna.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Klute looks around the disorderly room. The plants in the windowsill have never been in worse shape. They look as if she deliberately let them die of thirst.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the jolly news. I thought maybe you'd left town by now. You kind of just disappeared. But you boys from Tuscarora have a habit of disappearing, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The next few weeks I would like to know where you are all the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just let me know when you are going out and where --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if i go out on tricks - you wanna come along? You could sit and read the National Geographic.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you do it to yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't get you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ligourin: How could you do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you before, you wouldn't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right, I don't understand. Explain it to me.  You were scared. Arlyn Page, that scared you. Well it should; that's death. So what did you do, you ran straight for it, death. Ligourin kills women.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no you're right, I'm sorry. He uses women; he lets them kill themselves. Is that how you want it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arlyn was a junkie; I'm not on junk!</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you can find some other way.  Explain it to me. Bree, show me any sense to --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Klute goes.</context>
      <utterance>You get the Christ out! You dumb stupid bastard, you don't know anything, you square, you get out! I don't have to show you anything; you get out!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pushes up her sleeve, points at tiny spot on her arm - a freckle. He peers at it then at her puzzledly.</context>
      <utterance>If I asked you something, would you not laugh? -- asked you to look at something?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought it was maybe changing shape or something. Klute looks at it again. Judiciously -- He shows her a spot or two on his own forearm. She compares, is reassured. Embarrassedly, she tries to smile. It is unsuccessful. She gets up and moves about. Her manner in general is totally unguarded, honest, undramatic, searching.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He only grunts. A sound like 'OK' or 'all right' -- an invitation to leave. But she won't be driven away. More urgently, helplessly:</context>
      <utterance>Look -- I hate everybody; and I'm sorry for everybody; and I'm scared all the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She's left the door a little ajar. He widens it for her.</context>
      <utterance>Look, I don't know either. It's like the only thing I know how to do -- I feel safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pushes it out of his hand, pushes it shut. A little more angrily:</context>
      <utterance>It's been a full day.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We did this before.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.  Well all right. But you want to and I want you to and we both know it and all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't like getting splashed. She accepts it decently. Tries to smile again, nods.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But she takes his hand -- and retains it -- rolls onto her back. Still relaxed, but a little more separate, thoughtful -- a mixture of the Bree we've seen before and the Bree we've glimpsed, the possible Bree. She observes:</context>
      <utterance>Go back to sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm still scared.  I mean different but still.  Look, I made it very clear from the start, you're a yokel, you don't excite me, you don't even interest me, and so I only have one question which is what the hell are you doing in my bed?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grins, then starts to reach for him, still receptive -- then feels another (and genuine) pang, turns her head away sharply.</context>
      <utterance>My bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her with concern, but only caresses her. She manages to explain --</context>
      <utterance>Oh!</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am scared. The things I do. The things I could do to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mm.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He settles himself beside her, makes overtures. She responds, but:</context>
      <utterance>No, not just 'mm'. You don't know what I --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh boy, say, you think you're pretty good.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pretends to bite -- they tussle -- she feels a suddenly growing excitement, seizes him. Fiercely, welcomingly, full out.</context>
      <utterance>Yup.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh -- And we cut directly to:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She waits. Spangler says nothing.</context>
      <utterance>The son of a bitch seduced me!</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know: it's ridiculous. But it's tearing me up and I don't know why. And look, all right, I came here didn't I? And if I have to, I'll keep coming here, the works, and talk about my mummy and my daddy and I'll even pay for it, but will you kindly for God's sakes say something?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPANGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd just be guessing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guess!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPANGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe this wasn't just a trick. Maybe you're in danger of real love, real involve --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do not love him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPANGLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've spent your life avoiding this. You'll try hard to deny it; you're quite likely to destroy it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>CUSTODIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four -- five -- what number'd I say?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Custodian finds it, unlocks for Klute's inspection. Reaches for paper Klute's holding.</context>
      <utterance>Four ninety-seven, Jane McKenna</utterance>
   <speaker>CUSTODIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- And I keep the authorization, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Klute pokes through a small collection of personal effects -- perhaps an ankle bracelet, rabbits foot, faded snapshot of a child, some letters, pitiful remnants of Jane McKenna's life. Klute closes the drawer, and the front of the drawer is marked McKENNA, JANE? Over the visual material of Klute's trip through the warehouse we hear WILD TRACK VOICE OVER bits and pieces of BREE talking with the psychiatrist.</context>
      <utterance>I thought there'd be more.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. Loneliness.  Well -- separated. From other people. Forgotten.  Well, as if I can be here, I can go through the motions, right? But the truth is, I don't belong.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPANGLER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't belong?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you always have to repeat?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPANGLER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>(then)</context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well it's more than loneliness. Hate. People hating me -- and watching me and following and waiting to hurt me -- you know? I'm all screwed up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPANGLER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think people hate you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The truth is I hate them: they must hate me. All right, the money.  All right, not the money. A kind of put-on. It gets things back together.  Well let's say I'd go to one of these cattle-calls, a tryout. I mean before -- before I got this job -- and they'd always say thank you very much and i'd feel, you know, brought down. They didn't want me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPANGLER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't want you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said that.  Well, so you have a choice. You can either feel lonely -- you know, the hate -- or --  So you take a call and go to a hotel room and there's some John you've never seen before, but he wants you. He must, he's paying for it.  And usually they're nervous and that's all right, too, because you're not; you know this thing. And then for a while, boy, they really pay attention, you're all there is.  And it's not real and you don't have to even like them -- you can even hate them, it's all right, it safe -- you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRASK'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, there's Tom Grunemann, you're right, different margins, different spacing absolutely, sloppy, right.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mm.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRASK'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The right-hand document is switched.</context>
      <utterance>All right, try this next guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE, TRASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Klute reacts.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think this is our guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. It looks familiar to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then -- with subdued satisfaction, switching the projector again.</context>
      <utterance>Thought it might. It's off an arrest report you typed two years ago. Man you wanted samples of everybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRASK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now the next cat. Mm?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what reason could he have? What possible reason?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unless he was involved with Grunemann's disappearance.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew Tom never wrote that letter.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What else do you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never could believe that Tom was a split personality. I never believed he was a Dumper; and I don't believe he disappeared of his own volition; and I don't believe he's alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have some very tentative circumstantial evidence of freeky behavior, but there's no evidence of murder - there's not even a body.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Klute talks he paces back and forth in the darkness. He crosses in front of the lighted screen; the letters projected on the screen ripple over his face.</context>
      <utterance>I don't believe Tom's alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But why? Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA goes in close on Klute.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Mr. Cable's office, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John, how are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be sending you on a report tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a beautiful day in Tuscarora - I don't envy you that humidity in the city.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a silence. Both Klute and Cable seem to be waiting for one or the other to make the next move.</context>
      <utterance>It's not so bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like to know what's in it? The report.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's in it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think Tom Grunemann's dead. I've been a lot of places - I've asked a lot of people. I've found no proof he's around. I've found no proof he was ever around.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you go from that to the idea Tom's dead? Suicide you're suggesting? He killed himself?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He could've been murdered.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure the FBI and the Police explored that possibility.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The next step. Unless something --</context>
      <utterance>No. They never did, really. But that's what I'm going to recommend.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you discussed this with them?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's in the report.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do they have the report? Have you discussed it with them?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanted to give it to you first.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. All right --  John, just sit tight will you? I'll read your report, I'll discuss it with the others. I'll be back next Thursday, we'll talk the whole thing over then. Nothing til Thursday, all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Goodbye, John.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Klute hangs up.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Pete.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The old black lady motions to Trask who crosses to her. She points to a picture in the file. She has obviously found her missing person among the photographs of the unidentified dead. She starts to stand but then sits again, obviously shaken. Klute crosses to her and gently helps her out of the chair. He sees in her face the same sense of loss he feels for his friend.</context>
      <utterance>He was always at their house on holidays. Tom and Holly always had him, over on holidays. Tom felt sorry for him - his whole life was work. Tom felt sorry for him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw Mr. Faber.  You remember Mr. Faber, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that all you have to say?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What am I supposed to say?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>teacher. Klute says nothing. They continue walking among the plants and he picks up a few that she had admired.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I told him I wouldn't - uh - go there any more.  I know it's tough to understand, but it wasn't easy. You see, he was nice to me. I mean, it wasn't just him. I got something out of it too I guess. Anyway, I told him I wouldn't go there anymore. She is like a child awaiting praise from her</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Considering his contempt for all the dead plant life he has seen in her apartment in the past, she is pleased by this act of belief in her.</context>
      <utterance>Well, here's your gold star.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spangler says we have a relationship.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You and I -- a relationship.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was wondering what that was.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell there's nothing so mysterious about the square life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Jesus. Oh Jesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves quickly to the rear of the apartment, looks at the rear window which has been broken inward in a litter of glass -- then returns to the table at the front of the apartment; his folders. Bree cracks wise, unsteadily.</context>
      <utterance>Don't touch anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You suppose he's a married fella?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He stands, looking down, taking no notice as --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then a moment later, she cries out again, more sharply:</context>
      <utterance>He got in my clothing!</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He turns quickly. She is holding out, at arms length, a pair of her underpants. With a disgust so extreme she can only laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh look what he did in them.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She doesn't respond. He seizes her arm, shakes the garment back onto the floor. She starts to gag, slaps her hand over her mouth, starts for the bathroom. Klute yanks her back.</context>
      <utterance>Drop it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She twists free of his hands, backs away. The same elementary terror we've seen before.</context>
      <utterance>Stay out of there.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to me: It's all right. I've been expecting something.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God, I thought it was over. And here I am, daddy, right back at the start.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bree --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right back at the start, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go down in my room.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's broken for the door; it's questionable that she's even heard him. He hasn't time to pursue -- shouts again --</context>
      <utterance>You said it was over, right? You said not to worry any more, all over, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then he turns back into the apartment.</context>
      <utterance>Go down in my room and wait.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But if Cable killed Grunemann why would he get you hired to look for Grunemann?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because he knew I couldn't leave the case alone. And this way at least he'd keep track of it. And me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Grunemann's letters to the girl, everything like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cable's letters, Cable's phone calls. Cable's everything else. He's been a Dumper a long time. He just passed off his own peculiar habits on the other man -- it kept things goin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OK, pretend I believe you. Tell me how you get an indictment.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't. Yet. Oh we got everythin' else: first rate evidence Cable typed those dumper letters to Bree Daniel. And Jane McKenna: Klute found a couple in her personal remains. We got dates of Cable's trips here coincidin' with phone calls to Bree Daniel, also the dates of death of McKenna and Page. We got some hints of his personal history. His father, unsuccessful salesman, committed suicide when he was 13. His mother pinned all her hopes on her son. He won a national science youth award at the age of eight. They had no money, but she hired special tutors for him in the summer time. She saw a good thing. He graduated from high school at 14 -- college at 16 -- no friends -- The kids in his class thought of him as a freak. He got his Ph.D. at 18 -- married at age 21 to his then employer's daughter. The marriage lasted 4 weeks. Her father had it annulled. She says he was impotent. World War II he got in bad trouble about a German girl, no details. We think we know why he killed Grunemann -- he found out Cable was a dumper; Cable couldn't take that. We think we know why he killed McKenna -- she wanted to blackmail him for it. All fine. But we got no body, no direct witnesses, we can't go any-damn-where.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Technicians, meanwhile have packed to depart. The first Technician scoops the torn up photographs into another collecting box. Trask retrieves the company outing photograph.</context>
      <utterance>That's the reason i told him we had no evidence Tom was still alive. We wanted to shake him into another phone call or another letter. It didn't work out just that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gov, want to leave me that one. How come he got to play with this one, anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trask eyes Klute for a moment, as if a querying his relationship with Bree. Klute is clearly unresponsive. Trask resumes.</context>
      <utterance>I left them here. I was doing some work here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's damn lucky you didn't have the dossier on Cable here.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody's seen that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we get anything from the lab, we'll have it by noon. And just think -- all he really had to do was write us a letter.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds to me you better shake him again. Put him in a spot he has to do something more -- but this time give him a time and a place to do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He called this morning from Tuscarora. Asked me to meet him at 3:00 at the downtown heliport. He's on his way to Chicago.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Klute starts gathering his papers we CUT TO --</context>
      <utterance>He sure chalks up a lot of flight time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, Schmendrick -- what's the scam?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those were police laboratory people, they've been over the apartment.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods; she starts by. Then --</context>
      <utterance>Oh zippidy-doo, they'll find my fingerprints.  Can I go in? I need some stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd you spend last night?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With Trina.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I called Trina.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I wasn't there when you called.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bree, what's actually happened? It wasn't that bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know how bad it was?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why couldn't you stay here with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. Then, evenly --</context>
      <utterance>Because I didn't want to be touched! I didn't think you'd get that!</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts on, then turns back toward him -- rather pleadingly --</context>
      <utterance>Trask wants to talk with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey -- look officer -- I can explain everything. It was just -- you know, everything all of a --</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She continues on up; Klute continues down.</context>
      <utterance>Trask wants to talk with you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>TRASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miss Daniel, be sensible, you find another place till we get things cleaned up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh well that shouldn't take you more than another, oh, two and a half or three years, should it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A few more days. We know who did this.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So do I.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She spins around -- mute -- terrified.</context>
      <utterance>No, not Grunemann. He's dead. The man that killed him -- also prob'ly Jane McKenna, also Arlyn Page.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arlyn and Jane commited suicide. He said they commited suicide.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now there's a picture I'd like you to --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said someone killed them, you said you know who, you said that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well we're pretty --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why isn't he locked up?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't want to just lock him up; we want a conviction, we wanted him to do something more.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that why Klute didn't tell me?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess he figured it was better.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was better? I made better bait?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, that's not --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that what he set me up for? Everything he's told me from the beginning? -- don't worry, don't --</utterance>
   <speaker>TRASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From the beginning I don't know why the hell he's messin with you. If he was me he'd know better. If he was even a city boy he'd know better. You're a whore Miss Daniel, that's the truth of it, right? Now somethin I'd like you to look at.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have to look at anything. I don't have --</utterance>
   <speaker>TRASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He coerces her to the table and unrolls the Company outing picture. (We see the rip extending up through the image of Tom Grunemann in the front row.)</context>
      <utterance>Here please.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like for you to look for the man.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trask has clamped his thumb over the torn image of Grunemann, indicates with the other hand --</context>
      <utterance>Grunemann? I've looked at him a --</utterance>
   <speaker>TRASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see her comply -- her eyes moving over the rows of faces. Then we see her stiffen, hear her gasp --</context>
      <utterance>No. Not Grunemann. The Dumper. Just look around -- I said look for the Dumper.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh! -- -- and WE CUT TO --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="43">
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry we had to meet here. But I'm pressed for time.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well there's a couple --</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I read your report. I had to go along with it -- the idea of this being a wild goose chase, Tom being nowhere around --</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well as a matter of --</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been up country, you know my summer place, my camp. I don't even have a telephone there. This morning they sent a messenger out, that you'd been trying to call me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm on my way to Chicago. Very important meeting tonight. Well -- any new developments?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, two things Pete, that --</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anything from that?</context>
      <utterance>You said Trask was arranging laboratory work. Police laboratory.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. It wasn't Tom.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wasn't Tom that broke in the room.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It has to be Tom. You said he ripped up his own pictures, he --</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not Tom. Whoever it was left a kind of souvenir, I told you, in her clothing. Semen. The laboratory got a blood group reading from that. The man was blood type 0; Tom was an AB.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some mistake perhaps that --</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. No mistake Pete. It doesn't prove who it was -- but proves it wasn't Tom.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must be discouraged.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not too bad. This brings back that Dumper in the picture.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That who?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dumper, the man Bree Daniel mentioned and Arlyn Page knew and Jane McKenna knew.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said he was no possible connection with Tom. The Page girl told you that, not Tom.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone's been doing all these things.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were hired to look for Tom, not someone.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pete, I've got a chance to buy Jane McKenna's black book.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I've been after it a long time.</context>
      <utterance>Call-girls generally keep a book, you know, a list of their clients. Sometimes, if a girl retires, she'll even sell it worth good money. Jane McKenna had a black book; when she died it was stolen.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were hired to look for Tom.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sometime -- right along about now -- it privately comes to Cable that Klute may know everything and that he, Cable, may be being trapped.</context>
      <utterance>I'm meeting a man tomorrow night. He wants to meet me on East-River Drive -- he wants five hundred dollars for the book. Can you get that for me Pete?</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't follow you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will the Company put up five hundred dollars to get Jane McKenna's list of clients?</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. It's ridiculous. This has nothing to do with Tom Grunemann.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It probably has the Dumper's name. It might give us some kind of new lead.  I want a look at it anyhow.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Klute, the Company's interest is Tom Grunemann. Solely and exclusively. You say you can't find Tom; all right, I'll see that you're paid off; the case is closed.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HELICOPTER FLIGHT is announced over loud speaker and Cable and Klute walk onto field.</context>
      <utterance>All right, but I'm going to see that list.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Klute is momentarily at a loss -- not a question he'd prepared for -- improvises.</context>
      <utterance>Why would they deal with you? You don't know these people.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cable takes an instant to compute the thing. Then --</context>
      <utterance>No, but Bree does. She's negotiating for me. Bree Daniel.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can talk it over; possibly I can get the money. When are you meeting the man?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow evening, nine. East River Drive and 73rd Street.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Suppose I meet you there a half hour before.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just send me a money order.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'd -- like to be in on it. ATTENDANT comes over to motion Cable onto the helicopter. Klute smiles awkwardly, raises his hand in a goodbye gesture.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well --</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow. See you tomorrow night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He still doesn't extract an answer. She returns with other dresses.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want you to do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. I said I don't want you to do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trask said I should move. Let's not make a thing of it. He continues to look at her; she continues to gather possessions. Then trying to smile, to deal with it casually --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, too much is going on here. I'm moving in with another girl, that's all. Just for a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. This other girl's got a very big apartment, big, plenty of room.  Look, it's not necessarily how it looks, right? It's -- He thinks better of continuing. Klute looks from him back to Bree. He speaks gravely, spacing his words -- unable to speak any faster.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Please. Not with this son of a bitch. Frank rises, both nervous and offended -- but dealing with Klute as between civilized men. Smiling.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Klute, let's handle it like grownups? I mean we're all grown up now, right?  -- we all respect each other, you know what I mean? -- I respect you, Bree respects you -- you could say, it just didn't work out between you and she. But you got to respect her too -- you know, her best interests, best for her -- Klute hits him, pursues, recovers, and starts to beat him. BLOOD thickly descends the side of Frank's face, as he struggles away. Bree is screaming. Bree grabs at him from behind. He thrusts her off. But it allows Frank to break away through the still-open door. Klute pursues.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Klute is restrained -- restrains himself. Frank has faced around on the stairs, still bleeding extravagantly from his torn scalp. Earnestly --</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Klute start's out after him -- Frank vaults away down the stairs -- we hear him stumbling and running -- Klute faces sharply around into the apartment.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, I'm gonna get you dropped.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- I have to close up now. Leave your name and number with his message service, Mrs. Daniel, and why don't you just go home and wait until he --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>LELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I have to close up now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look -- could I use your phone?</utterance>
   <speaker>LELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes indeed.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look. I almost killed my -- I almost killed someone.</utterance>
   <speaker>LELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I'm certain Doctor Spangler will want to talk with you; excuse me. Bree moves to the desk and telephone. But we move with the Secretary as she moves into Spangler's inner office and switches out the lights  and as we hear, O.S., the sound of DIALING and BREE'S VOICE --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is Mr. Faber there?  Mr. Faber Senior.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up, immediately starts to dial again, then pauses to check a list he's laid out by the telephone. While he's doing this, his PHONE RINGS.</context>
      <utterance>Trina, will you call me if you hear from, her? Will you check other people she might call? Yeah, if it wasn't trouble I wouldn't ask vou.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?  Nothing yet, Trask; I'm going down the list. I've tried Spangler's office and Spangler's home; I just get his message service. I'll keep--  I may have steered Cable that way. I told him Bree was dealing for me, for Jane McKenna's book. Have you found any -- He is interrupted again -- Trask wasting no words on his end of things -- nods once --</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>-- and depresses the receiver just long enough to clear the connection, and starts dialing again -- We CUT TO --</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FOREMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lady, it's closing up there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOREMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're closing up, quitting time, Fabers.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Faber.</context>
      <utterance>I have an appointment with Mr.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOREMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah. He lets her pass, glances after her like the others, continues on his way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Faber.</context>
      <utterance>I have an appointment with Mr.</utterance>
   <speaker>RECEPTIONIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bree goes on nervously in the direction indicated, toward --</context>
      <utterance>In there.  Mr. Faber --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry -- Mr. Faber Senior.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father went home about fifteen minutes ago; he wasn't feeling too good. She has already started away. He calls after her evenly --</utterance>
   <speaker>NATHAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She looks back quickly, smiles nervously --</context>
      <utterance>Can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But we hold on him for a moment as she continues out of scene -- until he turns away to other matters. Then --</context>
      <utterance>It wasn't important.</utterance>
   <speaker>RECEPTION AREA: RECEPTIONIST, BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bree returns toward Receptionist, awkwardly --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bree Daniel.</context>
      <utterance>Did Mr. Faber leave a message for me or anything? Mr. Faber Senior?</utterance>
   <speaker>RECEPTIONIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Receptionist riffles through a stack of assorted envelopes -- hands one out to Bree -- and promptly takes her way off. Out. Bree starts to open the envelope then and there -- but OTHERS continue to move past her. She seeks a more private place.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I thought that was for tomorrow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bree Daniel. Has he called in yet? Well if he does, I'm at --  -- two seven eight, three one hundred, and I guess I can wait here five minutes; then I'll try from somewhere else.  Just tell him Bree Daniel; he knows who. She hangs up, goes back to readdressing the envelope. FOOTSTEPS are approaching in her direction. She glances up apologetically.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Faber, I just wanted to leave this for your father, and I wondered if you'd -- She pauses --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did she leave a number?  This is a police call; don't make me take time to prove it. Did she leave a number? What is the number?  What is the number? --</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't we talk together reasonably, just -- ordinarily?  I know you're expecting some kind of -- extravagant behavior, but believe me -- do you believe me? --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes -- all right --</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- We can talk --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her discerningly. She seems not to have followed his exposition. He tries patiently to clarify it.</context>
      <utterance>All right, then, an ordinary matter. I'm a quite well off man, I have a -- position to respect. I would feel personally uncomfortable to be connected with a -- certain kind of woman, I'm sure you understand. Do you? Well I'd like to buy Jane McKenna's book.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The PHONE RINGS, an explosive noise. Bree startles. It has been put on night-ring, to sound all over the loft, and the noise is deafening. But -- the most bizarre element is Cable's absolute lack of response to it. It rings and rings as he talks and talks -- in the same expository tone as before, without raising his voice. It drowns out most of his words -- at most we catch only odd phrases of all the following -- but he seems not to hear it any more than the clamor of other things torturing his soul.</context>
      <utterance>Her black book, Jane McKenna's, her list of -- of persons. I was told you're negotiating for it on behalf of --</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He turns and lifts a phone (one of the extension phones situated around the loft) -- though up to now he's given no evidence of even hearing the ringing. He just stands holding the phone for a time, then lowers it back on the receiver. With a sort of absolute quiet --</context>
      <utterance>That was what Klute told me -- you were negotiating for him to buy that list. And I'm in a position to pay a good deal more for it than he can. Do you understand? I'd like you to acquire it on my --  Miss Daniel, do you not understand?  Miss Daniel, I can't tell whether you understand me.  Is this something Klute just invented? Is this a trap for me, Miss Daniel; does Klute know about me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have no idea what I'm talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes -- Jane McKenna's book -- I could make a phone call.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you're frightened, you're pretending. Well -- Klute knows about me then. Does everybody know, can you tell me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. Then he shudders slightly.</context>
      <utterance>Then it doesn't matter what I do any more, does it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>We CUT TO --</context>
      <utterance>You people know nothing about pain.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He happens too close; she can't avoid shrinking.</context>
      <utterance>I've got no idea what I shall do.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not going to hurt you, absolutely, I'm not.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He seems not to have heard the request. He sits for a moment. An intellectual interest, a curiosity. (Meanwhile, perhaps, we see her starting to slip her shoes off, in hopes of running.)</context>
      <utterance>Will you let me go then?</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It puzzles me so badly. I've done terrible things but I can't consider myself a terrible man. I've killed three people and I'd still want to say it was accident, do you see?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you'll let me go I could tell them what --</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tom Grunemann discovered me -- we were here on business together, he discovered me with Jane McKenna. Then I suppose it was the -- the contempt I saw in his face and the certainty that sooner or later he'd use it against me. Within the Company. I endured that as long as I could, do you see?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yes.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, I'm just frightened.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me Miss Daniel?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said yes, I see.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no, I don't think --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rises, approaches her -- apparently taken in, credulous, grateful, wondering --</context>
      <utterance>Tell me. I'll listen.  I just want you to tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hits her.</context>
      <utterance>You're willing to listen? You want me just to keep talking?</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He hits her again.</context>
      <utterance>That's what you do, isn't it; you make a man feel accepted. That's what you all do. Your stock in trade a man's weakness.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you ask for mercy? My God, what mercy has anyone given me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a person of no value, you have no value --</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE, SHIFTING CLOSER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>steadily increasing pressure, as the pursuit and beating continue as SOUNDS, O.S. Even close at hand the noises are ambiguous -- the clatter of footsteps, grunts, a slap of flesh -- rather than distinct. Once or twice we hear CABLE'S VOICE clearly enough to make out words --</context>
      <utterance>Klute works his way steadily closer -- under</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Klute tries to gain aim --</context>
      <utterance>-- Is that contempt? Is it?  No, I'm the one who feels contempt. -- and once or twice a CRY from Bree.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Klute moves on -- moves on -- gains position -- springs.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cable catches the sound, whirls, screams --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't at least expel her. She ventures in, sits on the table, swings her heels, watches him pack. His arm impairs him. At length --</context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They've notified his wife.</context>
      <utterance>I got a call from Ross this morning. Cable owned a plot of woodland -- he'd go there on weekends. They found Tom Grunemann's body buried there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.  Well it wasn't us city people that did it -- your fine rosy-cheeked country boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mm.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going back?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. She compresses her lips, slips down from the table, starts smartly out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>Mm.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She returns and sits on the table again, waits. But Klute doesn't seem about to say anything more -- goes on packing.</context>
      <utterance>Wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well suppose I hadn't come downstairs. Would you just have folded up and sneaked away?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(pause)</context>
      <utterance>No. I was going to come up. I wanted to ask you to marry me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanted to, or you are?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He complies, stands and looks, folding a necktie. But now she finds she has to look away. Somewhat brokenly --</context>
      <utterance>You could at least look at me!</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look -- yes. I mean thanks, but -- don't you think we better be realistic?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at me. I'm pretty and sort of clever and very well intentioned, and dear God I'd tear your heart out!</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so. He resumes packing, continues through the following.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you not think so? You know the things I can do.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't scare me any more.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thereafter he guards his silence, staunchly goes on packing, as she comes at the thing from various sharp angles.</context>
      <utterance>Doesn't scare me. I think we could handle it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, why should it be yes or no? Can't we keep it going and see? I mean we can keep in touch and visit each other and see. People do that, that's realistic.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't believe that either, do you? Why can't you see my side?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sets the fan beside her, hands her the LOUDLY TICKING clock. She holds it in her lap, numbly. He's packed -- closes various drawers, leaving in good order -- snaps the suitcase shut, lifts it stiffly down from the table. She remains sitting.</context>
      <utterance>Can you use these?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I carry something for you, to the car?  Will you kiss me?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves to the door, pauses, half-smiles --</context>
      <utterance>No. I'm sore.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLUTE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She smiles back. He goes. We hear the entryway door opening and closing. She slips down off the table. We CUT TO --</context>
      <utterance>Well --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then, as a man not to be dallied with, he picks up the suitcase again. She looks at him strickenly, but it doesn't precipitate her into speech. He puts it down again. And then -- then, after all, goddamit, he reaches out, grabs her wrist, and simply hauls her along, suitcase in one hand, Bree in the other. As she yanks, shouts, struggles --</context>
      <utterance>Oh heck --  Oh heck --</utterance>
   <speaker>BREE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't decided yet!  I haven't decided yet!  I haven't decided yet! --</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
