<movie id="336" title="Kundun">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>A woman speaks:</context>
      <utterance>Mama, my story.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Again?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>Portrait of a mountain - Khangbochen - craggy peaks covered with snow, twenty-four thousand feet high.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your father had been very ill, We thought he would die, and some animals had died.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>Portrait of a mountain - Shishapangma - twenty-six thousand feet high.</context>
      <utterance>Cow.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>Portrait of a mountain - Anye Machin II - twenty thousand feet high and slightly obscured by clouds.</context>
      <utterance>And a yak. And chickens. And we had four years of bad crops, all the farmers did.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>Now, the foothills. The still photograph of this barren mountain range comes to life as we see something moving. It is a small caravan - traveling this narrow mountain pass.</context>
      <utterance>In the night, I knew you were coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>CLOSER on this caravan. We can make out eight or ten men, walking, and on horseback, dressed in heavy, brocade coats, and large woolen hats, black braids trailing down their backs. A yellow palanquin is carried by four large monks, wearing maroon robes. The caravan reaches the top of the mountain pass and turns - a sudden shift in direction - a switchback. The travelers head downhill.</context>
      <utterance>At dawn, you were born.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>Now, we see the mens's destination. A lake. An incredibly blue, circular lake, sunk between snow-dusted mountains. It is LHAMO I' LATSO - "the Oracle Lake" - and it shimmers in the sunlight. As the lake comes into view, a young man pushes back the curtain of the yellow palanquin and peers down at it. The man is dressed in royal robes. He is young, twenty four years old. His name is RETING RINPOCHE. He is the Regent of Tibet. The color of the lake changes - from brilliant turquoise, to a deep, murky, unfathomable darkness.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>So calm.</context>
      <utterance>You were a beautiful baby.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>The woman laughs.</context>
      <utterance>No cried?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>The palanquin is set down on a flat rock overlooking the lake. The water's color changes again, to a deep purple, then blue again, then red, then indigo.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe, just a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>"The Protector."</context>
      <utterance>And that day, your father got better. He named you Lhamo.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>The noblemen and monks surround Reting as he steps out of the palanquin. One man stands out here, a monk, a high lama in fact, with a kind face and fantastic, mesmerizing eyes. He is the LAMA</context>
      <utterance>I know. Silence.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LHAMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. This must stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>LHAMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me. Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am the father. You sit there.</utterance>
   <speaker>LHAMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is the harm?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He must know his place.</context>
      <utterance>He will grow up all wrong. Only you can serve him, only you can wash his bowl. Too tidy, everything just so.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOBSANG SAMTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No respect.</context>
      <utterance>He thinks he is king here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Father reluctantly gets up and gives his seat to Lhamo. Lhamo settles and waits for his Mother to hand him his bowl of tsampa. He bestows a most beautiful smile on his family.</context>
      <utterance>What is the harm?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LHAMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His Mother is making bread in the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>I go away. Look, mama, I go away. Far, far, far.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, no. Where will he go?</utterance>
   <speaker>LHAMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Far, far away.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode>OC</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good day.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode>OC</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good day.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode>OC</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, come in, so cold.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode>OC</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are traveling to Lhasa. May we...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode>OC</mode>
      <context>Your servant may use the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Of course, please, this way.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode>OC</mode>
      <context>A middle-aged man, the SERVANT, wearing heavy, ragged clothes and wrapped boots, enters the kitchen. Lhamo slides over so that the man can sit on the platform beside him. The man picks up a few pebbles and drops them - he knows the game. We recognize this servant. His name is KEUSTANG RINPOCHE. He is one of the monks we saw at the Oracle lake, the one with the mesmerizing eyes. Keustang Rinpoche is the Lama of Sera Monastery. Lhamo sees a dark brown rosary around the Servant's neck and immediately pulls at the string of beads.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LHAMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Servant takes the rosary off and gives it to the boy. Lhamo hangs the string of beads around his own neck. The Servant makes a move to take back the rosary, but Lhamo resists.</context>
      <utterance>Mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>LHAMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERVANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>LHAMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERVANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lhamo looks up, into the man's piercing, black eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I will give it to, if you can tell me who I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>LHAMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Mother enters and immediately sees the rosary around her son's neck. She gives it back to the Servant.</context>
      <utterance>The Lama of Sera. You come.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lhamo goes back to his game. The Mother hands the tired man a slice of bread and a steaming cup of tea. The man's hands are shaking. He cannot look the woman in the eye.</context>
      <utterance>Lhamo, no.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERVANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LHAMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men stop. Lhamo runs to the Servant.</context>
      <utterance>Wait! No!</utterance>
   <speaker>LHAMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lhamo is in tears.</context>
      <utterance>Me, too. Me go, too. Lhasa!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, no. Lhasa! He always says he will travel far away. He always wants to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERVANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We cannot, young master.</utterance>
   <speaker>LHAMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause.</context>
      <utterance>You come back?</utterance>
   <speaker>SERVANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The travelers head down the road. Mother and child return to their home, the Mother carrying the boy on her hip as he swings himself around to take a last look at the strangers.</context>
      <utterance>We will.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, Kumbum Monastery.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOBSANG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kumbum. It is not far away.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is not far at all, and it is a beautiful place. And your big brother is abbott there. You will not be alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOBSANG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will be very smart.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You will be a fine monk.</context>
      <utterance>You will be fine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We thought he would die.</context>
      <utterance>Your father had been very sick. He had been sick from the time you began growing in me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LHAMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cow.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. A cow had died. One night, you stopped all your moving, and I said to your sister, "His time has come."</utterance>
   <speaker>LHAMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me. First break of day.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At dawn, you were born. One eye was closed, and your sister opened it with her thumb. We gave you the sweet drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>LHAMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His Mother laughs.</context>
      <utterance>I pooped.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did. We washed you and wrapped you in sheepskin and took you to your father. That day he father got better And that day, a pair of crows came to nest in our roof. I just remembered.</utterance>
   <speaker>LHAMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I miss my brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I miss him too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>LAMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am the Lama of Sera.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sera Monastery? From Lhasa?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lhamo jumps off the wall. He carefully lifts the smaller beetle from the path of the larger beetle. He places the rescued bug safely in a clump of grass.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. We have business here.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEUSTANG RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lhamo considers the request, then climbs onto the bed to study the objects. The drum and the bell he chooses quickly. Keustang Rinpoche watches the boy gather the items. He looks at the yellow silk and the boy's small, fine hands. He dares not look directly at the boy. Lhamo picks up one walking stick - a lovely, bronze-handled one. He swings it around, but he finally rejects it in favor of a plain, iron-handled stick. He makes his own pile of these things, then looks at the Lama of Sera.</context>
      <utterance>This is yours, you say. What else belongs to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KEUSTANG RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Keustang Rinpoche takes the boy's hands in his own. He turns them over, examines them.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, those are yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEUSTANG RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Lama carefully pulls back the boy's overalls. There is a little birthmark, like a conch shell, on his shoulder. Keustang Rinpoche pulls up the boy's pants legs. There is a funny skin marking on the legs, like tiger stripes. The Lama rearranges the boy's clothing, then one more time, takes the beautiful, little hands in his own and whispers:</context>
      <utterance>With permission?</utterance>
   <speaker>KEUSTANG RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He says to the others, in a soft, secretive voice:</context>
      <utterance>"Kundun"</utterance>
   <speaker>KEUSTANG RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the background, by an open curtain, we see Lhamo's Mother. She says, softly:</context>
      <utterance>He is the Presence.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My oldest boy is an incarnation.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEUSTANG RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Keustang releases the boy's hands and brings his own closed palms up to his forehead.</context>
      <utterance>So is your youngest.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEUSTANG RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Mother begins to cry.</context>
      <utterance>I wish you long life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will be back in a few days.</utterance>
   <speaker>LHAMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lhamo holds up two fingers.</context>
      <utterance>Two.</utterance>
   <speaker>LHAMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This many?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Takster moves closer. She places the sad youngster in Takster's arms.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, yes. Your brothers are here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lhamo kisses her, as does Lobsang and even Takster falls into her arms for a moment. Then, she turns and goes, quickly. A Monk appears. He produces a concertina and begins to play for the little boy. But, Lhamo begins to cry, through the music, through the hugs of his brothers. As a result of Lhamo's tears, Lobsang begins to cry. Takster holds them both. The music continues. The older, wiser, Takster begins to cry, too. The three brothers hold one another. Three brothers, three monks, crying for their mother. The music continues, echoing in this stone monastery. The young "Kundun" is gently rocked by his older brother. He begins to fall asleep.</context>
      <utterance>One more kiss.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BOYS'S VOICES</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>A TEACHER, a very stern-looking monk, carrying a thick, flat board, menacingly, behind his back, walks among the students. A golden head of a Buddha - a huge head - appears to be bursting through an archway at the end of a dark hallway. The Chinese Governor stands, like a giant, against the blue sky. Omnipotent. Frightening.</context>
      <utterance>"May I be the doctor and the medicine, And may I be the nurse, For all sick beings in the world, until everyone is healed."</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINESE GOVERNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Keustang Rinpoche, also a head against blue sky, argues:</context>
      <utterance>I want him accompanied by my Chinese soldiers.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEUSTANG RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE on the Chinese Governor.</context>
      <utterance>This is Tibet. We are not under your authority.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINESE GOVERNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE on Keustang Rinpoche. Slowly, he nods. An image of the Father and the Mother, standing in their courtyard, staring at the departing search party. The Mother asks over and over:</context>
      <utterance>I want one hundred thousand Chinese dollars, if you want the boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>View of the Mother, on the roof, feeding cedar and yak chips into the incense burner. We hear: BOYS (reciting) "May I be protector for those without one."</context>
      <utterance>But why? Who is Lhamo? Who do they say he is? Her husband does not know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TEACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"May I be a bridge, a boat, a ship For all who wish to cross the water." Lhamo looks down at the complicated words.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy just waits, sad, lonely. The Teacher offers Lhamo an apricot. Lhamo takes the fruit. The Monk pats the boy's head, gently, and Lhamo takes shelter in the kind man's massive robes. The view becomes sunlight through deep, maroon wool.</context>
      <utterance>Can you recite?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LHAMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have all the room.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOBSANG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be a baby, move over.</utterance>
   <speaker>LHAMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You move.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOBSANG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hit and pinch until finally the movement of the carriage stops. The Driver reaches in through the open curtains and separates the boys, each to his own side of the dreljam. Inside his tiny carriage, young Lhamo now sits quiet and composed.</context>
      <utterance>You! You think you are so big!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LHAMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who am I?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We do not know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RETING RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the Regent turns, hikes up his gorgeous robes, and prostrates before the child.</context>
      <utterance>Chenrezi, the Buddha of compassion. The Wish Fulfilling Jewel. The Fourteenth Dalai Lama.</utterance>
   <speaker>RETING RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the crowd stand Lhamo's Mother and Father and Lobsang Samten. On their faces, we must see that they did not realize who their son, their brother, was believed to be. First the Mother, and then the Father, bow in front of their youngest child.</context>
      <utterance>Long life.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Long life.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finally, Lobsang.</context>
      <utterance>Long life.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOBSANG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear peels of childish laughter.</context>
      <utterance>Long life, Lhamo. We hear the sound of a great, Tibetan horn.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RETING RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reting blows his nose.</context>
      <utterance>Centuries ago, a young boy was born. His name was Gedundrub. The night of his birth, robbers came to his home and his family fled hiding the baby in a cattle pen. When they returned the next day, the baby was safe. They found him guarded by a pair of black crows. He was the first Dalai Lama. The Living Buddha of Compassion. Now, you have chosen to come back to this life once again.</utterance>
   <speaker>RETING RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE on Lhamo - Tenzin Gyatso.</context>
      <utterance>We name you Tenzin Gyatso.</utterance>
   <speaker>RETING RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the curtain behind Lhamo, we notice the curly-toed shoes of a monk, a man who must be standing in the next room.</context>
      <utterance>Your job is simple. You are to love all living things. Just love them. Care for them. Have compassion for them. "As long as any living thing draws breath, wherever he shall be, there in compassion, shall the Buddha appear, incarnate."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Lord Chamberlain points to a golden statue of a round man in a peaked hat.</context>
      <utterance>Fifth Dalai Lama. The boy looks.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Lord Chamberlain lifts a framed photograph of a bald, charismatic man, with razor sharp eyebrows, pictured sitting on a throne.</context>
      <utterance>Seventh Dalai Lama. Tenzin Gyatso nods.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Lord Chamberlain places the state seal in the young boy's hands and indicates that the boy should bring the heavy instrument down hard on the parchment. The boy does. The Lord Chamberlain scribbles a little something on a tab of attached paper, then bows to the boy.</context>
      <utterance>Thirteenth Dalai Lama. The boy looks at the photo.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fourteenth Dalai Lama.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NORBU THUNDRUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tenzin Gyatso is ferocious in his strategy, taking Norbu's men.</context>
      <utterance>My name is Norbu, Holiness. I will be good, you be bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I am stronger.</context>
      <utterance>I'm on a big mountain and hitting at the bad men. And after the game, we're going to trade. You just stay over there, no, there!, Norbu, and I will shoot at you. I want your land. I take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORBU THUNDRUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norbu Thundrup plays like a child. It is a fight to the finish.</context>
      <utterance>I am braver.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tenzin Gyatso has lost; he dissolves into tears.</context>
      <utterance>I have more men. NORBU ThUNDRUP I have smarter men.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORBU THUNDRUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norbu snaps his fingers.</context>
      <utterance>Today you lose. Tomorrow you may win.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORBU THUNDRUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Things change, Kundun.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why is your beard so funny? Let me touch this. Tenzin touches the soft, bald, chin of Norbu.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then, Tenzin Gyatso tries to snap his fingers. He cannot.</context>
      <utterance>Soft.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is audible expression of tension.</context>
      <utterance>We note this. Now, the Chinese.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Layman gets to his knees.</context>
      <utterance>The Allies wish to build a supply- road from India, crossing Tibet, as part of their war effort. The road would lead directly to China.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAYMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We cannot allow it. Right now, we have a only a small Chinese mission in Lhasa, the first since the Thirteenth Dalai Lama threw them out in 1912. The road would increase the size of that mission. The Chinese would try to control our trade, as they did once before, control our contact with the outside world.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MONKS</speaker>
      <mode>OC</mode>
      <context>The door opens. The boys disappear inside.</context>
      <utterance>Kundun! Kundun!</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE ATTENDANTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With this you can see a long way.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, it is a telescope, Holiness.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And, is it mine?</utterance>
   <speaker>ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are all gifts sent to your predecessors.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOBSANG SAMTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes! Then it is yours!</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NORBU THUNDRUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She carried a basket in her arms, a big, heavy basket, and the old monk cautiously approached. She opened her basket and showed what she had. Heads. Human heads. Only the heads.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that true or pretend?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORBU THUNDRUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is a story, you decide.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretend.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORBU THUNDRUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Sweeper tucks the boy in as the Master of the Robe finishes his nightly preparations and with a pat and a smile, the two men leave the room. A mouse steals a bit of tsampa from the offerings placed on the altar before the Buddha. Tenzin Gyatso peeks out from under his covers and looks to see if those curly-toed shoes are visible under the partition. They are. The Master of the Kitchen is still near. Tenzin Gyatso pulls the golden pocket watch from under the covers. He pries and digs at the back of the watch until he succeeds in popping it open, revealing its miraculous insides. Finally, Tenzin Gyatso's eyelids grow heavy. The camera passes over his face, as his eyes close. The boy begins to speak, mumble, as he falls asleep:</context>
      <utterance>As you say.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We find two scrolls; the first is PENDEN LHAMO, the special protectress of the Dalai Lama. She rides her wild mule through a sea of blood - between rows of jagged mountains. Pointed fingers and spreading toes, her hair gone crazy, her fangs revealed - the details are incredible. A garland of freshly severed heads hangs around her body, snakes hold up her skirt, five skulls form ber crown.</context>
      <utterance>"I be an island for those who seek one, a lamp for light."</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>Beside her, on the second scroll is MAHAKALA. He is the fierce representation of the Buddha of Compassion. Crows fly in the clouds to the left of the terrifying, black, six- armed figure. A skull rosary is held in the upper right arm, a Trident is held in the left hand. The deity wears a crown of five skulls. He has three eyes. He tramples an elephant. We might have been in a dream, as the camera finally moves back to find the peaceful1 protected face of the young Dalai Lama. Asleep. The camera moves across the mural devoted to the story of the Fifth Dalai Lama. It is a fantasy of green, with mountains and lakes and deities and monsters. We find the statue of Seventh Dalai Lama, sitting on his golden cushion, and we look, deep into the eyes of the Thirteenth Dalai Lama. Fantastic. Deeper. Deeper.</context>
      <utterance>"May I be a bed for all who wish to rest, and a slave for all who want a slave."</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"May I be wishing jewel, a magic vase...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to go down there.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORBU THUNDRUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can only go with attendants and a big ceremony.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to run down the street. I want to buy a toy. Eat from the shops.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORBU THUNDRUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You cannot.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to be a shepherd, taking those goats and cows out to the hillside.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORBU THUNDRUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you are not a shepherd, you are the Dalai Lama.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The view travels and we see a prison yard. Shackled men share the yard with hairy, fat dogs. One man looks up and sees that the yard is under surveillance. Of course the men all know that this terrace belongs to the boy Dalai Lama. As the boy watches, first one poor, ragged man, then another prostrates. Tenzin Gyatso pulls away from the telescope. He waves to the prisoners.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe in the next life, the world will not need a Dalai Lama. NORNU ThUNDRUP I would not know. Maybe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>LOBSANG SAMTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Father uses the grease from the roasted lamb on the table to caress his long mustache and twirl each side into a point. The Dalai Lama takes another, and then, suddenly, the boy reaches up and for no reason, he pulls on his Father's mustache, obviously hurting the man. The Father slaps the boy's hand, hard. The boy sits back, and begins drawing imaginary letters on the tabletop with his slapped hand. His Father reaches out and takes the hurt hand. He pulls the boy into his arms.</context>
      <utterance>The Dalai Lama is not supposed to eat pork. It is not good for your brain.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am sorry, Lhamo.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Master of the Robe knocks at the door. Father and son look up.</context>
      <utterance>It is alright, Father.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASTER OF THE ROBE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The young boy sits straight up on his Father's lap and says, defiantly:</context>
      <utterance>Kundun, you must come back now.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The surprised Monk backs away from the door.</context>
      <utterance>Go away.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not the way to talk to people.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I do anything I want?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, I am in charge.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy thinks.</context>
      <utterance>Are you? Of whom?</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I save the sheep from going to the market? So they don't die.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOBSANG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could buy them.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I have money?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOBSANG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have money?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do, now.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You love horses.</context>
      <utterance>And you have horses?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thank you, Holiness.</context>
      <utterance>I do, beautiful horses.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you buy the sheep for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where will you keep them?</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here. We'll collect them.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will buy them for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I free the prisoners?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmmm.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOBSANG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't do anything real until you are Dalai Lama.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOBSANG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not until you are eighteen.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode>OC</mode>
      <context>The Mother has been in the doorway, listening. Tenzin Gyatso disengages from his Father's arms and goes to his Mother. Tenzin reaches into one of her large, apron pockets and finds nothing. Another. Nothing. He reaches into her sash and pulls out a special-looking sweet. She takes the boy's hand and leads him from the house.</context>
      <utterance>You have escaped once more.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOBSANG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lobsang looks at his Father.</context>
      <utterance>Go study. I get in trouble if you do not study.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOBSANG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes you strike the goat, to scare the sheep.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOBSANG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is a naughty sheep.</context>
      <utterance>I am the goat.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE on the Father's face.</context>
      <utterance>He will not be ours much longer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have news. The Regent has resigned his post.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he a bad man? Norbu says he is "lavish" and "willful". "How can he give you monk's vows if he has not kept them himself?"</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another will be chosen.</context>
      <utterance>Well, some say. It's not for you to worry about.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was always nice to me. He found me. He saw me in his dreams.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I turn you over again, today, Lhamo. One day, you will not be able to come running to us.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you will always be here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me?</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will always!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tenzin grabs at her stomach and shrieks with laughter.</context>
      <utterance>I have one more piece of news. A baby is coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Mother places her hands on Tenzin Gyatso's.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Mama! Who will it be?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A string of old monks, stand, waiting for the naughty boy.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no! Who can it be?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A monk takes the boy by the hand and leads him down a hallway.</context>
      <utterance>My teeth! My teeth are in here!</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My old teeth!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TAKTRA RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the boy leaps up from his table and goes to Taktra and hangs around his neck, shouting:</context>
      <utterance>"I take refuge in the three jewels, The Buddha, the Dharma and the Sangra."</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taktra gives the boy just the slightest of looks.</context>
      <utterance>You recite! You recite!</utterance>
   <speaker>TAKTRA RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tenzin Gyatso releases the Lama and goes back to his own table.</context>
      <utterance>"I take refuge in the three jewels, The Buddha, the Dharma and the Sangra."</utterance>
   <speaker>TAKTRA RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taktra Rinpoche has a small table with the same hand instruments in front of him. The teacher lifts the dorge, in a particular fashion, and rotates it. Tenzin Gyatso lifts his dorge. Taktra's hands move to the boy's and show him the correct movement. It is tried again. Now, the bell is lifted and rung.</context>
      <utterance>"Until I attain enlightenment."</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the chanting continues, Taktra Rinpoche begins a weaving motion with his hands, delicate, beautiful, hypnotic. Tenzin Gyatso copies the elder. We are CLOSE on the boy's moving hands. The chanting becomes the voices of a hundred men, as we FADE OUT. FADE IN: on the boy's hands, but they are a little larger - they are the hands of an eleven or twelve year-old boy - and the motion they carry out is on the verge of becoming extraordinarily beautiful.</context>
      <utterance>I would like you to be my new Regent. Taktra stops. He nods to the boy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LING RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tenzin Gyatso, sitting cross legged on a cushion, responds.</context>
      <utterance>The Four Noble Truths.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Four Noble Truths, as taught by the Lord Sakyamuni Buddha are: The Truth of Suffering The Truth of the Cause of Suffering, The Truth of the Cessation of Suffering, the Truth of the Way which leads to the cessation of Suffering.</utterance>
   <speaker>LING RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What is suffering?</context>
      <utterance>I accept it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>True suffering arises from contaminated actions and afflictions. Birth, illness, grief, old age, poverty, pain, death - these are surferings.</utterance>
   <speaker>LING RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What are the causes of suffering?</context>
      <utterance>I accept it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now we CUT BACK to Ling Rinpoche, but he is standing, outside, in a courtyard. He asks another question, but he raises his right hand as he speaks, and lowers his left, completing the question with a clap of the hands.</context>
      <utterance>The causes of suffering arise from true sources. Attachment, desire, envy, hatred, greed, unkindness, wrong view and so forth - these are some causes of suffering.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LING RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long silence from His Holiness. The Lamas wait on tender hooks. Finally, the boy says:</context>
      <utterance>How does one progress from the realization of one Noble Truth to another?</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is laughter. Even Ling Rinpoche laughs and the boy erupts into his beautiful, free, easy laugh.</context>
      <utterance>We will have to think about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to squeeze this brain.</utterance>
   <speaker>LING RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Answer.  A pause, and then:</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks to the elders.</context>
      <utterance>When one understands that he causes some of his own suffering, needlessly, then he looks for the causes in his own life. And when and he looks for those causes, when he investigates, then he is putting confidence in his own ability to eliminate the sources and end the suffering. A wish to find a path to peace arises. For all beings desire happiness. All wish to find their purest selves. Ling nods in approval.</utterance>
   <speaker>LING RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taktra Rinpoche and the Lord Chamberlain are proud.</context>
      <utterance>I accept it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TAKTRA RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tenzin Gyatso shouts:</context>
      <utterance>Careful! Careful!</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I love to jump!</context>
      <utterance>I need to jump!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Lord Chamberlain enters.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, nicely done, Norbu. I will get you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I listen to the news with you, Holiness?</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A large, old-fashioned, short-wave radio broadcasts that there is still a real war in progress. The BBC report is of the Pacific front.</context>
      <utterance>Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How big is Tibet's army?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CPIAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roughly five thousand men.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that big?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Not very big.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The broadcast reports news of the civil war in China.</context>
      <utterance>The Regent is adding men. And he bought rifles and ammunition from India. Mountain guns, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will we be in this war?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. This war is almost over.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Lord Chamberlain is silent. Norbu answers.</context>
      <utterance>Will we ever be in war?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORBU THUNDRUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have enemies.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Chinese.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORBU THUNDRUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We don't believe in killing.</context>
      <utterance>But, surely, we are safe in Tibet.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tenzin Gyatso gets to his feet and takes an atlas from his table. He lays the book open on the floor.</context>
      <utterance>No, we don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Britain.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORBU THUNDRUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahh.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Lord chamberlain sits on the floor. He points to Poland.</context>
      <utterance>Where is Poland?</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Master of the Kitchen comes to look at the atlas.</context>
      <utterance>Where is Pearl Harbor?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the Pacific Ocean. It is an island. American territory.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is Alsace?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tenzin Gyatso turns to a well thumbed page: Tibet.</context>
      <utterance>I do not know, Holiness.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And this is China.</context>
      <utterance>This is Tibet.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORBU THUNDRUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all look at huge China.</context>
      <utterance>Ahh.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finally, as Norbu Thundrup begins to gather up the tsampa- dough:</context>
      <utterance>Certainly, we are safe in Tibet. No one answers.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORBU THUNDRUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tenzin Gyatso turns to the Lord Chamberlain.</context>
      <utterance>We hope, Kundun.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was the warning of the Thirteenth Dalai Lama?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He warned about the future of Tibet.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When it is time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The old Monk mutters something in Chinese. They thread a roll of dusty film into the reel and spin the wheel. The film breaks. The old monk bangs the table again. The work continues.</context>
      <utterance>Patience is the first of the Six Perfections.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The monks slaps his head in horrid anticipation.</context>
      <utterance>One day, we will get that automobile running.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LING RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We find His Holiness, sitting, listening to the debate.</context>
      <utterance>"To be born in a time when the Buddha has appeared. To be born in a time when the Buddha has taught. To be born when the teaching of Buddha is alive."</utterance>
   <speaker>LING RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The view widens now and we are under a softly billowing, appliqued canopy. Maybe fifty monks and lamas are present. This is an informal group.</context>
      <utterance>"To be born where the dharma is practiced. To be born in a time when people have compassion for other people."</utterance>
   <speaker>QUESTIONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is human life precious?</utterance>
   <speaker>LING RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men jump to their feet, and rush out from under the canopy. The Dalai Lama is right in front. More shots as the men stare out across the countryside. We hear murmurs of:</context>
      <utterance>As a result of previous karma, you have obtained this human life. By means of this rebirth, through work and study, you can attain all everlasting happiness. In the words of Shantideva: "With the boat of this precious life, You can cross the waters of Samsara. How rare to find this boat!" "Oh, ignorant one, do not fall asleep now!" Shots ring out.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear these snippets as the Dalai Lama runs from the group.</context>
      <utterance>Sera, Sera Monastery. Reting. Under arrest. The army is taking him right past Sera! Monastery! Those crazy monks! Have been threatening trouble. Reting tried to assassinate Taktra Rinpoche.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The shooting continues.</context>
      <utterance>It's the army, firing on Sera Monastery! Oh, no! Oh, no!</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tell me!</context>
      <utterance>Why is this? What is happening?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORBU THUNDRUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Lord Chamberlain arrives on the terrace.</context>
      <utterance>Reting Rinpoche has been arrested. He tried to overthrow Regent Taktra. Today, he is brought back to Lhasa by government officials. The monks at Sera Monastery have been on his side. Now, there is trouble between them and the army.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am sorry for you to have to witness this, Kundun.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Lord Chamberlain peers through the telescope as the shooting continues.</context>
      <utterance>Look here!</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Lord Chamberlain steps away from the telescope and the boy takes his place. The shooting slowly stops.</context>
      <utterance>Tragic. Unnecessary.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy looks up.</context>
      <utterance>Holiness? I have a letter.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Lord Chamberlain walks to a far, sheltered end of the terrace. Tenzin Gyatso slowly turns the telescope to see the prison yard. View through the telescope; the yard is full of prisoners, listening to the shooting. One man sees the telescope aimed at the prison and prostrates. Then another, and another. Tenzin Gyatso steps away from the telescope and turns to follow his Lord Chamberlain.</context>
      <utterance>The Thirteenth Dalai Lama's warning. He wrote to you, the year before he died. The year before you were born.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE on the Lord Chamberlain. Today, he appears tired; the whites of his eyes appear enormous. His voice is quite beautiful.</context>
      <utterance>"It may happen, that here in Tibet, religion and government will be attacked both from without and within. Unless we guard our own country..."</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tenzin Gyatso unwinds the rosary from his wrist and begins thumbing the brown beads.</context>
      <utterance>"...it will now happen that the Dalai and Panchen Lamas, the Father and the Son, and all the revered holders of the faith, will disappear and become nameless."</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Monks and their monasteries will be destroyed. The rule of law will be weakened. The lands and properties will be seized. They themselves will be forced to serve their enemies or wander the country like beggars." "All beings will be sunk in great hardship and overwhelming fear; the days and nights will drag on slowly in suffering." He is finished.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can I do? I am only a boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are the man who wrote this letter. You are the man who has come back to lead us. You will soon have great responsibilities. You must know what to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORBU THUNDRUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tenzin Gyatso enters the adjacent room.</context>
      <utterance>You remember who you are. You called for them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Taktra Rinpoche, I understand there was an attempt on your life.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAKTRA RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is possible, Holiness.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are unharmed?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAKTRA RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Completely.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. Where is Reting Rinpoche now?</utterance>
   <speaker>KASHAG MEMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He has been imprisoned, here in the Potala, Holiness.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Sera monks have surrendered?</utterance>
   <speaker>KASHAG MEMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy motions to the table.</context>
      <utterance>It is calm.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The tea is poured.</context>
      <utterance>Please, have tea.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to know what you know. I am no longer a child.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ask whatever you will.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is the danger from the Chinese, now?</utterance>
   <speaker>KASHAG MEMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very complicated, Holiness. Let me tell you current news. The Chinese have launched a deceptive campaign aimed at convincing the world that Tibet belongs to China. We sent a mission to the Chinese National Conference. Our attendance was a grave mistake. The Tibetans were introduced as delegates from the "Chinese region of Tibet". We protested this reference and demanded a letter rebutting it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you receive the letter?</utterance>
   <speaker>KASHAG MEMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We did not.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The war is over. This is a time in when nations are redefining themselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, Tibet, too, needs to define itself.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. As a free country. But our attempts have proven futile. We continue to be badly outmaneuvered by the Chinese.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can India help us?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>India is a newly independent nation. They are struggling. India is in no position to help us.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Britain?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Britain chooses not to.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And, America?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>America, we shall see.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A shocking suggestion.</context>
      <utterance>Ask the Chinese mission to leave our country. Immediately.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quite simple. Yes. Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men agree to this.</context>
      <utterance>I shall send a letter to America, to the President, informing him of our problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want Reting Rinpoche well cared for. He is my teacher. He found me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The President of the United States of America I am glad that you are enjoying the best of health and doing good service to uplift the happiness and prosperity of the whole world. Here, I am well and doing my best for the religion of Lord Buddha and welfare of all beings. This is all, so far.</context>
      <utterance>Listen to this, Norbu. : To Mr Truman</utterance>
   <speaker>NORBU THUNDRUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tenzin Gyatso lays down his pen.</context>
      <utterance>Reting Rinpoche has died in prison.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LAYMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A murmuring in the room.</context>
      <utterance>Now, as his great army, stands idle on our borders, Chairman Mao has presented Tibet with three demands: One, Tibet must accept that it is part of China.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAYMAN</speaker>
      <mode>OC</mode>
      <context>A voice shouts out:</context>
      <utterance>Two, Tibet's defenses must be handled by China. Three, all political and trade matters concerning foreign countries must be conducted through China.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE IN BACK OF ROOM</speaker>
      <mode>OC</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give the Dalai Lama his majority!</utterance>
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can concede that Tibet is a part of China if we can guarantee that the Dalai Lama's name and authority will remain...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAYMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And do you believe that the Tibetan government will be allowed to continue to function as it is? Do you believe that our religion will be protected?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give the Dalai Lama his majority!</utterance>
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We can deal with it now.</context>
      <utterance>We have dealt with this Chinese obsession for hundreds of years.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAYMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>These are Communists.</context>
      <utterance>These are not the Chinese we know.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see the Lord Chamberlain look toward the open door.</context>
      <utterance>Make him Dalai Lama now!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we agree that we are part of China, nothing else will matter. Not trade, not defense. We will be lost.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAKTRA RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shepherds are leading their flock of sheep back toward town on the far side of the tributary. The two men stand side by side, one so young, one seeming so old.</context>
      <utterance>What would you do, Holiness? The boy looks out over the water.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What should I do about my doubt, Teacher?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAKTRA RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is a difficult situation.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Am I Him?</context>
      <utterance>I mean, my doubt. Why me?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAKTRA RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>Doubt is an affliction. Reliquish it. Accept.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tenzin Gyatso stands alone by the river. The boy watches the herders, and before the young shepherds disappear from sight, the Dalai Lama turns and waves a hand behind him. Two Bodyguards approach. We can not hear, but as the Dalai Lama walks away from us, down the river, one Bodyguard runs up river, shouting: BODYGUARD (shouting) We will buy them! We will buy them!</context>
      <utterance>I believe we must make no concesions to the Chinese. But, I am one voice. The Dalai Lama has always trusted in the forces of Buddha. Let us consult the protective deities. Taktra Rinpoche bows and leaves him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TAKTRA RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode>OC</mode>
      <context>The Regent is next door. The boy climbs up on a chest and peeks through a tiny window in the wall which separates this enclosure from the Regent's. Taktra Rinpoche reads a telegram. His aging face becomes quite grave. The Regent leaves his side of the enclosure.</context>
      <utterance>Enter.</utterance>
   <speaker>REGENT</speaker>
      <mode>OC</mode>
      <context>And then, there is a knock on the Dalai Lama's door.</context>
      <utterance>Summon the Lord Chamberlain and the Kashag.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is the Regent.</context>
      <utterance>Enter.</utterance>
   <speaker>REGENT TAKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holiness.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>REGENT TAKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Chinese have invaded.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They crossed the river, Holiness. They have invaded in six locations, Chando Province, Kham, eastern Tibet.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is the size of our army, now?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Little statues are placed facing what stands-in for the river. The Lord Chamberlain helps the boy to create this panorama.</context>
      <utterance>Eight thousand, five hundred, soldiers and officers. We have recently requested mortars, anti-aircraft guns and ammunition from India. We have several hundred in the area.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Has anyone died?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tenzin Gyatso lifts one statue, a small, golden Buddha, from the display. He cradles the Buddha in his hands.</context>
      <utterance>The radio contact said one officer had died. Then he said, "The Chinese soldiers - they are coming." And then, the radio went dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One man is too many.</context>
      <utterance>One man. A man has died.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"This week, the People's Liberation Army crossed the Drichu River east of Chamdo and began the peaceful liberation of Tibet. Tibet is in the hands of imperialist enemies of the people. The Dalai Lama, a foolish reminder of an illiterate past, is the figure head of this autonomous region of China. Accept our help, Tibet! The people shall be free!"</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norbu is not shy in his report.</context>
      <utterance>What do the people say, Norbu?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORBU THUNDRUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tenzin Gyatso listens carefully to the man.</context>
      <utterance>Tibetan officials have retreated from Chamdo. They are scared and running. The Chinese strategy has destroyed the heart of our defense forces. Chamdo falls, several other villages are lost. You know what happens. The road to Lhasa will be wide open.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORBU THUNDRUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The people want you made Dalai Lama.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I am still too young.</context>
      <utterance>Then, I am lucky.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORBU THUNDRUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are dangerous times. They want the Dalai Lama to lead them.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, I have no experience.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORBU THUNDRUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Who else would be here?</context>
      <utterance>Oh, but you do, Kundun.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Lord Chamberlain and the four members of the Kashag agree. The boy continues:</context>
      <utterance>"To the members of the United Nations: The attention of the world is riveted on Korea where aggression is being resisted by an international force. Similar happenings in remote Tibet are passing without notice. The problem is not of Tibet's own making but is largely the outcome of unthwarted Chinese ambition to bring weaker nations on her periphery within her active domination." This is very good. Quite strong.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the background, we see monks on top of a wall, long horns in front of them. The blowing begins. In a courtyard below, a debating session is in progress. We hear the shouts and the claps and watch the beautiful body movements of the questioners. Laughter fills the air. Below that, the small capital of Tibet - the mysterious city, the forbidden city of Lhasa - carries on, for now.</context>
      <utterance>"Tibetans have for long lived a cloistered life in their mountain fastness, remote and aloof..."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>TAKSTER RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tenzin Gyatso plays with a box of those special sweets which comes from his mother.</context>
      <utterance>I was never alone. Two Chinese were with me every minute of the day.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAKSTER RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Takster Rinpoche begins to say something, but holds back.</context>
      <utterance>Their talk is always of liberation and helpfulness. They put their words like honey on a knife, but if you lick the honey, you will bleed.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAKSTER RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They think they have convinced me. They think I am on their side. They have allowed me to leave Kumbum and come to Lhasa believing that I will try to turn you to their ways. If I do not succeed, I am to eliminate you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You, kill me?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAKSTER RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The tension is great, the idea profound.</context>
      <utterance>Eliminate you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TARSTER RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The brothers try to resist, but cannot. They laugh like crazy.</context>
      <utterance>I can be Governor of Lhasa, they say.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAKSTER RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You'll get sick.</context>
      <utterance>Don't eat all those sweets.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And you comforted me?</context>
      <utterance>Do you remember the day I came to your monastery, when I was a baby?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAKSTER RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I am frightened now.</context>
      <utterance>I remember, too, actually. I was frightened then.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAKSTER RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Our only hope is to fight.</context>
      <utterance>The Chinese have one goal. The complete dissolution of our nation. The destruction of our culture. There is no room for Buddha in their world.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We cannot.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAKSTER RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is a fight for Tibet.</context>
      <utterance>This is not a fight to put bread just in one's own mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buddha teaches that we must learn from our enemy. We have compassion for all people.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAKSTER RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>These are not human beings. They are worse than ghosts.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAKSTER RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You must flee.</context>
      <utterance>You are in great danger. The Dalai Lama cannot fall into Chinese hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How could I ever leave?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAKSTER RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It may not be your decision to make.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks around these rooms.</context>
      <utterance>We have telegraphed our appeal to the United Nations and await its reply. I am sending a delegation to China to negotiate the Chinese withdrawal.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men rise to their knees - LUKHANGWA, an incredible looking layman, with a long white beard, and LOBSANG TASHI, a monk.</context>
      <utterance>It seems that I must depart Lhasa. The majority wills it. Lukhangwa and Lobsang Tashi?</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men bow to His Holiness.</context>
      <utterance>I am making you my Prime Ministers. You will stay here. You must always keep me informed, no matter how bad the news. I want plain information.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Today, I declare a general amnesty. I have always wanted to free the prisoners.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>NORBU THUNDRUP</speaker>
      <mode>OC</mode>
      <context>Tenzin Gyatso lets go of the eyepiece and turns to see Norbu.</context>
      <utterance>It's time to take this down.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will not come?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORBU THUNDRUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Holiness.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I running away?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORBU THUNDRUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Together, the friends break-down the telescope.</context>
      <utterance>The people will cry when they learn you are gone. But they would all want you safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORBU THUNDRUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norbu folds up the tripod.</context>
      <utterance>Let me take this.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORBU THUNDRUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must study very hard, do not neglect the holy things during this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will miss you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORBU THUNDRUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have had fun, you and I. Fun for a little boy in an old palace.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORBU THUNDRUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have grown up very good.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norbu laughs. The telescope is wrapped.</context>
      <utterance>And you have grown older and your chin has grown balder.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORBU THUNDRUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norbu Thundrup ties a tight knot in a cord.</context>
      <utterance>Tonight, Kundun, you see the world. You place your feet on the shepherd boy's path.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORBU THUNDRUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE on the gold seal of state as it is packed in a silk- lined box.</context>
      <utterance>"The Gods will be avenged."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BODYGUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We must go, Holiness.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another drawer. Empty. And then, success. In a small drawer, there is something, wrapped in red velvet. The boy opens it, with shaking hands. Teeth. False teeth. Tenzin Gyatso releases a sharp laugh, he has been holding his breath. He wraps up the teeth and puts them back, but behind the teeth is something more. A rolled, white silk scarf, a kata. Tenzin Gyatso takes the scarf. He unrolls it. Something falls on the floor. A tiny, lead soldier. Tenzin Gyatso lifts the soldier. It is a Ghurka. An Indian soldier.</context>
      <utterance>A moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>BODYGUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, come, Holiness.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy places the scarf around his own shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. I am ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE on the golden statue of Mahakala, wearing his white scarf. We hear the roar of the Kyichu river.</context>
      <utterance>Safe journey. Safe return. I am him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MONKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We beg of you, do not take him from us! One monk clutches for an instant at the layman's wrapping on Tenzin Gyatso - but he does not recognize him as the Dalai Lama The boy tenderly embraces this distraught figure, but the monk drops away from him and clings to the shy, sweet presence of Ling Rinpoche. The Dalai Lama is quickly and quietly surrounded by soldiers - discreetly, so as not to give away his identity. Ling Rinpoche speaks to a group.</context>
      <utterance>Do not let him go!</utterance>
   <speaker>LING RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pain on these monks's faces, in their voices, is tragic. Tenzin Gyatso is overwhelmed. He sees before him a line of prostrate monks - but they are not bowing to him, they are laying down in the pass, trying to block the way of the caravan. Ling Rinpoche goes to these men and gently helps them to their feet.</context>
      <utterance>He goes for a short time, until the danger can be determined. He will not leave Tibet. He will return.</utterance>
   <speaker>LING RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He will return. The Precious One will not abandon you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All quiet?</utterance>
   <speaker>BODYGUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Holiness.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you from?</utterance>
   <speaker>BODYGUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kham, Holiness.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not even me.</context>
      <utterance>Your people are very brave. They are fighting the Chinese. No one can stop them.</utterance>
   <speaker>BODYGUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is silence as the two men look out at the cold night.</context>
      <utterance>Khambas are wild men.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I worry about them.</utterance>
   <speaker>BODYGUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy steps back inside.</context>
      <utterance>Do not worry, Holiness. They fight for you. They are under your protection.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MUSLIM MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eighteen children.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eighteen, wonderful.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSLIM MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Dalai Lama laughs.</context>
      <utterance>And not a monk among them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUSLIM MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy laughs again.</context>
      <utterance>No, no son of mine will sit and read books and eat up the poor people's butter while my people have to butcher the cows and sheep because these holy men can't kill an animal. They can eat it, can't they?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you love your husband, before you married?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIBETAN WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did not know him before I married him. I loved his brother, but then, I married his brother, too. He is dead now.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmm.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIBETAN WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The land has stayed in the family. We work together. The nobleman is not too bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A laugh from her.</context>
      <utterance>Does he treat you fairly?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIBETAN WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Attendants walk behind the boy, eavesdropping. Tenzin Gyatso's Mother plays along.</context>
      <utterance>Not too bad. Rich is rich, poor is poor. We are different. Are you married? Tenzin Gyatso laughs.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIBETAN WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too young?</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Much too young.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIBETAN WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look for a strong woman, not too occupied with her beauty. Look for a woinan who keeps her hands busy. Look for a kind heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like my mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIBETAN WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This little brother was terribly sweet. When he died, my mother was so sad. A lama said to her, before the little brother was laid out for burial, take a bit of butter and rub a spot on his skin. He will come back to you, you will see. So, my mother did this, and a few years later, a new boy was born.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOBLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does he have the spot?</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He does, a little spot where the butter had been.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOBLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that a true story, or pretend?</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOBLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>True.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk.</context>
      <utterance>You decide.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOBLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does the butter spot feel like?</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soft. Nice. I have a good friend back in Lhasa. He has a very poor beard, with a little spot on his chin where no hair grows. It feels like that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KASHAG MEMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of the Tibetan delegations sent abroad, all have been turned away.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode>OC</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>KASHAG MEMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>Britain, Nepal, America, India. All of those governments have refused to meet with our representatives.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the United Nations? Surely?</utterance>
   <speaker>KASHAG MEMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The United Nations voted not to hear our appeal.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One country did sponsor the resolution. A land called "El Salvador".</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>In the Americas.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, we must face China and all her might alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>KASHAG MEMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Most of the Chamdo region is now in Chinese hands. There is a report from Chamdo which makes quite clear that, unless some settlement can soon be reached, Communist troops will soon be marching on Lhasa.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With much bloodshed.</utterance>
   <speaker>KASHAG MEMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am afraid.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want at all costs to avoid this. Do we have news from the delegation in China?</utterance>
   <speaker>KASHAG MEMBERR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet, but the Governor of Chamdo, Ngabo Jigme, suggests we must negotiate and offers to go to Peking.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is a capable man.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your prime minsters would argue that such negotiations should take place in Lhasa.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Is that all?</context>
      <utterance>And then they would concede that the times are desperate and we must go to Peking. Agreed. Send Ngabo.</utterance>
   <speaker>KASHAG MEMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy gets up. The prostrations begin.</context>
      <utterance>Time to study.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tenzin Gyatso waves a hand. The men get up, awkwardly.</context>
      <utterance>Wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One man still goes down to his knees.</context>
      <utterance>We are in the last outposts of Tibet. Let's do away with some of this formality. The Dalai Lama leaves the room.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just like he was the last time.</context>
      <utterance>He is a modern man.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The lead soldier of the Indian Ghurka sits on the low table, beside Buddha and the tantric instruments.</context>
      <utterance>"I will liberate those not liberated." I will release those not released. I will relieve those not relieved. May I deliver them to the state of enlightenment."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RADIO VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>Tenzin Gyatso drops his work. He turns to face the offending radio.</context>
      <utterance>"Today in Peking, a Seventeen Point Agreement for the peaceful Liberation of Tibet has been signed by Representatives of the Government of the People's Republic of China and the Local Government of Tibet."</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>The boy moves closer to the radio, he appears physically ill.</context>
      <utterance>"Over the last hundred years or more aggressive, imperialist forces have penetrated into Tibet and carried out all manner of deceptions and provocations. Under such conditions the Tibetan nationality was plunged into the depths of enslavement and suffering."</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Today, this enslavement ends. Point One: The Tibetan people shall unite and drive out imperialist aggressive forces from Tibet. The Tibetan people shall return to the big family of the Motherland - the People's Republic of China." Point Two: The Local Government of Tibet will actively assist the People's Liberation Army to enter Tibet and consolidate the national defense." Tenzin Gyatso is stunned. Frozen.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode>OC</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It means we have lost our status as an independent nation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KASHAG MEMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ngabo did not have the state seal. He could not sign.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A Kashag Member is reading along as the message comes in.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, but they say he did.</utterance>
   <speaker>KASHAG MEMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holiness?</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>KASHAG MEMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is coming to meet you.</context>
      <utterance>General Chiang Chin-wu, the Chinese representative, is en route to Dromo.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then, we shall meet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>GENERAL CHIANG CHIN-WU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dalai Lama.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>General Chiang.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL CHIANG CHIN-WU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We bring greetings from Chairman Mao.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The General does. So does the Dalai Lama. The other two Chinese remain standing. Tenzin Gyatso is quiet, reserved. Awkward.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Please sit.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL CHIANG CHIN-WU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you heard the terms of the Seventeen Point Agreement?</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL CHIANG CHIN-WU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A document is produced. We notice that the General is wearing a gold rolex watch. The Dalai Lama notices, too. A member of the Kashag takes the document.</context>
      <utterance>I have a copy for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL CHIANG CHIN-WU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He makes no response.</context>
      <utterance>We come in genuine friendship. CLOSE on the Dalai Lama.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL CHIANG CHIN-WU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tenzin Gyatso remains silent.</context>
      <utterance>I am certain you wish to return to Lhasa.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL CHIANG CHIN-WU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have plans to return soon, Dalai Lama?</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL CHIANG CHIN-WU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No response.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Our first request is that you allow us to build a road. You have no roads in Tibet. We can discuss the plans in Lhasa. When you return.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL CHIANG-WU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The General rises as the boy remains seated. With a moment of awkward silence, the Chinese depart.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you. We leave now.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is handed to him. He opens to the last page and looks at the impression made by the state seal.</context>
      <utterance>Let me see the agreement.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He closes the document and hands it back to the official.</context>
      <utterance>Counterfeit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought he would be some kind of monster, even with horns growing out of his head. But, he is only a man, just an ordinary human being, like myself. Life is always a lesson.</utterance>
   <speaker>KASHAG MEMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your Prime Ministers, support the proposal that you return to Lhasa. On the opposite hand, some officials urge you not to return. They believe you should leave now, for India.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I were to go into exile, could we expect any serious assistance, from India, suppose?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHANBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is unlikely. America, perhaps. There is great anti-communist feeling in America.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At this point, the most likely result of a foreign pact is war.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAABERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Chinese would see such a pact as an open declaration of war.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tibet, at war? No. China is close, America is far away. After countless people die, China would still, always, be close. We will work with what we have.</utterance>
   <speaker>KASHAG MEMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause.</context>
      <utterance>And as for your own safety, Holiness?</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am scared.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shall we consult the protective deities, Holiness?</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy snaps his fingers.</context>
      <utterance>My first and foremost duty is to protect my people. I feel sure of this. And, things change. Maybe not right away, maybe not soon. But I believe this - things will change.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I shall return.</context>
      <utterance>Impermanence. Our own short lifetimes are not the only valid consideration.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TAKTRA RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy does not speak, just looks, kindly, at the man.</context>
      <utterance>I hope you will not feel badly about all the things of childhood you missed.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAKTRA RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy shakes his head "no".</context>
      <utterance>You lost so much. I am sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAKTRA RINPOCHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, another man speaks;</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Kundun.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORBU THUNDRUP</speaker>
      <mode>OC</mode>
      <context>Tenzin Gyatso turns his head to see his best friend.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Kundun.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now, the Dalai Lama's Father is seen in a corner of the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy turns to the sweeper once more, holds out his hand, and mouths:</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Kundun. TENZIN GYATSO  No!</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reverse on Norbu, fading away.</context>
      <utterance>No, Norbu!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>GENERAL CHIANG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He adjusts his new eye glasses.</context>
      <utterance>I am not a foreigner! I refuse to be treated like one. The Dalai Lama is shaken by this violent behavior.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see here thangkas of the Fifth Dalai Lama, the founder of our government. It is tradition at formal meetings for these thangkas to be hung.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL CHIANG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The General sits.</context>
      <utterance>Superstitions. Tibet is part of a modern nation.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL CHIANG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want the songs stopped.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A slight smile.</context>
      <utterance>Songs? What songs?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIME MINISTER LUKHANGWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Street songs about the General. Reference to his gold watch. He is right, they are quite insulting.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have no authority to ban singing in my country.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL CHIANG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must also do something about the public meetings. I see this, memorandum circulating, with Tibetan grievances.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKHANGWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have cracked a man's skull and that crack has not healed. It is too soon to expect him to be your friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL CHIANG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are simply respecting the terms of the Seventeen Point Agreement.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKHANGWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you, General?</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL CHIANG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We want 2,000 more tons of barley distributed.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKHANGWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Impossible! You will bring famine down on the people of Tibet with these insatiable demands! More food, the best land for your soldiers to camp.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL CHIANG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The People's Liberation Army pays for all food and lodging.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKHANGWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men glare at one another.</context>
      <utterance>So far, they do. But, the quantity, it does not exist. You will have to re- evaluate your needs.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL CHIANG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much tea do you drink, Prime Minister?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKHANGWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The General leaps to his feet and is about to strike the Prime Minister. The Dalai Lama runs between then. He holds the General back.</context>
      <utterance>It depends on the quality. And, that it be Indian.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKHANGWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why is it necessary for the Chinese to keep so many soldiers in Lhasa?</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL CHIANG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To protect. To serve you. Chairman Mao wants you to feel that China belongs to you now.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKHANGWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The General backs away and brings himself under control.</context>
      <utterance>Chairman Mao can keep China. Just give us back Tibet.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL CHIANG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Plans for absorbing the Tibetan army into the People's Army will soon be finalized.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKHANGWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will not approve it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL CHIANG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then, we will begin with replacing the Tibetan flag with the flag of the Motherland.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKHANGWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tenzin Gyatso stands between these furious men. He raises a hand, silently requesting peace.</context>
      <utterance>And we will begin with tearing it down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am so sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKHANGWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It must be done. We can no longer meet with the Chinese, they refuse us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I accept your resignations.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOBSANG TASHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you chosen your new Prime Ministers, Holiness?</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There will be no new Prime Ministers.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKHANGWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy affixes his small piece of parchment to the document and makes a mark on it.</context>
      <utterance>You will face great difficulties, Holiness.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They have taken away our silence.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MAO TSE TUNG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tenzin Gyatso quietly sips his tea.</context>
      <utterance>I am so glad that Tibet has come back to the Motherland.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAO TSE TUNG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must inform me at once if any of our people abuse the Tibetans trust and good nature.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have great hopes for the future of our co-operation.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAO TSE TUNG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mao speaks and moves very slowly. He pants and wheezes. He appears to be sick. Tenzin Gyatso takes notes.</context>
      <utterance>It is too early to implement all the clauses of the Seventeen Point Agreement. We will establish a Preparatory Committee for the Autonomous Region of Tibet. The pace of reform must meet with the desires of the Tibetan people. Changes must be made slowly, as you, yourself, judge necessary.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am happy to hear you say this, Chairman Mao. I have created a reform committee to investigate grievances and we have abolished Inherited Tax, and forgiven all money owed the Government by people who are unable to pay.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAO TSE TUNG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tenzin Gyatso writes in his notebook.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Very good. Tibet is a great country. A a wonderful history. Long ago, you even conquered part of China. But now you have fallen behind and we want to help you. In twenty years time you could be ahead of us. Then it will be your turn to help China.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAO TSE TUNG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I have great respect for your Lord Buddha. He was anti-caste. Anti-corruption. Anti-exploitation. For some, politics and religion can mix.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For me, I think such a mix is crucial.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAO TSE TUNG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Dalai Lama accepts.</context>
      <utterance>Have a sweet. Made in my home province. The kind my mother used to make.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"If moral discipline is learned from the beginning, one possesses the root for achieving higher rebirth. A staircase for achieving liberation. An antidote eliminating misery and sorrow. Without discipline there is no method." Pause.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Lord Chamberlain simply looks at the young man. He has nothing to say.</context>
      <utterance>I am thinking of becoming a Communist Party Member. I like what I see of Marxism. It is based on equality and justice for all. I believe Chairman Mao wishes the best for our people. Our path must be non-violence. Co-operation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MAO TSE TUNG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, Dalai Lama, thank you for coming so late.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I leave tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAO TSE TUNG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tenzin Gyatso sits. He takes out his book and pen, ready to take notes.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I am aware. How has your time in China been?</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have been greatly impressed by your accomplishments. Industrial progress. Great efficiency. Your people are capable and courteous.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAO TSE TUNG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have a lot to learn about organization. How to draw out people's opinions. How to make key decisions. Train your young Tibetans. When I make contact with you, I want to reach you through a Tibetan.</utterance>
   <speaker>DALAI LAMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tenzin Gyatso records Mao's words.</context>
      <utterance>Always.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAO TSE TUNG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy cannot look up. He is in shock. We see the last words he writes: "Religion is poison."</context>
      <utterance>Your attitude is good, you know. I understand you well. But you need to learn this: religion is poison. It undermines the race and it retards the progress of the people. Tibet has been poisoned by religion.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAO TSE TUNG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tenzin Gyatso slowly gets to his feet. We must see on his face that he realizes it has all been lies. All the kind words and promises, it must all be lies. He is unable to raise his face to Mao's. All he sees before him are those shinny shoes, those exquisitely shaped, glistening hands.</context>
      <utterance>Well, let me walk you to your car.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The view pulls back. The Lord Chamberlain sits beside the young man.</context>
      <utterance>He will betray us.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBEPIAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you ever doubt it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had relinquished doubt.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The OLD WOMAN says, with tears in her eyes:</context>
      <utterance>Are you happy?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Dalai Lama touches her head. She weeps and clutches his hands. The young man looks up, over her head, to Kyeri, the protectress mountain of this small village. We hear loudspeakers, blaring, in the background - trumpeting propaganda about Chairman Mao and the People's Liberation Army. Tibetan horns blow. It sounds like a warning. CLOSE on a newspaper. It is a Chinese newspaper and the picture on the front page shows a row of severed, Tibetan heads.</context>
      <utterance>I am very happy and prosperous under the guidance of the Chinese Communist Party and chairman Mao Tse Tung. It is a horrifying announcement.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ask them to stop, to lay down their guns.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Dalai Lama rubs his face with his hands.</context>
      <utterance>The Khamba's gun is his most prized possession. I admire them so. They face a modern, well equipped army, and still, they fight.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Land reform is underway in Amdo. The large estates are being confiscated and redistributed. Landlords are being punished.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men are silent. We hear the constant sound of trucks and cars. The Lord Chamberlain is notably pausing.</context>
      <utterance>A beggar can be called a landlord if he disapproves of the Chinese.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have always asked for plain information. Just the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again, silence.</context>
      <utterance>The Communists put their guns in the hands of the Khamba children and force the child to kill the parent. They have dropped bombs on the monastery of Lithang in Kham. It has been destroyed. Women and children, trying to escape from the fighting, have been shot with machine guns, fired from airplanes.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Very difficult.</context>
      <utterance>The pursuit of non-violence.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Non-violence means co-operation when it is possible. Resistance, when it is not.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>GENERAL CHIANG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>We have decided that no drastic changes will take place in Tibet for six years. This should make you happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL CHIANG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Dalai Lama answers.</context>
      <utterance>It seems a revolt has broken out in the east. We have decided that the Tibetan army must be used against the Khamba guerrillas. The General sips.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The General looks up, surprised. It took a great deal of courage for the young man to answer back, so determinedly.</context>
      <utterance>I will not approve it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have bombed on peaceful people.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL CHIANG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We must deal with these reactionaries!</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The General sputters:</context>
      <utterance>No. We are peace loving people. I am afraid we cannot trust you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL CHIANG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now, the boy finds his voice.</context>
      <utterance>We are here to heal the people of Tibet. You need reform. You have no sense of what is good for your people. We are here to liberate you!</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The General starts to speak but Tenzin Gyatso keeps talking.</context>
      <utterance>I burn here, but I am not suppose to let the smoke show. Yes, we need reform. The monasteries. Communications. Schools. But we want change for Tibet, as Tibet needs it, not for China.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The General leaves the room.</context>
      <utterance>Buddha is our physician, General, he will heal us. Comapssion and enlightnement will set us free. You can not liberate me I can only liberate myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They will take Lhasa next.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The people will not allow it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NECHUNG ORACLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is a strange and confusing prophecy.</context>
      <utterance>Where there is no crossing a big river, no fords, no shallows, where the only hope is a boat, and there is no boat... I will put a boat, Kundun. The wish-Fulfilling Jewel will shine from the West.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXT./ INT.  NORBULINKA  DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The wandering deer and peacocks. The fish pond and its inhabitants. Over these pictures we hear words:</context>
      <utterance>A few random views of the Norbulinka:</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode>OC</mode>
      <context>The projection room. The full sheep pen. The parents's home.</context>
      <utterance>"I rejoice in the Awakening of the Buddhas, and also in the spiritual levels of their Sons."</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode>OC</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"And with gladness I rejoice in the ocean of virtue from developing an awakening mind that wishes all beings to be happy..." The Yellow Wall. The Dalai Lama's red room.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode>OC</mode>
      <context>And now, we hear the voices of a great many people, reciting:</context>
      <utterance>"As well as in the deeds that bring them benefit.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode>OC</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"With folded hands I beseech the Buddhas of all directions. To shine the lamp of Dharma For all bewildered in the gloom of misery."</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO AND OTHERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>the Conquerors who wish to pass away, to please remain for countless aeons And not to leave the world in darkness." The Dalai Lama proceeds with the ceremony. He handles and blesses sacred objects, he lifts his bell and dorge. Rice is passed among the people. Rice is thrown. A Tibetan chant is sung. Beside His Holiness is a large, yellow silk pagoda. The view moves inside the pagoda as the chanting continues.</context>
      <utterance>"With folded hands I beseech</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>WOMEN AND MEN</speaker>
      <mode>OC</mode>
      <context>The young man looks around at the peaceful premises. People we know - uembers of the Kashag, attendants, tutors, the Dalai Lama's Mother, sweepers - appear in the garden, one by one, all listening to the sounds of a uob gathering outside the walls of the Norbulinka.</context>
      <utterance>Chinese, GO! Chinese, GO! Chinese, GO!</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMEN AND HEN</speaker>
      <mode>OC</mode>
      <context>Chinese, GO!</context>
      <utterance>Chinese, GO! Chinese, GO!</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The crowd will not disperse until you give your assurance that you will not attend the Chinese festivities. Many who have been invited to dine with the Chinese do not return home.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will not go.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will alert the Chinese delegation. You know, I would never have let you go alone, Kundun.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode>OC</mode>
      <context>The boy fills the seven bowls with water. His Mother lights the butter lamps.</context>
      <utterance>Did you come to tell me we are leaving Lhasa?</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think I must?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He says, softly:</context>
      <utterance>You decide.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tibet has never been part of China. We are different races. We are different cultures. We need change, we know that. But we could do it alone. We were just about to do it alone. The young man fills the last bowl with water.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Far, far away.</context>
      <utterance>I am afraid I will go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are now accused of aiding the rebels. The Chinese said we can expect drastic measures to be taken to crush this revolt.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Lord Chamberlain hurries away.</context>
      <utterance>Arrange for me to speak to the people's leaders.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I am safe.</context>
      <utterance>I fear that there will be great bloodshed if you cannot convince the people to disperse and go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holiness, the Chinese tried to entice you to their garrison with out protection of bodyguard. Even now, they urge you to come to them for safety. They are bringing more troops and guns and artillery into Lhasa. There are three airplanes waiting outside Lhasa. What do they wait for? They are planning to kill the Dalai Lama. Don't you see?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Chinese are planning to attack the crowd and shell the Norbulinka. You are asked to indicate on a map where you will be so that the artillery men will not mistakenly aim at you. The Dalai Lama walks down the outdoor stairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With my people. Right here.</context>
      <utterance>Tell them I will be here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ORACLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Oracle staggers forward, snatches up some paper and a pen and begins to draw a map, a route, out of Lhasa. He keeps repeating:</context>
      <utterance>Go! Go! Tonight!</utterance>
   <speaker>ORACLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE on the map - drawn with a shaking, sweating hand. We see mountains, and a pass, and the names of towns along the way. Tenzin Gyatso rises and goes to the Oracle. He looks down at the map. The Oracle hands the Dalai Lama the map and faints as his frightened attendants rush to loosen the strap of the headdress before the poor man chokes.</context>
      <utterance>Go! Tonight! Go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The young man leaves them.</context>
      <utterance>Wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy returns to the front steps.</context>
      <utterance>I see a safe journey.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The soldiers wait.</context>
      <utterance>I see a safe return.</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tenzin Gyatso places the scroll over one shoulder. A soldier lays a rifle over the other one.</context>
      <utterance>Now. I am ready.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Of course, we see only a fraction of the crowd - angry men and women. A man steps beside His Holiness. Tenzin Gyatso looks up - face to face. It is the Khamba bodyguard, the monk who guarded him so many times. The man with the horrible face.</context>
      <utterance>Move aside, tour of inspection, move aside.</utterance>
   <speaker>KHAMBA BODYGUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Dalai Lama is between the soldiers, shouldering his own gun. The Bodyguard falls in behind. The little group makes its way through the crowd. EXT. TRIBUTARY OF ThE KYICHU RIVER NIGHT In the same place where the little Tenzin Gyatso tentatively tested one rock, the escape party crosses on the slippery, stepping stones.</context>
      <utterance>Move aside, let us through. Move aside!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now, the others do the same. The Lord Chamberlain says:</context>
      <utterance>"Right will be victorious."</utterance>
   <speaker>LORD CHAMBERLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"The Gods will be avenged!"</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a slap of the State Seal of Tibet, this is done. The Lord Chamberlain removes this document and replaces it with another.</context>
      <utterance>I repudiate the Seventeen Point Agreement</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The seal comes down hard once more. It is done.</context>
      <utterance>I constitute the Government of Tibet, the only legal authority in the land.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The young man smiles at the Soldier - a man who looks like the lead soldier come alive.</context>
      <utterance>With all respect, may I ask? Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you see before you is a man. A simple monk.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>Are you the Lord Buddha?</utterance>
   <speaker>TENZIN GYATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I am a reflection, like the moon, on water. When you see me, and I try to be a good man, see yourself</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
