<movie id="337" title="Labor of Love">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>POLICE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get back in your cars and continue with the traffic. There is nothing you can do.  Get back in your cars...</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PIERCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the story?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER DANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's been dead about ten minutes. The jaws are on the way... Ran a license check. Her name is Ellen Parker. Forty-two years old.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PIERCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pierce gestures to a HISPANIC TEENAGER who is cuffed behind his back and being led to a police car.</context>
      <utterance>What about him?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>OFFICER PIERCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit... How old is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER DANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pierce lets it sink in.</context>
      <utterance>Seventeen. It's his grandfather's car. On his way back from drinking with the 'boys'.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PIERCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dana checks the papers in her hand.</context>
      <utterance>Who do we contact for her?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER DANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pierce looks back at what remains of the HONDA PRELUDE. Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Her husband. Maurice Parker. They live in Wynnewood. Married seventeen years.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PIERCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE UP of the hypnotic RED AND BLUE LIGHTS that consume the highway.</context>
      <utterance>There isn't any good left in the world, Dana. Not one damn thing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We finally see the person standing in the REEBOK CROSS TRAINERS... MRS. ELLEN PARKER, a woman in her forties with a heart-warming smile and wise glint in her eyes. The kind of woman that somehow becomes more beautiful with age. She carefully squeezes each loaf. Her hand hovers over the middle loaf.</context>
      <utterance>Very good batch today.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice studies them.</context>
      <utterance>The flowers... they're beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. This takes Ellen by surprise. Maurice catches the expression.</context>
      <utterance>They are... who sent them?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You thought I sent them?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice reaches over and searches the bouquet.</context>
      <utterance>There was no card.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have I forgotten something? Is this a special day?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice pulls out a small bent card from between the stems.</context>
      <utterance>It's just a regular day.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice hands Ellen the card, she looks at it uninterested.</context>
      <utterance>It's from Dan and Kate Wilkins... for dinner last week...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a special day isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm sure it's not Christmas, because you'd be worried about how much money we don't have to spend on each other... I know it's not New Years, because you'd be going on and on about wearing a tuxedo and how much you don't like to dance... and I'm sure it's not our anniversary, because I didn't find an envelope with a hundred dollars cash on my bureau with a note that says, 'Pick out something pretty'... Yes -- Maurice -- I'm virtually certain it's not a special day today. Ellen begins to eat. Maurice stares at her...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>You're mad at me... You were beaming a minute ago, but since I didn't send the flowers... now you're mad at me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen instantly becomes emotional.</context>
      <utterance>Why would I send flowers? What's the occasion.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen returns to eating. Maurice stares at her quietly.</context>
      <utterance>Occasion? Because you love me... That's the occasion.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice comes around the corner -- the boys HAUL ASS out of the store. They're long gone before Maurice reaches the door. He yells after them.</context>
      <utterance>I see that!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen who is sitting in the back room doing the accounts, comes out when she hears the commotion.</context>
      <utterance>I'm getting a Doberman! Two!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice looks up as a young man, early twenties, hurries in. KRIS REDDY walks past Maurice, his black locks of hair peeking out from under his Philadelphia Eagles cap.</context>
      <utterance>You've been saying that for two years; I think they know you're bluffing. Maurice inspects the "Philosophy" section.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lizy Bennett?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kris waves as he removes his jacket. He is wearing a PARKER BOOKS T-shirt underneath. He pins an "Assistant Manager" tag on. Maurice thinks to himself.</context>
      <utterance>Hi Kris.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lizy, Eliza... Elizabeth Bennett...  Pride and Prejudice.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're amazing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It has to be a full character's name.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They called her 'Lizy' in the book...  Sorry I was late. My jeep died on the way over from the paper.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They printed your article on, 'Dry Verses Can Dog Food'... Very enlightening.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kris notices as Maurice goes back to searching the isles.</context>
      <utterance>Pulitzer, here I come.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never have children. If they're not a burden to you, they're a burden to someone else.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kris, go to the pharmacy. Ask Mr. Donnavan to get you a large bottle of Geritol... Tell him, Maurice has officially become a grumpy old man.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd they take this time?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice moves back behind the counter clearly irritated.</context>
      <utterance>Nietzsche!... As if they're going to read Nietzsche.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kris quickly opens his black shoulder bag and pulls out a mini-tape recorder. He talks into it -- dead serious.</context>
      <utterance>They pick on you because they can get a rise out of you... children can sense those things.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLICK. The tape recorder returns to the bag. Ellen stares at him curiously.</context>
      <utterance>Monday -- August 24... Juvenile delinquency -- Are the victims to blame?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen nods with realization. Ellen and Kris turn their attention to Maurice who is mumbling to himself angrily. He looks out the window to the street to see a familiar group of school boys waving at him tauntingly.</context>
      <utterance>Story ideas. I'll forget them otherwise.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen is not listening. She is staring at a young couple two tables over, who can't take their eyes off each other.</context>
      <utterance>Two thousand square feet... We can add a used book section.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice finally notices Ellen is not listening.</context>
      <utterance>Next door is a jewelry store with a full-time security guard... He stands outside all day. Let's see them try and take Nietzsche then...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ellen?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The new store?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey, I told you. If it makes you happy, we should just do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a tremendous amount of work -- moving.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice needed the support. His face brightens.</context>
      <utterance>We can do it together.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>What's your's say?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Love is shown through actions not just words.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that? That's not a fortune... You will be rich... That's a fortune. What you have is a statement.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What it is -- is the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>I don't follow.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice notices the STRAIN IN HER VOICE.</context>
      <utterance>Maurice, what would you do for me? What would you do for our love? I'm not talking about saying, I'm talking about doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this going to be similar to the flower incident?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes people need to see things done for them -- because sooner or later they don't believe the words anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Customers react.</context>
      <utterance>You don't think I love you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to be shown...  Maurice would you do anything for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want from me? Would I swim across an ocean for you?... Would I walk across the United States for you? Yes... Yes I would. You know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No I don't. I don't even know if you'd walk across the street for me. Maurice is getting redder by the second. The entire restaurant hangs on his response...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waiter closest to the table cringes with Maurice's words. Ellen drains of color. She stares at him in complete and utter disbelief. She drills him with this iron glare for an eternity then grabs her purse and heads to the exit. Maurice stares at the table for a moment to gather what's left of his dignity and follows her out. The waiter moves to the table and clears the aftermath. He sees Ellen's fortune crumpled next to her tea cup. He unravels it. The fortune reads...</context>
      <utterance>So what have you done for me that's so earth-shattering?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you polish that thing all the time?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're talking to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice studies the impressive silver medallion.</context>
      <utterance>Why do you polish it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A Book Society Award is a very prestigious thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you polishing it -- in bed -- in your pajamas -- at 11:15 at night? Are you going to show it to someone?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no reason.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice has no answer. He just stares at his hands. ELLEN'S face can be seen under the covers facing away from Maurice. Her eyes are red. The tears roll off her nose and land on the pillow unseen and unheard.</context>
      <utterance>Exactly. No reason. No occasion. It just makes you feel good to do something for it, to express your pride and affection for it some how...  How come you'd do that for a piece of metal and not for me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice smiles warmly at his wife's back before moving to her and hugging her from behind. He whispers in her ear.</context>
      <utterance>Onions?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Why do you put up with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice reaches over and turns off the stove. He then turn Ellen around and kisses her long and hard. Ellen pulls away gently and stares into his eyes. Maurice looks very emotional.</context>
      <utterance>Love... has something to do with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do love you... very, very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Show me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen kisses Maurice and returns to the eggs. Maurice continues to hug her from behind. The MORNING SUN pours into the kitchen covering Ellen and Maurice in a golden bath.</context>
      <utterance>I will -- I promise.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His hand makes a grand swirl pointing to another area. He says the next two words with great awe as if he was saying something holy.</context>
      <utterance>History and the arts will be here...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carl watches curiously as Maurice walks around in a trance. He moves to the bay window that over looks the street.</context>
      <utterance>The Classics...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice's already bright eyes, brighten even more as he spots the security guard strolling up and down the front of the jewelry store. The guard catches his stare and waves. Maurice is aglow... He turns to Carl.</context>
      <utterance>We'll have a hand-painted sign...  ... Parker Books.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carl has to smile -- rarely does he see someone so happy.</context>
      <utterance>This is my dream... it's finally here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish my wife were here. She should see this...  She had a doctors appointment in Blue Bell. That's a one and a half hour drive. Ellen's been going to that doctor since she moved to Pennsylvania...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We could do this tomorrow?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice gathers his strength as he puts pen to paper... He scribbles his signature quickly and let's the pen drop to the table top as if all the energy drained from his body. He looks up to Carl with powerful eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Ellen gave me strict orders to sign it... We invited some friends over -- you see, for a celebration. Carl smiles patiently, he's seen this before.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Every journey begins with one step right?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carl and Maurice shake hands like best friends.</context>
      <utterance>Enjoy your party Mr. Parker... Your new store will be waiting for you Monday morning.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone near the SOFA LAUGHS. A CAR LIGHT DANCES ON THE CURTAINS... Maurice quickly pulls the curtain aside and watches as the car pulls past the house and around the corner. Maurice turns back from the window hiding his concern and without missing a beat...</context>
      <utterance>... So she says the "L" word, after two dates, the "L" word! She says 'Don't you believe in true love? Love that can conquer all?' I say, 'Whoa, hold on. Just so we're clear on things, I think love these days is shit. It don't mean a thing and it don't stand for nothing. Shit.'... You know what she says, 'Fine, but how do you feel about kids?'</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This brings on another ROUND OF LAUGHTER.</context>
      <utterance>It's nice to see you don't have any scars from your divorce.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The room goes SILENT as all eyes fall on Adelle and Gerald.</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>GERALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Maurice, can we go into the dining room?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This hits everyone in the room like a bomb. A dread hangs over every passing second... Gerald crumbles under the moment... Adelle begins to cry.</context>
      <utterance>What's happened to my wife?</utterance>
   <speaker>GERALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some of the crowd reacts. A women covers her mouth. The moment is unbearable.</context>
      <utterance>There was a car accident... Drunk driver.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gerald cracks -- the tears start to flow from his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Please God -- don't do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gerald buries his face into the heels of his palms as if trying to contain an explosion in his head.</context>
      <utterance>Maurice, it was serious... I don't know how to --</utterance>
   <speaker>GERALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice closes his eyes shut tightly... like a child scared of the dark. Adelle blacks out, knocking over the wine chiller on the way to the ground. In less than a minute the room has transformed from a celebration to a mourning. Everyone is frozen staring at Maurice for their cue... A child in her mother's arms begins to cry as if aware of the circumstances. EXTREME CLOSE UP. Maurice opens his eyes slowly. The room stays still as Maurice stares at Ellen's HAT sitting on the piano.</context>
      <utterance>Oh Jesus, please help me... She didn't... Ellen didn't make it... Ellen's dead Maurice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The old woman glances at the empty baby carriage standing next to the bench.</context>
      <utterance>Good morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it a boy or a girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice gestures to the woman and baby who are sitting on a blanket in the grass.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, that's not mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The old woman studies him.</context>
      <utterance>You should. Children are a blessing from God. I have four.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods, "Yes."</context>
      <utterance>Is that your husband?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look so happy -- how long have you been married?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This hits Maurice hard.</context>
      <utterance>Forty-seven years.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This hits Maurice even harder.</context>
      <utterance>Are you married?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The old woman looks down the path for her husband.</context>
      <utterance>Yes... Seventeen years.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did he go?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>He's getting my sweater from the car. I said there was a breeze.  I told him not to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I ask you a question that might sound strange?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The old woman looks at him oddly.</context>
      <utterance>How do you know he loves you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She thinks hard... tough question. No answer for a moment then -- The old woman sees something out of the corner of her eye -- her husband is walking up the path with her white lace sweater over his arm... She smiles as the answer comes to her.</context>
      <utterance>I mean besides... time -- how did you know ten years ago -- twenty years ago?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice sits back -- her answer lingers in the air like a haunting voice. Maurice watches as the old man comes back and drapes his wife with the sweater. The old woman waves as they continue down the path... hand in hand.</context>
      <utterance>Because he shows me... he's not much for words, but he shows me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>DR. ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's the deal Maurice?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pardon?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean why the sudden voluntary visit -- usually it takes gun- point to get you in here...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Routine, I assure you. I just wanted to gage my health. Am I healthy?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes -- you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Royce folds his arms and waits... What's this all about?</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to ask you a question that may sound peculiar.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Royce stares at him suspiciously.</context>
      <utterance>How far could an individual walk if they had no athletic training -- you understand, just an ordinary person?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know what you're getting at.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've seen it before.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're feeling old and you want to start exercising. A lot of men your age feel the need to recapture their youth. Don't feel embarrassed about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should start slow and easy -- fifteen minutes a day.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The doctor is confused again.</context>
      <utterance>No. How far in one attempt -- what's the farthest someone like myself could walk?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just for curiosity sake that's all?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. ROYCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know -- maybe twenty miles... Of course I'm not recommending that... if someone like you had to I mean... that's how far they'd probably get before encountering serious physical walls.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice thinks about it carefully as the doctor returns to the chart.</context>
      <utterance>Twenty miles? I see.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JOSELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Each inch represents 150 miles...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Making the grand total?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice is a bit pale. He follows the yellow highlighted highways winding it's way across the U.S.</context>
      <utterance>Damn baby, relax. I'm getting to it.  From Philadelphia following the route highlighted to Pacifica California -- you're traveling an estimated three thousand two hundred miles...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three thousand miles?... How many times does twenty go into three thousand?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps there's another route?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joselle studies his concerned expression.</context>
      <utterance>This is the route approved by triple A. Even if you followed back roads the entire way, you'd still be looking at roughly the same distance...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry baby, it shouldn't take you more than five days if you just stop to sleep and eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joselle scrunches her face in exaggerated shock and takes a step back to look Maurice up and down.</context>
      <utterance>By car right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOSELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice gives her a sad expression. If she only knew.</context>
      <utterance>How else you gonna get there on the ground?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Why do you want to be a journalist Kris? What sparked your interest?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to reach people. Nobody listens to me. This is my way to reach them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To reach people, you have to feel something first... You write about the wrong things. How can you feel for dog food? The people at the Gazette don't respect it, and neither do you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a ghost town. Nothing ever happens.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Write from your heart. That's why the classics are great.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice looks out the window and picks up an envelope from the coffee table between them. He hands it to Kris.</context>
      <utterance>Why are you telling me this Mr. Parker?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kris opens the envelope and finds money.</context>
      <utterance>Your bus is arriving.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's one month's pay. Kris gets up. A shock of adrenaline hits him.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you firing me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kris grabs his coat, shifting his attention between the window and Maurice?</context>
      <utterance>No. No... I won't be here for a while. The store will be closed in the interim.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You going on a trip Mr. Parker?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kris moves to the door.</context>
      <utterance>California.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>That's cool. What day are you arriving?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kris stops cold. The door to the street half-open.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure -- sometime in January I think.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When are you leaving?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kris is seriously confused now. Maurice decides to end the confusion.</context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm walking there Kris.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Walking where?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kris' jaw hits the floor as the bus pulls to a stop across the street. Kris pulls up his sleeve and glances at his forearm.</context>
      <utterance>California.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hairs on my arm are standing up... Something strange is happening.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kris hesitates before darting out of the store, across the street and into the bus. Kris takes a seat in the back and digs into his bag and pulls out the tape recorder. CLICK.</context>
      <utterance>I always knew you had good instincts...  Goodbye Kris. I'll see you when I get back.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thursday, September 25... 'The Death Of A Spouse - Can It Drive You Insane?'</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>YOUNG MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A young woman emerges from the crowd of browsers. Maurice begins to speak but is caught off guard by YOUNG ELLEN'S beautiful features. Maurice manages a few words.</context>
      <utterance>Three dollars a piece... Two for four dollars! All the classics!</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice looks over to find an enormous man serving food.</context>
      <utterance>My father owns the food stall over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen places the soda she had at her side on the table. Maurice is completely flustered.</context>
      <utterance>You look thirsty.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen places her hand out. Maurice grabs it instinctively and shakes.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, I'm Ellen.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen looks at the full table of books.</context>
      <utterance>Maurice.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice nods "no."</context>
      <utterance>Not doing too good huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen waits for Maurice to say something but nothing comes out.</context>
      <utterance>It'll pick up. I've been coming to these things my whole life... people don't want to carry things as they walk around... you'll sell as the fair starts to end...</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't talk much do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen's father BELLOWS FOR HER OVER THE CROWD. Maurice jumps at the sound.</context>
      <utterance>I read a lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen disappears into a sea of people. Maurice stands in awe for a second before snapping out. He shakes his head to himself.</context>
      <utterance>I better go...  ... Come over if you get hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I read a lot?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Maurice eyes Ellen's dad who throws him deadly glances. Maurice is very intimidated. He whispers to her.</context>
      <utterance>Are you trying to tell me something?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Walk with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like to take walks?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen looks at him carefully... looks right through him.</context>
      <utterance>No. But I want to take a walk with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just said something very sweet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen looks out onto the water.</context>
      <utterance>What are you thinking?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's one of those thoughts you keep to yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Please tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice is bright red. Ellen giggles at his shyness. Maurice gathers his strength and looks her straight in the eyes. Maurice leans forward and kisses her softly.</context>
      <utterance>I was just thinking that if we actually became a couple -- this was a beautiful place to begin things.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Phileas Fogg?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... Hello Kris.</context>
      <utterance>... Round The World In Eighty Days.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're amazing... What are you doing Mr. Parker?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you. Beat. Cars HONK as they pull by the slow duo.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're walking to California?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pacifica, California -- it's a coastal city.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kris looks around to see if anyone else sees the lunacy in this moment.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, a coastal city. That's good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ellen told me that she didn't know if I loved her.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She knew you loved her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>She wasn't certain... I never really showed her.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm really lost. What does this have to do with walking?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice looks to Kris rolling along beside him. He sees the worried expression on his face.</context>
      <utterance>I said, 'I would do anything for her'... and she didn't believe me. I said, 'I'd walk across the country for her'... she didn't believe me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to show her how much I love her Kris.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why know?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Because I should have shown her before... Everyday, I should have shown her.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pacifica, California... that's a long ways away.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kris tries to act calm, but it doesn't last long.</context>
      <utterance>So I've been informed.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice takes his time with the response. Kris waves more cars to pass them.</context>
      <utterance>Shit Mr. Parker. You can't walk across the United States -- it's over three thousand miles.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ellen got up every morning and went to the corner store to get me my bread for breakfast... Everyday. Now that's about a quarter mile each way... 17 years... that comes to about three thousand miles...  And you know what Kris?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What Mr. Parker?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice picks up speed -- surer with every step... Kris slows the jeep to a stop and reaches into his bag. The mini tape recorder goes on with a CLICK.</context>
      <utterance>She never ate a slice.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kris watches through the windshield as Mr. Parker disappears down Route 32.</context>
      <utterance>Thursday, September 26... 'The Question We Never Ask - What Would We Do For Love?'</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gerald looks on with an assuring smile.</context>
      <utterance>Something's wrong. I'm worried.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He probably just went somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>GERALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>For a walk. I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hates walking.</context>
      <utterance>Uncle Maurice? Are you kidding?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pool times are 11 am to 5 pm, there's cable in every room with two premium channels. HBO and CINEMAX. Pay Per View Channels can be --</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>that's all.</context>
      <utterance>I need a bed and I need Tylenol...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice stares at him with exhausted eyes.</context>
      <utterance>The room comes with two twin Sealy Posturepedics... but the Tylenol will be extra.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone's got a hot story.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kris Reddy keeps typing. He spits out the answer after a few seconds.</context>
      <utterance>What time did you get in?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five... Couldn't sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this one about Kris? 'Blinds or Curtains - The Eternal Question?'</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank and Seth crack up laughing. Frank reaches for the printouts... Kris immediately covers them with his hand. He stares up with a smile.</context>
      <utterance>No, no... 'Boxers Verses Tight Undies - The Battle Continues.'</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Read about it on Sunday.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GERALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares silently at the paper laid out on the table. The headline beams at her:</context>
      <utterance>Adelle... Maurice is in the paper.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She STORMS off into the kitchen with the golden pancakes. Gerald looks down at his empty plate longingly.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>DALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What would you like us to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put out a P.B.S.... Or whatever it's called.</utterance>
   <speaker>DALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A.P.B.... He isn't breaking any law. He's a grown man... He can crawl on his hands and knees to China if that's what he wants to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sergeant, I'm a psychologist and I know the difference between normal whims people have and actions that clearly display psychological problems... My uncle lost his wife and it devastated him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're very sorry about that. Some of our men were on the scene of the accident.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think my uncle is suffering from a condition called Mania which is linked with depression. It is a time when an individual will act over-confident, and will act out impractical, grandiose plans. Sometimes these plans can be dangerous.</utterance>
   <speaker>DALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long does this... Mania last?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dally digests this information.</context>
      <utterance>A couple days to a few months if untreated.</utterance>
   <speaker>DALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I'll see if anyone has spotted him recently. If I get any information, I'll call you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adelle looks very emotional... on the verge of tears.</context>
      <utterance>Don't wait by the phone. If he's really been walking this whole time, he's out of our jurisdiction...</utterance>
   <speaker>DALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry he'll be back. He's in his forties. He's had no physical training... He'll be back by the end of the week.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice realizes they're talking to him.</context>
      <utterance>Nice sneaks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They are?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys keep walking. Maurice looks down at his sneakers with new-found pride. After a while, Maurice's attention switches back to the cars. One car in question catches Maurice's eye. A woman consoles a small child who doesn't want to leave the car. She wipes his tiny tears with her hand and hugs him tenderly. The little boy's head cradled in her arms.</context>
      <utterance>Sure man, High-Top Nike Cross Trainers with heel supports and air cushioned soles -- They're nasty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought we both wanted the same things.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've changed my mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Ellen takes a seat on the only sofa.</context>
      <utterance>You can't change your mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want children.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've just decided, is that right?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Young Maurice is visibly upset.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ellen, there are two kinds of people in the world --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please not, 'The two kinds of people' speech.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... People that were made to be parents, and people who were not made to be parents... My parents, were people who were not made to be parents but had kids anyway. I don't want us to be that way Ellen.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can change.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But you love me anyway.</context>
      <utterance>Face it Ellen, I'm not the type of person who reads bedtime stories.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen fiddles with her dress. She bites her bottom lip as she tries not to cry.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be so sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice lifts her chin with his hand gently. She blinks her eyes and a tear rolls down her cheek. He takes a deep breath.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing will happen to us. It's a bleak picture, I know, but we're going to be together till were old and grey and you don't remember my name anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen brightens up immediately.</context>
      <utterance>Let me think about it okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen gives her patented glowing smile. She hugs him with all her strength. She whispers in his ear.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not saying anytime soon. I'm just saying that maybe we can consider it down the road sometime.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you Maurice Parker.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Do you mind ten miles?</context>
      <utterance>I can show you the main roads, but that'll add ten miles to your trip.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mind.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Denny gives Maurice a greasy curious look. He squints his glazed eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Are you and your friends planning on driving soon?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice, doesn't look scared, in fact he looks angered.</context>
      <utterance>Yes we are. Who the fuck are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. Then everyone in the group BURSTS OUT IN DRUNKEN</context>
      <utterance>You don't know me from Adam, but I want you to do something for me. I want you to wait until you sobered up before you get behind the wheel. I know this is out of the ordinary, but one man to another, would you do me that favor?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you a preacher?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Denny's face goes blank. No emotion. His steady gaze almost terrifying.</context>
      <utterance>No, I just don't want anybody dying because I didn't say something when I had the chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice looks around at the hostile faces and decides on a retreat. Denny watches Maurice with predatory eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I'll drive my truck shit-faced if I want to. You better turn around and walk away preacher. You don't know who you're talking to.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Indiana -- nothing's going to happen to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men walk up to Maurice.</context>
      <utterance>You need a ride, Preacher?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A tall lanky gentleman gestures to Maurice's shoulder bag with his beer can. Some beer sprays Maurice's feet with the gesture.</context>
      <utterance>No thank you I'll walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you coming from?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look gentlemen, I'm late, I need to --</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Denny gives Maurice that inhuman stare. Maurice is clearly frightened.</context>
      <utterance>I've been thinking -- who the hell is this preacher guy? Coming up to me and my friends? Looking like he wanted to kick my ass for drinking?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice is frozen.</context>
      <utterance>Then I figured it. You're angry. You lost somebody, because some asshole was drinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice looks up for a millisecond. Denny doesn't miss it.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe you lost a son? A sister? A wife?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A wife?... Did someone piss drunk run into your wife? Crushed her like a bug. Snapped her bones?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice is red with anger. Denny loves it.</context>
      <utterance>That's enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh the preacher's getting angry again...  Tell me something. Did she die instantly or did she feel every torn muscle and shattered bone? Were you there to help her? Or were you safe at home when the windshield sliced into her face --</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice swings. Denny easily avoids it. Maurice doesn't see the first BLOW COMING, IT HITS HIM IN THE CHEST -- Maurice gasps for air as he buckles to the dirt. Hands grab -- restrain. A POWERFUL KICK IN THE RIBS -- ANOTHER... LAUGHTER... ANOTHER SET OF VICIOUS KICKS... The road and forest begin to spin... A PAINFUL SLASH ACROSS HIS FACE... Maurice prepares for the next blow... it never comes. RED AND BLUE lights swirl... Maurice looks up, barely focusing -- a man leans over a car door... The image becomes clearer -- a POLICEMAN stands poised -- gun aimed directly at the men hovering over him.</context>
      <utterance>I'll kill you!</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Step away from him now!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OFFICER GREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grey reads Maurice's license.</context>
      <utterance>Need an I.D. check on a Maurice A. Parker...</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER GREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Driver's number 22 184 877...  He was assaulted by a group of men just outside Elkhart, Indiana...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gesturing to a young officer at another desk to come over. Dally, cups the phone.</context>
      <utterance>How is he?... That's good.</utterance>
   <speaker>DALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call Adelle Matlin... tell her we found her uncle.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>GREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice slowly gets up. Adelle is in shock as she looks at the stranger before her. Maurice stands in a 'COLTS' football T-shirt, faded jeans and sneakers. His left cheek is black and blue, and his arm and side are bandaged.</context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Matlin... good morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uncle Maurice, you're wearing sneakers?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adelle wasn't sure what that meant. She shakes it off and hugs Maurice. She is visibly relieved to have him in her arms.</context>
      <utterance>High-top Nike Cross-Trainers with heel support and air-cushioned soles. They're nasty.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adelle notices the ROSE in Grey's hand. Grey catches her glance.</context>
      <utterance>My shift ended an hour ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's for my wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grey looks to Maurice -- they exchange a knowing smile.</context>
      <utterance>What's the occasion?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adelle notices the WINK exchanged between Grey and Maurice.</context>
      <utterance>No occasion.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can use the conference room, if you want to talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That won't be necessary.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>We can talk on the way back -- I rented a car.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adelle gives Maurice an angry glare -- Maurice holds his ground.</context>
      <utterance>It'll be kind of hard to talk, since you'll be in the car and I won't.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The conference room is down the hall on your right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And your store? What about your new store? What about all your dreams?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have new dreams now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't accept that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe one day -- after you've been married twenty years you'll understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uncle Maurice -- I spent all our frequent flyer miles on a one way ticket here... I have a rented car outside, just listen to me.  Come back with me now, and if you still want to do something like this in a year -- maybe we'll plan a car trip across the country -- Gerald and I will come along --</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to walk -- by myself -- all the way -- every inch.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's what she asked for... It's what I'm going to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was being symbolic. What if she asked you to fly to the moon?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adelle changes gears. She takes a seat next to Maurice and studies his legs and tired face carefully before uttering the words.</context>
      <utterance>You'd be visiting me at Nasa.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if you don't make it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you really want to do this... plan it out. Rest up. Train for it. Build up your body. Plan every stop along the way. How much money? Time? Really do it properly. This is all so -- by the seat of your pants.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No it's not.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Why did you take the back roads here? They're not safe. You'd know that if you'd planned.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've all ready gone six hundred miles... I can't do it again.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice is stumped. He looks unsure. He instantly looks on the verge of tears.</context>
      <utterance>If you can't redo these six hundred miles when you're rested and ready, how are you possible going to walk another two thousand-five hundred miles in your present condition?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing's going to happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice stares down at the table -- the life draining from him with every word she says.</context>
      <utterance>Uncle, the way I was told, if that police car didn't happen down that road, you would be dead right now. That guy Denny, had jumped bail in another state, he's dangerous... They'll be other Dennys, if you don't plan.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ellen, deserves you to do this right. Really make it -- if you're going to do it. She deserves it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares at Maurice covered in a blanket with his back to her... an unresponsive blob.</context>
      <utterance>You want something to eat?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adelle puts the Celica into drive and pulls out onto the highway.</context>
      <utterance>I know you're feeling a lot of emotions right now. It's okay to be mad. It's okay to feel helpless. It's part of the healing process. I understand. I do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adelle and Gerald move to the back door of the Celica. They open it and stare at Maurice covered by the blanket. Adelle shakes the blanket.</context>
      <utterance>He was exhausted -- slept the whole way.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adelle shakes Maurice, who stirs a little as he wakes. His feet slide out from under the blanket -- Adelle stares curiously at the ARMY COMBAT BOOTS that dangle out.</context>
      <utterance>Uncle Maurice we're home... Uncle Maurice.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adelle pulls aside the covers... THE HOMELESS MAN, from the gas station, sits up. ADELLE'S SHRILL SCREAM BLASTS THROUGH THE AIR. Gerald and Adelle stumble back as the large, bearded man struggles out of the car and looks around the quiet neighborhood.</context>
      <utterance>Uncle Maurice?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOMELESS MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The homeless man raises his hand. He holds up MAURICE'S WELL POLISHED BOOK SOCIETY MEDALLION and kisses it lovingly. Adelle and Gerald stare back speechless.</context>
      <utterance>So this is the City of Brotherly Love.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice looks closer -- and notices it's wings. The feathers bend back -- a dark area at the center.</context>
      <utterance>Ellen would have loved you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice watches the bird hop around the branch -- unable to fly.</context>
      <utterance>How did that happen?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It must've hit the window... I think its neck is broken.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen finds an eye dropper from the table and fills it with water -- she lets a few drops fall into the birds mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Don't bring it in here -- it probably has all kinds of diseases.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Let the poor thing go quietly.</context>
      <utterance>It isn't going to make it Ellen.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her delicate hand rubs the bird's stomach.</context>
      <utterance>It'll make it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KITCHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maurice is reading his paper.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice looks through the window to see Ellen waving to him frantically.</context>
      <utterance>Maurice! Maurice! Come out here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen hugs Maurice.</context>
      <utterance>I don't believe it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Young Maurice and Ellen watch the bird soar into the blue sky.</context>
      <utterance>All he needed was love. Once you have that, you can do anything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice carries the bird back to the trees. He lays it back on the branch. He stares at it's beautiful coat with a smile.</context>
      <utterance>You'll be all right. A couple days and you'll be up there again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ellen would have loved you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gerald is cooking. He gently flips the chicken breast in a butter and garlic sauce.</context>
      <utterance>Yes I understand, it does sound humorous, but this is a very serious situation.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This smells good.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why am I such an authority?</utterance>
   <speaker>GERALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here comes the resume.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gerald brings the sizzling pan over and divides the steaming dish into both plates.</context>
      <utterance>I received my B.S. from the University of Pennsylvania, my P.H.D. from Bryn Mawr College. I worked three years at the Boston University School of Medicine, during which time I had articles printed in the "Journal of Educational Psychology", "American Journal of Psychology", "Psychology Review" and "Science"... So I think it's safe to say my opinion is valid.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gerald quickly scoops some rice onto both plates. His mouth is watering as he goes for the utensils. Adelle abruptly stands at her place.</context>
      <utterance>Look, please find him for me... Officer, I tried... but I brought back the wrong person.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gerald gets into his seat at the table just in time to see Adelle angrily hang up the phone. She stares off into space before unconsciously cleaning the table. Adelle picks up both plates of food...</context>
      <utterance>Stop laughing!</utterance>
   <speaker>GERALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gerald's heart sinks as Adelle pops open the trash can with a tap of her foot and dumps the picture perfect meal into the garbage. She goes to the sink and rinses the plates completely preoccupied with her thoughts. She mumbles to herself as she shuts off the water.</context>
      <utterance>Adelle --</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adelle storms out of the kitchen. Gerald sits at the empty table with a fork in his hands. He shakes his head in disbelief.</context>
      <utterance>He says he admires him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cars IMPACT with a sickening CRUNCH -- BACK TO REAL TIME: The Firebird spins into a guardrail, breaking through it and coming to a stop in a bank of snow. The Volvo isn't so lucky. It flips from the impact... sliding on its roof, driving through the snow, down the road... It comes to a rest a hundred feet away. SILENCE. STILLNESS. The entire event took only seconds. Maurice runs frantically after the Volvo. The windows are SHATTERED. Snow has packed into the over-turned car. No one can be seen inside the vehicle. Maurice kneels down and punctures the wall of snow with his hand. His arm disappears up to the shoulder. His face grimacing with the strain. His arm comes out slowly... A few MUFFLED SOBS ARE HEARD BEFORE the little girl breaks through the wall of snow and slides out of the window. She lets out a DESPERATE GASP for air as Maurice pulls her out by the wrist. Maurice clears her mouth and face and watches as she coughs.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice lays her gently against a snow bank, before moving to the other side of the car.</context>
      <utterance>It's okay. It's all over.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Maurice looks up to see the driver of the Firebird walking towards him. He looks dazed. Maurice doesn't waste another second and plunges his arm in the snow... deeper than before. His cheek pressed against the snow, almost laying flat on the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Is she okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice, out of breath, clears the woman's face and mouth -- no movement. No sound.</context>
      <utterance>It wasn't my fault. It wasn't my fault.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice holds her nose and breaths into her mouth...</context>
      <utterance>Come on... please...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She doesn't respond.</context>
      <utterance>Please...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>OUTSIDE THE CAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OFFICER HANSEN AND OFFICER TANDY converse.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's his story?</utterance>
   <speaker>TANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His name is Maurice. He's dancing around everything else.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Red flag, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hansen looks in at the drawn, exhausted face of Maurice through the window. Hansen opens the back door.</context>
      <utterance>If he's in trouble with the law -- fine. Not our problem. He yanked two people from a car wreck, let's give him some space.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maurice, you need anything? Which way were you headed? We can drive you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hansen throws a sharp glance to Tandy. Hansen turns back to Maurice.</context>
      <utterance>No thank you officer. I'll walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice mulls this offer.</context>
      <utterance>Grub? Food? How about food? Our dime at the local diner...</utterance>
   <speaker>HANSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Come on man, you're a hero. In Nebraska we don't let hero's walk around with empty stomachs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... I need to be brought back here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Deal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>HANSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice takes a couple strained breaths.</context>
      <utterance>You look like shit Maurice.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Getting old.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>How long have you been footing it Maurice?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice gets up and heads to the bathroom. Hansen and Tandy stare at Maurice's shoulder bag laying on his seat.</context>
      <utterance>Too long...  Excuse me gentlemen.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Red flags man.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not our problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why so vague? Why so evasive? He could be somebody hot.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not our problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's going to look beautiful when he turns out to be that animal who paid a visit to the Steadman's house.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This guy's not a murderer.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That makes Tandy think.</context>
      <utterance>If he is, half the town has seen us take him out for dinner like a couple of jack-asses.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tandy looks to the men's bathroom door.</context>
      <utterance>If he's clean, he'll never know about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hansen instantly reaches over and begins rummaging through the shoulder bag. Hansen pulls out a little folder. He opens the folder to reveal an old certificate. Hansen shows Tandy the worn piece of paper.</context>
      <utterance>Do it quick.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A marriage certificate? Who the hell carries their marriage certificate around?</utterance>
   <speaker>TANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hansen returns the certificate and folder to the bag and leaves the booth quickly.</context>
      <utterance>Maurice and Ellen Parker... it was issued in Philly... Mr. Maurice Parker has come a long way from home. Why?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Line one Sarg.</utterance>
   <speaker>DALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dally zips his coat.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the Nebraska state police.</utterance>
   <speaker>DALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nebraska?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dally freezes. He shakes his head as he unzips his jacket.</context>
      <utterance>You know somebody named -- Maurice Parker?</utterance>
   <speaker>DALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dally grabs the phone.</context>
      <utterance>That son of a bitch made it to Nebraska.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>OFFICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Michelle scribbles down notes.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.B./NEBRASKA POLICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kris stands, jaw hanging wide open.</context>
      <utterance>... He saved a little girl, and her mother. Pulled them right out of the car...</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michelle checks her notes.</context>
      <utterance>Where is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kris practically falls over. Michelle scribbles down more quotes.</context>
      <utterance>Umm, Elm Creek, Nebraska.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This story is big huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mammoth.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>The Gazette's small huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you saying? This story is too big for this paper?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Umm, no. It's just that --</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kris' mind is racing as the C.B. conversation continues.</context>
      <utterance>God damn, you're right... You don't say much Michelle, but what you say is golden.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HANSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tandy winks at Maurice with a smile.</context>
      <utterance>I was expecting a call. Hansen moves to the phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whipped.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode>ON PHONE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... I'm on first name basis with half the city of Philadelphia... Hansen, apparently this guy Parker lost his wife and went a little fruity. I spoke with his niece, Adelle Matlin and she says to restrain him. That he's dangerous to himself. She says to call when we have him in the station.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good work.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hansen and Tandy exchange looks.</context>
      <utterance>Where are you taking me?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to drop off Tandy at the station and then drop you back.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all right isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hansen looks back to the road. The drive continues in silence. Tandy checks his watch just when a CLICK -- A HARD WIND -- AND A METALLIC SLAM in quick succession shakes the car.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tandy looks back -- Maurice is GONE. The back seat empty. Tandy stares out the blackness of the back window.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit! He jumped!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jumped where?</utterance>
   <speaker>TANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out of the car. He jumped out of the god damn car!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did they ask?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I had seen you. By the way I'm sorry about your wife. They told me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you... I'm sorry you had to lie. It must have been difficult.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is the father's own room. Very sparse as one would expect. He moves to his bureau and retrieves some pills.</context>
      <utterance>I asked the officers if you had committed some crime... If they had said 'yes', you would be speaking with them right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice follows the father's instructions and tightens the blanket around his shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>Take these, and if you're up to it, try to explain how it is you came to be sitting here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>I'm walking for my wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To where?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pacifica, California.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From where?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. The father nods as if this is not shocking news.</context>
      <utterance>I see.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you believe a person's soul lives on after their death?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Most certainly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that that soul takes part of the person they were on this earth with them.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a reasonable assumption.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want my wife's soul having any doubts.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doubts? About what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The father nods with understanding as if everything became very clear with that statement.</context>
      <utterance>About my love for her.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to prove anything to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The father studies this stranger before him with great admiration.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not proving to her. I'm showing her. And I know I don't have to. I want to. I've realized, love is about giving. I'm alive, I can still give to her. I want to give her everything I can.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice struggles with the last words. He slumps back -- physically drained. The father gets up and takes the empty glass of water from Maurice's hands.</context>
      <utterance>There are some people, including those officers, that are trying to stop me. They mean well. But they don't understand. I wouldn't either if I were them.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The father moves for the curtain.</context>
      <utterance>I want you to stay here a few days until you're better. You're no use to your wife in this condition.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The father turns and smiles warmly.</context>
      <utterance>You think I'm crazy too.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice's eyes well up instantly.</context>
      <utterance>I have spent my life dedicated to love. Love of God. Love of humanity. And here you are living through love. Bathing in it. Using its strength, its magic, its ability to overcome any barrier... If you are crazy, I hope my insanity is not far off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Maurice looks down to find an adorable little boy, black hair, big eyes and an even bigger grin. This is three year old ISAAC CALDWELL.</context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISAAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Isaac... I'm three.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Isaac thinks.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Maurice Parker... I'm much older than three. Are your parents home?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISAAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what, I can play baseball with my brothers when I'm bigger.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that right?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISAAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what... I'm just little now, but I'll be big soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll probably be bigger than your brothers.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISAAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice looks up as MRS. CALDWELL comes to the door.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah! Isaac is happy with this thought.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you talking to Isaac? Mrs. Caldwell stops as she stares at Maurice.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Caldwell doesn't listen, but instead yells behind the door.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, I'm Maurice Parker. I'm just passing through and I need to conserve what little funds I have... I need some food and a roof to sleep under for one night... Now I don't look like much, but if there are any things that need to get done around the house --</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice looks at her oddly. MR. CALDWELL comes to the door; his face lights up.</context>
      <utterance>Dave... you're not going to believe who's here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Caldwell is completely floored. So, for that matter is Maurice. Mr. Caldwell puts out his hand with awe.</context>
      <utterance>This is Maurice Parker -- the one walking for his wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If that ain't fate?... Hi, I'm Dave Caldwell. I do the copy for the anchor on the evening news down here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evening News?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice is truly surprised.</context>
      <utterance>We did a piece after your story ran in the New York Times.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Caldwell ushers Maurice in the doorway by the elbow.</context>
      <utterance>New York Times?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone said they spotted you in town... Mr. Parker, you're a celebrity.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you were asleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISAAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Isaac walks silently to Maurice... Tip-toeing all the way.</context>
      <utterance>You know what... I remembered you were here and I woke up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your parents would want you to be in bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISAAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You tell stories?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Too late. Isaac climbs up into Maurice's lap with great effort. Maurice looks down at Isaac who waits patiently for him to begin.</context>
      <utterance>Oh no... I'm not good at that. Very bad in fact...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Isaac waits.</context>
      <utterance>I would be exceedingly boring.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Isaac -- still waiting.</context>
      <utterance>I don't do these type of things.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Isaac gets in position, cradled in Maurice's arms. Maurice searches for something to say.</context>
      <utterance>See there are two kinds of people in this world.  ... Just a short one okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was a boy named Isaac who wanted to play baseball, but he was too small and no one would let him play... but he kept practicing by himself -- waiting... He went to every game and sat in the stands with his glove.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISAAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what... maybe I ran onto the field and hit a home run.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Isaac points to Maurice.</context>
      <utterance>Who's telling this story?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Isaac didn't understand that last part.</context>
      <utterance>Good, now the team had this great big player -- Big Billy. He was the best. He had them in the World Super-Bowl-Championship of little kids baseball. But right before the game, the second best player on the team was suspended because he played a prank on a nice man who owned a book store... When that boy grew up he was convicted on burglary charges and spent fifteen years in prison -- where he belongs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyway, Big Billy needed another player so he yelled into the stands. 'Who can play baseball?' And there was a little voice that yelled out, 'Me, I can play.' Everyone turned to see a little boy standing with a glove.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISAAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. But everyone saw how small Isaac was and laughed... but not Big Billy. He stared at Isaac carefully and then told him to join the game. It came to the end of the game. It was the eleventh or twelfth inning or whatever is the last inning of a game...</utterance>
   <speaker>ISAAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay nine. Big Billy's team was losing and he was on base. That's when Isaac came up. He could barely hold the bat... Big Billy winked at Isaac... The ball was pitched -- Isaac hit the ball hard. It soared up and out over the stadium. Everyone cheered. Isaac hit a home run and won the game. After the game, Isaac asked Big Billy why he let he play. Big Billy smiled and said, I wasn't always Big Billy, I was Little Billy first... Isaac and Big Billy went off after the game and read a classic book together. The end.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISAAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice has to smile as Isaac looks up anxiously.</context>
      <utterance>You know what -- that was a really good story... Tell it again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WE BACK OUT as Maurice rocks back and forth in his chair. Isaac falling asleep in his arms.</context>
      <utterance>There was a boy named Isaac who liked to play baseball...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MR. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice looks down at his beat-up Seiko.</context>
      <utterance>That's a nice watch.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've always wanted a watch like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice watches him suspiciously as he pulls out an envelope from his jacket pocket.</context>
      <utterance>No. I won't take it unless I pay for it... Let's see, that's a pretty nice watch -- I can see that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice is handed the envelope. He opens it to find a thick</context>
      <utterance>Let's say I give you what's in this envelope for that beautiful watch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MR. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I really want that watch.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice stares into the envelope emotionally and hands over the watch tentatively.</context>
      <utterance>This is my only chance to get a watch like that. It would mean a lot to me and my family. Please take it. It really isn't that much.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Caldwell straps on the watch and then hugs Maurice. The rest of the family say their good-byes. Isaac won't let go of Maurice's hand as he walks out into the street.</context>
      <utterance>This is a loan.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. CALDWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Isaac just holds on tighter. After Maurice and Isaac have walked a few steps out into the street, Maurice kneels down.</context>
      <utterance>Isaac, come back here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Isaac's bottom lip protrudes as he tries not to cry. Maurice has to hold back a few tears himself. He hugs Isaac tightly.</context>
      <utterance>I have to go now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice stares at his rented shoes.</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong? They said something was wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen moves to him and kneels before him. She lifts his chin.</context>
      <utterance>I'm fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice moves his gaze from her to the half open door.</context>
      <utterance>Everyone's here. Everything looks beautiful. They even got the white dove I wanted for the cake -- so what's wrong? What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen looks back.</context>
      <utterance>It's him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your father?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's plastered.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's okay -- really it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice looks like he may cry.</context>
      <utterance>No it's not. He should be here with me now, not trying to find some fucking bottle of Johnny Walker. He's never been there for me. I've always been alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen takes both his hands and squeezes them between hers.</context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid Ellen... I'm scared of being alone again. What if one day you realize how boring I am? What if one day you realize you're not happy?  I could have been alone before, but now you've changed things. I can't be alone anymore Ellen. I'm scared what's going to happen to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The day I met you, I gave you my heart. Today, I give you my soul. Where ever you are, where ever you go, I will be with you. Maurice Parker, I promise --  I promise, you will never be alone again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kris hangs up.</context>
      <utterance>-- Come on Pete, this is important, this is racism in our backyard... Aw, that's bull... just think about it, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kris notices Michelle's familiar bright red face.</context>
      <utterance>They're pushing my Jewish temple vandalism story to the Metro section...</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michelle is completely flustered as usual.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Michelle, breathe... that's it, what is it, talk to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kris studies the fax before jumping up from his desk and moving to the wall. An enormous U.S. MAP covers three quarters of the wall. RED TACKS mark a trail across the United States, beginning with Philadelphia. Kris puts a red tack at the top right corner of Utah. Kris notices through the open officer door that Frank and Seth are listening in. Kris nods to Michelle. Who immediately shuts the door on their view. Kris waves bye before it closes.</context>
      <utterance>Umm, Coalville Utah.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kris paces the room -- charged with excitement -- eyes occasionally stopping on the map. Michelle watches Kris' animated expressions.</context>
      <utterance>He's taking highway 80 all the way.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michelle enjoys watching Kris when he's like this.</context>
      <utterance>You know what this is, don't you? It's a miracle. Not like... 'It was a miracle little Johnny passed his math test.' No! This is a real miracle... Turning water to wine kind of miracle. People should know about this, everyone, every single person... It's time for a blitz. Let's see what kind of TV interest we can generate.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Umm, he's going to make it isn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kris studies the map.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But he hasn't hit the toughest miles yet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TV ANCHOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gerald sighs. He puts the sandwich on the plate and hands it to his left -- obediently. PAN TO LEFT to find Adelle wide awake now. She glares at the TV screen silently as she takes the sandwich and dumps it in the waste basket releasing some of her frustration. A COMPUTER MAP OF THE U.S. trails Maurice's walk on the screen.</context>
      <utterance>What would you do for love? This is the question Americans are starting to ask themselves. The incredible tale of Maurice Parker's walk across the country has caught the imaginations of young and old.</utterance>
   <speaker>TV ANCHOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At 44, this bookstore owner from Wynnewood Pennsylvania has tallied an estimated 2,400 miles. His latest appearance in Coalville Utah brought the spotlight of the country to that small town.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coalville Utah?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TV ANCHOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever has carried Mr. Parker through snow and rain and thousands of miles of this countryside, will have to carry him through the most dangerous part of his trek... The three hundred miles through the sweltering roads of Nevada...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's over Ellen... I failed you again. Maurice looks down the road at the cloud of dust growing larger.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cloud is now clearly a car... Maurice stares up into the sky again... The tears racing the sweat down his cheeks. Maurice YELLS TO THE HEAVENS.</context>
      <utterance>I tried Ellen, I really tried... I don't have the strength.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice's is interrupted by A SLIGHT RUSTLING BEHIND HIS HEAD. Maurice turns and looks through his tears... There, a few feet from him, perched quietly and majestically on the guardrail is a GOLDEN EAGLE. It stands two and half feet tall. It spreads it's great wings. The feathers expand like a blanket, spanning six feet, and throwing a gentle shade on Maurice's face. Maurice is frozen in wonder. The MAGIC of the moment glows in his eyes. Maurice's face gains life... The dark feathered eagle stands like a god before Maurice. The moment is breathtaking.</context>
      <utterance>You said I would never be alone!... You promised...  ... You promised.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice's face filled with strength. He grins through the pain.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, man are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you doing out here? You need a ride somewhere?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The driver is concerned. He opens the driver door.</context>
      <utterance>No thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>You by yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This pacifies the driver somewhat. He nods and gets in the car. Maurice watches as the car pulls away. He turns back to the guardrail -- the eagle is gone. Maurice looks up into the sky. The Golden Eagle is flying overhead... a tiny dot against the blazing sun. Maurice struggles to his feet using the guardrail as support. Maurice takes his first step...</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JANIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Janis and Ammie stare to the street where a sunburnt MAURICE staggers in a daze.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. What's the matter with him?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Maurice turns his head to the side. A pretty woman in her late twenties, with LARGE LOCKS OF BROWN HAIR smiles back. This is STEPHANIE.</context>
      <utterance>Good morning Mr. Parker.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are a lot of people worried about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where am I?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In a hospital.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie understands his worry.</context>
      <utterance>Which hospital? Did you take me back?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice closes his eyes in relief.</context>
      <utterance>You are in St. Vincent's Hospital in Roseville California. You've been here three days.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank God.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice looks across to ADELLE AND GERALD.</context>
      <utterance>I can't believe you're here. I'm touched.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you two planning kids?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe later.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adelle and Gerald are in shock. Maurice forks another fish stick with a smile.</context>
      <utterance>You should definitely have children. They're really special.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think you realize how serious this is Uncle.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DR. RAY, who has been standing by the window listening, steps forward.</context>
      <utterance>How serious is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice gives a comforting smile to Adelle.</context>
      <utterance>You have two broken ribs, a punctured spleen and Acute Rheumatoid Arthritis.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The normal amount of build up in your arteries has been aggravated by over exertion. This is called, "Claudication," As a result, there isn't enough circulation to your body. That accounts for the discoloration in your extremities and the muscle spasms I'm sure you've encountered.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can it kill me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This surprises Maurice.</context>
      <utterance>It can, but it'll have to wait in line.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is dead silence in the room.</context>
      <utterance>We ran a C.T. and an M.R.I. We found bleeding in your brain. Your collapse was caused by "Transient Cerebral-Ischemia"... a sudden loss of blood circulation to the brain. In other words, Mr. Parker, you had a mild stroke.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adelle moves over to Maurice's side and holds his hand.</context>
      <utterance>I suppose I over did it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What steps do we take now?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We operate. We find the artery in the brain and close the bleeding... I just did this procedure on a Senator and he's doing fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are the odds? Do I have a fifty-fifty chance of surviving the operation?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adelle strokes Maurice's hair. Maurice stares down at his food before looking up with great resolve.</context>
      <utterance>It's hard to say. It's a delicate surgery. There's no getting around the fact that it's a very high-risk situation.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then it'll have to wait until I finish.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The room is stunned. Adelle gets off the bed and collects herself.</context>
      <utterance>I finish the walk, and then we may take all the chances we want.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to me very carefully, because I don't want you to misunderstand me... The walk is over Uncle Maurice. Done. Finished. You've made it to California, it was a miracle, now let's try to save your life.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm completing the walk. I'm almost there.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice is crushed.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, Maurice keep it calm...  We can talk about this again, but just so you know, we have a guard on this floor who's sole job it is to keep an eye on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The room is dead again. Maurice drowns in his thoughts.</context>
      <utterance>There are a lot of people out there who would like to see you finish, including me, but I'm not willing to put your life in anymore risk than it is... We do the operation, and when you're better, you finish the walk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Mr. Parker.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you feeling?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Confused. I'm not sure what to do now. I'm not sure what he wants for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wants to reward you... That's why I'm here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice is lost.</context>
      <utterance>I mean you've done a great thing. You should be rewarded monetarily.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your shoe size?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The priest reaches into his jacket -- for the first time WE SEE a Polo design on his shirt and a gaudy gold chain around his neck.</context>
      <utterance>What? Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice stares at the card in disbelief.</context>
      <utterance>Clive Silver -- Marketing Executive at Reebok.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We want you to do some spots for us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some of the patients turn around.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice is flustered. He can't take this. His eyes become desperate. Clive waves his hands in the air excitedly.</context>
      <utterance>I'm talking six figures, pay or play -- for two spots. We want to push a new line with you... America's New Hero.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clive finishes. He is surprised to find Maurice in tears. Clive is thrown totally off as Maurice stares at him angrily through streaming tears.</context>
      <utterance>Imagine grainy black and white shots of long stretches of highway -- quick cuts with a slow pounding beat underneath... Then we see a man walking up a steep incline -- it's you Maurice. We see shots of you walking. Cut. Cut. Cut. Fast... Music crescendoes -- Bham! Close up -- and you say... 'Reebok, Because There's Nothing You Can't Do.'</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice continues his powerful gaze until Clive looks away. Clive gathers his things and leaves the chapel without another word. Maurice drops his head into his hands and cries quietly.</context>
      <utterance>My wife is dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tom Joad?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... The Grapes of Wrath.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're amazing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I missed you Kris.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I missed you to Mr. Parker.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Adelle told me, your writing is going well. The Crusader for social issues and all.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>You were right. From the heart is always better.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I drove by the bookstore -- it's boarded up now. There's a sign over the wood -- "Office space available." The loss is evident on Maurice's eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't been too punctual with the rent.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice forces a smile.</context>
      <utterance>I was thinking you could open another store with investors. I'm sure a lot of people would want to get involved with you now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Kris glances at the hair on his forearm.</context>
      <utterance>Actually, I'm not worried about my career right now... I'm more worried about how you're getting me out of here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are they standing?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Saluting.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on Mr. Parker.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, come on?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice sits back straight. He looks upset.</context>
      <utterance>I can't do it. I want you to finish, but I want you to live more.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We do the operation after I finish. I can't risk not finishing... I thought you understood what I was doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why in God's name did you fly all the way here then?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kris gets very emotional. He rises from this chair.</context>
      <utterance>... To look me in the eye and say what's important to you isn't as important to me? To tell me you know what's best? To tell me life is more precious than what I feel for my wife?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Parker, you can yell at me, if it'll help. But I'm not risking your life.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice turns to the window away from Kris.</context>
      <utterance>It's mine to risk.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kris walks to the door and stops.</context>
      <utterance>Your operation is scheduled for Friday. I'll be back before then.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She knows now.</context>
      <utterance>She knows you love her Mr. Parker.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kris is tortured. He leaves the room.</context>
      <utterance>No more words. Until I touch the ocean with my hands... it's all just words.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The face stares back from the shadows. She feels him watching.</context>
      <utterance>You should be in bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do your friends call you?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Steph.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Do you have a car, Steph?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stephanie moves to Maurice... She stops short when his face comes into view. His eyes are raw -- red. His face puffy.</context>
      <utterance>You should be in bed...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're in pain.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need your help.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They told me, you might try to talk me into something... You need to rest Mr. Parker... It's for your own good.  I've been following your story for a long while. It's a beautiful thing you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever lose somebody Stephanie?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Maurice melts her with his expression.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Parker, I'm supposed to give you your fish sticks.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... My father.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes her head "No" -- the tears welling up in her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Did you tell him everything you wanted to? Did you do everything you could while he was here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice reaches out and squeezes her soft trembling hand.</context>
      <utterance>If I don't do this Steph, my life isn't worth saving.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, help me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FEMALE DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DOWN THE HALL... Maurice pauses and turns around -- fear etched across his face. The female doctor looks around the barren hall then turns back to Maurice.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, doctor...</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The female doctor smiles as the doors shut. After a few moments of shock -- Maurice smiles back. Stephanie yanks Maurice down the hall and out the EMERGENCY</context>
      <utterance>Good luck.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns back to Stephanie who stares back at him emotionally.</context>
      <utterance>This is it... This is where I fell.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice holds her sad face in his scared hands.</context>
      <utterance>I never thanked my father. He did so much for me... I never thanked him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice gets out of the car painfully slow. He pulls his shoulder back upright with a laborious breath. A sense of pride returns to his face. He turns back to Stephanie and catches a horrified look. He follows her stare... She is staring at his shirt... He looks down to see a DARK CRIMSON STAIN GROWING beneath the surface. He covers the area with his hand.</context>
      <utterance>It's not too late.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going to have a lot of work to do when I get back.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Someone should be with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives her his best smile and begins shuffling his feet over the loose gravel of the road... one step at a time.</context>
      <utterance>Someone is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OUTSIDE DOOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Newton stops Emory before entering.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Emory lets the warning sink in before opening the door. Adelle's VOICE IS BOOMING.</context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid Mrs. Matlin is very upset.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She catches her breath.</context>
      <utterance>... "American Journal of Psychology", "Psychological Review", and "Science", so I think it's safe to say my opinion is valid.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adelle notices the new people in the room.</context>
      <utterance>How does a grown man who can barely walk, just stroll out?... This is not James Bond here, this is my uncle who owns a bookstore, and gets outwitted by grade school kids pulling pranks!</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adelle walks up to Emory.</context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Matlin, this is Sergeant Emory. He'll help us find your uncle.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adelle looks around at all the engrossed faces.</context>
      <utterance>Let me tell you a story Sergeant. There was a patient of mine who had a Golden Retriever, Mac... She loved Mac, not like a pet, but like a family member. One day, she had to leave Mac with 'friends', and wouldn't you know it, Mac gets away and ends up falling into a sewer. My patient comes back -- goes nuts when she hears that Mac has been in the sewer for over 48 hours. Apparently the cop who found the dog didn't want to get his pants dirty. And neither did anyone else. So of course, my patient decides to go in after it... she falls... breaks her hip and lands next to her dead dog, who died of toxic fumes down there...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adelle and Emory have a staring contest. Adelle wins. Adelle stands alone in a room with four men, and she is clearly the one in charge. The door flies open. A police officer walks in pushing KRIS REDDY through the door.</context>
      <utterance>The moral of the story is... She sued for a lot of money! She sued the friends, the city, and the officer for negligence on duty. She has no Mac, no happiness, but she's very rich now... That was a dog. We're talking about a human being...  I hope everyone clearly understands the chain of events that will occur if something should happen to my uncle, whom I love more than you can possibly imagine... Now Sergeant I would like to know right now, if you're willing to get your pants dirty for my uncle?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The officer holds out a long coat and hat. Emory walks up to Kris.</context>
      <utterance>I found him sneaking up the back stairs with this.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kris looks to the empty bed and smiles... a BIG SMILE.</context>
      <utterance>Did you help Mr. Parker leave this hospital?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Emory turns to the officer and ushers him to the door.</context>
      <utterance>No... But I was going to.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adelle smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Forget him. It's time to get our pants dirty.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want three black and whites from here to Handley Avenue. And no communication with the station. The press monitors the transmissions.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They can do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kris smiles innocently.</context>
      <utterance>That goes for all of you. Not a word about this disappearance to anyone. Absolutely no press.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>KLEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... L.A. Times -- 'He's Back.'... San Francisco Chronicle -- 'Have You Seen Maurice?'... New York Post 'Unstoppable!' Klein lays the last paper on the table.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that all?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. The Mayor sent word, that he wants this thing handled quickly, before anything unfortunate happens. He said he doesn't want to be known as the 'Mayor of the City Where Maurice Parker Died!'</utterance>
   <speaker>EMORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that all?</utterance>
   <speaker>KLEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Klein opens the door. Adelle walks in and stands at a distance from Emory. She looks beat. Her eyes are bloodshot, and tired.</context>
      <utterance>No. Mrs. Matlin's waiting for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened with the museum sighting?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adelle is visibly dejected.</context>
      <utterance>False alarm.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's been a long couple of days for all of us. So let me be honest. If he hasn't turned up yet, he's probably --</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... No.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adelle fiddles with her coat.</context>
      <utterance>I spoke with Dr. Ray this morning, and he said it was highly unlikely that someone in his condition could survive this long without medical attention, let alone walk sixty miles -- in fact his exact word was, 'Impossible'.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I knew where he was, I'd get him off the street, but I think it's time that you, the Mayor, and everyone else be braced for the inevitable.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OVERWEIGHT WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't stop Maurice!</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cars start to HONK... More and more people turn to see the commotion... The YELLING AND HONKING IS JOINED BY WHISTLES</context>
      <utterance>Go Mr. Parker!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KLEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adelle is instantly charged with life.</context>
      <utterance>They found him.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dawson's on the C.B. -- wants to talk with you Sarg.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DAWSON</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's just getting off 280. It's amazing Sarg... everybody's out of their cars and cheering him on.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Shit, get him in your car and take him to St. Vincents.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAWSON</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Adelle and the room of officers look confused.</context>
      <utterance>You ever see that concert footage of the Doors, Sarg?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAWSON</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Emory is thinking fast.</context>
      <utterance>The Doors, the musical group. I saw a documentary where the police stopped one of their concerts, snatched Jim Morrison right off the stage... the crowd went frickin nuts -- they tore up the place -- it turned into a war.  ... I'm not stopping this concert by myself. And there's no way you're getting backup here -- it's jammed up for miles.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAWSON</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Beat. Emory looks at Adelle's expectant face. He talks into the C.B. without taking his eyes off her.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't we just let him finish Sarg?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How does he look?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAWSON</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Emory thinks. He talks to the other officers in the room.</context>
      <utterance>Like shit. He's bleeding heavily. He's having breathing problems and he's as pale as stone. If he wasn't moving, I'd swear he was dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bring him in. Now! If he dies out there, who the hell knows what that crowd will do...  Let alone the Mayor. The room empties fast. Emory talks to Adelle.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somehow, Adelle's face doesn't convey much confidence.</context>
      <utterance>He'll be in a hospital within a half an hour.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TV ANCHOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A shock of concern shoots through the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>... He's headed West on Sharp Park Road... Witnesses describe him as seriously injured.</utterance>
   <speaker>TV ANCHOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The picture cuts to a HELICOPTER SHOT OF DOWNTOWN PACIFICA -- at first it just looks like an aerial of buildings, then the camera ZOOMS. It catches a tiny figure struggling through a street intersection.</context>
      <utterance>Lynn McCay and our Highway Cam -- has just spotted him...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kris lets go of his arm and moves like lightning. He jumps atop a fire-hydrant and yells to the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Don't stop walking.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kris points to the squad cars inching their way up the street.</context>
      <utterance>The police are here. They're coming to take Mr. Parker away. He needs our help.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Help Mr. Parker! Don't let them end the walk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EMORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is going on? It's frickin wall to wall people and they're way too emotional. We need mucho backup -- now!... Officers are to bring in Mr. Parker on sight, don't ask questions, don't hesitate, bring him in... I want a barricade placed along the entire beach area... Now God damn it, now! Emory CLICKS OFF and looks around at the growing crowd -- he turns to see a PUBLIC BUS UNLOADING PASSENGERS -- fifty more spectators rush off the bus and rush toward the crowded street.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TV ANCHOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Through ten states and over three thousand miles...</utterance>
   <speaker>TV ANCHOR 2</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... A bookstore owner from Philadelphia Pennsylvania...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice opens his eyes and stares at his beautiful wife.</context>
      <utterance>What do you think heaven is like?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it's a different place for each person.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Did you have a dream?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know where my heaven is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice chuckles.</context>
      <utterance>Pacifica, California.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why there?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>When I was ten, my family lived in Pacifica for a year. I used to go to the beach everyday that summer. I never felt so happy, carefree. It was a magic place for me... That's where my heaven will be.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maurice?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I die, you'll know where to look for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go to sleep Ellen.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>No really, if God takes us away from each other, you know where to look now?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The beach of Pacifica, California.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen smiles as she cradles deeper into Maurice's arms. Husband and wife fall asleep together.</context>
      <utterance>Go to sleep Ellen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adelle looks at her wounded Uncle sadly. She touches his shirt and her hand comes away with blood.</context>
      <utterance>Uncle Maurice, please, we have to get you to a hospital.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to finish first.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The inner circle of people bursts open, as KRIS BREAKS</context>
      <utterance>I won't let you die.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>KRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let him finish Adelle. He's almost there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's almost dead. Can't you see that! This has nothing to do with you. Maurice touches Adelle's cheek turning her attention back to him. He barely manages to get the words out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Maurice begins crying uncontrollably.</context>
      <utterance>It has nothing to do with you either... This is between Ellen and me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice takes her hand and bends down putting his forehead to her hand as if getting blessings from her.</context>
      <utterance>I'm begging you...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adelle's heart is breaking. She weeps openly as she straightens her Uncle to an upright position. She wipes the tears from his eyes with her hand gently.</context>
      <utterance>Let me do this for Ellen, let me do this for my wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adelle stands firm, the strength in her growing with each second.</context>
      <utterance>Touch him, and they'll be a riot...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The officers are taken off guard. They look around at the countless sea of eyes on them. Adelle sees they won't do anything and moves to Maurice's side. Maurice begins to walk again. Adelle to one side, Kris to the other and thousands of people following in step.</context>
      <utterance>... and I'll start it.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
