<movie id="346" title="Legion">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE MOJAVE DESERT - DUSK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A BLOOD RED SUN is sinking behind the distant mountains. The unbearable heat will soon become an unbearable cold. A YOUNG WOMAN'S VOICE. Solemn. Weary. Determined.</context>
      <utterance>Vast. Barren. No signs of life.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with these words the last trace of sunlight is SNUFFED OUT, leaving us in:</context>
      <utterance>When I was a little girl, my mother would remind me each night before bed to be sure to open my heart to God, for he was kind, merciful and just. Things changed after my father left a few years later, leaving her to raise me and my brothers alone in a little place out on the edge of the Mojave Desert. She never talked about a kind and merciful God again. Instead she spoke of a prophecy. Of a time when all the world would be covered in darkness and the fate of Mankind would be decided. One night I finally got up the courage to ask my mother why God had changed, why was he mad at his children. "I don't know," she said, tucking the covers around me, "I guess he just got tired of all the bullshit."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BURTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamn' animals. Nights like this I wish I could take a match to this city just so I could watch all these motherfuckers burn.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTEVEZ</speaker>
      <mode>LAUGHS</mode>
      <context>Burton doesn't even smile. He's dead fucking serious.</context>
      <utterance>A good ol' boy barbecue, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds his finger up like a pistol. Aims it at the people they pass, picking them off one by one.</context>
      <utterance>A fresh start. That's what this place needs.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now Burton laughs, a dark, mean laugh. Estevez eyes his partner, wary.</context>
      <utterance>Pow! Pow! Pow!</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTEVEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KABOOM! Through the WINDSHIELD, we see a storefront EXPLODE just ahead, raining fiery debris onto the squad car. Burton slams on the breaks and the cops look up just in time to see...</context>
      <utterance>Jesus... You know Burton, I'm so happy we get to share beautiful moments like this. They really brighten my da--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ESTEVEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the distance, the POP-POP of GUNFIRE. The POLICE RADIO CRACKLES with URGENT CHATTER. MANY VOICES TALKING AT ONCE. "Shots fired...Code Three...Officer down!" The cops shift about nervously, trying to stay focused.</context>
      <utterance>Drop the bags! Hands on your head!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cops shoot a quick, anxious glance at each other -- "what the hell?" -- then they turn back to Michael.</context>
      <utterance>It's starting. There isn't much time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael lets the gun bags hit the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Shut the fuck up and drop the bags now!</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTEVEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael slowly places his palms on his skull.</context>
      <utterance>Hands on your head! On your head!</utterance>
   <speaker>BURTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Estevez rushes in to restrain Michael, grabbing his wrist, FINGERS TIGHTENING. Michael closes his eyes, a terrible decision made. And that's when he moves, a fucking blur! In an instant Michael's broken the cop's arm, spinning him helplessly around, turning him into a human shield. Now it's Michael who's in charge, gun to Estevez's head, facing off with Burton. Burton struggles to find a shot, can't.</context>
      <utterance>Turn around! Turn the fuck around! Michael slowly turns around. Calm.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let `em go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ESTEVEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take the shot, Burton!</utterance>
   <speaker>BURTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Burton starts to SHAKE, the words stuck in his throat like a skipping record.</context>
      <utterance>I said let `em fuckin' g-g-g-g--</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTEVEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE STREET LAMPS BEGIN TO FLICKER AND STROBE, adding to the confusion. Burton squeezes his eyes shut in pain, his WHOLE BODY QUAKING, heels CLICKING the pavement, as if some massive pressure were building inside him. And with the horrific sound of CRACKING BONES, BURTON'S MOUTH</context>
      <utterance>Burton!?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BURTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing, Michael? These weren't your orders. Estevez looks at his partner with confusion.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTEVEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael, however, seems to know exactly who he's talking to.</context>
      <utterance>What did you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm following my own orders now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you will die along with the child.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTEVEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BLAM! Burton shoots his partner in the head. Estevez drops, leaving Michael without cover. Burton re-aims, but Michael's faster, already FIRING back. Bullets rip up the concrete. SMASH! The squad car window SHATTERS, Burton's chest EXPLODING!</context>
      <utterance>Burton, you fuckin' know this guy?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>"PARADISE FALLS GAS `N' GRUB"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A beat as Jeep contemplates the sign.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Jeep turns to see CHARLIE, a very pregnant girl of about twenty, standing in the trailer doorway, rubbing the sleep from her eyes. Even with the trailer-trash veneer, she's strikingly beautiful.</context>
      <utterance>You okay, Jeep?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry to wake you, Charlie.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>stepping out of the trailer, hands on her</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLY)</speaker>
      <mode> BELLY)</mode>
      <context>She approaches Jeep. Sees the strain in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Wasn't you. He's been kickin' up a storm all night. Must know somethin' I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He struggles for a moment, nods.</context>
      <utterance>Another bad dream?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just stress, Jeep, that's all. You do too much worryin'. About this place. About your dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>A glimmer of a smile crosses Jeep's face.</context>
      <utterance>About me...</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the only thing I like worrying about.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeep turns away, dejected.</context>
      <utterance>See what I mean? You're worried about a girl eight months pregnant and it isn't even your baby. Now that's enough to give anybody nightmares.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everybody else does.</context>
      <utterance>Go ahead, make fun of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is not news Jeep wants to hear.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, I was only kiddin'. You know how much I appreciate everything you and Bob are doing for me, but a month from now, this baby'll have a new family and I'll have to start thinkin' about what the hell I'm doin' with my life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're still going through with it...?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeep, I'm not ready to be a mama. Christ, I can barely take care of myself as it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie smiles sadly at him, touched by his sweetness, but this just isn't where she's at.</context>
      <utterance>I could help you. We could do it together, you know? I want to.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeep nods, tries to hide the fact that he's dying inside.</context>
      <utterance>You gotta stop carryin' the weight of the world on your shoulders.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now can we go back in? I'm freezing my ass off out here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie kisses him on the cheek and heads back to the trailer. He watches her, longing in his eyes. With the clank of the door, she's gone. And over Jeep's troubled look, the perennial holiday cheer of FRANK CAPRA'S "IT'S A WONDERFUL LIFE" MIXES up.</context>
      <utterance>Go on. I'll be right there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY STEWART</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know whether I like it very much being seen around with an angel without any wings.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The JUKEBOX on the other side of the diner starts up with the MERLE HAGGARD tune "I'M A LONESOME FUGITIVE". A stunning looking sixteen-year-old GIRL with dyed-black hair and a piercing or three, is leaning seductively over the jukebox, swaying gently to the music. The headband doubling as her mini-skirt reveals her knock-out figure in a way that really doesn't leave much up to the imagination. She's a billboard of rebellion.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, they got names for that kind a relationship.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's disgusting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really, how can she go out in public wearing that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Why don't we just ask her?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Howard, don't. You'll embarrass me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>shouting across the</utterance>
   <speaker>DINER)</speaker>
      <mode> DINER)</mode>
      <context>The girl who we now know as AUDREY ANDERSON turns to Howard with a caustic smile.</context>
      <utterance>Audrey, honey? Your mother was wondering if you got dressed this morning with the specific intention of showing your ass off to the entire world?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that's cuz I woke up hoping to get double teamed by a couple of meth head truckers in the bathroom of some desert shithole.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>And with that she turns back to the jukebox. Percy watches the exchange discreetly from behind the counter. Loving it. Howard turns back to his wife. Rigid smile.</context>
      <utterance>Good thing we stopped here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandra buries her face in her hands.</context>
      <utterance>I feel satisfied with that answer. I really do.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm being punished for something, I know it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He checks his cell phone again. No chance of a signal way out here. So he shuffles around to the side of the diner in search of a pay phone. The good news is that he finds one. The bad news is that it's been broken for ten years. Leaning next to the broken phone, however, is Charlie wearing a shabby, faded WAITRESS uniform stretched tight around her very pregnant belly. Adding to her perfect mother-to-be look is that cigarette dangling from her lips. The plastic name tag pinned to her chest says "CHARLIE".</context>
      <utterance>Darren, your fuckin' directions suck, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She eyes him, mildly intrigued, takes a drag.</context>
      <utterance>Hey...</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lets out a long slow exhale.</context>
      <utterance>You know that shit right there ain't good for the baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guess I should think `bout quittin' then.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now hold on, girl, let me bum one before you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can buy a whole pack inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She considers him for a moment, then pulls out a cigarette. Lights it off the end of hers then hands it to him. Kyle takes a drag, pulls out his crumpled map.</context>
      <utterance>Tell ya what. You let me have one of yours, and I'll give you two from the new pack you're gonna sell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I in the right place?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only if nowhere's right, `cause that's where you are.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sonuvabitch. There another phone around here? You know, one that works?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bob'll probably let you use the diner phone if you ask him real nice...And pay `im somethin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can handle that. You got pancakes here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, we got a buttermilk stack for three seventy-five. We also got french toast for four dollars if you're into that. I personally like the pancakes though.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>They both turn to see Jeep behind the diner, wearing mechanic's coveralls and holding a DUSTY OLD CRIB. Charlie quickly hides her cigarette behind her back. Busted.</context>
      <utterance>You okay, Charlie?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeep nods, uncertain, eyes Kyle another moment, then he shuffles along out of sight. Charlie brings the cigarette back up to her lips. An awkward beat.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'm okay. This guy's just lost.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three seventy-five, huh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope Salem Lights are okay, `cause that's all we got left.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I can smoke `em, I'll take `em.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Bob steps off the chair.</context>
      <utterance>Where ya been, Charlie?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In truth there aren't any orders stacking up, but it certainly makes Bob feel better to say it.</context>
      <utterance>This ain't a resort you know. I got orders stacking up here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You best not be smokin' again. Not in your condition.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bob, do you see where am I right now? Can my condition really get any worse? `Sides, you ain't one to talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? I quit two years ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, so why you still carryin' that fancy lighter `round for?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was a gift from my ex-wife, alright? I'm sentimental. I don't wanna forget how much I hate her guts.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob turns to Kyle. Doesn't like what he sees.</context>
      <utterance>Hey man?</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob is about to respond when:</context>
      <utterance>Can I use your phone? My cell doesn't get a signal out here and the pay phone outside is busted.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob's expression darkens at this news.</context>
      <utterance>Any news about when our truck might be fixed? You said your boy would have us on the road two hours ago. The rate we're going, we'll be lucky to make it to Scottsdale by Christmas.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamn it. Where the hell is Jeep?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Jeep freezes, knows he's in trouble He reluctantly turns to see his father standing next to the Anderson's broken-down Uhual.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Leonardo...!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeep stares at the ground. Couldn't be anymore uncomfortable.</context>
      <utterance>The fact that this truck's hood's up mean anything to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob looks down at the crib with dismay.</context>
      <utterance>Nothin'... Jeep tries feebly to block his path, fails.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob considers him, softens.</context>
      <utterance>Found it under a bunch of stuff in the storage shed. I know you never like to throw anything away...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whaddya doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What...?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeep, I like Charlie. I do. And I think it's real good of you to lend her a helping hand, but she is not your responsibility.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh whatever, leave me alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't walk away from me while I'm talkin' to you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeep stiffens. Turns to his father:</context>
      <utterance>How long you gonna follow her around like a puppy dog? Cleanin' up the messes she makes while she steps out with every guy around here other than you?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't say that about her! She's not like that!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeeps shakes his head, burns.</context>
      <utterance>You really think she's gonna stick around here after that baby's born and off her hands?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob sighs, feels for his boy.</context>
      <utterance>Look, I know it doesn't make any sense to you, but it's just something I have to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See that up there? Your mother thought I was crazy for wanting to buy this place, middle of nowhere...But I just knew this was what I was supposed to do. Told your mom, "just wait." Told her when they finally ran the freeway through here like they were plannin' on, this place would be like Grand Central Station.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I was wrong. The freeway never came and now the only people who ever stop here are the ones who are lost.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And your mom? Well she got tired of waitin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon Dad. You can't blame yourself for what she did--</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I can. And I'm sayin' you're about to make the same damn mistake I made, believing in something that's never gonna happen...Or someone.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's time for you to move on from this place, Jeep. I don't wanna see you wake up one morning old and pissed off, realizing you're lost just like everybody else who stops here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>holding up a silencing</utterance>
   <speaker>HAND)</speaker>
      <mode> HAND)</mode>
      <context>The TV has gone on the fritz again. Only now the image is mostly snow. Bob climbs back onto the chair. Faces the TV.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, wait a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with you today?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But you don't wanna listen.</context>
      <utterance>I told you to get the satellite TV.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell do I need that crap for?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>History Channel, man!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got all the history I can take.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's for sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your problem now?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do I start?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know this was the top-of-the- line model when I bought it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, in the Fifties.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the picture snaps into FOCUS. Only it isn't the picture he was expecting. The STARK GRAPHIC OF THE EMERGENCY BROADCASTING SYSTEM and its accompanying HOLLOW TONE fill the diner. Everybody in the place stops and turns to the TV.</context>
      <utterance>You shouldn't be watchin' anyways.  Okay, baby, this is gonna do it. Bob gives the TV one final wallop -- WHACK!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See? Clear as day.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice work, Bob. What the hell's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That'd be true, except for the words at the bottom of the screen, which read:</context>
      <utterance>It's just one of those test things.</utterance>
   <speaker>"THIS IS NOT A TEST"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bob switches the channels. All the same.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't look like a test.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kyle peels a five dollar bill off a serious WAD OF CASH. That gets Bob's attention. Bob snaps the money out of his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Yo, am I the Invisible motherfuckin' Man here? Do you have a phone or not?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie is standing by the Anderson's table, clearing dishes. Everybody's eyes are locked on the TV.</context>
      <utterance>In the back past the kitchen. Make it fast. Kyle hustles passed Percy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If there's a real emergency aren't they supposed to give us some information about what to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure it's a mistake.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Percy grabs an old battery powered radio off a kitchen shelf. Switches it on. STATIC. He spins the dial until he reaches a clear signal. The same HOLLOW TONE of Emergency Broadcasting. Station after station the same thing. The diner is overwhelmed by a chilling chorus of HOLLOW TONES. Everyone goes very still.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Percy, give that old radio of yours a shot. Maybe they got some news about the TV.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me talk to him...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He keeps trying. Nothing.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe there was an earthquake?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They keep sayin' we're overdue for a big one.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lot a folks could be hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not if it was centered in the desert.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly. Could be nothing to worry about.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So then why's the TV out?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe it just hit the relay stations. Aren't those usually in remote areas?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, `cause of the radiation they give off.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There ain't no radiation comin' from those things. Plus that don't explain the radio being out too. Some of those stations broadcast over hundreds of miles. Any quake that big and we would a felt it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Percy's right. I didn't feel nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's a terrorist attack or something...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone considers that grimly, then:</context>
      <utterance>Oh god...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, for cryin' out loud. There's no use in speculating. I'll just call my brother up in Needles. He must a heard something.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Kyle has reappeared in the diner.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whaddya talkin' about?</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Phone's dead. Just tried to make a call.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kyle shakes his head, sits down at the counter.</context>
      <utterance>You're shittin' me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, this is just great.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Relax, Mrs. Anderson. Nothing to get excited about. Probably just working on the lines.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have a seat wherever you want, Ma'am. Specials are on the board.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The old lady settles at a table across from the Andersons. She smiles at them pleasantly. Charlie is about to hand her a menu, when:</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, dear.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I already know what I want.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, what'll it be?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll have the steak, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And how'd you like that cooked?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rare if you would. And water, no ice.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coming right up.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charlie, is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What an unusual name for a girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The old lady turns to the Andersons.</context>
      <utterance>So they say. I'll be right back with your water.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, I'm Gladys. Gladys Foster.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice to meet you, Gladys. I'm Sandra and this is my husband Howard.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What brings you out to these parts?</context>
      <utterance>What a nice young couple you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're moving out to Scottsdale. But our truck broke down, and so we're stuck here while it's being fixed.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A FLY begins to buzz around Gladys's head. She doesn't seem to notice it.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, what a nuisance.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, Gladys, it seems the lines are down around here. The phone and TV, you know?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandra nods at the old woman, unsure of what to make of that response. The fly that was circling her head, now lands on GLADYS'S FACE. It crawls across her cheek without her reacting in the least. Howard and Sandra exchange looks. Creepy. The door JINGLES and Jeep walks in. He heads straight for a quiet huddle with Bob. All the while though, he keeps one eye fixed on the old lady sitting at the table near the Andersons. Something about her...</context>
      <utterance>Oh, don't worry yourself about that, sweetheart. It'll all be over soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The carburetor's shot. Don't know why. Looks brand new.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>glances over at the</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDERSONS)</speaker>
      <mode> ANDERSONS)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, shit. They're gonna be pissed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could try to rebuild it, but it'd take a while, and I don't think we have all the parts. If we call right now, we might be able to get a new one down here tomorrow morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not gonna happen. Goddamn phone's out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Across the diner, Charlie places a bloody red steak in front of Gladys.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, dear. How far along are you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just about there.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The father must be very proud.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean he's...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out of sight. Out of mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A fly lands on Gladys's steak. Charlie tries to wave it away. But another one lands in its place.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I see. So you're not married, I take it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gladys starts to dig in to the steak with a real ferociousness you wouldn't expect from an old lady. More FLIES begin to land on her body. On her food. Charlie is still trying to wave them away.</context>
      <utterance>Nope.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's too bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I prefer it that way. I don't a need a man tellin' me what to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what about the baby?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got it under control.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie freezes. The Andersons turn to look as well. Kyle glances over from the counter.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but it's gonna burn.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you just say?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie shakes her head at the woman, not giving in.</context>
      <utterance>I said your fucking baby's gonna burn.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slaps the check down on the table and walks back toward the kitchen, passing Jeep and Bob.</context>
      <utterance>Go to hell, lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gladys begins to laugh innocently as she continues to devour her meat. Red juice drips down her chin. The flies are swarming now. How did so many get in here? Sandra and Howard are mortified at this sudden turn of events.</context>
      <utterance>Total fucking Jesus freak.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All those babies. They're gonna burn.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gladys, please. There's no reason to -- Gladys's head suddenly whips toward her.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandra covers her mouth in shock. Everybody in the diner is now focused on the old lady. Howard gets up from the booth.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up, you stupid fucking cunt! All you do is complain! Complain! Complain!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Howard's already standing over Gladys.</context>
      <utterance>Howard, it's okay! Don't listen to her!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the hell do you think you are, lady?! Now, I'd like you to apologize to my --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RAZOR SHARP TEETH.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gladys rockets to her feet, knocking her table over. Blood covers her face and chest.</context>
      <utterance>EVERYBODY FREAKS as Howard crumbles to the floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLADYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Percy is the first to react. From behind the counter, he whips a heavy metal frying pan at Gladys that knocks her head sideways. THWACK! BONES BREAK AND BURST FROM HER NECK. Impossibly, Gladys is still standing. She lets out an INHUMAN SCREAM and SCRAMBLES ACROSS THE DINER, knocking tables and chairs over in her wake. Bob pulls a shotgun from behind the counter.</context>
      <utterance>You're all going to fucking die!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Gladys not only moves, SHE SCURRIES RIGHT UP THE FUCKING</context>
      <utterance>Don't move!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>struggles to cock the</utterance>
   <speaker>GUN)</speaker>
      <mode> GUN)</mode>
      <context>Gladys smiles sweetly before SLAPPING HIM CLEAR ACROSS THE</context>
      <utterance>Fuck!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Sandra is on the floor with her husband. Blood pours freely from his neck. Kyle stares at the dying man -- a moment of hesitation -- then he rushes to help.</context>
      <utterance>Somebody help me!</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandra looks fearfully up at Kyle, at the gun still in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Press your hands over the hole!</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Obeying, she cups her hands over the hole in his neck, desperately trying to stop the flow of blood leaking out between her fingers. Percy scrambles over with a first-aid kit and together he and Kyle get to work on Howard's neck.</context>
      <utterance>Don't look at me like that, lady! I'm tryin' to fuckin' help you! Now put your goddamn hands over the hole before your husband bleeds to death!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How far to the hospital?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kyle shoots him a look. Eighty miles?! Pedal to the floor time. Audrey leans forward from the back seat.</context>
      <utterance>Seventy, maybe eighty miles.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Up ahead, the DARK CLOUDS Jeep saw earlier have finally closed in, descending onto the highway like a WALL.</context>
      <utterance>What's that on the road?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're fuckin' clouds! What the fuck do they look like?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's right. They're black... Undulating... BUZZING!</context>
      <utterance>Not clouds. Clouds don't buzz.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I swear I did.</context>
      <utterance>I don't understand how she was still standin' after Percy hit `er with that goddamn fryin' pan. Broke her fuckin' neck. I saw it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>Bob looks over at Jeep, sees him trembling.</context>
      <utterance>And did you see that kid's gun? The hell's he doin' with a gun like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But for Jeep it's not okay. He's hurting real bad inside.</context>
      <utterance>It's okay, Jeep. It's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I couldn't pull the trigger. I froze. I saw what I needed to do, but I was afraid...  She could've killed you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's nothin' to be ashamed of, Jeep.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>Before Jeep can respond, they hear the sound of the front</context>
      <utterance>Not everybody can play the hero.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>catching Percy by the</utterance>
   <speaker>ARM)</speaker>
      <mode> ARM)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you going?!</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To get my bible!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hell you need that for?!</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob's about to respond when he hears the BUZZING. Bob, Charlie and Jeep slowly approach the windows to see the</context>
      <utterance>Well somebody's gotta start prayin'...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>raises a bottle of</utterance>
   <speaker>ALCOHOL)</speaker>
      <mode> ALCOHOL)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, hold `em steady.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>nods, peakish, to</utterance>
   <speaker>HERSELF)</speaker>
      <mode> HERSELF)</mode>
      <context>Howard writhes as Percy pours alcohol on the wound. Sandra can't help but stare at Percy's hook. Meanwhile across the diner, Bob and Jeep peel back the tablecloth to examine Gladys' bullet riddled corpse. Kyle stands over them with Bob's shotgun trained on the body -- just in case. Gladys is a real horror show. Bones jut out at obtuse angles from her neck -- a result of the blow to her head from Percy's frying pan.</context>
      <utterance>Oh god, please don't throw up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob rolls Gladys over, revealing her face -- her enlarged mouth filled with dozens of razor sharp baby teeth.</context>
      <utterance>She's cold as a freakin' ice cube. If I hadn't just seen her walk in here, I'd say the old bag's been dead for hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't care how long she's been dead, the bitch ain't stayin' in here with us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't get it. Why don't they come closer?</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A CLANK and Jeep notices the old lady's car keys have dropped to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>How the fuck am I supposed to know, man? You askin' me to explain the behavior of a motherfuckin' pestilence.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeep slips the key into the driver's side door. Unlocks it.</context>
      <utterance>No Twilight Zone shit if that's what you mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeep slowly swings the door open and that's when the smell hits them.</context>
      <utterance>Careful. Old lady could have some kind of rabid poodle locked up in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob covers his nose.</context>
      <utterance>Agh! What the fuck is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kyle opens the passenger door, looks in. Dark, dirty. But nothing unusual.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothin' here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bitch's got motherfuckin' dead cats in her hoopty! What the fuck is wrong with white people?!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Least now we know where that smell was coming from.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it was a real motherfuckin' necessity we figured that out, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>sees something up the</utterance>
   <speaker>ROAD)</speaker>
      <mode> ROAD)</mode>
      <context>They turn to see HEADLIGHTS growing larger in the dim haze. A POLICE CRUISER careens off the highway and skids to a wild stop in front of the diner. Its ENGINE RATTLES as the dust clears around it. No movement can be seen behind its bug splattered windows.</context>
      <utterance>Hey...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, now we're talkin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob and Jeep look over at Kyle.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute. Check it out. It's LAPD. What's an LA cop doing way out here?</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They consider the police car a moment more. See the SHATTERED PASSENGER WINDOW, the BLOOD STAINS.</context>
      <utterance>I'm from Nevada, man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long beat as Michael considers Bob. Icy cold.</context>
      <utterance>Take one step closer and I'll drop you right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That how you greet all your customers?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael stares at him blankly.</context>
      <utterance>Mister, after what we've been through here today, you're lucky we didn't shoot you first and greet you later. Now let me see your teeth.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael offers up a dangerous smile, revealing a not so well kept but definitely normal set of teeth. Bob and the others ease slightly.</context>
      <utterance>Your teeth goddamn it! Lemme see `em!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob lowers the gun.</context>
      <utterance>No, shark teeth, Pop.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay... Suppose you tell us your name then.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Michael.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael remains silent. Doesn't seemed shocked in the least by what he's heard.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry about all that, Michael. This old lady just went crazy inside my place here. She had these teeth. Never seen anything like `em. Practically bit a man in half.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob chuckles for a moment. When Michael doesn't respond in kind, Bob falls silent. Anxious. He slowly raises the shotgun again. Michael sizes up this raggedy group. His gaze drifts over to the loosely wrapped body in front of the diner. The plastic table cloth flaps wildly in the wind. Turning back to Bob:</context>
      <utterance>So what are you doin' out here? Gotta say you don't exactly look like a police officer. Even one from L.A. Then again, you have to be, right? I mean, who the hell'd be crazy enough to steal a cop car?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Know what?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael just shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>We don't know anything. Nothing's working here. The TV, the radio, the phone...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael steps toward Charlie with a sense of purpose, but Bob blocks his path, brandishing the shotgun.</context>
      <utterance>I'm running out of time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Back off, fella...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>In a BLUR OF MOVEMENT, Michael rips the shotgun from Bob's hands. It all happens so fast that Bob is stunned to find himself holding air. He's even more stunned to now have the barrel of the gun pressed to the bridge of his nose. Everyone freezes.</context>
      <utterance>Now, I don't care if this is the second coming of Jesus fucking Christ, I say it's time for you to either get talkin' or get the hell outta here!</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael's expression is totally calm. Merciless.</context>
      <utterance>Easy! Easy!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Bob can't even speak, he's so scared. He squeezes his eyes closed.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Dad, tell `em you're sorry. Tell `em you were only kidding!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael's eyes flit momentarily in Charlie's direction. Considering her. The diner door opens and Percy steps cautiously out with hand and hook held up to show no threat. He's followed by Sandra and Audrey. Michael sees them, but offers no indication that he cares.</context>
      <utterance>Let `em go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, son, I'm sure you don't wanna go spillin' blood for no good reason in front of all these decent people, do ya? Our friend Bob here ain't worth the trouble it'd cause ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>But Michael doesn't seem to register this plea. It's not looking good. No one BREATHES. That's when Kyle notices something out in the direction of the road.</context>
      <utterance>So whaddya say `bout just lettin' `im go and then you can be on your way? Nice `n' easy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael turns, sees the lights.</context>
      <utterance>What the--?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael whips the gun away from Bob's head and thrusts it back into his hands. Bob's looks down at the gun, speechless.</context>
      <utterance>They're here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael walks swiftly around to the trunk of the cruiser. Pops it, revealing a staggering ARSENAL OF WEAPONRY.</context>
      <utterance>You're going to need this.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(waving back Audrey and</context>
      <utterance>Lord, have mercy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ladies best get back inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it? What's happening? Who is this man? Why's he driving a police car?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up, mom!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait. I don't think that's such a good idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, I can handle it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's just a kid --</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael's eyes narrow, studying Jeep.</context>
      <utterance>I said, I can handle it!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael pulls out twin MP5s for himself. GLOCK 9s are tucked everywhere they can go. Michael tosses clip belts to the men. Boxes of shotgun shells. The works.</context>
      <utterance>He can handle it. He doesn't have a choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slams the trunk closed and approaches Charlie. He cocks a Glock and hands it to her.</context>
      <utterance>If you want to live, you'll do exactly as I say.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives her a hard look. She nods nervously. Trusting him but not sure why. Michael marches into the diner. Kyle glances quickly at the others, then he bolts after Michael. Percy follows. Then Charlie. Now it's only Jeep and his father left.</context>
      <utterance>When you fire, you keep your thumb off the slide. Don't hesitate. Don't do anything brave. There's no safety.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Jeep. We gotta go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sandra? What's happening?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandra closes her eyes. Struggling to believe it. Suddenly the ELECTRICITY GOES OUT, dipping the room into</context>
      <utterance>It's okay! Everything's okay!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeep, get the flashlights!</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody just stay still!</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A flicker of LIGHT. And then FLASHLIGHT BEAMS CUT THROUGH THE DARKNESS...coming to rest on Michael's pale face. Michael looks up at the ceiling.</context>
      <utterance>Now that we're locked in here, what the fuck are we supposed to do?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob turns to Michael sharply.</context>
      <utterance>Where the hell did they go?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael is about to answer, when:</context>
      <utterance>Alright, Rambo. You got us up here. Now you mind explaining what the fuck we're fighting?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Over the wind, another sound becomes audible. The delicate chime of a CALLIOPE.</context>
      <utterance>Listen!</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You hear what I'm hearing?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CALLIOPE MUSIC grows louder, the melody more distinct. Now we recognize the song: SANTA CLAUS IS COMING TO TOWN. But instead of filling them with cheer, it fills them with dread.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah...The hell is that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It sounds almost like...</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TWO HEADLIGHTS appear in the darkness. And sure enough, an ICE CREAM TRUCK rolls slowly toward the diner. The EERIE CALLIOPE MUSIC emanates from a speaker on its roof. It's too dark to see who's behind the wheel.</context>
      <utterance>Ice cream.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got to be fuckin' kidding me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men quickly do as they're told.</context>
      <utterance>Alright. There's a safety switch on the side of your gun. Push it all the way down. Two clicks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kyle, Bob shoot quick anxious looks at Percy.</context>
      <utterance>Now when this starts, you hold on tight, you hear me? If you don't, you're going to blow your hand off. Understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The fuck y'all lookin' at me for?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode>WHISPERS</mode>
      <context>The Ice Cream Man's gaze snaps up to the roof. He heard.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, he don't look that bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's when the Ice Cream Man's JAW UNHINGES, STRETCHING</context>
      <utterance>Oh, shit. Oh, shit. Oh, shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Percy tosses him a box of shells. But Bob fumbles the catch and the box slides halfway down the sloped roof.</context>
      <utterance>Shells!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With the gun still in one hand, Bob reaches frantically down for the ammo. Stretching... Further...</context>
      <utterance>Fuck!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob reaches up and clasps Percy's hook, praying that it stays on. But this chick ain't finished yet. Up she comes once more. Her razor sharp fingernails claw up the metal roof. SCREECH!</context>
      <utterance>Grab my hand!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gun!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>jamming the gun in her</utterance>
   <speaker>MOUTH)</speaker>
      <mode> MOUTH)</mode>
      <context>BLAM! BLAM! BLAM! The back of her head EXPLODES. Her body goes limp. Bob struggles to push the corpse off of him.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck off!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Percy extends his hook hand, helping Bob ascend to safety.</context>
      <utterance>Pull me up!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Audrey shakes her head, tears streaming down her cheeks. She looks over at her mother. Sandra's eyes are closed. It's too much.</context>
      <utterance>Where is it?!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom! Open your eyes!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Howard's body is TORN AWAY from Sandra. Something's got hold of his legs! That gets Sandra's eyes open!</context>
      <utterance>I can't! I can't!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>springing after her</utterance>
   <speaker>HUSBAND)</speaker>
      <mode> HUSBAND)</mode>
      <context>Howard screams deliriously as he's dragged rapidly through the diner toward the broken front window. He flails about, desperately trying to grab a hold of something. Sandra scrambles after her husband. Reaching for him.</context>
      <utterance>Howard!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The creature reaches the window. Sandra dives for Howard's outstretched hands. She has him! The creature's progress is abruptly halted at the shattered window. It turns back toward Sandra -- a shaft of light falling across its face, reveals: A TEENAGE GIRL of about Audrey's age. Her skin is a deathly blue. Her pupils a GHASTLY WHITE.</context>
      <utterance>Daddy!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TEENAGE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandra screams, holds on.</context>
      <utterance>See what you made me do, mother!?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie and Audrey rush to Sandra's side, grabbing Howard's arms. Jeep is right behind them ready to fire at the creature, but with the women in the way, he can't get a clear shot. So he discards the gun and grabs Howard's arms. Howard screams as his body is torturously stretched. A human tug-of-war.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandra slaps at him frantically as he carries her away from the window and thrusts her down into a back booth.</context>
      <utterance>Let me go! He's alive!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's alive!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandra breaks down.</context>
      <utterance>No... Not anymore.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode>RECOVERING</mode>
      <context>She glances back at Michael. He's watching her. Those eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I'm okay. I'm fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie doesn't know how to respond. She's about to say something when -- Kyle rushes into the room. A smile on his face.</context>
      <utterance>I told you not to do anything brave.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then Kyle notices the broken window, takes in the room, his excitement falling.</context>
      <utterance>We got `em runnin'!</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No one responds. Sandra and Audrey are huddled together. Crying. Bob and Percy follow Kyle in, still shaking from the adrenaline.</context>
      <utterance>Where's Howard?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone needs to be on the roof.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob grabs Kyle's arm.</context>
      <utterance>I'll go.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(approaches Michael,</context>
      <utterance>Hold on.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETERMINED)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All eyes on Michael. These people want answers. Finally:</context>
      <utterance>You better start talking.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone takes that in for a moment, then:</context>
      <utterance>The first time God lost faith in Man he sent a flood. The second time...he sent what you see outside.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sayin' this is the Apocalypse...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm saying this is an extermination.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those things out there are vessels. The Possessed. The weakest willed are the easiest to turn.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Possessed by what? Demons?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That silences the room.</context>
      <utterance>No...by angels.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael looks squarely at Percy.</context>
      <utterance>Son, I don't know what bible you been readin', but in my version, the angels are the good guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's where your book is wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come you know so much about them?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know because until last night, I was on their side.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael considers Jeep, then:</context>
      <utterance>You mean you're...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not anymore...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right and yesterday I was the fuckin' Easter Bunny. You know, fuck this. I don't even believe in God.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob stares at Michael, uncertain how to respond to that.</context>
      <utterance>That's fine, because He doesn't believe in you either.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Bob. Have you looked outside recently? Those aren't exactly our regular customers out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do we know he didn't bring them here himself?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Audrey hesitantly approaches Michael.</context>
      <utterance>He brings them here and then he saves us from them? You're a genius, Bob. Bob falls silent, confounded.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're here to protect us?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie reacts in shock, as all eyes are suddenly on her.</context>
      <utterance>Not you...  Her.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me?! Why me?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In response to that, Charlie does the only thing someone can do when told such a thing. She LAUGHS.</context>
      <utterance>Because your child is the only hope humanity has of surviving.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Michael isn't joking and Charlie's laughter becomes genuine fear.</context>
      <utterance>No way!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode>STUNNED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeep stares at Charlie, as if suddenly his entire life is starting to make sense.</context>
      <utterance>Exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're sayin' she's the mother of the Messiah?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute, isn't Mary supposed to be a vi--</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go fuck yourself, Bob!</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Makes you wonder about Mary.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, this is not possible! I'm just a waitress! I'm nobody! I can't give birth to the Savior of Mankind!  I don't even own a car!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>None of that matters anymore. Either your child lives or Mankind dies.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what, we're supposed to just hold those things off until Mary over there squeezes one out?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That can't be. I'm only eight months pregnant.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh we're fucked. We are so fucked!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are we supposed to survive here for a month?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At this Charlie goes white, the realization hitting her.</context>
      <utterance>We won't have to...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie sways on her feet. Jeep rests a hand on her shoulder, steadying her. With a CLANK Michael re-arms his weapon, turns to the group with finality.</context>
      <utterance>It's coming soon, isn't it? Michael nods.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you want to live you'll do what I say. This first attack was a test of our strength. The next one will be a test of our weakness.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>Everyone exchanges terrified looks. Finally, Kyle steps forward.</context>
      <utterance>Something much worse is on its way.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, what's your plan?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeep looks anxiously at Charlie, silent, scared, and then he follows after Michael, leaving Charlie to stare at the SHATTERED WINDOW, the blinds flipping wildly in the wind.</context>
      <utterance>We'll keep watch on the roof in shifts of two. Jeep, go get some tools. We need to close up this window before somebody else goes out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're out there. Sons of bitches. I can feel `em.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>Percy makes the unconscious motion of rubbing his "hands" together to keep them warm. Kyle notices. Sees the dog tags.</context>
      <utterance>Damn it's cold!</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were in the Army?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Navy, two tours. But the second one didn't work out so well, so I didn't get to go back for a third. Suppose that makes me lucky in a way. Served with Bob, you know. That's how I ended up in this place.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was it like? Being in a war?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kyle nods. Scared. He takes out his 45. Nervously switches it from hand to hand.</context>
      <utterance>Dark. Like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's with that gun?</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your piece. The one you killed grandma with. Don't reckon it's for huntin' buck.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I uh -- keep it for protection.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Protection from what?</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Percy looks at him skeptically.</context>
      <utterance>From people.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, people who might try to give me a hard time, you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just regular people or uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, no, not regular, regular people.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Irregular people then.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm talkin' people whose job it is to give other people a hard time. Kinda person who doesn't get enough fiber in their diet, you know what I'm sayin?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So it's a work thing, is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly. Strictly business.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kyle's eyes narrow.</context>
      <utterance>This business of yours... You like it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Percy just stares at him, penetrating. Finally:</context>
      <utterance>Who the fuck are you to be sweatin' me, man? I got my reasons for doin' what I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kyle looks at Percy, fear in his eyes, then he turns back to the darkness...and the evil that surrounds them.</context>
      <utterance>When I was a kid my father would sit by my bed every night before I'd go to sleep and he'd say to me, Percy, if you don't wake up tomorrow, if it turns out that today was your last day on earth, would you be proud of what you've done in this life? Cuz if you ain't, then you better start gettin' square.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks up at him. Smiles weakly. Takes a sip.</context>
      <utterance>On the house.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You hungry?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Couldn't eat if my life depended on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandra takes another sip of beer. Considers it.</context>
      <utterance>Well I figure just cuz the world's coming to an end, it doesn't mean a man's gotta starve. All I can say is thank heavens they left the gas on.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The moment the words leave her mouth, the grief hits her again. She gathers up some pills from the counter, tosses them back and downs her beer like there's no tomorrow. This is a battle she's losing.</context>
      <utterance>Never much cared for beer. Howard's the beer drinker in the family.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you do...you know, before you came here...? Michael considers the question a beat, then:</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was a soldier, a general, in His army.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what changed? What made you leave?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael drives the last nail into place, securing the window.</context>
      <utterance>I was given an order I didn't believe in...  He lost faith. I hadn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael pauses a beat, as if unsure how much to say, then:</context>
      <utterance>So what happens to you...after this is over?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael picks up his gun.</context>
      <utterance>Sometimes we have to face the thing we fear the most in order to be free of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael heads for the roof, leaving Jeep to stare after him, deep in thought.</context>
      <utterance>It's almost time for the next shift.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandra freezes.</context>
      <utterance>Sandra...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat then:</context>
      <utterance>Who's there?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandra spins around. Searching.</context>
      <utterance>Sandra...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It sure sounded like Howard.</context>
      <utterance>Howard? Is that you?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This time, it's clear where the voice is coming from. Sandra turns to face the BACK DOOR. A desk blocks it. Sandra ever so slowly approaches the door.</context>
      <utterance>Help me... Please...</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandra is stricken. What the hell is she going to do? That's when Sandra notices the TRANSOM WINDOW above the door. She climbs onto the desk and stretches up until she can see out.</context>
      <utterance>Help me. Sandra...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Howard's torn open shirt reveals the BREATHING PUSTULES covering his body. He writhes in slow, excruciating agony.</context>
      <utterance>Help me, please!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandra scrambles down off the desk and frantically pushes it away from the door. She's reaching for the dead bolt when Audrey and Kyle appear in the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>Howard!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kyle races to restrain Sandra.</context>
      <utterance>Mom!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me go! He's alive!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should get back out there...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeep nods, quietly leaves his father at the side of his dead friend.</context>
      <utterance>Just gimme another minute with him, okay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLEARER. Yes. It's a VOICE!</context>
      <utterance>Hey...</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone drops what they're doing and quickly gathers around the radio.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! You guys, I think I got something here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>RADIO VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... battling has been fierce. The numbers of casualties are unknown but all indications are that they must be unimaginably large.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're just joining us, we're getting some of the first bits of good news, if you can call it that, since this apocalypse began just twenty-four ago. A human militia has formed on the outskirts of Las Vegas and has begun to engage the enemy. Also down in the Four Corners area, we've been receiving unconfirmed reports of another resistance force gathering in Red Rock National in the northern Mojave Desert area.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Red Rock...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That can't be more than an hour up the highway from here.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does that mean we can leave?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. We're not going anywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you talkin' about? This is our chance!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob looks over at Charlie, defeated. She shakes her head, anger building. She sweeps some plates off the counter and races for the bathroom.</context>
      <utterance>We can't risk being on the move when the child comes. It's too dangerous.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... And as we fight this new enemy, may God give us the strength to survive and show mercy for those of us who are already lost...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Charlie looks up to see Jeep sit down across from her.</context>
      <utterance>Guess it's your turn not to sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeep sees the strain on her face.</context>
      <utterance>Hey...</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeep smiles, nods.</context>
      <utterance>You mean besides the fact that I just found out that I'm the mother of the Messiah?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crazy thing is...I didn't want this baby. I even went down to the clinic, you know that?  I remember sitting there in the waiting room, absolutely sure I was doin' the right thing...And that's when the feeling started. Like I was falling into the deepest, darkest hole imaginable. I couldn't breathe, I couldn't speak. I kept thinking this must be what death is like. And when finally they called my name, I ran.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>A long beat, as Jeep considers her, then:</context>
      <utterance>For a while after that I tried pretending that it was just cold feet, that I could go back if I wanted to, that I could decide to end it like I'd planned. Then I'd start to have that feeling again and I knew I didn't have a choice. Somehow this had already been decided. And it made me hate this thing that's been growing inside me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to him, the bitterness overtaking her:</context>
      <utterance>You shouldn't say things like that, Charlie. It isn't right. You'll get through this. I know you will.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeep's face hardens. He gets up. Hurt. Frustrated.</context>
      <utterance>How come you have so much faith in me, Jeep? God knows I've never given you or anybody else a reason to. Or is it that you just can't find any other hard-luck case to follow around?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Then you just flip this -- Audrey flips the safety.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She points the gun out into the haze like she's been holding one all her life. Off Kyle's surprised look:</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I got it. All the way down. Two clicks.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parents hated him.</context>
      <utterance>Dated this guy last summer. A marine. Had a thing for guns.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a moment, Audrey switches the safety back on. Hands the gun over to Kyle. Audrey stares into the red nothingness surrounding them. Her expression growing distant. She seems to have aged years overnight.</context>
      <utterance>I bet they did.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's why we were moving.</context>
      <utterance>My parents hate everything I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kyle considers her thoughtfully.</context>
      <utterance>They thought a more "wholesome" environment would help me "change my ways." So fucked up. Only reason they care at all is cuz they don't want to be embarrassed in front of their friends at the country club.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The only time my old man ever paid attention to me was when I was doing somethin' bad. So you know what I did?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles at this confession. Can obviously relate. He wipes a tear from her cheek. She leans in. Kisses him. Passionately. Desperately. His hands trace over her body. She claws at him. Her passion growing out of control. She's practically devouring him. Kyle can barely keep up. It's like something else beyond sensual need has taken over. She moves down his chest. Further. Kyle leans his head back. Further. Just then the SPOT LIGHTS that illuminate the roof sign come to life. The young couple stops to look up at the brilliant red word "Paradise" illuminated above them. Down below, the gas pumps LIGHT UP. The station's FLUORESCENTS flicker on.</context>
      <utterance>I got really good at being bad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We back in business?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it over?</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEADLIGHTS appear on the highway.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You better get downstairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kyle stares at Audrey's beautiful, determined face. Then he pulls out his silver 45.</context>
      <utterance>No, I can handle it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The headlights become a FAMILY MINIVAN careening wildly off the highway to stop at the pumps.</context>
      <utterance>Just in case.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They aim their weapons at the vehicle. A well dressed MAN in his mid-thirties jumps out of the car. He looks around nervously, scared. Then, seeing that the coast is clear, he offers a calming wave to his WIFE and YOUNG BOY who wait anxiously for him inside the car.</context>
      <utterance>Get ready.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A distant SCREECH from behind. Kyle and Audrey spin to look out over the back side of the diner. AN ARMY OF DARK SHAPES are swarming in fast. Kyle looks urgently back at the family. The father lifts the pump. Flips the lever.</context>
      <utterance>Kyle, are they...</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kyle and Audrey wave their arms frantically at the family.</context>
      <utterance>It's a trap. They saw them coming and turned on the lights. It's a fucking trap!</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE AND AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But down below, the man can only hear the sound of RAGING WIND as he pumps the gas. Kyle fires his gun in the air. BLAM! BLAM! BLAM! At the sound of gunfire, the man looks quickly up to the roof. His family heard it too and they start to SCREAM TO HIM. The man can only see silhouettes in this light, but he's not waiting around to see if it's friend or foe. Audrey watches in horror as the dark shapes reach the diner.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Get back in your car! It's a trap!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The father dashes to the driver's side. He throws open the door. But he's too late. He looks over his shoulder just in time to see a BLUR OF MOVEMENT RUSHING AT HIM. His BLOOD PAINTS the car windows. Kyle raises his MP5 to fire upon the dark shapes that surround the vehicle like swarming insects. The wife and boy scream hysterically as they are torn from the vehicle by skeletal hands.</context>
      <utterance>They're not gonna make it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>So Kyle makes a desperately courageous play. He leaps onto the roof's sloped overhang -- sliding fast -- he drops to the ground in front of the diner.</context>
      <utterance>Wait! You'll hit them too!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kyle charges the dark mob. Creatures peel away from the woman and boy to confront Kyle head-on. He lets loose with a rain of bullets, eviscerating everything that comes at him.</context>
      <utterance>Kyle!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ, what the hell is that boy doin'!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob springs into action. Pushes the booth away from the front door. The sound of a gun COCKING. Bob looks over to see Michael pointing a gun at his head.</context>
      <utterance>We have to get `im back in here!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't. You open that door and we could all be dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kyle moves on to the mother. But something odd is happening. The creatures have stopped coming at him. In fact, they're just standing there watching him. Waiting. Kyle freezes. CLOSE ON HIM as he senses something terribly wrong.</context>
      <utterance>I got you!</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG BOY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Kyle looks over at the boy in his arms. GHOSTLY WHITE EYES stare back at him.</context>
      <utterance>Mister...</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG BOY</speaker>
      <mode>WHISPERS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fooled ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kyle!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn it all to hell!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Out the window they see Audrey drop down from the roof and run towards Kyle.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no. Audrey...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>YOUNG BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry! I didn't mean to!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Audrey raises the 45 and ... CLICK. CLICK. CLICK. She keeps pulling the trigger. Nothing. The boy's tears stop instantly. He looks at her with an eerie calm for someone so young.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you!</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy moves toward Audrey, stepping over Kyle's body. Audrey backs away. She looks toward the entrance to the diner. Blocked by advancing creatures. They're everywhere. She's trapped. She notices the open door to the MINIVAN. And so she BOLTS. Audrey dives into the car as the throng of creatures rapidly closes in. She hammers the auto door lock. CLUNK! She moves to the center of the car as gruesome faces press against the windows. A nightmare come to life.</context>
      <utterance>You're gonna die now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he's immovable.</context>
      <utterance>Do you have no heart?! She's just a kid!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(grabbing a gun from the</context>
      <utterance>You can't let her die!</utterance>
   <speaker>TABLE)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie COCKS the gun, moves toward the door.</context>
      <utterance>I swear if you don't do something, I will!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meanwhile, fire is spreading quickly under the car... Michael pulls Audrey from the flaming vehicle.</context>
      <utterance>Come with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Run.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Michael!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BURSTING OUT OF THE FLAMES, Michael marches confidently into the diner. Jeep slams the door CLOSED just as the WALL OF</context>
      <utterance>Get back!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>YOUNG BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's it. She's backed against the end of the counter! The boy raises the knife to strike. Charlie grabs a baking pan off a shelf. Swings it out in front of her body like a shield, as the KNIFE IS DRIVEN DOWN. CLANG! The knife hits the pan hard and stops. But the boy's hands don't. They slip off the handle and run right down the blade. The knife CLATTERS to the ground. The boy instinctively raises his hands to strike again, but there's no knife. Charlie watches in horror as the boy calmly realizes that his THUMBS ARE MISSING. Blood sprays from the stumps. Charlie pulls her legs in close then rockets them out at the boy's chest. He's catapulted away from her. Michael leaps over the counter, landing in front of Charlie, guns ready for action. But the boy is gone.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, don't be scared. I just wanna play with your baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie shakes her head no.</context>
      <utterance>Are you hurt?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's when the electricity goes out once again, PLUNGING THE</context>
      <utterance>Where is he?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JEEP'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LIGHTING under chairs. Under tables.</context>
      <utterance>He's still in here! FLASHLIGHT BEAMS fan out across the diner.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A SCAMPERING SOUND... MOVING FAST. Everybody spins to track the location of the sound.</context>
      <utterance>Where the fuck is he?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeep can't get a clear shot. Bob's gasping for air. Michael grabs the boy and fiercely rips him off of Bob's back. He swings the boy around like a living shot put.</context>
      <utterance>Dad!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeep and Bob whip up their guns as Michael throws the wicked creature into the air. Sandra's vacant face flickers in the light as the SOUND OF GUNFIRE AND INHUMAN SCREAMING fill the diner. And then in moments... All is QUIET. BEHIND THE COUNTER, Audrey helps Charlie to her feet. She WINCES. Doubles over, clutching her stomach.</context>
      <utterance>Get ready!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael lowers his flashlight. CLEAR FLUID runs down Charlie's legs.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What am I supposed to do? Just `cause I'm a girl doesn't mean I automatically know how to do this!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just do as I say.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but, how do you know how to do this?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a way to bring a child into the world.  She ever tell you his name?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob hears the spite in Jeep's voice.</context>
      <utterance>She's never said. I just assumed it was Joe Danvers. You know how she's always had a thing for bad boys.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeep, sooner or later she'll realize you're the best thing that's ever happened to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you said I should move on?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeep considers Bob with a smile, then comes the sound... A DEEP, LONG, BODY RUMBLING TONE rising up off the plain, as if emanating from the largest HORN ever constructed.</context>
      <utterance>Can't a father be wrong sometimes?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SPECTRAL LIGHTS dot the landscape now with untold numbers.</context>
      <utterance>What was that...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is that?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's coming. We have to hurry.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's coming? Whaddya mean hurry? This isn't something you can exactly hurry, is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charlie, I need you to push. I need you to push as hard as you can.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie pushes, tears streaming down her face, delirious with pain. It's a gruesome, bloody affair. It's getting close.</context>
      <utterance>Michael, who's coming?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're almost there...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob looks at his son. The agony stretched across his face.</context>
      <utterance>We're not gonna make it outta here, are we?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeep rests a comforting hand on his father's shoulder. Bob pulls his son close and hugs him with all his might, tears filling his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry Jeep. This shouldn't be happening to you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Audrey places the child in Charlie's arms. She stares at the baby, holding it at a distance, unsure of whether to embrace it or be terrified by it. A commitment she's not yet ready to make, even at this late hour.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my god...we did it! Charlie, you did it!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode>CONFUSED</mode>
      <context>Charlie looks to Audrey, tears streaming down her face.</context>
      <utterance>It's okay. The baby's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Audrey looks to Michael, unsure.</context>
      <utterance>I don't...I...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Audrey nods, takes the baby back from Charlie, tries to soothe him by pacing around the diner.</context>
      <utterance>Take him... Give her a minute.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another DRONE OF THE HORN RATTLES THE WALLS. Menacing. Closer. Audrey reacts, crosses to the counter, turns on the radio, trying to drown out the sound of the approaching menace. Out of the STATIC, the haunting sounds of BING CROSBY singing SILENT NIGHT fills the room. The quiet before the storm. Michael helps Charlie quickly clean herself up. She stares at him, a burning spite in her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>It's okay...It's okay...Shhh...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So are we safe now? Is it over?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Those words provide her little comfort.</context>
      <utterance>No. Killing the child would have ended the war before it had begun. Now, at least, he will have a chance to grow up, a chance to lead the world out of darkness.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what happens until then...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie shakes her head, this is all too much.</context>
      <utterance>You'll need to teach him how.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What makes you think I can do that? What makes you think I want to do that? If he's so important, why don't you take him?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Off Charlie's look, we move across the diner where Audrey approaches her mother, kneels down in front of her. Despite how much her mother pisses her off, it breaks her heart to see her in such a demoralized state.</context>
      <utterance>Each of us has a burden. This one is yours and yours alone. Maybe someday you'll understand what that means.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mama? Can you hear me?  We did it...The baby's alive.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Someone like me.</context>
      <utterance>The Possessed can't come near the child, so He sent someone that can.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON JEEP as the realization hits him.</context>
      <utterance>Gabriel. My lieutenant. He's come to do what I wouldn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael looks at Jeep.</context>
      <utterance>Your orders...</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael nods grimly. Charlie looks urgently at Michael.</context>
      <utterance>You were the one who was supposed to kill the baby? That was the order you didn't obey.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The baby CRIES LOUDER.</context>
      <utterance>What's he talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Michael, what the hell's he talking about?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie, shaken by this revelation, reaches out to Audrey.</context>
      <utterance>There was never meant to be a Second Coming. But we've just changed that. The child lives. The future is unwritten. There's still hope.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Audrey moves to hand over the baby to Charlie...</context>
      <utterance>Audrey...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay away from me! Don't come any closer!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't do it, lady!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael cocks his gun. Points it at Sandra.</context>
      <utterance>You heard what he said. They just want the baby. Maybe if we just give it to them, then they'll let us go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give him to me!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie stares at her in horror, the truth of those words rattling her to the very core.</context>
      <utterance>Why?! You never wanted him in the first place!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandra is almost to the front door.</context>
      <utterance>No... I...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just one baby. Just one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a sweep of his hand, Gabriel sends Bob flying across the diner where he crashes down behind the counter near the stove. Michael GRABS JEEP'S HAND before the boy can rush back into the fray.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Jeep! You must protect the child now!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me?! What about you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeep shakes his head, panic setting in.</context>
      <utterance>My path ends here. You are the true protector. You always have been.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I don't know what to do!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael lets go of Jeep's hand and turns away to face Gabriel, leaving Jeep to contemplate those final words.</context>
      <utterance>Find the Prophets. Learn to read the instructions.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And that's when Jeep opens his hand to find the KEYS to Michael's Police Cruiser. Jeep looks up from the keys to see Charlie, Audrey and the baby. The responsibility crashing in on him. Then he closes his hand around the keys, determination building.</context>
      <utterance>Prophets? What Prophets? What instructions?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait! We can't leave him!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls Charlie past the counter toward the back office. Jeep stops when he sees his father's broken body lying on the ground by the stove in a pool of his own blood. Bob's half open eyes focus on his son. In his outstretched hand is that goddamn ZIPPO LIGHTER... and next to that, a BROKEN GAS PIPE leading to the stove. Jeep is terrified.</context>
      <utterance>We have no choice! We have to get to Red Rock!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeep tries to help him up.</context>
      <utterance>Dad!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave me, Jeep. My place is here, remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob smiles weakly at his son and says simply:</context>
      <utterance>But Dad...!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And so Jeep, fighting back tears, does what his father says.</context>
      <utterance>Run.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew he'd send you, Gabriel. You were always so eager to please Him.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unlike you...the rebellious son.  Pity about your wings. They would have helped you now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To not feel their burden...is a dream.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think you can defy Him and not pay the price?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The child lives. What happens to me doesn't matter now.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yours is a fool's sacrifice. You can help them sneak out the back door, but they won't escape.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>Michael slowly approaches Gabriel.</context>
      <utterance>And neither will you, brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>SOFT</mode>
      <context>Gabriel hesitates, doubt clouding his face. This was not what he was expecting.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not running anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>SENSING</mode>
      <context>A beat, then Gabriel's expression hardens.</context>
      <utterance>Join with me. You don't need do this. There's another way.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls back from Michael, raising the mace -- SCHING! -- LONG DEADLY SHARP SPIKES BURSTS FROM ALL ITS SIDES...as if it wasn't bad-ass enough. And the fight begins.</context>
      <utterance>There is no other way...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Jeep!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeep gives it some gas, but the ENGINE'S NOT CATCHING. A DARK SHAPE POUNCES ONTO THE HOOD OF THE CAR. The light catches it, revealing the disfigured face and beard of a SHOPPING MALL SANTA CLAUS, his oversized belly gruesomely distended. Charlie screams.</context>
      <utterance>I'm trying!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeep pumps the gas and the ENGINE BURSTS TO LIFE! The creature's about to punch a fist through the glass</context>
      <utterance>Fuck!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>throwing the car in</utterance>
   <speaker>REVERSE)</speaker>
      <mode> REVERSE)</mode>
      <context>Jeep floors it, causing the cruiser to rocket backwards toward the highway.</context>
      <utterance>Hang on!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeep places his Glock on the dash. He sees that he's got a police issue shotgun in the front seat rack. Charlie searches under her seat. Pulls out a...GRENADE.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, we need to figure out our weapon situation. Hopefully Michael didn't take everything out of the car.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this what I think it is?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Audrey fishes around in the backseat.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Now just put it down... Slowly. Charlie places it onto the seat.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, all I got is a flare gun thing. Looks like we got a box of flares to go with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Okay. Handgun. Shotgun. A a flare gun... And a grenade. Alright.  Load this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Audrey, can you figure out how to load that flare gun without killing us all?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can try.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Audrey anxiously sets about loading the flare gun.</context>
      <utterance>Try real hard, okay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go faster!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie's desperately trying to soothe her SCREAMING baby. ON THE AIR VENTS as FLIES start crawling in.</context>
      <utterance>I can't fuckin' see!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, no.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeep sees it, eyes go wide.</context>
      <utterance>Jeep, your arm!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat, as Jeep remembers Michael's parting words...</context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Up front Jeep stares out at the dark road ahead.</context>
      <utterance>I can't believe it. Is it really over...?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No...It's just starting...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie looks over, feels his lingering anger.</context>
      <utterance>Better not hold him too long. Might get attached.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I'm sorry for what I said to you earlier, `bout you following me around. I didn't mean it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeep tries to hide his pleasure that the tables have turned at least a little. Charlie is about to respond when Audrey leans in from the back seat.</context>
      <utterance>Nothin' to be sorry about. It's true. I did follow you around. At least now I know there was a good reason. Charlie's reacts, a bit stung.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She points ahead to a beaten up road sign that says: "Now Entering Red Rock National Park, Next Rest Stop 30</context>
      <utterance>We're here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AUDREY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeep swings the gun around.</context>
      <utterance>Jeep!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BLAM! Gabriel takes one in the shoulder, but it doesn't slow him down.</context>
      <utterance>Duck!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Audrey desperately tries to load a flare while avoiding Gabriel's grasp. Jeep can't get off another shot without the risk of hitting Audrey. Gabriel is almost entirely in the car now. Audrey swings the flare gun toward Gabriel, but he knocks her hand aside just as she pulls the trigger and the flare goes off INSIDE THE CAR! Jeep ducks. The CAR SWERVES MADLY. The flare RICOCHETS through the cabin, lighting it up like the Fourth of July! Gabriel lunges for Charlie just as the flare bounces off the windshield - PING! - and nails him right in the face, SETTING</context>
      <utterance>Audrey, the flare gun!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kicks open her door and begins pulling him out.</context>
      <utterance>Jeep!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The baby?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what about...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing could have survived that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode>ANGUISHED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Audrey...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie, the baby bundled in her hands, leads Jeep away from the demolished Cruiser.</context>
      <utterance>She saved us, Jeep. Audrey saved us. Now c'mon, we gotta go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can this happen?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeep shifts his eyes to the TOP OF THE RIDGE just ahead.</context>
      <utterance>How can this happen in a world so beautiful? Jeep follows her gaze to the sky. Endless stars. Confounding.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeep's feet dangle. His eyes bulge out. He claws at Gabriel's iron-fast grip, but there's no hope. Charlie watches in horror.</context>
      <utterance>So brave. So pointless. You should have worried more about saving yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Gabriel is doing just that. Jeep is rapidly losing consciousness. The battle is lost.</context>
      <utterance>Stop! Please! Don't kill him!</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeep's eyes flutter. He's almost gone.</context>
      <utterance>Go to sleep...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie climbs to her feet, holding the bloody bundle out to him.</context>
      <utterance>Stop it! I'LL GIVE YOU THE BABY! This gets Gabriel's attention.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tears run down her face. She's dead fucking serious. Gabriel lets go of Jeep. He falls to the ground, gasping desperately for air.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want this responsibility!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel takes the bundle from Charlie, turning away from her.</context>
      <utterance>Charlie, no!</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"And as the child's cries are extinguished, an eternal darkness at last descended upon the world." He peels the cloth back, revealing...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE GRENADE.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's holding the pin.</context>
      <utterance>He spins around to face Charlie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We made it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now we see it too:</context>
      <utterance>Yep, we sure did.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances at Charlie. Worry in her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sure they're just over the next ridge.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if we're on our own now?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be afraid. We'll be okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEEP</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>At those words, Charlie looks deep into Jeep's eyes. Sees a confidence in them she's never seen before. And she leans in and kisses him. Tender. When they part, Jeep stares back at her with surprise. Then the surprise melts into a smile. And they descend the ridge...out of sight, leaving us with a view once again of --</context>
      <utterance>Believe me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHARLIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie sits across from him, the baby cradled in her arms. It's strange, but you might actually mistake them for a happy family. Of course you'll have to ignore the ARSENAL OF WEAPONRY in the back seat.</context>
      <utterance>... And how just at the moment when everything seemed lost...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jeep glances over at Charlie and the baby. He smiles at the image of maternal bliss.</context>
      <utterance>...a mighty warrior fell in order to save me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The sun shines through the car windows, filling our eyes with its fiery light.</context>
      <utterance>And a boy faced his fear and rose up to save us all.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
