<movie id="347" title="Leviathan">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Burritos...Enchiladas...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, gag, man, how can you eat that stuff?...</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK'S VOICE/ RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause, then more voices.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, cut the chatter. You're not out of here, yet. Who's the hook? Seven?...You got a hook on container 22?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIXPACK'S VOICE/ RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The man's asking if you're hooked on 22, you dumb shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES' VOICE/ RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A light flares out of the darkness, suddenly illuminating an IMMENSE SHAPE--fifteen hundred pounds of hardened metal nearly seven feet tall. It is a motorized diving suit and we see the stenciled name, WILLIE across the front breastplate. As it pivots we see the stationary worklights around the base of a large underwater mining operation, THE SHACK. Then a woman's voice.</context>
      <utterance>Watch your mouth, Sixpack. Hello, Shack, Seven, here. I ain't the hook, over.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six to Shack. I'm the hook.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SIXPACK'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Willie, you trip on a tit or something? We're all waiting on you, honey.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six to Shack...Hook's on. Ready to winch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly a red warning light begins blinking in the bottom corner inside DeJesus' helmet. The words to the song freeze in his mouth. His voice becomes edged with panic. DEJESUS(cont'd) Oh, shit...</context>
      <utterance>...beer after beer...</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES/ RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Hazy, I'm not that bad, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck! Doc! Help me!...</context>
      <utterance>Jonesy! I'm losing compression... I'm going to blow my suit, man!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me a readout, DeJesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode>ON RADIO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahhhh!</utterance>
   <speaker>OUTSIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The other divers move quickly to DeJesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode>ON RADIO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>DeJesus! A readout!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He don't need a readout, man, he needs help!</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode>RADIO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay calm!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Calm!? Where's Doc?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Doc?!</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode>RADIO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not at his station.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, mother of Jesus, forgive me of my--</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DeJesus' gauges begins a countdown to implosion. "15, 14, 13..." DeJesus is grabbed by his co-workers and hurried the last few yards to the SHACK.</context>
      <utterance>Get him into the Shack.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BOWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm telling you, it's the suits!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck the suits, it's the people monitoring them. It Doc had been there like he's supposed to it never would've happened!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIXPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sixpack looks over the group, then suddenly crushes the empty Coke can in his hand, punctuating the action with a huge belch. SIXPACK(cont'd) That would have been you, DeJesus... DeJesus keeps his head down. SIXPACK(cont'd) Yeah...I was standing next to a guy who blew a suit once in the Indian Ocean...little tiny hole in the fucking toe of his suit ...ocean came in and the pressure crammed his whole fucking body up into his helmet. They just buried his helmet.</context>
      <utterance>And just what the fuck would he have done to stop it, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know all about implosion, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIXPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DeJesus springs for Sixpack's throat AS WE CUT TO</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I bet you do.  I bet you were imploding in your pants.  Jonesy! Doc!...Help me! Help me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck glares, ready for an argument, but as WE PULL BACK we see he's talking to the mirror, in his tiny quarters. Apparently he fails to convince himself because his hard look fades and he mutters unhappily as he turns away.</context>
      <utterance>Knock it off, Sixpack! I know it's been a long month for every- one, but we can't let something like this tear us apart...</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns around to face a smiling picture of himself at college graduation with his Eastern establishment looking father. Leadership "how-to" books like</context>
      <utterance>Shit...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just as suddenly as it began the GROANING NOISE STOPS and in its place WE HEAR an intermittent RATTLE in the air system. Only Cobb seems undisturbed by this sound.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck the suits man...this place is going to kill us first.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There it is again...  Two more days. I tell myself 'you can make it two more days--'</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the weather like up top?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clear for pickup.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb looks up disgustingly.</context>
      <utterance>Let's hope it holds.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what? Huh?  Then what? You folks think going up top's the answer to all your problems. Well, it ain't.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give us a break, Cobb...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A break? You folks don't need a break, you need psychiatrists. 'Know what you'd be doing if you were up there, right now?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIXPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eating pussy and drinking brew...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eating pussy my ass. What about lines at the bank: What about getting stuck in traffic?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIXPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone laughs but Cobb, WE SEE he's serious.</context>
      <utterance>Wherever I can find it.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bullshit! I'll tell you what you'd be doing! You'd be watching news on TV that's so fucking bad it makes you nauseous. So you go out and get in your car to get some fresh air and after you've been driving for five minutes you realize the air's so damn dirty you don't dare breath it! That's what you've got to look forward to...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doc eat already?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looks are exchanged. Sixpack smirks knowingly.</context>
      <utterance>The good doctor hasn't showed yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you feel, DeJesus?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better let the Doc take a look at you, after dinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIXPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He cracks up and Beck turns on him.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, since he was busy earlier when you needed him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sixpack shuts up, but Beck notices the others feel the seriousness of Doc's absence during the emergency. BECK(cont'd) Leave the Doc to me. I'm going to talk to him.</context>
      <utterance>Cut it, Sixpack.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIXPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck gets his tray but it is clear he is thinking about something else. He clears his throat.</context>
      <utterance>'Makes me feel better already...</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been looking at the duty roster...at the shack hours outstanding...</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, oh...I see where this is going...</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...all of you owe time and I thought tonight would be a good time to---</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way, Mister Beck!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIXPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Company got to abide by the rules.</context>
      <utterance>Hear that Becky, er, Mr. Beck?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This leaves the group momentarily speechless. Even DeJesus comes out of his stupor.</context>
      <utterance>I know all about the contract. The point is you can follow the goddamn contract to the letter and pull your shack duty tomorrow...or you can get it done tonight and call tomorrow a down day. It's up to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck nods. Cobb eyes him suspiciously.</context>
      <utterance>You giving us a day off?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about our quota?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others look around for agreement but Jones doesn't need anyone else's approval, he's already made up his mind.</context>
      <utterance>You're only twenty-five tons off quota. Barring an unforeseen problem you should reach it easily on the last day.  It's just a day off. You don't have to take it, I just thought it might help.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bowman nods her head also and the others unanimously agree. Buoyed, Beck moves ahead, businesslike...</context>
      <utterance>Count me in.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cobb, Jones, I want you to do something about that damn rattle in the air system...  Bowman and Sixpack...living quarters...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIXPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit...</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sixpack suddenly looks up as the group disperses.</context>
      <utterance>Williams...get DeJesus' suit on the "sick rack" and do a diagnostics.  Any other suit problems she should know about?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIXPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My pocket. Check my pocket, will ya, honey?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your pocket?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIXPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The latch is screwed up. Or the hinge.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did good...</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Today...with DeJesus. That was smart thinking to get him inside...</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There probably wasn't anything wrong with his suit...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns off toward the Swamp, leaving Beck with the tiny, but honest compliment. He savors it.</context>
      <utterance>Still...you did the right thing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck looks on the cabinet and sees a bottle of Old Granddad Whiskey. He picks it up. DOC(cont'd) Snakebite medicine...Never pack my bag without it. Beck doesn't smile. He puts the bottle back down and Doc watches him in the mirror.</context>
      <utterance>I must have dozed off.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you planning on working tomorrow?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'll be on the golf course in the morning. Then, if I don't have any babies to deliver--</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Doc stops buttoning his shirt and locks eyes with Beck.</context>
      <utterance>We almost had an accident today. DeJesus' suit...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck definitely has something to say, but confronted, he falters.</context>
      <utterance>You got something to say to me, son?...</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc smiles, and goes back to buttoning his shirt.</context>
      <utterance>I...I think it's important to have the second officer on deck.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll keep it to nine holes in the morning.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SIXPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ...what a pair...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was that? What'd you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIXPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said, "What a pair" the boy wonder Shack Boss and his drunken doctor buddy make...  Why? What did ya think I said?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to it for Christsake.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls a retractable ladder from inside the hole and drops it down into the wet darkness, without hesitating he climbs down, stopping at the bottom to look up at Jones. Jones seems in no hurry to accompany him. COBB(cont'd) You gonna sit there on your butt or give me a hand? Jones reluctantly starts down after him.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, it's just old, like me. You don't see the Doc opening me up every time I get a new creak in my joints...I say, as long as it's recycling the air let the next shift deal with it. But, 'long as we're here...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two hundred and fifty-two tons of Magnesium and 15 tons of Sodium.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds like a good week, Beck. In fact...I put your folder in front of the Vice President of District Operations last night... Beck stops. Martin notices his concern. MARTIN You're good executive timber, Beck. A lot of management trainees wash out when they have to go under for their first tour. But you've done well.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Martin.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares hard at Beck, but doesn't wait for an answer. MARTIN(cont'd) The one thing I've learned in this company is you can't have enough friends. It's the only way to survive.</context>
      <utterance>Don't thank me, yet, but it is important to know where you're going and who your friends are... 'Know what I mean?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So that's all you do?...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shhhh...don't tell no one.  Job security.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Made your million, yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This causes Bowman to turn and look at Willie.</context>
      <utterance>How's TransOcean doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got money in this tub?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bowman shakes her head and goes back to the computer and types in TransOcean Corp.</context>
      <utterance>I signed-up for the stock option.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fifty-four!</context>
      <utterance>Hey, man, you know that in Switzerland--and this country's the size of East L.A., okay?--they speak 54 different dialects?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who cares?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up and sees Cobb's sunbathing attire and laughs.</context>
      <utterance>I do, man. That's a beautiful place. When I get out of here I'm going there. Find a nice little snow covered chalet, warm little woman, crackling fire--</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Cobb...Man, why don't you take off your shirt and pants, man? You should do that wearing what you're going to wear at the beach.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is what I wear at the beach, goddamnit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BOWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Willie looks at Bowman a moment, then keeps exercising.</context>
      <utterance>"Major development in South Indian Ocean set for fall of 2010..."  That sounds interesting, but they're too tied to their holdings. Remember a year ago when they lost that tanker?... The bottom fell out of their stock and I lost a bloody fortune. That's when I decided to diversify.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You take your money, too seriously, Bo.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're damn right I do. Five years down here and I'll pull in more than 15 topside. I'm not down here for the fun, I'll tell you that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIXPACK'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>They look up to see Sixpack at the door to the Mess wearing only a robe. With a leer he stares at Willie exercising. SIXPACK(cont'd) (saccharine sweet) Hey, Willie, honey...Sorry about that little incident tonight...Everyone's been so tight lately, I thought a little humor'd loosen us all up, you know? Willie doesn't bite, she looks hard at Sixpack.</context>
      <utterance>"Fun?" Somebody talking fun?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sixpack smirks. He waves a copy of Penthouse opened to the Pet of the Month and sings cheerfully.</context>
      <utterance>Get out of here, Sixpack.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Bo...when're you going to be off that thing? I want to find out tonight's NBA scores and check the weather.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The weather's good, I already checked, but I'll be off in a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Jonesy, who's the best power forward in the NBA...Jameson?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They grin at each other--a standing joke and Jones leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Jameson? Who're you trying to con?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DEJESUS catches the can and pops the top sending a shower of carbonation all over Cobb under the sunlamp. JONES(cont'd) How about you, brother Cobb? Little Wild Turkey? Cobb wipes the Coke from his sunglasses and shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Hazy! We got a day off tomorrow, Kemosabi! Let's get shit-faced!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones and DeJesus laugh and take long pulls on their Cokes. Cobb turns and watches them. This is obviously a nightly ritual.</context>
      <utterance>No, man, Cobb is a Chivas drinker, from way back. Ain't that right Cobbie?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys are crazy. What the hell you play that stupid game for?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What game, Cobb?...I'm on my way to Nirvana...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're on your way somewhere all right...the looney bin.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm on the way to the looney bin? Hey, man, I'm not the dude sun bathing in his clothes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SIXPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stirs in the bed and adjusts his pillow and SCREAMS! The SEA SPIDER is suddenly right there on his shoulder, dead. Sixpack sits bolt upright in his bunk and slams his head against the roof of the bunk, then stumbles out screaming. He hits the floor and rams his foot into a table and screams in more pain. The whole dorm looks up amazed, Cobb takes off his sunglasses, even Jones and DeJesus temporarily "sober up" to stare.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Darlin'...come sit on my face...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIXPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That bitch!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SIXPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bitch! Look what you did!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone laughs, but Sixpack. He has revenge in his eyes. He holds out the ugly, limp creature and advances toward Willie.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, darling...Just thought a little humor would loosen us all up...you know?...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIXPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he pushes the dead creature into her face BECK'S VOICE behind him makes him freeze.</context>
      <utterance>You think you're so funny? Wait till you taste this!</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Everybody turns to see Beck standing in the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>That's enough!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIXPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at my foot, sir! This bitch put a goddamn sea monster in my bunk!</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know it was Williams?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIXPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh? I...uh...uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, Sixpack, you and Williams are gonna pull water duty tomorrow--</utterance>
   <speaker>SIXPACK AND WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bullshit! What?! She...He...</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At ease! You both have a half day...Anymore shit and its a full one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Turn down the music.</context>
      <utterance>Oooooh. Damn! Not so loud.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DeJesus enters holding his head and sits on the other side of Cobb.</context>
      <utterance>What music? There ain't no music.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb looks from one man to the other, realizing what they're doing.</context>
      <utterance>Oooooh.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know it's really crazy to pretend to be drunk, but it's fucking insane to pretend to have a hangover.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your "hangovers" made you miss the Sixpack Good Morning Show.  "No goddamn boy is going to make me go out on a down day."</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? How'd the kid hold up?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretty good. He sent them out videotaping outcrop.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charge set?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>RADIO</mode>
      <context>Like a good dog, the ROV follows her to a safe position.</context>
      <utterance>Charge set. Backing off.  C'mon Rover let's get out of here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is no answer. Willie turns around. Her helmet lamp eerily illuminating the darkness around her. Sixpack is nowhere to be seen. WILLIE(cont'd) Sixpack? She turns in the other direction and suddenly blinding lights are turned on.</context>
      <utterance>Roger...  More light, Sixpack...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIXPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sixpack laughs. His lights now on, he stands right behind her.</context>
      <utterance>Boo!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shit....</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on, Four? What's happening?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She again holds out her hand to the ROV.</context>
      <utterance>We're fine, Shack. His lights malfunctioned for a minute. How's this?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You screw around like that again and--</utterance>
   <speaker>SIXPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong, did you miss me?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hardly.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIXPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Sixpack's foot hits some loose rock and slides. Willie turns in his direction and sees his headlight turning, becoming smaller, then disappearing as his radio goes dead.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, darlin, I'm...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then she looks down--a cliff right in front of her feet. The drop is thirty feet into a waving sea of tubers. BECK'S VOICE brings Willie back.</context>
      <utterance>Sixpack?! Sixpack...</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>RADIO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Willie? What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's gone. I think he's fallen. I'm going down after him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones grits his teeth and struggles against the weight, suddenly Bowman throws open the door and sticks her head in.</context>
      <utterance>That's it Jonesy...Sweat it out, man...Got to get the poison out of our blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sixpack is lost.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all enter the</context>
      <utterance>Weren't they tied? They're supposed to be tied.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONTROL ROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beck is at the console with Doc in his chair.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How far away is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WILLIE'S VOICE silences them.</context>
      <utterance>Two hundred meters.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>RADIO</mode>
      <context>They all stare at the monitor. The screen is filled with huge waving tubers.</context>
      <utterance>Four to Shack...nearing the bottom. Look at this...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God, look at the size of those tubers....</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nine, ten feet high...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If he had his blinkers on--</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wouldn't make any difference in there...He could be two feet away and on fire and she'd still not see him!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why can't we pick up his signal?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe he got eaten?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What would be dumb enough to eat Sixpack?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The image on the screen widens and we see the opening is a huge gash in the side of a sunken ship. BECK(cont'd) (to DOC) Tighten the picture on the upper righthand corner. CLOSE ON THE MONITOR: The picture zooms in on the corner and Willie's added light suddenly brings the letter "M" into focus. Beck presses the red record button and pans the ROV slowly across the bulkhead of the ship. The next letter is an "A". Then suddenly a Cyrillic letter appears, then others.</context>
      <utterance>Affirmative...Widening picture.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the?...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Russian.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>RADIO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your air reading?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty minutes...</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty minutes!...Who had tank duty?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who else...Sixpack.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I say, leave him in there.</context>
      <utterance>The man is unbelievable...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about his suit? That's a million five the company's got to replace. They'll make somebody go get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Willie, we're giving you five minutes...after that we're coming in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She throws open another door. It also looks empty, then WHAM! a grotesque ECHONODERM slams into her helmet. Willie bats it aside and as soon as she recovers shines her light into the room. WHAT SHE SEES: The ship's infirmary. Broken glass, stainless steel...the light does strange things, reflecting, sparkling...</context>
      <utterance>Sixpack?...Answer me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode>ON RADIO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The infirmary...</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>RADIO</mode>
      <context>Her helmet-mounted camera pans the room one more time, then as she turns to leave it captures a strange gleam of white in the corner--A LARGE HUMAN-LIKE SKELETON. Willie doesn't see it.</context>
      <utterance>Three minutes...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BECK'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>RADIO</mode>
      <context>Willie hesitates at the junction and PUSHES OPEN the door on her left, SOMETHING HUGE BEHIND IT MOVES--IT'S SIXPACK. His mechanical arms suddenly rise and in their grasp we see the ship's huge safe.</context>
      <utterance>One minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIXPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm rich, honey. Rich!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>SIXPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ain't that right, Cobbie?</context>
      <utterance>It's all mine if I'm on report. Otherwise you gotta take me off report before you look at any more...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DeJesus pries off the top from the first safety deposit box and dumps the contents on the workbench...several wallets, wristwatches, a pocket watch, a wedding ring...Bowman who stands with a clipboard begins taking inventory.</context>
      <utterance>You're on your own, Sixpack, you fucked up everybody's day off...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Personal effects...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She picks up something else, a pack of soggy chewing gum and tosses it to Cobb. WILLIE(cont'd) Here's something for you, Cobbie.</context>
      <utterance>Timex...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'd say you can retire with all this loot.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIXPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone chuckles. More papers and a small, book-shaped object wrapped in plastic. Jones unwraps it. It's a video tape. He looks at the label.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Debbie Does Dallas"...  Hell, it's in Russian. I can't read it...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones hands it to Doc who looks at it. DOC (cont'd) It's a log of some sort. Jones pries the lid off another box and dumps it out--Papers, more cheap watches. ON SIXPACK He notices something silver, the size of a paperback book, under a stack of papers. Discreetly he covers the object with a piece of paper and slides it off the table out of sight. Jones opens the last box, and something rolls across the table toward the edge and starts to drop when it is caught by DeJesus. He holds it up and we see--a clear liquor bottle.</context>
      <utterance>May I see it?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vodka.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What assholes, they lock booze in the safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc turns the bottle around in DeJesus' hand so he can read the label.</context>
      <utterance>Probably confiscated. No booze on board, same as us.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone looks at Doc.</context>
      <utterance>Stolichnaya.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You read Russian?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb stares at him a second then:</context>
      <utterance>Russian, French, Italian, Spanish, Greek, German, a little Hindu, some Serbo Croat and a smattering of Swahili...standard pre-med background...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bullshit.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck ignores them and addresses Bowman.</context>
      <utterance>...and a Russian grandmother...</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lifts the bottle of Stolie out of DeJesus' hands. BECK(cont'd) ...except this...it goes in my safe. A disappointed crew watches Beck leave with the bottle. Doc stops him.</context>
      <utterance>I want all this stuff impounded in the supply safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mind if I take a look at this?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be my guest.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sixpack and Jones are there too. Sixpack scowls.</context>
      <utterance>You got 'em!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIXPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What good's the kid's med records anyway!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watch and learn, amigo...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That it all sounds mysterious?</context>
      <utterance>What do you want me to say?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These observers were doing something. A test...I think they sank that ship on purpose to cover up their mistakes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets up and goes to the door. Doc watches him.</context>
      <utterance>What mistakes?  Look, I think it's no big deal but if you want to find out why this ship sank have Maritime run a check.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck stops. This is a mystery.</context>
      <utterance>I did. They have no record of the wreck.  The Marshal Goloviev is now on a tour in the Baltic Sea.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BOWMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DeJesus puts his fingers back, on the safe dial.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, try the social security number...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, give it to me...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BOWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two...twelve...ninety-six.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIXPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys are so full of shit... Who's going to use their birthday...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SIXPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like I said, that bottle's mine!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONTROL ROOM - SAME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>ON Beck at the door and Doc.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck looks at him. It is obvious that he doesn't trust Doc, with the vodka, but he's diplomatic.</context>
      <utterance>I want your permission to check that vodka.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a mining shack, not a lab, Doc. If there's something strange with the vodka it's safe till we get back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something wrong, Cobb?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh..Excuse me sir, it's the air recirculating system, sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with it?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I'd really have to show it to you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BOWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cute, DeJesus...Specimen cups?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Willie shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>Aw, loosen up, Bowman...  Hey, Willie, I got one served up for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, thanks. I've got my blood tests in three days.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You got to learn to live a little.</context>
      <utterance>That's all you do is exercise.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After my astronaut training physical,</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey what happens it he goes back and finds the bottle missing?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up a plastic IV bag filled with clear liquid. DEJESUS(cont'd) I poured the vodka in here. Cobb, Jones, DeJesus, Bowman, and Sixpack grin and clink glasses, then knock back their vodka. Afterwards we get their reactions. JONES: Looks concerned. BOWMAN: Shakes her head, something's wrong. DEJESUS: Can't get the taste off his tongue. COBB: Seems totally satisfied. SIXPACK: who has held the liquid in his mouth savoring it, suddenly spits the vodka out.</context>
      <utterance>He won't...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIXPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit! It's water!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beck switched it!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Willie grins at her co-workers and Beck's move and jogs out into the corridor. Sixpack disgustedly tosses his shot glass away and leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Can you beat that? The sonof- abitch doesn't trust us!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIXPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others put down their glasses disappointedly except Bowman. She watches Sixpack.</context>
      <utterance>That little turd. If I ever get the chance I'll fix his ass.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was a loud one wasn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves into the Swamp and goes to the Lift Lock, stopping under one of the ladders she leaps up and grabs a metal rung above her and begins doing her chin-ups as Beck watches her lean body easily doing the exercises.</context>
      <utterance>After a month of it you'd think I'd be used to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's astronaut training?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? You going to give me hard time like the others?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I'm just being friendly.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck tries to concentrate on his inventory, but continues to watch Willie's sexy, athletic body.</context>
      <utterance>Good...It's going good.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever made you want to do a tour down here?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need electrical field experience on my resume. Everything helps...  Why are you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody in corporate training serves a tour on the line. Sup- posed to hone leadership skills or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Has it helped?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck looks up and they lock eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I guess there's not a lot of adventure in the Control Room.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I should hang around more with the crew?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck looks up from his clipboard and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I always heard you don't "learn" leadership, you earn it.  How did you know they'd get into the vodka?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess I figured if I was in their shoes that's what I would've done.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you're more one of us than you think...sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sixpack obliges as Beck enters.</context>
      <utterance>Let's see your tongue.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretty good imitation of a hangover and I ought to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIXPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it ain't! It feels a thousand times worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIXPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>wrong.</context>
      <utterance>I...I dunno. I just feel...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sixpack pulls off his shirt. Doc frowns in surprise. WHAT HE SEES: SIXPACK'S TORSO There are strange black areas, each of them an inch in diameter. DOC (cont'd) (concerned) How long...how long have you had these?</context>
      <utterance>Take off your shirt.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIXPACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc peers closely at the skin where it's discolored. It's a different texture. Beck watches as Doc touches a spot and Sixpack screams in agony. Doc and Beck lock eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Shit, Doc...I didn't know I had them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...as long as you know it's not in your contract.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck interrupts impatiently.</context>
      <utterance>Well, suit yourself, then...its your decision...  Ha ha...a little joke...suit yourself...</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's the weather for pickup tomorrow?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE SWAMP - MORNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The crew members climb into their suits.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You just can't do it.</context>
      <utterance>Bad as he is there's no way we can make our quota with- out his sad self out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's tanking on us...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No...he's really sick. I heard him last night. The company will take that into consideration...</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey, the company don't give a flying fuck about "whys," they just look at the numbers and the contract says if we miss our quota they only got to pay us half-pay for the entire month.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly all eyes go to the door, Beck enters.</context>
      <utterance>'Cocksucker's tanking on us...</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crew increases its bitching...</context>
      <utterance>No, he's really sick...He won't be going out today.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There goes our quota...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck ignores them and goes to the control rack which sends the suits around the room and pushes number 8--his suit. DeJesus and Jones share a look. Bowman and Willie watch him carefully. As Beck's suit stops in front of him the room is quiet, they can't believe their eyes. Awkwardly, Beck tries to get into his suit. Cobb breaks the silence.</context>
      <utterance>Thirty days, right down the toilet...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this a contract violation, Mr. Cobb?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck sees he's sincere, then looks at the others and Willie. She nods slightly. Beck turns back to Cobb.</context>
      <utterance>No sir...I just wanted to know if you needed a hand?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, number 23's full.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's get it out of here and bring in a new one.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hook's on 24...</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Container transporters fill with compressed air and lift the container as the miners guide it to the track...</context>
      <utterance>Let's have her...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck, obviously pleased, looks at the others. Jones sums up the feelings of the entire group.</context>
      <utterance>Good work out there, Mr. Becky.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck's grin suddenly disappears at the sight of a flashing red light over the intercom.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dead? This morning you said he had some skin disorder.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He did.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc looks at Beck wearily and hands him a mask.</context>
      <utterance>Well, how the hell does a skin rash kill you in eight hours?!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here. Put this on. You examine him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not a doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck hesitates, then puts on the mask.</context>
      <utterance>For this...you don't need to be.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The mask is because you think it might be...catching?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I've been back and forth with Narragansett Naval all day, consulting with the best people in maritime medicine, the best people in viruses...</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And they didn't believe the symptoms I described...</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why Sixpack?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It could be a million things, something in the air, food....  But he went on that ship and so did Williams...  I want to examine the crew.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to the door and Doc watches him.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah...right...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've reported the death to the company.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Routine," my ass! Ain't nothin' "routine" about no physical check- up 10,000 feet down...especially when we're getting picked up the next day!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He didn't say it was a "routine check-up," he said it was a "routine</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's this fucking air system....</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bowman suddenly becomes pale.</context>
      <utterance>Ain't the food or the air system, he's just sick... Everybody gets sick every now and then. It's all part of being human!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets up from the table and dashes for the toilet.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I must be human because I'm sure as hell sick.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>COBB'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Like herpes, or measles, or what?</context>
      <utterance>I guess I'm kinda...outta shape...  This skin condition...what is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Doc is scrutinizing Cobb's flabby body closely. They're alone in the shower room. Stainless steel, and mirrors. Doc stops and checks a place on Cobb more closely.</context>
      <utterance>It's difficult to describe.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc peers closely, satisfies himself that it's nothing.</context>
      <utterance>Christ, it'd be a hell of a thing if I went back to the roof with some kind of herpes thing. My wife wouldn't understand that at all...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You seem all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We're looking at Jones' naked body...rippling muscles.</context>
      <utterance>She wouldn't understand. She'd think I was down here fucking my head off. DARK SKIN/ PORES Black skin, seen very close, the pores appearing like craters.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This whole thing's unnecessary, Doc. Only "skin problem" I got is white people...  How come you're wearing those gloves?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Doc turns Willie around and examines her firm naked buttocks.</context>
      <utterance>This disease...do you know what causes it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet. You got any ideas?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't think it was from going on that ship do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc turns away to let her dress.</context>
      <utterance>That's a possibility. But if it was that simple why haven't the symptoms begun on you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean I'm okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're fine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DEJESUS' VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>DeJesus, naked, with his back to us. Doc examines him.</context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, "a skin problem"... your skin changes?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It blackens...becomes scaly.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DeJesus chuckles, but something about the thought stops Doc.</context>
      <utterance>You mean like a fish?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes...like a fish...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just joking, Doc.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, according to Maritime law, you, as commander of the Shack have the authority to dispose of the body. However, the company doesn't want you to do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you don't understand is that my crew is in jeopardy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you don't have any proof at this point to assume that this disease is contagious, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not anxious to find out, either.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We could be there in a few hours.</context>
      <utterance>Beck, trust me. If the company felt that you or your crew were in any danger we would authorize an immediate emergency pickup.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unfortunately. We can't. He picks up a sheet of computer paper. MARTIN There is a typhoon about 600 miles off the coast of Baja. It's not coming your way but the Company doesn't want to lose you folks or an emergency ship should it veer your way.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you saying? That we're not even going to be picked up tomorrow?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It shouldn't be a long delay.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A day? Two days?!</context>
      <utterance>But it's a delay! How long?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twelve hours, no big deal. We should know something first thing in the morning. Don't worry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is no answer and Jones slowly approaches the body.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Sixpack...Hey, my man... How you feeling?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is almost to the table and reaches out to touch Sixpack when suddenly the body stirs. Sixpack's foot moves slightly under the sheet as if shifting in his sleep. Jones stops. JONES(cont'd) Oh, man, sorry...you go back to sleep.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, man, we made quota to- day. No thanks to you, you dog, but we made it...Beck helped us...We just dropped Bowman off. I hope what you've got ain't catching...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who were you talking to?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sixpack...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They leave Bowman GROANING on the examination table and head back to the main corridor. As they leave WE HOLD ON the door to the sick room behind Bowman. Bowman writhes on the examination table in pain. Carefully she climbs off the table and goes behind a partition to throw up.</context>
      <utterance>Sleeping. No sign of Doc, though. I'll check the control room. You look in the shower room...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BOWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns and looks at the light on in the Sick Room. Slowly she goes to the door and enters.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, God...what's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>SICK ROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bowman approaches the body of Sixpack.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer. She pulls back the sheet and gasps.</context>
      <utterance>Sixpack...what's going on?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones enters.</context>
      <utterance>You have to call them back. Explain that this is an emergency.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, sir...Bowman's sick. She's downstairs in the infirmary.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The infirmary?...</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir, ain't that where we usually go when we're sick?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're simply concerned about her...proximity to...</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones looks from one officer to the other then grins.</context>
      <utterance>Sixpack's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bullshit...I was just talking to him. I saw him move.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is no answer and he moves toward the shower.</context>
      <utterance>Bowman?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The water continues to run. No answer. Carefully, Doc opens the shower door. WHAT HE SEES: Bowman. Dead. Her wrists have been cut and blood swirls down the drain. Doc sadly squats down beside her. The death effects him greatly. He feels helpless, then suddenly his eyes widen and he carefully reaches out and takes Bowman's limp arm, turning it supine. There, running the length of the arm, WE SEE the black scales.</context>
      <utterance>Bowman. It's Doc. I'm here to help you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't tell you much about it, except that none of you show any symptoms.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And it killed Bo?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON WILLIE the news hits her hard.</context>
      <utterance>No...she killed herself.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're getting out of here just in time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's now a problem with the weather for pickup. There's a typhoon in our sector... ...We're going to be delayed twelve hours...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Typhoon?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twelve hours!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least we get time and a half. That's in the contract.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their argument is suddenly cut short by a NOISE from the corridor. A THUMP! The crew stops their grumbling and listens. A moment later we hear another THUMP! Beck looks at Jones.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck double pay, man! I want out of here!</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jones...  Stay here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Cobb...you're slacking...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Jones can argue, Beck cuts them off.</context>
      <utterance>I ain't, goddamnit...It's Jones!..</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up, all of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Beck, the contract states that no body can be disposed of without authorization of---</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The group turns into the Swamp where Doc waits for them by the Lift Lock. Rounding the corner Cobb bangs into the side of a bulkhead and drops his corner of the "package." Like dominoes, Willie also looses her grip, then DeJesus. The bodybag splashes into the grimy bilge water making it even harder for everyone to get a handhold. BECK(cont'd) C'mon...Lift! The group struggles to raise the bodybag and just get it to their shoulder when suddenly we go tight on DeJesus's face.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck the contract, man!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's moving! He's alive!</context>
      <utterance>Hey!...I feel something.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb drops his end intentionally and he kneels looking for the zipper.</context>
      <utterance>I feel it, too...Someone's trying to get out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cobb, what're you doing!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But he ain't dead! He ain't dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Cobb grabs the zipper and starts to unzip the heavy bag. Beck tries to stop him when suddenly, WHAM! a DARK APPENDAGE RIPS through the zipper and flails like a pressurized firehose. It beats wildly for several second, then lashes out at Cobb--ripping a gash on his forearm. While Cobb screams in pain, Beck yanks the appendage off Cobb's arm revealing a mouth full of needlesharp teeth and a sharp tongue-like proboscis which has stabbed Cobb like a dagger.</context>
      <utterance>Cobb! Stop!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>While Beck and Willie wrestle the strong flopping appendage, Doc rushes to the Lift Lock. DeJesus and Jones struggle to force the lurching bodybag into the Lift Lock.</context>
      <utterance>It bit me! It bit me!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The bodybag shudders like a huge cocoon about to lose its occupant. Jones digs his shoulder down into the task just as the bag suddenly RIPS in several places. A tear RIPS OPEN next to Jones' head revealing the head of BOWMAN, her vacant eyes only inches from Jones' face.</context>
      <utterance>Push Hazy!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly a WHINING NOISE sounds behind them. Beck looks back to see Cobb approaching with a battery operated underwater chain saw. He's clearly intending to cut the Creature with the whirring blade.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jesus Christ! I ain't never gonna sleep again!</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It bit me!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Sixpack!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DeJesus turns to block Cobb while the others continue to wrestle the bodybag into the Lift Lock. The bag suddenly splits and a scaly arm protrudes. It reaches out grabbing DeJesus. Beck pulls him free and yells.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to kill it!</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc hits the lever. The elevator doesn't move! RRRRRRIIIIIPPP! A scaly leg rips out of the body bag! BECK(cont'd) Hit it again! Doc hits the elevator switch again, harder. NNNNNNN! The Lift Lock door whines closed and a horrifying SCREAM rises from the Lock.</context>
      <utterance>Close the Lock! Now!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Serves his ass right to get it. Motherfucker brings that shit onboard. I hope his fucking ass rots in the sea and is shit upon by the fish.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Fucker could have gotten us all killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Willie finishes tying up her shoes and looks at them all coldly.</context>
      <utterance>He knew better than that.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets up and walks out into the Ring corridor.</context>
      <utterance>You guys sure weren't so holy when you were shooting that vodka...It could have been you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON SCREEN we see the scene again. Light dancing off the cabinets. As the light starts to turn--</context>
      <utterance>Hold it! Rewind it. Beck rewinds it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck pauses the tape. We see nothing. Doc is confused.</context>
      <utterance>Stop it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck does and we watch Doc's face as he stares intently at the screen. Suddenly he sees it.</context>
      <utterance>Back it up slowly.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON SCREEN We see it. Caught in the turn of the camera, now frozen on the screen is the clear gleaming skeletal remains of a man. Only it is clear that this is no ordinary man. Fingers and appendages are lengthened and broader than normal. But it is the large head and long sharp teeth that especially catches our attention.</context>
      <utterance>There.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up another piece of blue sky and effortlessly fits it into place as Jones watches. It's blowing Jones' mind.</context>
      <utterance>You know that Innsbruck has 64 square miles of ski slopes, man? Think about that. Sixty-four square miles.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd you do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets up to go into the mess and Jones looks at him in amazement.</context>
      <utterance>What? That?...I've done this one before. You hungry? I'm hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hungry? After what we just went through I may never eat again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They found this?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Homo aquaticus...</context>
      <utterance>No. I think they isolated him in genetic engineering.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was there such a thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Danakil man?...one of our ancestors. Named for the Danakil Alps in Ethiopia.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not exactly a big ocean country.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was when it counted a couple of million years ago when the seas came in and drove us into the water. Most homo sapiens didn't make it...Danakil man...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CONTROL ROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On Doc.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some say that's why we're basically hairless, for less water resistance, faster swimming speeds...</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what about those scales... or that leech-like thing that bit Cobb?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why stop with just one aspect of marine life? Why not incorporate the best genetic components the ocean has to offer?...</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc looks up at the image on the screen. The huge skull stares back hauntingly.</context>
      <utterance>Well, if they were perfecting an aquaman, then why's there a dead one onboard that Russian ship? Why isn't he out swimming around?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He obviously lacked something in his environment.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JONES' VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At first startled, Cobb recovers and answers sharply.</context>
      <utterance>Turned black yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That ain't funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Relax, Cobb. If it was going to turn, it would have done its trick by now.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones starts to leave when he suddenly notices something on Cobb's bunk. He picks it up and we see a photo of Cobb's family.</context>
      <utterance>That's easy for you to say. You ain't the one that got bit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb snatches the photo back from Jones and glares at him with the same old, hard "Cobb look."</context>
      <utterance>Don't tell me you're getting soft on us, Cobbie? You're the fellow who always said--</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones leaves, and Cobb waits till he is gone then looks back at his photo. His look changes, softening. Absently he scratches his bandage.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing's changed, goddamnit!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not fully recovered from the start, DeJesus rubs his bruised head.</context>
      <utterance>Man, everybody is jumpy... What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Getting some food.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DeJesus gets to his feet, points at the water under the sink.</context>
      <utterance>Under there?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look. Water.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DeJesus continues to scrutinize the water then looks back at Jones.</context>
      <utterance>Probably the plumbing. You gonna make me finish that puzzle by myself, or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks down at his sandwich as Jones starts out of the galley. Something is missing.</context>
      <utterance>No, I'll be right there.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens the refrigerator and finds the mustard jar empty.</context>
      <utterance>Mustard. Need mustard...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He throws the jar in the trash then opens the cabinet next to the refrigerator for a new jar, and reaches inside.</context>
      <utterance>Sixpack...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes to the door and looks in. His eyes widen at the sight of DeJesus staggering toward him with the squeezing hunk of muscle. JONES(cont'd) Holy shit!</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Hazy...what're you doing now...cooking? There is no answer and Jones looks up. JONES  Hazy?...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He keeps coming at Jones who backs away slowly from his friend.</context>
      <utterance>Help me, Jonesy. Oh, God, help me! It's getting inside me, I can feel it!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones finds himself backing away until he is by the door to the Galley. He closes it, rushing through into the Mess to the Ring corridor where he runs into Cobb.</context>
      <utterance>Hazy, please...I'm going to get you some help, man...just don't touch me...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones runs out and leaves Cobb by the door. Cobb watches him go. As the noise in the Mess intensifies, we hear banging on the door, then DeJesus' anguished cries.</context>
      <utterance>It's Hazy...It's got him! Stay here and don't let him out. I'm going to get the Doc.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb backs slowly down the corridor toward the dorm.</context>
      <utterance>Help me! Help me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's got Hazy!</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What has?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One of those chunks of Sixpack! Like a big leech, with those teeth!...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've got to get him to the infirmary.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you going to do to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to try to remove it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got Cobbie downstairs watching the door.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb returns with a mining tool.</context>
      <utterance>Cobb? Hazy? Oh, shit...He's gone...</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You let him get away!</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't doing nothing for that thing without something to defend myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, God, she's out there...</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jones...come with me. Cobb, you and Doc check the rooms.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Willie lowers herself from the bar behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Willie...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sudden sight of her nearly gives Jones heart failure, he stumbles backwards into the ankle deep water and Willie drops from the bar laughing.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What on earth's the matter with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Willie picks up the strain in Jones' voice, her smile fades.</context>
      <utterance>I ought to smack your face!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>DeJesus...It's got him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought they were your friends?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were, Doss</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jones to Doc. Doc?...Cobb? He looks back to Beck, concerned. JONES  Think it got 'em?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's not going through. The intercom's busted. I thought DeJesus fixed that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He did.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It...almost got you.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc shakes his head dumbly. He is in total shock.</context>
      <utterance>What was it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>COBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw it! It's big!</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bigger than DeJesus? How?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds out the empty blood bags. A change has come over Doc since Bowman's death. The experience has slightly deadened him.</context>
      <utterance>It's had a meal.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It needs blood?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fucking great...You telling me we got a fucking dracula in here with us?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It would explain the suction- like appendages.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like a leech.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why there's a dead one on the ship. It ran out of blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doc looks at Beck, then Jones.</context>
      <utterance>What dead one on the ship? He looks from Doc to Beck. JONES  Someone want to let the rank and file in on your little secret?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The monster appears to be a genetic aberration...</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No fuckin' lie...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...It has many traits of deep sea marine life...regeneration, scales, gills, even a period of dormancy...  but the fact that it remembered where the plasma was stored, or where the communication wiring was, may imply that it has some other quality...</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck locks eyes with Doc.</context>
      <utterance>What?...What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That it acquires intelligence from its victims?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Intelligence may not be the right word...</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck semantics, Doc! You saying its like part DeJesus, part Sixpack, part Bowman?!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I'm guessing.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I say we should go get in the escape bubbles and get the hell out of here!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Willie looks at Beck.</context>
      <utterance>And hit the surface in the middle of a typhoon?...No, thank you. I'll take my chance down here.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can we do?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our only chance is to lure it to the Swamp and flush it like we did the other.</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck checks his flamethrower and looks at Jones.</context>
      <utterance>And how're we going to do that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be careful with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks over at Jones who watches the door. Jones looks back and nods. The coast is clear.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, I don't want to give up any more.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still bothering you?</utterance>
   <speaker>COBB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Itches like hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cobb pulls back the bandage and looks at the gash. INSERT COBB'S WOUND Pink and healing.</context>
      <utterance>Take it off and let me have a look.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and Willie stops him with a firm grip.</context>
      <utterance>Looks good to me. I'll re-bandage it, though. He looks at Willie. DOC Willie, would you clean it for me. I'm going to the infirmary for supplies.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't go out there alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the Doctor. I have to do what's best for this crew.  I need my bag.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods. Doc turns back to the sink and Cobb holds out his arm to let Willie put the new bandage on. As Cobb's arm comes up we suddenly notice a slight movement under his shirt. Willie stops just before applying the bandage. The movement intensifies--like snakes moving wildly beneath the cloth. Cobb whitens...breaks out in a sweat. Willie backs off.</context>
      <utterance>There, good as new. Just keep your paws off of it.  Do you have the new bandage ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She steps back and Doc moves into her place as suddenly a leech-mouthed tentacle erupts from Cobb's waist. It's razor sharp proboscis punctures Doc's chest right at the heart and the leach mouth with it's hundreds of teeth attaches with vacuum-like suction.</context>
      <utterance>Doc?...Doc!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But it is too late. Willie falls back screaming as Cobb's gash RRRRRRRIPS OPEN! THE FLESH OPENING GROTESQUELY FROM</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hear something. Don't fire until we're both in the Swamp. Jones moves a little farther back. BECK Don't let him see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the Creature approaches WE SEE Beck stand up like a wounded animal. He begins dragging his "injured" leg behind him as he retreats toward the Swamp. THE FOOTSTEPS MOVE</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AS THE CREATURE starts to turn for Willie, Beck suddenly closes the vault-like door to the swamp on Creature's hand, trapping it vise-like in the door.</context>
      <utterance>Oh God...</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Creature throws back its head and SCREAMS in pain as the heavy door severs its appendage.</context>
      <utterance>Run Willie! Run!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Cobb and Doc?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It got Doc...</context>
      <utterance>Cobb's cut...It was in him!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh man, that's just great...</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones rolls the large vault-like door closed and locks them. Beck goes to the console and checks the instruments. Suddenly he sees something that causes him to freeze in his tracks. A red light blinks ominously on the console.</context>
      <utterance>Lock the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit! He sent them all.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The escape bubbles? She and Jones stop in front of Doc's console.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck looks at Doc's computer screen. ON SCREEN WE SEE DOC'S MESSAGE: "...hope that our sacrifice will mean that the human race will never know this awful mutation..."</context>
      <utterance>Look at this.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The good doctor signed our death warrant.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, at least we're safe inside here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck slides behind the Console and quickly types in a message. WE SEE IT ON THE SCREEN. "SHACK SIX REPORTING.</context>
      <utterance>For how long?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank goodness, you're still alive!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, man, you better get your ass out here right now and get us. You hear me, motherfucker?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When are you coming?!</context>
      <utterance>Just answer the question, man!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hopefully in the next 48 hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forty-eight hours!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I realize you must have gone through hell--</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gone? Man, we're still here!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns off his screen and the picture in front of Beck, Jones and Willie goes blank.</context>
      <utterance>I can't change the weather. Try to get some rest. I'll keep you posted.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's right. Why don't you get some rest. I'll stand the first watch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly he hears a voice behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Martin, you asshole...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They know, don't they?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...I think they're just deciding what to do with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves into Doc's seat in front of the console and calls up the stock market program that Bowman was monitoring earlier. ON SCREEN WE SEE: Stock prices. Willie types in a series of commands.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe they already have.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON SCREEN: The words TransOcean Corp. The capsulized report comes up on screen: "TransOcean Corp. took a bath on world markets today when news of a tragic mining accident was revealed to investors. The Board of Directors...."</context>
      <utterance>Seeing how my stock's doing...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She scrolls forward in the report and suddenly freezes the words. THE SCREEN: "...accident took place in Shack Six, Southeast Sector of Pacific Zone 10...Seven dead. All bodies missing." Their names follow. ON WILLIE as her name comes up she shivers.</context>
      <utterance>Where?....</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A voice behind them causes them to turn.</context>
      <utterance>I can't believe they'd just leave us.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is now awake. He sits up against the air vent. Suddenly, Beck listens, the room is deathly silent. He looks over to the air vent. Jones is listening also.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome to the union, boss. We're all expendable.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WHOOP! WHOOP! Suddenly a KLAXON HORN sounds hysterically. A blue light on the console blinks on and off. It says "AIR." Beck turns to the instruments.</context>
      <utterance>The air's stopped.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're on backup air.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much time does that give us?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Less than an hour. It's ruptured an air duct.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't we fix it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There're twenty miles of pipe in the bilge, they could have tapped-in anywhere.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He locks eyes with Beck.</context>
      <utterance>Cobb...Job security...</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaves his seat and Jones checks his weapon as Willie watches.</context>
      <utterance>They're drawing us out.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck checks his make-shift flamethrower.</context>
      <utterance>You can't go out there, that's what they want.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't have much choice... without air, the internal pressure will fall and--</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Willie watches them a moment then picks up one of the mining tools, the laser-drill, she powers-it up to check it. Her action stops both men and she catches their looks.</context>
      <utterance>Crunch...Implosion.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't think I'm sitting in here, do you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The shack...</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's wondering what's happening. We're losing air faster than I thought.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones moves to the lead and turns down Corridor "A."</context>
      <utterance>Which way?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Jones can protest Beck drops the ladder and climbs down into the dark bilge. Jones waits till he's at the bottom, then starts down behind him. Willie looks back.</context>
      <utterance>I'll go first.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't spend all day down there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't fuckin' worry, I ain't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ...</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you fix it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way...</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think! Can we stop it?! Block it up?! Shut down the line somewhere?! Think!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly his eyes widen. Beck sees this and turns. In his light WE SEE THE GLINT OF LONG TEETH AND THE HUGE BLACK FRAME OF THE COBB/DOC CREATURE! It's leech-like appendage whipping in front of it like an excited cat's tail. Before it can strike, Jones pushes Beck out of the way and fires a blast of flame from his flamethrower. The CREATURE SCREAMS and disappears. As Beck falls his light lands in the bilge water and goes out sending the bilge into greater darkness.</context>
      <utterance>I am thinking, man! You think I want to die! I am thinking! I--</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hit it. But I can't see it! Can you see it?!</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones looks back at the ruptured pipe and suddenly has a thought.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start for the ladder when WWWWHHHHHHHHIP! out of the darkness the appendage wraps like a bullwhip around Jones' arm. The deadly proboscis, which stabbed Cobb, is poised like a dagger about to be plunged into the black man's thigh.</context>
      <utterance>The Swamp. There's an over- ride switch in the Swamp.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Instinctively Beck whips out the mining saw and severs the tentacle. The unseen Creature's SCREAM echoes through the Bilge. Beck grabs Jones by the arm and pulls him toward the ladder.</context>
      <utterance>Ahhh!</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quickly they slosh toward the ladder and hole in the floor fifteen feet away, moving closer...ten...eight....then suddenly ANOTHER APPENDAGE thrusts between the rungs of the ladder at them. Beck ducks and leaps to the side. He is less than six feet from the Creature. In the dim light WE SEE it wickedly bare its teeth. Beck's eyes go to the walls from one side to the other and spot the exposed power cable. The Creature steps forward directly under the hole in the floor. It is about to lunge when a voice from above distracts it.</context>
      <utterance>Hurry...Get out!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>The Creature looks up and sees:</context>
      <utterance>Hey, you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start for the Swamp down Corridor "A" when an enormous shudder goes through the Shack, causing the lights to blink and the floor to open beneath Beck. The jolt knocks him back into the bilge. Only grabbing onto the pipes just above the water stops him from falling back in. JONES stops and looks back over the missing grating.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, the Swamp!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones moves instinctively back for him, but another jolt only widens the gap. Beck yells to be heard over the din of the collapsing Shack.</context>
      <utterance>Beck!</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go on!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's an order!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaps across the gap onto a remaining grating and thrusts his hand down into the darkness. Beck lets go of one hand, then the other, to grab Jones' extended arm. In one Herculean effort Jones pulls him out of the bilge. Together they leap across the chasm as the Desalinization Conduit collapses over their heads and water floods into Corridor "A" behind them. They have to go around the other way!</context>
      <utterance>Fuck your orders!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where the hell've you been?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Willie stands back and Beck thrusts the Spreader into the tiny crack in the door the hand crank had made. With Jones' help the two men force open the door and all three rush inside the SWAMP. Beck closes the door behind them. THE RECORDED FEMALE VOICE INTONES: "Five minutes to implosion." And we feel it happening:</context>
      <utterance>I got hung up! Try this!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Willie moves quickly but Jones doesn't.</context>
      <utterance>The suits! Get in them!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck yanks open the equipment locker revealing TANKS OF</context>
      <utterance>The suits! Are you crazy! How're we going to get to the surface?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up at Jones who grins with renewed hope and they begin pulling the equipment out. BECK(cont'd) Get them in the Lock! Jones and Beck drag the tanks and the parachute-like Container transporters to the lock. ON WILLIE She climbs into her suit and activates her generator. Instantly her Vital Signs spring to life around the perimeter of her helmet. THE FEMALE VOICE TREMBLES FROM THE VIBRATIONS..."Three minutes...to...implosion..." Beck and Jones throw the last of the supplies onto the elevator and Beck holds out the SEISMIC TOOL Jones tried to arm himself with earlier. He takes the tool from Beck and sticks it in the vest of his wet suit. Then suddenly he sees that there are only two suits in the Lock. Beck will have to wait on his to move along the track to the Lock.</context>
      <utterance>Like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your suit, Becky!</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones climbs onto the Lock platform and slides into his suit. Beck hits the Suit track button and his suit begins moving along the track toward the Lock. A suit turns the corner from the storage room followed by one labeled BECK. Beck looks at the walls, they're shaking harder. He moves along the suit rack when suddenly THE CREATURE BURSTS FROM</context>
      <utterance>Just get in yours!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But it is too late. It knocks the ax from Beck's hand and sends him to the floor. Beck looks up at the Lock in time to see Jones seal himself into his suit.</context>
      <utterance>Look out!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES/RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm in.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE/RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CREATURE APPROACHES BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beck looks at the others one last time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones hits the elevator button and the Lock closes as the elevator sends them down without Beck. BECK stands and arms himself with a mining drill, which he swings at the Creature driving it back. As Beck gets the upper hand, the Creature turns its hideous face and Beck freezes. There attached to the back of the Creature's head is the grotesque face of DeJesus! DeJesus' eyes suddenly blink. He's still alive! His lips tremble in agony.</context>
      <utterance>Go, now! That's an order!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEJESUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck, momentarily stopped by the face, lunges forward with the drill and embeds it in the side of the Creature. As the Creature falls back hurt, Beck looks up at the lock elevator as it returns--IT IS EMPTY--The others have made it out! His suit continues down the track and stops in the Lock. He still has to make it, if he can just get there! THE RECORDED FEMALE VOICE SOUNDS: "One minute to implosion..." Beck races to the Lock and starts to climb into the suit. His arms slide into place, his legs drop into the heavy metal shell and as he seals up the back he activates the generator. BECK'S POV. His vital signs light up around the perimeter of his helmet, but he sees something else--the Creature charges toward the Lock--its arm reaches out to yank Beck out of the elevator! Instinctively, Beck swings his motorized leg into the Creature's snarling mouth, knocking it backwards and stunning it long enough for Beck to hit the elevator button. BUT IT DOESN'T WORK!</context>
      <utterance>Kill me...Kill me!</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hits again, still nothing! THE RECORDED FEMALE VOICE..."Nineteen, eighteen..." Her voice begins to quiver.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode>RADIO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait till you reach thirty- five before you blow your suit...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>RADIO</mode>
      <context>WILLIE'S POV Her numbers count down "....70, 60, 50, 40..."</context>
      <utterance>Roger.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode>RADIO</mode>
      <context>She yanks at the handle on the chest plate and WHOOSH! The plate bursts open and reveals a second interior handle. Her hand gropes for it.</context>
      <utterance>Ejecting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We made it!</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holding onto each other Willie and Beck ride a swell. At the crest WE SEE JONES in the trough below, face down. Beck breaks away from Willie and swims through the waves to reach Jones. Reaching him Beck pulls his face out of the water and inflates his life jacket.</context>
      <utterance>Where's Jones?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck lays Jones head back against the life jacket. For a moment. Jones seems lifeless, then his eyes blink and squint against the sunlight. Beck turns back to Willie and as he and Jones ride the next crest he gives her the "thumbs-up." WILLIE(cont'd) (jubilant) The sun! The sun! Jones looks at Beck and grins.</context>
      <utterance>Is he okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to that typhoon?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure you saw something?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many times I got to tell you. I saw a ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, why haven't they answered our flares?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BECK pulls the flare off his latex wet suit and fires it into the sky casting a comforting yellow glow over the dark water. The light fades, Willie looks at Jones.</context>
      <utterance>We'll fire one more, that leaves us one last one.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you okay, Jonesy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tip top, Willie...tip top.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's the best power forward in the NBA...Jameson?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both manage a weak laugh, then Beck sees something.</context>
      <utterance>Jameson? Who are you trying to con...?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As a small swell lifts them up we can see a tiny flare just fading against the sky.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be damned. Look!...A flare!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It saw us!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Answer them and quit kicking me!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WHOOOOOOOOSH! Beck fires another flare into the sky. As the flare arcs downward, Willie feels another bump and for the first time sees the SHARKS CIRCLING THEM.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not touching you!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SHARKS tighten the circle as the flare fades.</context>
      <utterance>No...no, no, no.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lowers his binoculars AS WE WIDEN TO REVEAL MARTIN standing on the bridge. He also lowers his binoculars and smiles coolly as he lies.</context>
      <utterance>I thought you said you'd combed this area?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We did....Many times.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hold on Martin's face as from</context>
      <utterance>Initiate rescue.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It hit me! Where are they?!</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly he is bumped by a shark. Willie sees one only two feet away. They are surrounded. Suddenly Jones stare to taunt the sharks aggressively.</context>
      <utterance>I can't see them!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pushes away from the group despite Beck's attempt to stop him. JONES(cont'd) (taunting sharks) What's wrong you snout-nosed bastards? My meat too tough for you?! Amazingly the sharks begin to disappear. Willie and Beck watch stunned. Even Jones is surprised. JONES(cont'd) (to Willie and Beck) Whoa! Did you see those fools run? They know whose boss. He jabs his arm upward in triumph and for the first time WE SEE a gash across his forearm.</context>
      <utterance>All right! I've had enough of this shit! You want meat, motherfucker? Come on, eat me, sucker, try some dark meat!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WILLIE reaches the helicopter and quickly climbs out of the harness. The Winch operator throws it back across the water where BECK grabs the harness.</context>
      <utterance>Jonesy...Give me your hand!</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones reaches out his hand. He is almost there WHEN</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Jones!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jonesy, No!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Creature grabs Jones and pulls him violently under. Beck watches horrified as his friend disappears. Numbed he clips the rescue harness around him when suddenly, WE SEE a boiling of water where Jones disappeared...bubbles rising...and then Jones' bloody and tattered life vest bobs to the surface several feet away from Beck. Beck reaches out for it just as the Creature appears again! It turns and focuses on Beck. Beck keeps going for the life vest as the Creature starts for him.</context>
      <utterance>Get out of here, Becky!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WINCH OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE ON JONES' TATTERED VEST Beck reaches it. His fingers wrap around the bicycle pump-like, seismic tool in Jones' vest pocket. The Creature is right on top of him! CHUNK, CHUNK, Beck cocks it like a pump shotgun as tentacles rise wickedly out of the water and wrap around Beck's body in a death grip. It's horrible mouth starts to open.</context>
      <utterance>Is he in the harness!</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Creature's mouth widens and as it starts to strike Beck thrusts the seismic tool into its gaping maw and</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, motherfucker open up!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Beck, I understand you passed your physical with flying colors. And Ms. Williams?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know yet, she's still in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck looks up surprised as suddenly Martin joins them.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you'll be glad to know you have a friend onboard.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck looks at Martin for an instant then hauls off and in one incredibly smooth punch knocks Martin on his can across the deck.</context>
      <utterance>Beck! I told them you'd make it. No one back at TransOcean believed me, but I never gave up on you once.  So, how are you feeling?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then the door to the infirmary opens and Willie appears with a new outfit on. Smiles at Beck.</context>
      <utterance>Better...A lot better.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck lets out a slight sigh of relief as a STEWARD approaches with a tray of WHOLE COOKED FISH, HIDEOUS LOOKING</context>
      <utterance>I'm fine!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Willie stares at the tray of seafood uneasily then looks at the Captain and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I thought we might have some wonderful seafood. But, if there's something else you'd rather have...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She and Beck laugh as they sit at a finely set table on the deck with the Captain. AS WE PULL BACK the ship becomes smaller and smaller in the distance and WE ARE AT THE</context>
      <utterance>How about a burger and fries?</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
