<movie id="350" title="Life">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>CHAPLAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In accordance with the regulations of the State of Mississippi, we gather here today to lay to rest the remains of inmates R. Gibson, number 4316, and C. Banks, number 4317. Ashes to ashes, dust to dust. May God have mercy on their souls.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The young inmates plunge their shovels into the dirt. One by one, the mourners head back toward a prison van parked on a nearby dirt road.</context>
      <utterance>Go ahead, fellas.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE HUMPHRIES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leaves Willie alone with Jake and Leon. He rolls his chair up to the edge of the graves and gazes at the pinewood caskets.</context>
      <utterance>I'll come back for you in a little while, Willie...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These two guys friends of yours, old man?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We spent some time together.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do I get the feeling when you say some time, you mean some time.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was already here a good many years when they came in in 1932.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>1932? That's like, that's like...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Willie pulls a bottle of moonshine from his jacket and takes a swig in their honor.</context>
      <utterance>Sixty-five years ago. They always said the farm couldn't hold 'em forever. Looks like you're finally free, boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, the dude's holdin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Willie passes the bottle to Leon, who takes a swig and winces from the unexpected kick.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, old-timer, hook the brothers up.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell of a way to get out. Heard they burned up in that fire yesterday.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I seen the bodies before they sealed 'em up. Them fellas sizzled up good. Looked like some shit from the X- Files.  Damn, that shit's nasty.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ray's special recipe. He always had exacting standards where the hooch was concerned.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Willie holds up the bottle, checking the clarity of the liquor.</context>
      <utterance>What were they, bootleggers?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something like that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>BOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, no, Ray. Not tonight. Spanky's not happy with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is Spanky here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what's the problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do yourself a favor and find another place where they let you in the front door.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But this is where the action is and I have to be where the action is. Look, when your old lady wanted those alligator shoes, didn't I come through for you? Ain't she stepping in style now?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, alright then. What do you think about this new tie?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sharp.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray heads inside.</context>
      <utterance>I look good tonight. And I feel lucky, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray slides through the crowd, pausing at the bar to nibble on the neck of a COCKTAIL WAITRESS.</context>
      <utterance>Anyone asks, it wasn't me who let you in.</utterance>
   <speaker>COCKTAIL WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't even try it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When do you get off?</utterance>
   <speaker>COCKTAIL WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She carries a tray of drinks into the crowd. Ray shakes his head in wonderment at her departing form. The BARKEEP steps up as Ray pulls out his bottle.</context>
      <utterance>I get off at two, but you ain't never getting off.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARKEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't drink that in here, Ray.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I sure can't drink that watered-down swill you're serving. Give me a glass of ice.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARKEEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Disregarding the warning, Ray tilts the bottle back. Shaking his head, the barkeep moves on to a paying customer. Ray's eyes follow a bottle of French Champagne as it is delivered to a nearby table. Here sits the straight-laced CLAUDE BANKS with his girlfriend, DAISY. She's enjoying the show. He's polishing the silverware. The WAITER pours two glasses of champagne and leaves the bottle on ice. Claude regards his glass skeptically.</context>
      <utterance>I can't give you a glass of ice. I can't give you anything until you pay your damn tab.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For the kind of money they charge here, you'd think they could hire somebody to actually wash the dishes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAISY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Claude. Here's to your new job down at the bank. I always knew you'd make something of yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daisy thinks she does. She leans in, eyes twinkling.</context>
      <utterance>Know what I'm going to buy with my first pay check?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Season tickets to the Yankees. Right there on the first base line.  What's wrong, baby?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAISY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was hoping you were gonna say an engagement ring, Claude. French Champagne shoots out of Claude's nose.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Engagement ring!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAISY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what respectable folks do. Get a job, get married, start having babies. That's what you want, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude leans in to kiss Daisy on the lips. She offers her cheek. He departs.</context>
      <utterance>Sure it is. I just don't see any reason to rush into things. Damn, look at this shirt. I'll be right back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BAG MAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Congratulations, Claude. We understand you finally got yourself a job.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAG MAN #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They rifle through Claude's jacket and quickly find his wallet.</context>
      <utterance>Guess that means you can pay Mr. Riley the fifty bucks you owe him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now wait a second, guys. I've got a bill to pay out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAG MAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They toss back his empty wallet.</context>
      <utterance>Twenty-two dollars. Not bad for a start.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, fellas, that's two weeks pay. I'm here with my girl. You gotta leave me something.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAG MAN #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about your legs?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The stall door swings shut as the bag men depart.</context>
      <utterance>My legs? Those are good, I'll keep the legs...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ATTENDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray offers the quarter, a gesture of uncommon generosity.</context>
      <utterance>Here you go.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep the change.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATTENDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray pats the cologne on his face. A toilet flushes and Claude steps over to the sink. Ray catches his eye in the mirror.</context>
      <utterance>Why, thank you, sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't I know you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure I do. What's your name again?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Claude Banks.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Claude Banks. How could I forget that? You've got to remember me. Ray Gibson. We went to high school together.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You went to Monroe?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude straightens his jacket and heads for the door. Ray stashes the stolen wallet in his jacket.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I went to Jefferson, so you must have a different Claude Banks in mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, man. My mistake.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pressed up against the wall, Ray reaches into his jacket and produces Claude's wallet. Bullethead snatches it, inspects it and is not impressed.</context>
      <utterance>Watch the threads, Bullethead. If this is about my tab, I've got it covered.</utterance>
   <speaker>BULLETHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stuffs the wallet back into Ray's jacket and hustles Ray out the back door past the bouncer who let him in.</context>
      <utterance>This ain't about your tab, Ray. You've got bigger problems than that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that Ray Gibson? Who the hell let him in here?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, honey, let's get out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAISY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I'm having a good time...</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waiter presents Claude with the bill.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, sir, I believe you forgot this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The bill. Of course, the bill. We couldn't leave without paying the bill. Especially such an incredibly large bill.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray is stretched out against the back wall. Claude is knocked to the floor as the van lurches into motion.</context>
      <utterance>Save your energy, Claude. You're gonna need it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here, this belongs to you.  It was empty when I found it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray swigs from his bottle and offers it to Claude, who isn't interested.</context>
      <utterance>Good old Monroe.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I want to know is what happened to your cush between the time that you got up from the table and when I caught up with you in the Johnny?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't see where that's any of your business.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Busted, Claude snatches the bottle and carefully wipes off the neck before tilting it high. Ray gets a good chuckle out of this straight cat in the bow tie.</context>
      <utterance>Did those two muscle heads shake you down? Swear I've seen them down at the track with Sure-shot Riley. That's it, ain't it? A gambling debt.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where they taking us, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably to Spanky's headquarters down at the pier.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good, I'm looking forward to meeting this Spanky. Give me a chance to straighten out this whole mess.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't wait to see that. You slay me, man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are they gonna do to us?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You? Dine and ditch, right?  Over ten bucks?  You're probably looking at a thumb.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude shoves his hands under his armpits at the sound of approaching FOOTSTEPS echoing across the vast space. Claude and Ray peer into the darkness.</context>
      <utterance>A thumb? What do you mean, like cut it off? For ten bucks?  That include the tip?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's he? Friend of yours, Ray?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never saw this man before tonight. He's a lowlife degenerate who lurks in bathrooms. I'm a professional man, an upstanding citizen. I go to church on Sunday.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BULLETHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Failure to pay.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spanky holds up a hand, silencing Claude.</context>
      <utterance>Look, Mr. Johnson, you seem like a reasonable man. I got a good job starts Monday. I'll pay you back with my first pay check. With interest. I don't want to tell you how to conduct your business, but if you cut off my finger you won't get jack. Working an adding machine, I gotta be whole.  I need my thumbs and all my fingers for praying and doing good...</utterance>
   <speaker>SPANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The choirboy wants to keep his fingers. Who am I to argue? Drop him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude protests loudly as Bullethead and the henchman bind his hands and feet. Spanky turns to Ray.</context>
      <utterance>Drop him? What does drop him mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The goons hoist Claude up on another pulley and dangle him head first over a hole in the floor. Several feet down, the Harlem River laps against the wooden pylons.</context>
      <utterance>You gotta lotta balls showing your face around my club. If a man's gonna run numbers on my side of Broadway, you think he'd have the common sense to keep a low profile. But not Ray Gibson.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shrugging, Ray pinches his nose and puffs out his cheeks. The goons release the rope and Claude plunges into the water. Spanky turns back to Ray.</context>
      <utterance>No, not down there! That water's filthy! Help me out here, man!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to drown that fella, Spanky. You already scared him half to death. He didn't know who he was fucking with.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you do. What does that say about you, Ray? What does that say about me? I've given you a lot of leeway over the years on account of your father. But he didn't last long enough to teach you the meaning of the word respect so I guess I'm gonna have to school you myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The henchman yanks on the rope. Claude emerges from the hole, gasping for breath.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Spank, I'm just trying to get by here. You remember how it was when you were starting out.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The henchman releases the rope, sending Claude back into the water. Ray reaches into his jacket. Bullethead pulls a gun and presses it into Ray's temple. Ray gives him a look and cautiously pulls out his bottle.</context>
      <utterance>I was supposed to wear this suit on Monday!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that, some of your bathtub brew?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray tosses him the bottle. Spanky uncorks, sniffs, samples the goods. He's impressed.</context>
      <utterance>Puerto Rican rum. See for yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd you get this?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Once again, the henchman yanks on the rope and Claude comes up sucking air desperately. He releases the rope, submerging Claude for a third time.</context>
      <utterance>Comes up the Mississippi. I can get more. A lot more. I was thinking about going into business for myself, but under the circumstances, I'd be willing to take on a partner.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm interested. Keep talking.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spanky considers the terms. Can he afford to trust Ray? Can he afford not to?</context>
      <utterance>All I need is the front money and a truck. I could be back in two, three days tops if I had somebody to share the driving.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you fuck me on this one, I'll spare no expense.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Understood.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray glances around. The pulley rope is still twitching in the water.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, Ray, you've got a deal. Pick your man and get going.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take the little choirboy, if you don't mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I was you, I'd want somebody who can handle himself in a tight spot.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spanky sees Ray's point. He nods to the henchman, who hoists Claude's limp body out of the water and onto the cement. Spanky plants a foot on Claude's chest and applies pressure. A geyser of Harlem River water shoots from Claude's mouth as he sputters back to life.</context>
      <utterance>I just want somebody who won't put a bullet in my back once the truck is full.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For your sake, I hope you can drive. Somebody give him some dry clothes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="38">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tight-lipped, Claude shifts in his seat.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me about that hot sketch you were hypin' last night. She was a choice bit of calico. You two been seeing each other a long time? Gonna slap the handcuffs on her and stroll down the aisle one of these days?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>If Claude does like it, he's not letting on.</context>
      <utterance>Sometimes I wish I could find me a sheba to settle down with. Suppose I'm just a tomcat by nature.  This little rum run is gonna seriously improve my relationship with Spanky. He's a good man to have on your side. He's got the capital and the connections. That's what you got to have in that business. Spanky's place is pretty plush, but one of these days I'm gonna open up my own establishment. Ray's Boom-Boom Room. You like that? Ray's Boom-Boom Room. That's in the groove, don't you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, daddy-o. You haven't said a word since we started. Least you could do is make some friendly conversation.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, man, I don't want friendly conversation. I don't want to be your friend. I've seen your friends and I don't like them. I just want to do this thing and get back to New York in time to start my job.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Start your job? What kind of job?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if you must know, bank teller at First Federal of Manhattan. I'm responsible for keeping track of hundreds, occasionally thousands of dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's some long green.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat of silence. Ray laughs to himself.</context>
      <utterance>Damn straight, it is. I got my own set of keys because I'm supposed to open up. So if I ain't there 8 a.m. Monday morning, there's gonna be hell to pay.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, tell me what's so funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Bank teller. Sounds like ladies work to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, maybe I should dig around in other people's clothes for money. It's obviously been highly successful for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, you'd be surprised what you find in other people's pockets. Just gotta avoid them deadbeat bank tellers. Get you every time.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't start out to be a bank teller. I was gonna be a ballplayer. Even had an offer to play short for the Newark Eagles.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you take it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Negro League don't pay so good. And you're always on the road. That don't wash with Daisy.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gave up baseball to be a bank teller? I can't latch on to that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At some point a man's got to get serious about his future. I'm sure you have no idea what I'm talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're talking about giving up baseball to be a bank teller.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bank teller's just a start. I got plans. Real plans. Not opening some Zoom-Boom Room. This time next year I'll be a loan officer.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A loan officer?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right, a loan officer.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you mean, if I needed some jack to get my nightclub up and running, I'd have to hype some square like you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray pulls out his pocket watch. A mechanical tune plays as he checks the time.</context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How would I get a loan, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need collateral.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That thing? Who'd you steal it from?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My daddy gave me this watch.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Who'd he steal it from?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My daddy is dead so watch your mouth. You can say what you want about me, but don't be dragging my daddy into it. This watch means the world to me. Solid gold. Keeps perfect time.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray stuffs his daddy's watch back in his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Looks like a fake to me. Loan denied!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, go chase yourself. I'll take my business elsewhere. And for future reference, you are no longer welcome at Ray's Boom-Boom Room.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is no Boom-Boom Room.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When there is, you can forget about it. And I swear to God, you ever talk about my daddy again I'm gonna kick your bank-telling, loan-denying ass, you got me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oooh...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I liked you better when you kept your trap shut.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nothing but sullen stares from all corners of the room.</context>
      <utterance>Man, something smells good in here. How's everybody doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe we oughta find another place.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding? Tell me you don't want a slice of that pie right over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude tugs Ray towards the door but Ray won't be dissuaded. He boldly addresses a YOUNG MAN in an apron behind the counter.</context>
      <utterance>I must have left my appetite outside, which is where I think we ought to be right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good evening, Billy. We'd like some coffee and a couple of slices of that homemade pie you've got advertised.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you know my name's Billy?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It says so right there on your shirt.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billy's MAMA sets a piping hot pie on the back counter and steps up next to her son. She casts a disparaging glance at Claude's suit.</context>
      <utterance>That what that says?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude considers the sign she's pointing to.</context>
      <utterance>If you boys can read so good, how come you missed that sign in the window?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean this sign? The one that says "No Coloreds Allowed." That's a good question. Ray, how come we missed the sign?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, ma'am, we've been driving all day. We'd just like to purchase one of those pies and we'll be on our way.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those are whites-only pies.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude jabs him.</context>
      <utterance>Got any nigger pies?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude starts tugging Ray toward the door.</context>
      <utterance>Any fool could see those are whites- only, not-for-blacks, come-on-let's- get-the-fuck-outta-here pies. Thank you very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for backing me up here, Uncle Claude.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't Uncle Claude me. You get a load of those crackers? Couldn't be a mouthful of teeth among the bunch of 'em. Why you want to pick a fight with people like that for?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're soft.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Diner patrons stare.</context>
      <utterance>What'd you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said you're soft.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, man, don't ever call me that.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude narrows his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I call it like I see it, and what I see is definitely soft.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright. You want some pie?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I want some pie.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Resolved, Claude stomps over to the counter.</context>
      <utterance>Okay then, I'm gonna walk over to that counter and get us some fucking pie.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude lays down a dollar bill. Mama casually pulls a shotgun from under the counter.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, ma'am, I bet a brick will turn that one right there into a colored pie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I bet this right here will turn you into a colored pie.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray gives the whole place a cool once-over as Claude pulls him out the door. Mama turns to Billy, still studying the stitching on his shirt.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, Ray, I think we can go now. Much obliged...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be concentrating so hard, baby. You're liable to seize yourself again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you doing? We're looking for Slim.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray cocks an eyebrow.</context>
      <utterance>You found him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>SLIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray pulls out a wad and slaps it in Slim's sweaty palm. The fat man starts counting it out.</context>
      <utterance>That's it, fellas. Thirty six cases of Puerto Rico's finest. At five bucks a case, that's $180.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, that music is hot. What goes on down there, Slim?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Natchez-under-the-Hill.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blacks welcome there?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Green's the only color that matters under the hill. They got gambling, girls. You oughta check it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slim slips into the shadows.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe we will. Nice meeting you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice meeting you? You've been here before, haven't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What gave you that idea?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I don't know, maybe because our lives depend on it, I just sort of thought you knew what you were doing!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't get all agitated on me. I bought a bottle of rum from a couple of dudes, I heard 'em talking...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me get this straight. We drove all the way down to Klan country 'cause you heard a couple of guys talking?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you complaining about? It worked out. Everything's cool. Now, come on, let's head down there and see what's shaking. We deserve a little reward.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reward?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A look of excitement crosses Claude's face, but he quickly shakes it off.</context>
      <utterance>There are people down there having fun. I want to be one of them. I want you to be one of them. On Monday you can be a bank teller if you want, but tonight you're a bootlegger with a truck full of Puerto Rican rum and a fistful of cash.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Exasperated, Ray stuffs a few bills into Claude's pocket.</context>
      <utterance>That's gas money.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Left alone, Claude mutters and kicks at the dirt. He leans against the truck.</context>
      <utterance>There's your gas money. You stay here and watch the truck. And don't worry, I've got the keys.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SYLVIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never seen you in here before.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's because I've never been here before.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYLVIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Against his better judgement, Claude's gaze follows the long, slender arm up past a bare shoulder and settles on SYLVIA'S angelic face. He is struck dumb.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Sylvia. What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>SYLVIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't you remember your own name?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know it begins with a "C"...</utterance>
   <speaker>SYLVIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Mr. "C", how about buying a girl a drink?  Two bourbons.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I really shouldn't. I gotta keep an eye on my friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYLVIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The drinks arrive. She places a shot glass in Claude's reluctant hand. She winks provocatively and slowly pours the whiskey down her throat. Instinctively, Claude tosses back his shot.</context>
      <utterance>He looks like he can take care of himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Claude. That's my name. Claude. That's never happened before.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYLVIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're cute. You have any money, Claude?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten dollars. But I need it to get home.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYLVIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The bartender refills their glasses.</context>
      <utterance>Why would you want to go home? It's so early.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dealer tosses Ray a couple of cards. INSERT -- Ray fans his cards to reveal a full house. After considering the other players at the table, Ray pushes what's left of his money into the center of the table. The three other PLAYERS fold with disgust. Winston squints long and hard at Ray, then pushes everything he has into the center of the table.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take two.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Winston reaches into his jacket and throws down some more money on the pile.</context>
      <utterance>I'll see that...</utterance>
   <speaker>WINSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And while we're at it, let's sweeten the pot.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like my sugar bowl's empty, Mr. Hancock.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's just too damn bad, ain't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray checks his cards again. He looks at the pot, it's a lot of money. With this hand, there's no way he can lose. He places his daddy's pocket watch on top of the pile. Winston checks the time piece.</context>
      <utterance>Now, hang on, slick. I ain't through with you yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray lays down his hand.</context>
      <utterance>That'll cover it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Full boat, ladies doing the paddling.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray sits back, stunned. Winston rakes in his winnings. The game is over for the night. The three other players head to the bar.</context>
      <utterance>Four threes.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Winston tosses a silver dollar to Ray, who snatches it out of the air. Winston drops his hat on his head and moves through the crowd and out the door.</context>
      <utterance>Don't take it too hard, New York. Have a round on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray shakes his head. Carefully, she begins to clear the table. Suddenly, he grabs her wrist. Winston's glass tips over. Ray flips over the cocktail napkin to reveal an extra pile of cards.</context>
      <utterance>Can I get you something?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like he had a whole lot of nothing in his hand until you came along.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're hurting my arm.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Winston tries to move past Pike, but the sheriff blocks his path with a night stick. As Winston backs off, another squad car pulls up behind him. TWO DEPUTIES step from the car, guns drawn.</context>
      <utterance>If it isn't Winston Hancock.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought we agreed that you were gonna leave town.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pike slams Winston with his club, sending the black man to his knees. As Winston struggles back to his feet, a stiletto flashes and he lunges for the sheriff, slashing his cheek. The deputies grab Winston from behind, holding him by both arms. The long knife clatters to ground. Pike touches his face, examining the blood on his fingers.</context>
      <utterance>I tried to leave, Sheriff Pike. But your wife begged me to stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just committed suicide, boy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="36">
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Ray. I've been looking for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guess we better get going, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still got that ten dollars?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, not exactly. See, I met this girl. Real nice girl. God-fearing girl. Her name's Sylvia.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That jelly you were talking to right here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's in a tight spot. Her mama needs this operation, and they ain't got the money for it. Their church took up a collection but they were still short...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you made a generous contribution.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can I say? When the spirit moves me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was mighty charitable of you, Claude. Looks like we both got fucked tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>While you were upstairs doing God's work, I was getting jack-legged by a fool with four threes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You lost all our money in a card game?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He even got my daddy's watch.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck that cheap-ass watch --  I mean, how the hell are we gonna get home without any money?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've still got 36 cases of rum. That's better than money.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, the bloodied figure of Winston Hancock lurches from the shadows and grabs Claude by the lapels. Claude is too scared to scream, staggering backward. But the man's grip loosens and he slips to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>You sure the truck's this way?  I swear it was back that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray turns back to find Claude trembling with fear and covered in blood. He just points down. Ray eyes widen. He kneels down and turns Winston's body over.</context>
      <utterance>Ray... Yo, Ray...!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think he's hurt pretty bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Much to Claude's horror, Ray starts rifling through Winston's pockets.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, man, I've never seen a dead body before!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think you're doing?! The man's been dead for two seconds! Don't you have any respect?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It ain't here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What ain't there?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, the glare of two bright headlights from a pickup truck freeze Ray and Claude in a guilty tableau. FIVE WHITE MEN appear at the end of the alley.</context>
      <utterance>My daddy's watch. This is the dude I was telling you about --</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN WITH LANTERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray gingerly releases Winston's lifeless body.</context>
      <utterance>What's going on here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN WITH LANTERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with that one?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Him? He's just drunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, nobody puts 'em away like old what's-his-name.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Winston. His name's Winston.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude and Ray hoist Winston's body to its feet. The man raises his lantern, takes a closer look at Winston's face.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Ray, better get Winston back to the truck.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN WITH LANTERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray and Claude check for themselves.</context>
      <utterance>This fella looks dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you look at that, Ray. Winston up and died on us.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell with him then. If he can't share the driving, he can't ride in the truck.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN WITH LANTERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, the men all have guns. And they're pointed at Ray and Claude.</context>
      <utterance>He can ride with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN WITH LANTERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So can you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, this is gonna delay everything. Spanky's gonna be pissed.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spanky's gonna be pissed? Poor Spanky. Fuck Spanky! What the hell kind of a name is Spanky, anyway? You're responsible for this situation. I blame you for everything. If it wasn't for you, I'd be home having a hot meal right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The jailhouse door opens and Sheriff Pike walks in. He pauses to give the prisoners the once-over. There's a fresh bandage over the cut on his cheek.</context>
      <utterance>If it wasn't for me, you'd be washing up on the beach at Coney Island right now.  "I need all my thumbs and fingers for praying and doing good."</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do we have here?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Billy Bob and the boys found them down down under the hill with Winston Hancock. He was dead. Looks like murder.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't say.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like they was running rum. Got thirty six cases of evidence out back. You want I should call in the federal prosecutor?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pike winks at his deputy, then turns to regard the prisoners.</context>
      <utterance>Let's not drag the feds into this. I can think of better uses for that rum than letting it collect dust in some government warehouse up in Nashville.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Besides, why bother with bootlegging when we got us a clear cut case of murder?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, sheriff. As we explained to your associate here, there's been a mistake. We didn't kill anybody. Now, as for the bootlegging, we happen to work for a very important man in New York.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. Does the name Spanky Johnson mean anything to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Afraid not.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Johnson is very well connected. If you were to let us go, I guarantee he would show you his appreciation, if you know what I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you offering me a bribe?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just trying to pay the toll on the road to justice.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You may be able to buy your way out of trouble up in New York City, but down here we take murder seriously.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, man, how many times we gotta tell you people, we didn't kill that guy!</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pike turns his back on the prisoners and checks the time on a gold pocket watch -- Ray's pocket watch. But from his cell, Ray can't hear the mechanical tune.</context>
      <utterance>Well, if that's the case, then you don't have anything to worry about, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the cell, Claude turns to Ray.</context>
      <utterance>Time to get home to the missus. See y'all in the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The man's gotta point. We're innocent, after all. I just gotta get a good night's sleep on this filthy mattress. Keep our heads on straight, stay cool, what's the worst thing that could happen to us?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JUDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The gavel comes down with a thundering crash. Stunned, Ray and Claude resist the BAILIFFS' efforts to remove them from the courtroom.</context>
      <utterance>Life!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Life?! How long is life? We were just walking back to the truck. We didn't do nothing! Fuck life!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They continue to protest loudly as they are dragged bodily through the door.</context>
      <utterance>Life?! What's life mean? There's no way I can do life. I got a job starts Monday morning!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Ray and Claude stare out the window, getting their first look at the harsh reality that awaits them. Cotton fields stretch to the horizon in every direction. HOE-GANGS till the earth under the watchful gaze of TRUSTY SHOOTERS...</context>
      <utterance>Welcome to the farm. Here you will be provided with ample opportunity to repay your debt to society through the rigors of hard labor...</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Along the road, CONVICTS cast hard looks at the new men as the cart passes. A WHITE SERGEANT on horseback shifts his rifle and casually spits tobacco juice in the dirt...</context>
      <utterance>In between harvest and planting season we got fields need clearing, roads need building and ditches need digging. You will eat only what you can grow. Your crop don't come in, you'll go hungry. If you die, don't worry 'bout us none. We'll find somebody to replace you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dillard plucks a hat off one of the new prisoners and tosses it over the gun line. SHOTS ring out from the nearest shack. The hat is torn to shreds.</context>
      <utterance>This here is Camp 8. Camp 8 is for incorrigibles, so whatever you've done to get here, believe me, we're not impressed. You new men are probably noticing that we have no fences here at Camp 8. We don't need no fences, we have the gun line. It runs from shack to shack clear around the yard. You are now inside the gun line. If you step outside the gun line without my permission, you will be shot. If you trip and fall over the gun line, you will be shot. If you spit, if you pee, if you stick your ass out and take a dump over the gun line, you will be shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dillard puts a cigarette in his mouth. Hoppin' Bob is right there with the flame.</context>
      <utterance>One of my trusties puts a bullet in you when you're trying to run, I'm liable to give him a pardon for saving me the trouble of tracking you down, so you can bet their aim is true.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nodding to Bob, Dillard saunters off.</context>
      <utterance>My name is Sgt. Dillard. In the unlikely event that you need to address me, you call me boss. You already met this handsome fella right here. Hoppin' Bob's my ace boon coon. You run afoul of Hoppin' Bob, you run afoul of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOPPIN' BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray and Claude share a look. Self-consciously, the men begin to undress.</context>
      <utterance>New men, strip down!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HOPPIN' BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All activity comes to a halt as the new men shuffle into the cage wearing their prison-issue "ring-arounds." Hoppin' Bob slams the metal doors shut behind them.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, ladies, got some fresh meat for ya!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOPPIN' BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The INCORRIGIBLES hungrily eye the new men in total silence. Claude sticks close to Ray as they shuffle toward their assigned bunks. The CAMERA SETTLES on a much younger WILLIE</context>
      <utterance>We ain't got no wallflowers at Camp 8. Everybody gotta dance eventually. But don't worry, they won't try nothing tonight. That would take all of the fun outta the courtship.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude stops to catch his breath and take off his shirt.</context>
      <utterance>I don't believe this before Abe jive. I didn't go to night school to sing in no Mississippi Boys Choir!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't do that if I was you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A SHOT rings out. Claude hits the ground as a bullet kicks up some dust nearby.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up. It's too damn hot. What do you know, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude looks up to see Dillard cracking pistachio nuts as Hoppin' Bob puts another round in the chamber of his rifle.</context>
      <utterance>Told ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why ain't his pick swinging?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOPPIN' BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why ain't that pick swinging?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's too hot, boss. I'm tired.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOPPIN' BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He says it's too hot, boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too hot, huh? Well, you tell that lazy jiggaboo the state of Mississippi ain't interested in his meteorological assessments.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOPPIN' BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen up, jiggaboo! State of Mississippi ain't interested in your... in your...  metropolitan assets!</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell him the state of Mississippi is only interested in getting this ditch cleared by sundown.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOPPIN' BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>State of Mississippi wants this ditch cleared by sundown. You got that?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got it... boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He don't sound like he's from 'round here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOPPIN' BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's from New York City. That one, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>New York. That's up north, ain't it? They'll find we do things different down here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annoyed, Dillard jabs the butt of his rifle into Ray's solar plexus. Ray sinks to his knees in the dirt.</context>
      <utterance>We noticed.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like we got a couple of live ones. How long these boys in for?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOPPIN' BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Judge gave 'em the long ride.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dillard swaggers off, dogged at the heels by the ever faithful Hoppin' Bob. Resigned, Ray and Claude return to their labor.</context>
      <utterance>Life, huh? They step outta line again, we'll shorten up that sentence real fast.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="30">
   <speaker>BISCUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Willie exchanges two cigarettes for a second ladle. POKER FACE pulls a crumpled envelope from his shirt. His expression never changes, hence the name.</context>
      <utterance>Drink it up!</utterance>
   <speaker>POKER FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Either of you new fellas know how to read? I've had this letter four months now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't read? None of these guys can read?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last fella who could read made parole 'round Christmas.</utterance>
   <speaker>POKER FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't even know who this is from.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray unfolds the letter and scans it.</context>
      <utterance>Here, gimme that.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The prisoners express their condolences. "Sorry, man." "That's some bad news." "I know you loved Bo like a brother..."</context>
      <utterance>It's from your mama's neighbor, Mrs. Tidwell. She thought you oughta know that your second cousin Bo died.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More sympathy from the men. "Ooh. Twice in one letter." "Rough break, Poker Face..."</context>
      <utterance>And your other cousin, Sally, on your daddy's side, she died.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Apparently, your sister died.</utterance>
   <speaker>POKER FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jenny?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Relief all around. "Thank goodness."</context>
      <utterance>No, it says Marleen here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>"Bad luck, man." "That's harsh..."</context>
      <utterance>Oh, wait, looks like Jenny died, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The prisoners share dark looks. Ray folds up the letter and hands it back to Poker Face.</context>
      <utterance>Then it goes on for a while about how the crop didn't come in on accounta the frost.  She finishes up with something about a tornado and how your mama and your daddy died in that. But don't worry none. She'll take care of the dog. That is, if it gets over the worms.</utterance>
   <speaker>POKER FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Appreciate it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>"No, man, we're good." The men shake their heads and return letters and cards to their pockets. Jangle Leg nods and switches places with one of the convicts, parking next to Claude.</context>
      <utterance>Anybody else need anything read?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANGLE LEG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANGLE LEG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever done time before?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You kidding? I've been in and out of prison my entire life. Mostly in. I'm hard-core.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANGLE LEG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you won't have no problem making the adjustment. You need anything, help of any kind, gimme a holler. Name's Jangle Leg.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they shake, Jangle Leg inspects Claude's hand thoroughly.</context>
      <utterance>'Preciate it. Claude.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANGLE LEG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soft and supple. Like a lady's.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I try to moisturize regularly.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOPPIN' BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Jangle Leg, what'd I tell you about pitching woo on the job?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANGLE LEG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude snatches back his hand and gives Jangle Leg a hard look.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Cap'n.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOPPIN' BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the men grab their tools and return to work, Claude leans over to Ray.</context>
      <utterance>Break's over! Back to work!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you think they call him Jangle Leg?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody just told me he wins the three-legged race every year.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He does it all by himself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="53">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Creamed chip beef on toast. Except we're outta beef, so I had to improvise.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't I get one of those steaks you got grilling back there?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another prisoner lays down some tobacco and gets a juicy steak. Ray grabs a hunk of corn bread and makes his way to the back of the room. Claude steps up, holds out his tray for Cookie.</context>
      <utterance>Those are for trusties, unless you got thirty cents or two packs of cigs.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, I don't like it when the food touches each other, so if you could just --</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode>SPLAT!</mode>
      <context>Disappointed, Claude turns to discover that the only seat left is next to Ray. Scowling, he limps toward it. Jangle Leg's eyes follow Claude as he approaches the table. Biscuit smacks him.</context>
      <utterance>-- keep everything separate.</utterance>
   <speaker>BISCUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude sits down and promptly goes to work scraping his burnt toast with his knife. The irritating sound slowly brings the entire room to dead silence. All eyes fall on Claude. Scratch, scratch, scratch...</context>
      <utterance>Eyes front, mister!</utterance>
   <speaker>COOKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Problem with the toast?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cookie glowers and takes a seat.</context>
      <utterance>It's fine now.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the room returns to normal, Claude starts polishing his fork with his shirttail. Irritated, Ray shoots him a look.</context>
      <utterance>Stop aggravating people. Just eat your food.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This fork is filthy.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Undeterred, Claude breathes on his fork and polishes it some more. Disgusted, Ray pushes aside his plate.</context>
      <utterance>The fork is the least of your worries, Claude.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me? Willie Long.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you in for, Willie?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a long story...</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When he was 13 years old he killed a son-of-a-bitch with a claw hammer.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They never proved that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a second, you've been in here since you were thirteen?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about you, Radio?</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Armed robbery.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANGLE LEG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn liar. Bitch killed his sister with an axe.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was my half-sister. Shit, I ain't the son-of-a-bitch who poisoned my own parents.</utterance>
   <speaker>BISCUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They deserved it. Very strict.</utterance>
   <speaker>POKER FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about you, Biscuit? You nearly skinned your poor old landlady alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least he didn't kill Santa Claus with his bare hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You killed Santa Claus?</utterance>
   <speaker>BISCUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On Christmas Eve.</utterance>
   <speaker>POKER FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wasn't the Santa Claus, he was just wearing the suit and ringing a bell.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The whole table waits expectantly for their reply.</context>
      <utterance>What did you guys do?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I kinda lost track of how many people we killed that night. Must have been 15 or twenty -- not counting women and children. It was a real bloodbath. All that screaming...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pack of lies. Don't listen to him. We didn't kill nobody. We were railroaded. And we gonna prove that.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the end of the table, GOLDMOUTH, a hulking specimen, snarls menacingly, flashing a glittering set of teeth.</context>
      <utterance>He just blocked it out. Nigger's crazy. He's the one who did all the stabbing. He's capable of some heinous shit.  How 'bout him down there?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goldmouth? They say he was born out back behind the shithouse. That's what they say.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You all been here a long time. Doesn't anybody ever escape from this place?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They run but they never get too far.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Couple years back, Cookie made it clear to Greenville.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Greenville, that the nearest town?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a two-day walk if you don't get lost. Take a mighty cagey country boy to navigate the woods and bayous between here and there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BISCUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those dogs they got can sniff a skid mark in your underpants from a half- mile off.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, well, let's say you make it to Greenville. What's there, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grandma Dodi's Pork Rib Joint.</utterance>
   <speaker>POKER FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's where they nabbed him.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't even get to have my peach cobbler.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, Goldmouth stands up, casting a shadow over Claude.</context>
      <utterance>The most important thing they got in Greenville is a train that heads up north.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOLDMOUTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude looks up, considering his options.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, girl, you gonna eat your corn bread?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, man. I want you to have it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait up there, Claude. You give that guy your corn bread and the next thing you know you'll be ironing his shirts and clipping his toenails.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOLDMOUTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I oughta eat your corn bread.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray picks up his corn bread and takes a huge bite out of it, rolling his eyes with enthusiasm.</context>
      <utterance>My corn bread? Oh no, my friend. I love corn bread.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray looks at the faces around the room, smiles broadly. Goldmouth is getting embarrassed.</context>
      <utterance>I thought my mama made good corn bread but this is really something special.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The prisoners begin to laugh. Ray's got them now.</context>
      <utterance>Who knew I'd have to come all the way down to this here prison, deep in the asshole of the great state of Mississippi, to find such a tasty piece of corn bread?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And who knew that in this great corn bread-making institution I'd come face to face with the biggest, ugliest, stinkiest, ugliest gold- mouthed negro in the entire world. Now get out of my face before I lose my appetite!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>GOLDMOUTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goldmouth and Ray square off. Goldmouth swings, Ray ducks and counters with a swift jab to the gut. Goldmouth just flashes a shiny grin and clobbers Ray with a fist the size of a Thanksgiving turkey. Ray sinks to the dust. Radio drops down near him.</context>
      <utterance>How you like your corn bread now, New York?</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray shakes his head and staggers back to his feet. He circles the big man and gets in a couple of good shots, much to the crowd's approval. Goldmouth shakes his head and wipes the blood from his nose. Now he's mad. He grabs Ray by the shirt and delivers a crushing blow. Ray reels backward into Cookie's arms.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, New York, you can do better than that! Get up and show him how they do it in Harlem!</utterance>
   <speaker>COOKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cookie shoves Ray back into the ring for more punishment. Claude emerges from the mess hall, munching on a piece of corn bread. He squeezes in between Poker Face and Willie.</context>
      <utterance>I appreciate you going to all this trouble over my corn bread. I don't get a lot of compliments in my line of work.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your pal's getting the tar whipped out of him on your account.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then Claude winces as Goldmouth delivers a jaw-crushing uppercut that knocks Ray on his back. Claude bristles under the incriminating looks coming at him from all directions.</context>
      <utterance>How many times I got to tell you? He ain't my pal. Besides, he looks like he knows what he's doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude crouches down as Ray rolls over on his stomach and pushes himself up onto all fours. His eyes are swollen shut, his face covered with blood.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, alright...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Ray, I think you made your point, whatever that is. Maybe now's a good time to throw in the towel. You know what I'm saying? Ray manages a smile and staggers to his feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cookie, Radio and Poker Face raise Ray to his feet. Goldmouth slings him over his shoulder and carries him toward the bunkhouse. Dazed, Ray catches Claude's eye.</context>
      <utterance>The man's taken enough of a beating. Let's get him inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A quick elbow jab from Goldmouth and Ray is out for good. Disgusted with himself, Claude tosses what's left of the corn bread to the mangy dog, who makes short work of it.</context>
      <utterance>Got him good, huh, Claude? He won't be bothering us anytime soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>BISCUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shame, shame, that's your name.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dillard considers Daisy.</context>
      <utterance>Request permission to go to the tonk, boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't see no wedding ring, Banks. Conjugal visits are for married prisoners only.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think you could make an exception just this once, boss? She came all the way down from New York.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daisy gets the picture. She reaches into her purse and hands Dillard a couple of dollars.</context>
      <utterance>I don't need the Baptists on my back, but I suppose I could issue a temporary marriage license for a nominal fee.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude takes Daisy's hand and leads her over the gun line.</context>
      <utterance>I now pronounce you man and wife.  Claude Banks going to the tonk!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="40">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Biscuit, when you're done with Jangle Leg, you think you could squeeze me in?</utterance>
   <speaker>BISCUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thought you'd never ask. Biscuit needs some gravy.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm talking about a haircut.</utterance>
   <speaker>BISCUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cost you a pair of nylons.</utterance>
   <speaker>POKER FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Ray, Goldmouth don't believe me. Ain't it so they got trains up in New York City that run under the streets?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Radio looks up from a vacuum tube receiver he's busy repairing.</context>
      <utterance>They're called subways. A nickel will take you from one end of Manhattan to the other. Helluva ride, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Ray, you ever been to the Cotton Club?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure I've been to the Cotton Club. It's pretty sweet. But it don't hold a candle to the Boom Boom Room. That's where the real action is.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the Boom Boom Room?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's my joint. The swinginest nightclub in town.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got your own nightclub?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, not yet. It's still in the planning stages.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOLDMOUTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So it don't exist.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hoppin' Bob calls to Ray from the gun line.</context>
      <utterance>Just because it's in my mind, Goldmouth, don't mean it ain't real. Everything worth anything starts with a dream.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOPPIN' BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray turns to find his MOTHER, a handsome woman in a floral dress, coming toward him.</context>
      <utterance>Gibson! Got yourself a visitor!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mama?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAMA GIBSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The incorrigibles elbow each other and repeat the name "Rayford" as Mama Gibson envelops her son in a fleshy embrace, smothering him with kisses.</context>
      <utterance>Rayford!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here, mama?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAMA GIBSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard some things so I went to see Spanky Johnson. He told me what happened and gave me some money to get down here. What happened to your face?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The motley crew gathers around, nodding politely. Goldmouth flashes a golden grin. Willie gallantly doffs his cap.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about that. Hey, fellas, this here is my mama. These are some of my friends. That's Willie, there's Poker Face, Radio, Cookie, Goldmouth, Biscuit, Jangle Leg.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mama manages a half-hearted smile, clutching her bag.</context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Gibson. Shame on Rayford here for failing to mention that he had such a beautiful mama.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAMA GIBSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice to meet you all.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOLDMOUTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How was your train ride?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAMA GIBSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quite comfortable, thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Them cookies in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAMA GIBSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, oatmeal.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Scuse me, you got any batteries on you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAMA GIBSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Biscuit sides up, fingering her dress.</context>
      <utterance>No. No I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>BISCUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a lovely dress. Make it yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAMA GIBSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long, uncomfortable beat. Mama's lip starts to tremble.</context>
      <utterance>This is a big surprise, mama. I sure didn't expect to see you down here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAMA GIBSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rayford, I wanted so much more for you than this.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't cry, mama. This place ain't so bad as it looks. Sure, we work hard, but there's plenty fresh air and sunshine... And you know something else, I've taken to going to church regular. They got services every Sunday right there in the mess hall.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAMA GIBSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts some money in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you lie to me, Rayford.  You still have your daddy's watch?  Well, this is all I can give you. I wish it was more.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't take that, mama.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAMA GIBSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reluctantly, Ray stashes the money in his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Don't argue with me. You need it more than I do. I know how a little money can help in a place like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe this. I always said I'd never end up like this. I thought I'd make something of myself, do something with my life. You know, be successful. Have a big house, a family. Now I'm gonna end up just like daddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAMA GIBSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't say that, Rayford. Don't ever say that. He gave up hope. That's where you gotta be different.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They gave me life, mama.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAMA GIBSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gave you life. And they can't take it away from you. Remember that. You'll get outta here someday. I believe that. You gotta believe it, too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daisy quickly buttons up her dress.</context>
      <utterance>Woman came all the way from New York, goddamnit! We'll come out when we're good and ready!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you go see my cousin Maynard like I asked you in my letter?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAISY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course I did. He said he'd file an appeal right away. You didn't tell me he was so good looking.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that side of the family has all the looks and none of the brains. I hope he don't mess things up.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAISY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He seemed like a pretty good lawyer to me. His offices take up an entire floor of that big, new building on 125th Street, and he was using all these words I never heard before. He even offered me a job.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daisy smiles weakly and looks away. She doesn't have much faith in this promise.</context>
      <utterance>A job, huh? Well, that's nice, real nice. You won't have to work long. I'll be back soon enough. After I start work at First Federal Bank of Manhattan, I'll be keeping you in style. Everything will get back to normal again. That's a promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAISY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Claude, Maynard wanted to know if he should file the appeal on behalf of your friend, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ray Gibson?  No, no. He's the reason I'm in here, Daisy. For all I know, he's got a record a mile long. I got a better shot of getting out of here on my own. You tell Maynard to think about me, concentrate on me. Understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAISY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, Claude, whatever you say.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We lost yesterday on accounta the rain. That means we gotta make up for it today, so put your backs to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOPPIN' BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray and Claude jump down after Willie.</context>
      <utterance>You heard the boss! Let's move!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like a scorcher.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bet the son of a bitch goes over a hundred and ten.</utterance>
   <speaker>POKER FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take that action.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dillard uses his foot to roll the stricken man over. He's still alive. Barely.</context>
      <utterance>Man down, boss!</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray and Claude drop their tools, grab the man by his arms and legs and lug him up to the road. Once out of earshot, Ray whispers to Claude.</context>
      <utterance>You two, put him on the truck!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cookie drew me a map to Greenville.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what I'm saying.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I know what your saying. And I'm saying if you made it that far, they'd be watching every train that pulls out of that station.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why we won't take the train. Cookie showed me where there's a farm house. They got a boat there.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They reach the truck. With effort, they swing the man back and forth and launch him into the back of the truck.</context>
      <utterance>What do you know about boats? I bet you can't even swim.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I know about boats is they take you to freedom. Come on, man. I think we can do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you always talking about we? There is no we. There is a me, there is a you. But there is no we between us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want out of this place, don't you? Don't tell me you're starting to like it here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I don't like it here. Look around. There's nothing but ass. Male ass! Balls and ass! Believe you me, I'm getting out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not gonna forget it. What does that mean? If you've got a plan, I think I have a right to know about it. I told you my plan.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude splits. Scowling, Ray finishes up his shave.</context>
      <utterance>Getting a map from a chubby chef named Cookie? Dragging our asses through the swamps in search of some worm-eaten boat? That ain't a plan, that's a vacation for two in the hole. When you've got a map to New York City, you get back to me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>JANGLE LEG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure was hot out there today.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still too hot to sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every bone in my body feel like a big son-of-a-bitch dog got hold of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOLDMOUTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't wait 'til Sunday.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Restless, Radio rolls over.</context>
      <utterance>What's so great about Sunday? Monday's right after it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Ray, what's the name of that nightclub of yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean the Boom-Boom Room?</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it. The Boom-Boom Room. Sure would like to see that place when you get it up and running.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should have come by last night, Radio. You woulda had yourself some fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last night? What are you talking about, Ray?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm talking about old Satchmo nearly blew the roof off the joint.</utterance>
   <speaker>POKER FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Satchmo.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOLDMOUTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean Louis Armstrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a good friend of mine. Drops by the club whenever he's in town.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>"Shut up, Claude!" echoes around the room. Irritated, Claude thumps his pillow and turns his back on the room.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, do we have to listen to this bullshit? I'm trying to get some sleep around here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BLAM! A high horn note sounds.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, things were hot last night, but you'll never guess who's playing tonight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BISCUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Biscuit is up on a makeshift platform in the bunkhouse, lipsyncing to Ella Fitzgerald. But its not the depressing bunkhouse anymore, it has transformed into Ray's Boom-Boom Room. PULL OUT SLOWLY as Ray, decked out in a sleek tuxedo steps in front of the CAMERA. He speaks into the CAMERA as he walks...</context>
      <utterance>A tisket a tasket...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right, fellas. Catch any cab heading uptown. All the drivers know Ray's Boom-Boom Room.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOLDMOUTH</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Ray looks to his left, sees Goldmouth in the old bunkhouse.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Ray...</utterance>
   <speaker>GOLDMOUTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where am I at, man?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE ON Cookie sitting a table eating a huge porterhouse. The CAMERA DOLLIES around to find Ray eating with him.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Ray, I could get used to this!</utterance>
   <speaker>COOKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ray, my man, this steak is like butter!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Made just for you, Cookie.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about some steak sauce?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray motions to a busboy clearing a table. It's Claude.</context>
      <utterance>No problem. Oh, boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude grimaces.</context>
      <utterance>How about some Worchestershire sauce! And clean that damn table.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CAMERA PULLS BACK as Ray throws the dice. A perfect seven. The CAMERA PANS UP to Poker Face in a tux clutching a fistful of cash.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Poker Face, what's a club without some dice?</utterance>
   <speaker>POKER FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Across the room, Jangle Leg, in a tux, sits at the piano. Radio, also in a tux, beats on the drums.</context>
      <utterance>Lucky seven! My nigger! Let it ride!</utterance>
   <speaker>JANGLE LEG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Biscuit sings the song, smiling lovingly at her man. Everyone is having a great time in Ray's Boom-Boom Room, until... Whistles blow. At the front door, Hoppin' Bob appears with FIVE TRUSTIES dressed in police outfits. The incorrigibles scatter.</context>
      <utterance>Sing, girlfriend!</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A hard white light from Hoppin' Bob's flashlight shines directly into the CAMERA. CLOSE ON Ray, in his bed, back in the old bunkhouse. The music stops abruptly. He shields his eyes from the harsh light. Hoppin' Bob is looming over him. It's back to reality.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Ray, looks like trouble!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOPPIN' BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A loud burst of flatulence cuts through the darkness. Hoppin' Bob turns his flashlight on Cookie.</context>
      <utterance>You don't shut up, you're gonna spend the rest of the night in the hole, Gibson! That goes for the rest of you girls, too. I don't want to hear another peep about no Boom-Boom fucking Room!</utterance>
   <speaker>COOKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scowling, Hoppin' Bob steps out of the cage and locks the door behind him. The men slowly settle back in.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Cap'n.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lights out at Camp 8.</context>
      <utterance>Pretty good story, Ray. Didn't much care for the ending though.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The incorrigibles quickly gather around as he calls off names, passing cards and letters through the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Mail call!</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Craddock!... Williams... Henshaw!... Banks!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dillard hands the letter to Ray, who glances at it before passing it back to Claude.</context>
      <utterance>Here!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maynard Banks, Esquire. Attorney at law.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gimme that. That doesn't concern you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure it don't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's up, Ray?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Claude.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure is hot today. Think it'll rain later?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want, Claude?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do I want? What makes you think I want something?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My daddy always said when a man starts talking about the weather keep you hand on your wallet.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your daddy must have been a helluva guy, a deep man, a wise man. Sure wish I could have met him --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cut the bullshit. What do you want, Claude?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You still got that map?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if you're still thinking about booking it, I want in. I think we can make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We? Did I hear you say we? As I recall, you're the one who said there is no we. Guess we got some bad news in that letter, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, my cousin Maynard is a lawyer. He filed an appeal on my behalf --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On your behalf. What happened to we?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The appeal was denied. Then Daisy went and fell for Maynard. They're engaged to be married, can you believe that?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, let's just think about that for a moment. He's a successful lawyer up in New York City and you're down here with a bright future in the cotton picking business. Eeny, meeny, miney, Maynard.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, man. Don't shut me out. I'm telling you, you and me, that map, we can go places.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long beat.</context>
      <utterance>You know what, Claude? This whole time we've been down here, you've done nothing but think about yourself, acting like this whole thing is my fault. That plan with your cousin, did that include me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least you're honest for once. So now you want to be my friend? Well, let me tell you something, Claude-my- shit-don't-stink-Banks. You got a lot to learn about friendship.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does that mean I'm in?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so, Claude. You'd just slow me down. We'd have to stop every five minutes so you could polish your silverware. There's no way around it, you're soft.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said you're soft.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray gets in Claude's face and silently mouths the word -- "soft." Claude throws down his hoe and sinks his fist deep into Ray's gut.</context>
      <utterance>Don't call me that. You know I hate it when you call me that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray touches the blood coming from his nose. Eyes blazing, he tackles Claude, dragging him to the ground. The two men roll around, trying to strangle each other. Hoppin' Bob hustles down the hill and drags Ray off of Claude. But Claude comes back for more. Hoppin' Bob finds himself in the middle of the fray. That's when the cavalry arrives. Two trusties use their rifles to crack Ray and Claude over the backs of their heads, sending them both down for the count. Hoppin' Bob empties his canteen over their faces. They sputter back to consciousness.</context>
      <utterance>Damn, that felt good. I should have done that the first time I met you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOPPIN' BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you girls set aside your differences and get back to work or I'll see to it --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray and Claude stagger to their feet and pick up their tools. Hoppin' Bob and the trusties head back up the hill. Ray starts to chuckle.</context>
      <utterance>-- we'll spend a night in the hole. We heard this shit before.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray opens his palm to reveal TWO PEBBLES. Claude regards Ray with new-found respect.</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck are you laughing about?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HOPPIN' BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All in, boss!</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Move it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOPPIN' BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dillard spurs his horse, escorting the mule carts back to camp.</context>
      <utterance>Movin' it out, boss.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did it, man! You got us out! Next stop, New York City!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>New York's a long way's off. Let's just keep moving, okay? As Ray and Claude disappear into the woods...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know these trees all look the same, but I'm getting an awful familiar vibration from this one right here. You sure you know where we're going?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely. The map is very clear.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude considers it from various angles.</context>
      <utterance>Let me take a look at that map.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You call this a map? What was Cookie smoking when he drew this?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cookie didn't draw it. I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You drew this?!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew you wouldn't come if I didn't have a map.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray shrugs and presses on. Dumbfounded, Claude considers the map again, then tears it to shreds. The braying of hounds echoes through the trees.</context>
      <utterance>That gripes my soul, man. We're out here in the middle of nowhere. There is shit nibbling at my balls! Don't tell me you don't know where we're going!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, wait up!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Ray, time to go!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude sees Ray caught up on the fence, then hears the sounds of the approaching posse. If he floored it right now, he might make it. But he can't just leave Ray hanging there.</context>
      <utterance>I'm stuck!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MAE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mae Rose is pointing down the drive, where Dillard and a couple of trusties march Ray and Claude toward the house.</context>
      <utterance>Look, daddy. They caught those two men who escaped last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABERNATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They ain't men, Mae Rose. They're convicts. And nigger convicts to boot. Can you say nigger?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nagger?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABERNATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, nigger.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nigger.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABERNATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bound by leg irons and handcuffs, Ray and Claude are deposited at the bottom of the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>That's my girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here they are, Superintendent. We tracked 'em all the way to the Tallahachie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABERNATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mae Rose considers their faces. Ray and Claude look like they've been to hell and back.</context>
      <utterance>That's quite a ways. I'm glad you New York boys could see some of our lovely countryside while you're down here. What do you say, Mae Rose? How should we teach these two a lesson?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAE ROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A night in the hole?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABERNATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dillard nods and turns Ray and Claude around. As they march back down the drive, Abernathy takes sip of his mint julep and affectionately pats Mae Rose on the head.</context>
      <utterance>Better make it a week.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See you in a week, boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>OMITTED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't mention it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell, you'd probably be half way to New York by now...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm serious, man. Don't mention it. Ever.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>COOKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take Claude to die on Wednesday for fifty cents.</utterance>
   <speaker>POKER FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wednesday for two bits. And don't forget you already owe me a steak.</utterance>
   <speaker>BISCUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With an ear to his receiver, Radio slaps his money on the table.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take Claude for Friday. That's my birthday.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Weatherman says a heat wave's coming. I say neither one of 'em son of bitches gonna last past Thursday.</utterance>
   <speaker>POKER FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you before, I don't take pennies. Two cigarettes or one nickel minimum. What about you, Willie? Gonna get in on this action?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This gives the men pause. Willie tosses his money on the table.</context>
      <utterance>I got a crispy new dollar bill says both of them gonna make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>POKER FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now that's what I call a bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOLDMOUTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a mighty long shot, Willie. Nobody ever made it a week in the hole.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANGLE LEG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Willie leaves the money where it is.</context>
      <utterance>Not in August, anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>POKER FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Poker Face makes notations as the betting resumes.</context>
      <utterance>Who else has some guts around here?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ABERNATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think these boys have learned their lesson. Let's give 'em another week for good measure.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure you want to do that, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABERNATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you ever question me, Sgt. Dillard. When I give an order, you jump to it, or I'll kick you and that first-cousin you call a wife outta that pretty little house so fast it'll make your pin-head spin. You got that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dillard slams the doors on Ray and Claude and clamps shut the padlocks. Abernathy smiles at the incorrigibles, who regard him with undisguised hatred.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>POKER FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, they made it a week. Looks like you win, Willie.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let it ride.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Claude? You alright?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude pounds against the door, raising a holy racket. We continue to cut back and forth between cells as needed.</context>
      <utterance>Can't take it no more, Ray! Die, motherfucker! Gotta get the fuck outta here!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep it together, Claude. You wake up the man, he'll shoot you for sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude continues shouting and pounding.</context>
      <utterance>He'd be doing me a favor. I'm getting outta here one way or the other! Goddamn rats and shit! Fuck!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, man, just settle down. We'll get outta here, Claude. We'll get outta here real soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray looks around his cell. Claude's pounding is bound to wake up somebody soon.</context>
      <utterance>How the fuck are we gonna do that, Ray?!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll just get off at the next stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say what?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right, we'll get off at the next stop. The train's pulling into the station right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hell you talking about? What train?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude focuses on what Ray is saying and starts to breathe easier.</context>
      <utterance>We're in the Bronx, my man. Hundred and Sixty First Street.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hundred and Sixty First Street? That's Yankee Stadium.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell, yes, Yankee Stadium. Bombers are playing a double-header against the Red Sox.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Red Sox... Who's on the mound?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Who do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Allie Reynolds. He's my boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, it says Allie Reynolds right here in the program. He's warming up right now. Man, we're so close to the field I need cleats. How'd you get such good seats?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know people.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They must be the right people. Whoa, there goes the hot dog man. Let's get a couple. Damn, that smells good. Nothing like a ballpark hot dog, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You get ketchup?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ketchup? Who eats ketchup on a hot dog? Mustard's what you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't eat it with mustard.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me back that hot dog. I'll eat it myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What am I gonna eat?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can starve to death for all I care. Now shut up, the game's about to start.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, man, is Babe Ruth in the lineup today?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on? Are they alive or dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOLDMOUTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't look too good.</utterance>
   <speaker>POKER FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're not moving.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray's eyes blink open. Claude holds out a hand and helps him stand up. They share a look. They made it.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Ray...</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray and Claude stagger toward the bunkhouse as the incorrigibles gather on the porch and help them in out of the sun.</context>
      <utterance>Go on, get inside.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dillard pauses in front of a big country boy who can't be more than 18 years old. The kid is bouncing a rubber ball.</context>
      <utterance>...Camp 8 is for incorrigibles, so whatever you've done to get here, believe me, we are not impressed. You new men are probably noticing that we have no fences here at Camp 8. We don't need no fences, we have the gun line. It runs from shack to shack clear around the yard --</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kid don't answer. An OLD GUY steps forward.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell you think you're doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, boss. That kid don't talk. Something wrong with his head, just can't get right, boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't get right, huh? We'll see how long he last. Now, where was I?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOPPIN' BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't need no fences at Camp 8, boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. We don't need no fences, we have the gun line. It runs from shack to shack clear around the yard. You are now inside the gun line...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another pitch, another strike.</context>
      <utterance>I try to teach 'em the finer points of the game, share my wisdom, but I don't know why I bother. They don't listen, they sure don't learn...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you're dealing with here is a complete lack of talent.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Radio knocks a grounder up the middle.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sick of watching Camp 12 win the championship. Every year they get to roast the victory pig and we get dick. This year I want that pig.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Can't Get Right looks at Ray.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, Radio, there you go. Who wants to hit next?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to hit?  Yo, Claude. Give Can't Get Right a shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Him?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't be worse than any of these other fools.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Can't Get Right shuffles to the plate. Goldmouth hands him the bat.</context>
      <utterance>All right, grab the bat. Let's see what you can do.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jangle Leg tosses the ball. Can't Get Right swings and connects with a mighty CRACK! The incorrigibles crane their necks as the ball disappears into the sky. They turn to look at Can't Get Right. Ray gives Claude a significant look, then tosses another ball out to Jangle Leg on the mound.</context>
      <utterance>Jangle Leg's gonna throw the ball nice and easy. You just go ahead and take a swing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jangle Leg nods, winds up and delivers a whistling fast ball. Can't Get Right clobbers it. Once again, the incorrigibles track the departing projectile.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Let's try that again. This time give it a little juice.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Can't Get Right smiles for the first time.</context>
      <utterance>Told ya.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard Camp 12 got themselves a son- of-a-bitch used to pitch for the Mud Hens.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOLDMOUTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That boy got a year for jay-walking.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Judge must have money riding on the championship.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then a U. S. Army Jeep swerves past the men and parks in front of the mansion. Young CAPT. TOM BURNETTE helps MAE ROSE out of the car. The prisoners stare furtively at her long legs and curly blonde tresses.</context>
      <utterance>Don't matter who Camp 12 puts on the mound. All I know is when this season's over Camp 8's gonna have pork chops.</utterance>
   <speaker>POKER FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like little Mae Rose has grown up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BISCUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And out.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmm-mm, that girl's got gams.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's got it all. And it's firm and round and fully packed.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Next to them, Can't Get Right stares openly, mesmerized by her beauty. Ray nudges him.</context>
      <utterance>You shred it, wheat. That there is fresh water.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Up at the mansion, Abernathy and his WIFE come out onto the porch, all smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Be cool, man. You can look, just don't drool.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABERNATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How was the honeymoon? Am I gonna be a grandaddy soon?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. ABERNATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't pay attention to the superintendent, Tom. You're going to stay for supper, aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The prisoners steal glances as Mae Rose kisses her new husband goodbye. She gives them quite a show, raising her leg behind her just like Betty Grable. Then Tom climbs into the Jeep and pulls away. Mae Rose takes a long glance at the prisoners. The men all look away -- except Can't Get Right who stands there smiling innocently. Mae Rose gives him a little wink, then turns her back and bounces up the steps.</context>
      <utterance>Afraid not. I'm shipping out this afternoon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>POKER FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think you can handle something that big, Cookie?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beyond the fence, a late-model sedan rolls up. STAN BLOCKER, in a straw hat and a rumpled suit, climbs out and stretches his legs. Irritated, he smacks a mosquito and exchanges a few words with Dillard.</context>
      <utterance>I handled your mama, didn't I? Don't y'all worry. I got plans for that bad boy. Ain't none of him going to waste.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude hustles over, removing his hat.</context>
      <utterance>Banks! Get over here!</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Stan Blocker. Scout for the Nigger Leagues.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLOCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Negro Leagues, actually. Pittsburgh Crawfords. Ever hear of us?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We get the games on the radio sometimes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLOCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We played down in Jackson yesterday. Heard a rumor you've got a boy up here who can hit the ball a ton.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You probably mean Can't Get Right. That's him over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLOCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't Get Right? That's the kid's name? Can I talk to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can try, but you won't get too far. Why you interested?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLOCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crawford's are always looking for new talent.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you didn't notice, but this is a prison.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLOCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blocker winks at Dillard, then glances at the incorrigibles practicing in the field. Goldmouth, Cookie, Poker Face, Biscuit -- they don't exactly inspire confidence.</context>
      <utterance>There are ways around that. Right sergeant?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLOCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blocker takes a seat on the bench.</context>
      <utterance>Nice looking squad. See you after the game.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MRS. ABERNATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course, the superintendent's hoping for a boy, but personally, I'd prefer a girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mae Rose sits next to them. She is SIX MONTHS PREGNANT. She removes her sunglasses and coyly bites a fingernail when she spots Can't Get Right in the on-deck circle.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever it is will be a little gift from heaven. Look at the way she glows.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BLOCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark my words, within five years there's gonna be a colored man playing in the majors.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, the world hasn't changed that much.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLOCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe not yet. But it will. And I'll be out of a job. Damn, that's some tasty hooch.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's amazing what Ray here can do with a couple of pounds of potato skins and some molasses.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, Blocker, what do you think of our boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLOCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blocker starts for his car, parked just beyond the gun line.</context>
      <utterance>I think that boy could be the next Josh Gibson. I'm gonna talk to the front office about him, you can bet on that. Damn, it's getting late. We got a game in Memphis tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about us? Don't forget to mention us.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're like his handlers. He can't function without us.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLOCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray and Claude's eyes gleam with hope as Blocker's car rumbles off down the road.</context>
      <utterance>I'll put in a good word for you. You've done a good job with that boy. Thanks for your hospitality.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ABERNATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The DOCTOR steps from behind the curtain, drawing it behind him. He checks Mrs. Abernathy's pulse.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, doctor...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She'll be fine. She just had a bit of a shock.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABERNATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is Mae Rose okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's doing just fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABERNATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the baby?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a big one.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABERNATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abernathy pushes past the doctor and yanks open the curtain. Mae Rose is propped up in bed, looking exhausted.</context>
      <utterance>It's a boy! Well, let's get a look at him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABERNATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The NURSE turns around, cradling the baby in her arms. Abernathy gently pulls back the soft blanket. His eyes widen with horror upon discovering that the newest member of the Abernathy family is black.</context>
      <utterance>Well, where is he? Where's my new grandson?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>POKER FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really think they'll let him out of here just to play baseball?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not? Boy's got God-given talent.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God may have given it, but Claude Banks spotted it and nurtured it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn straight. I expect those Pittsburgh Crawdads to remember that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crawfords.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heads up, here comes trouble.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, listen up! I want every man lined up out here in the yard on the double! Let's move it!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOPPIN' BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You heard what the man said! Move it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ABERNATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Disgusted, Abernathy hands the baby back to Mae Rose. Then he turns, walks back to Can't Get Right and places a revolver against his head.</context>
      <utterance>I know it was somebody from this camp. I can feel it in my bones.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABERNATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Can't Get Right nods slowly. Abernathy smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Do you know who the father of that little chocolated baby is?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABERNATHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Up and down the line, the men brace themselves for the worst. Can't Get Right just grins. Enraged, Abernathy cocks the revolver. That's when Ray steps forward.</context>
      <utterance>Well, then, who is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stunned, Abernathy lowers the gun and approaches Ray. Then Claude steps forward.</context>
      <utterance>The baby's mine, boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Confused, Abernathy looks back and forth between the two men. Then Willie steps forward.</context>
      <utterance>He's lying, boss. I'm the father of that baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, it was me, boss. I know I may look old...</utterance>
   <speaker>BISCUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any fool could see that baby's mine, boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I beg to differ. That cute little rascal belongs to me...</utterance>
   <speaker>POKER FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the father...</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the father, boss...</utterance>
   <speaker>GOLDMOUTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the father...</utterance>
   <speaker>JANGLE LEG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And so it goes down the line, until every last man of Camp 8 has stepped forward to claim kinship with the Superintendent. Even hard-ass Dillard can't help cracking a smile. Disgusted, confused and thoroughly fed up, Abernathy jams the revolver into his belt and climbs into the car. As he guns the engine, Mae Rose gazes out the back window, smiling one last time at the father of her baby. Can't Get Right smiles back.</context>
      <utterance>I'm the father...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The incorrigibles erupt in boisterous agreement. Claude grabs Can't Get Right and shakes him.</context>
      <utterance>To Superintendent Abernathy. May he have many more grandchildren!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I want to know is where? When? How?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, Rev. Clay and his daughter emerge from the mess hall and start across the yard. It's a good thing the old man is blind because he wouldn't want to see how far his flock has strayed. The Reverend inhales deeply as one of Sylvia's girls passes nearby.</context>
      <utterance>Wasting your breath, Claude. He ain't the type to kiss and tell.</utterance>
   <speaker>REV. CLAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a sweet fragrance in the air today.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAY'S DAUGHTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blissed out incorrigibles enjoy a last dance as the band downshifts into a slow, sultry number. In the midst of the dancers, Claude clings to Sylvia. Nearby, Jangle Leg dances intimately with a YOUNG WOMAN. Up on the porch, Ray refreshes Biscuit's drink. Biscuit has been crying and it shows. The liquor probably isn't helping.</context>
      <utterance>The magnolias are blooming early this year, daddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't take it so hard, Biscuit. She don't mean nothin' to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BISCUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls some folded sheets of paper from his pocket, passes them to Ray.</context>
      <utterance>Hell with him. It ain't that.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are free papers.</utterance>
   <speaker>BISCUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What am I gonna do out there, Ray? I can't go home to my mama like this. I'll get the strap for sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Poker Face leans in.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Biscuit, this is good news. Your mama's gonna break down in tears when you show up on her doorstep.</utterance>
   <speaker>POKER FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray gives Poker face a shove, then turns back to Biscuit.</context>
      <utterance>I'll give you three to one she gives him the strap.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's 1945. It's a different world now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BISCUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not for me, it ain't.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray hands back the papers and heads off to dance with a PRETTY YOUNG WOMAN lingering nearby. Left alone, Biscuit polishes off his moonshine and checks his reflection in the bunkhouse window.</context>
      <utterance>Well you can't stay here, Biscuit. This ain't no life for a man. Any one of these fellas would give their right arm to be in your shoes. I sure know I would.</utterance>
   <speaker>BISCUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He crumples the discharge papers and drops them. Then he steps down from the porch and walks calmly past the dancing prisoners toward the gun line. Ray lifts his head off his date's shoulder. Something about the way Biscuit is walking suggests that he isn't going to stop.</context>
      <utterance>No life on the inside, no life on the outside...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But it's too late. Biscuit crosses the gun line and keeps walking, his eyes focused on the horizon.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Biscuit...!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The band stops playing, the dancers grow still. Dillard turns around and squints.</context>
      <utterance>Man over the line!</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Biscuit isn't paying attention. He breaks into a run. Dillard nods to Hoppin' Bob who raises his rifle and draws a bead. But he can't pull the trigger. He lowers his gun. Shots ring out from the shooter shacks. Biscuit reels from the impact of the bullets and looks down sadly at the blood spreading across his ring-arounds... Prisoners silently gather at the gunline. Jangle Leg pushes his way through the crowd and crosses the gunline without hesitation. Dillard indicates for the shooters to hold their fire. They train their rifles on Jangle Leg as he strides toward his fallen companion. Jangle Leg gently lifts Biscuit's lifeless body into his big arms and somberly carries him back toward the camp. The CAMERA RISES HIGH OVERHEAD as the prisoners make way for Jangle Leg to cross back over the gunline.</context>
      <utterance>Goddamnit, Biscuit, get back here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But nobody can muster much enthusiasm for this news. Radio shrugs and drops down on his bunk. Just then, Can't Get Right walks past heading for the door. He's dressed in civilian clothes, his bindle slung over his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, fellas, I got Chicago.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Can't Get Right holds out a piece of paper which Ray scrutinizes.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Can't Get Right, where you going? Why you dressed like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a pardon from the governor.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The incorrigibles gather around for a glimpse at Can't Get Right's ticket to freedom.</context>
      <utterance>Let me see that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Can't Get Right nods out the window. Stan Blocker is waiting by his car.</context>
      <utterance>Where'd you get this?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="32">
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo, Blocker, what's going on here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLOCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kid's getting out. I got him a pardon.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but what about me and Ray? I didn't see our names on that pardon. You said you were gonna put in a good word for us.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLOCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This hits Claude hard.</context>
      <utterance>I did, Claude. I mentioned you. I mentioned you both. But the fact is, pardons don't come cheap. The kid can hit. What can you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let it go, Claude.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not gonna let it go. The man needs to explain himself. Makin' promises.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLOCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I am truly sorry about this. I'd like to help you...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLOCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude looks around as the incorrigibles begin to gather. He's on the spot. Dillard approaches with Can't Get Right. Claude looks into the big kid's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>At least the kid's getting out. Isn't this what you wanted?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Steeling himself to the reality of the situation, Claude gives Can't Get Right a hug.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Of course it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You show them Crawfords how to play ball.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Can't Get Right nods. He steps up to the gun line and looks at both shooter shacks.</context>
      <utterance>Make 'em throw strikes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Can't Get Right steps across the gun line. Blocker opens the car door for him. But before he climbs in, Can't Get Right reaches into his pocket and pulls out his rubber ball. With a smile, he tosses it to Claude, who snatches it out of the air.</context>
      <utterance>It's alright. You're a free man now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLOCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blocker tips his hat and climbs behind the wheel. Claude and Ray watch Blocker's car drive off under a red Mississippi sunset. Slowly, the inmates drift back toward the bunkhouse until Ray an Claude are left alone at the gun line.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, we'll take good care of him.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One of the new kids said they're farming those acres just north of the swamp. He said he saw a crop duster flying around the place.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not in the mood right now, Ray.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said they keep it parked out behind the barn. Can't be that hard to fly a plane. Lots of people do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're called pilots! I'm serious, Ray. I'm not in the mood for one of your stupid, fucked-up plans right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't see you coming up with any plans.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My plan is on his way to Pittsburgh right now. That congenital idiot just got himself a pardon signed by the governor thanks to us, but we can't seem to do nothing for ourselves. Don't you feel a little disgusted right now?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crop duster.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly enraged, Ray hauls off and knocks Claude down with a solid right. Surprised, Claude touches his bloody lip.</context>
      <utterance>I ain't getting in no airplane with you. I'm finally wrapping my mind around the concept. They threw us in this shithole for life. Don't you get it, Ray? We're gonna die here! Might as well head up to the cemetery, pick a plot and start digging.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My daddy died in prison. He gave up hope and hung himself. What you're talking about is the same damn thing. That ain't how I'm going.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you're fooling yourself, Ray. Maybe you're just a chip off the old block.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take that back or we ain't friends no more, Claude Banks.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A hard look comes to Ray's eyes as Claude rises to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>Here's a news flash, Ray. We never were friends. We've just been stuck together for 12 years. It's been nothing but bad luck since the moment I ran into you. Every time I look at you I get sick to my stomach thinking about what my life could have been if I'd never bumped into Ray Gibson.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better watch yourself Claude, before you say something you regret.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The only thing I regret is the day I met you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if that's the way it is...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the way it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray walks away, leaving Claude to nurse his split lip.</context>
      <utterance>Then I have nothing left to say to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You never said nothing of value anyway.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright Willie, I think I got everything. I'll talk to Dillard, see if I can get up to the infirmary and check up on you. Make sure they're changing your diapers regular.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll be sending you up there soon enough. And not just for a visit, neither.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>YVETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude turns to face YVETTE, a pretty young woman.</context>
      <utterance>Are you Claude Banks?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>YVETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name's Yvette. Sylvia sent me. You look just like she said.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's alright, isn't she?</utterance>
   <speaker>YVETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, she's fine. She's just not coming today.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>YVETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She got married last month.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Married?</utterance>
   <speaker>YVETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Real nice guy, too. Trumpet player. They moved down to New Orleans. Claude takes this in, staring off into space.</utterance>
   <speaker>YVETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She always said that if you were on the outside...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I'm not on the outside. I'm in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>YVETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know she's sorry she won't be seeing you anymore. Anyway, she wanted me to take care of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take care of me?</utterance>
   <speaker>YVETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, go to the tonk or whatever.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm too old for you. Besides, I'm not much in the mood.</utterance>
   <speaker>YVETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want me to come back some other time?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice girl like you don't belong in a place like this. But if you talk to Sylvia, tell her old Claude said congratulations.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, he makes a break for the Dillard house.</context>
      <utterance>Whites-only pies...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUSTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray turns to see Claude dashing across no-man's land. Shots ring out from the shooter shack, kicking up dirt around Claude's feet as he serpentines across the field.</context>
      <utterance>Man over the line!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Comfortable?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As a pair of fur-lined bedroom slippers, boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a trusty's rifle and moves among the inmates, who have gathered around. He stops when he gets to Ray.</context>
      <utterance>We'll see what those slippers feel like after, say, 24 hours. And if you step down off them bottles -- if one toe so much as touches the dirt -- one of these boys is gonna shoot you dead. Let's see. We need a special man for this job.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray glances at Claude, then back at Dillard.</context>
      <utterance>How about it, Ray?</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dillard offers the rifle to Ray, who doesn't have to think too long.</context>
      <utterance>I'll make you trusty right now. If that pie-eatin' son of a bitch falls off those bottles and you have to shoot him, I'll see to it you get a pardon. Hell, I'll personally escort you out the gate.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't want to give me a gun, boss. I'm liable to use it on you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a sucker. I'd have taken that deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me? Are you talking to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd have knocked you off those bottles, put a bullet in your ass and be half way to New York right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After all these years of blissful silence, I almost forgot how annoying the sound of your voice can be.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope you don't think I owe you anything. Because I don't owe you a damn thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The trusty tightens his grip on his rifle. He'd love the opportunity.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't do if for you, anyway. I just ain't no boot-licking trusty, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was sorry to hear about your mama passing.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was five years ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, but since we're talking, I thought I'd mention it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stand in stony silence. Then Ray starts to laugh. A long, low belly laugh.</context>
      <utterance>We're not talking, you're talking, and doing too damn much of it, if you ask me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure looked funny running for those pies, bullets flying all around you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men start to laugh. Really laugh. Nearly a decade's worth of laughter comes welling up out of them, and they nearly lose their balance, which only makes them laugh harder.</context>
      <utterance>Bullets weren't the problem. That pie was too hot. Burned my tongue.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude and Ray step out of line and approach Dillard.</context>
      <utterance>Fourteen acres today and only 12 hours of daylight! Eat up and move it out! Gibson! Banks! Get your sorry asses over here!</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every morning I wake up praying that Ray Gibson and Claude Banks have died in their sleep and every morning you disappoint me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY AND CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>DILLARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray and Claude share a look. Then Ray embraces Dillard, who stoically endures the breach of his personal space.</context>
      <utterance>I stand before you a defeated man. Try as I might, I can't seem to break you. I swear, if they dropped a nuclear bomb on this camp, you and the cockroaches would be the only things left. But starting today at least I won't have to endure your presence any longer. You've got fifteen minutes to clear out your footlockers. You're both being reassigned to the Superintendent's mansion. And I, for one, will not miss you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I always wanted to do that.  There is so much love inside of this man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OMITTED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
   <speaker>OMITTED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>WILKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn dentures slipping again. Everything falls apart when you grow old, eh, Claude? Time sure marches on.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude glances at a glossy brochure. From outside, Ray peers suspiciously through the dining room window as he hacks at a rose bush.</context>
      <utterance>You know, I'm fixing on retiring at the end of the summer, gonna try to enjoy what few years I have left. What do you think of this place? It's one of those new retirement communities down on the Gulf.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude returns the brochure.</context>
      <utterance>Ocean views, palm trees, two heated swimming pools and a golf course -- sounds a damn sight better than that infirmary across the way where I'm gonna end up.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I apologize, Claude. That was rude of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's alright, boss. Takes a lot more than a colorful brochure to hurt my feelings.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You been on the farm for quite a spell, haven't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wilkins glances over at the window. Ray ducks out of view.</context>
      <utterance>Over forty years now. Me and Ray Gibson out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forty years. That's a long time for any crime, even murder.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a hell of a lot longer when you're innocent.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Half the men in this prison swear they're innocent. Don't you think that's kinda funny?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude pushes back into the kitchen, leaving Wilkins to think this one over.</context>
      <utterance>You have to forgive me if I don't laugh.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You and Wilkins sure are getting chummy. You two planning on going steady, or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's just a lonely old man. He likes to talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I'm a lonely old man. I like to talk, too. So why don't we start by talking about what kind of a plan you're working on?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not working on a plan.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't fool me, Claude. I know you got something brewing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude punches his pillow and turns off the light.</context>
      <utterance>Goodnight, Ray.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude pulls out a hanky and buffs Ray's finger print off the hood.</context>
      <utterance>Don't touch that car.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wilkins' driver's got the flu, so he asked me to fill in for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You haven't driven in 40 years, you ain't even got a license. Man's taking his life in his hands, putting you behind the wheel! Where you taking him?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray scowls as Claude straightens his chauffeur uniform and heads up the path to the mansion.</context>
      <utterance>Greenville. We're picking up the new Superintendent at the bus station.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>WILKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know I trust you, Claude.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wilkins heads into the station, leaving Claude alone with the Continental. All around him are the sights, sounds and smells of the free world. A woman rushes into the arms of a man as he climbs off a bus. Across the street is Grandma Dodi's Pork Rib Joint where Cookie never made it to the peach cobbler. A young brother with a boom box walks by. In the street, kids crowd around the back of an ice cream truck. Then Claude catches his reflection in the car window and frowns. When did he get this old? Unnerved, he moves around to the back of the car and pops open the trunk.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be right back.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn, it was getting hot in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you doing in that trunk?!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't think I was gonna let you escape alone, did you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't escaping! We're picking up the new super just like I told you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you're lucky I came along. Doesn't take a visionary to spot a golden opportunity like this. Now help me out of this trunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ain't getting out of that trunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, man, I'm starting to cramp up here.  We have the chance right here, right now, I say we go!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go where, Ray?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Back to New York for starters.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what will we do when we get there? I'm sixty-five years old, Ray. So are you. What are we gonna do out here? Get married, have kids, settle down? That boat sailed without us, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This boat's gonna sail without you, too. I don't care if I last one day out here. At least it's one day of freedom. Now gimme those keys.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget about that. You run if you want to, but you're not taking this car.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Claude, man, I'm serious. Give me those keys.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't spending a month in the hole so you can take a joy ride.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't make me take them away from you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray looks, Claude clocks him. Ray slumps back into the trunk. Claude stuffs Ray's legs back into the trunk and slams the lid.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, there's Wilkins!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up just as Wilkins and the new superintendent exit the bus station. Warren Pike's hair has gone grey and he's 40 years older, but there's no mistaking the former sheriff of Natchez County. He still bears a nasty scar on his cheek from a wound inflicted long ago. CLAUDE'S POV -- Pike appears as a young man in his sheriff's uniform striding slowly toward him. Claude blinks and looks again. Pike has returned to his old self as he and Wilkins step up.</context>
      <utterance>Who's driving now, bitch?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oblivious, Pike climbs into the back seat. Wilkins nods to Claude.</context>
      <utterance>There you go, boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude snaps to it, grabbing the bags. He considers opening the trunk, but decides to carry them around to the front seat with him.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Claude, time to go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure it was him?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some faces you just don't forget. Warren Pike's is one of 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't like it, I don't like it one bit. We shoulda taken that car when we had the opportunity. We'd be half way to New York by now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'd be in the hole by now. Hey, man, you're peeing on my shoe.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. Simultaneously, they shake and zip. Claude bends down and picks up a bowl of gumbo, placing it on a tray next to an identical one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>WILKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lemonade?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I prefer bourbon.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, I don't keep any liquor in the house.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pike pulls a flask from his jacket and tilts it high. Claude enters from the kitchen with the two steaming bowls of gumbo.</context>
      <utterance>Well, fortunately, I carry my own.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hunting's been pretty good on the farm the last few years. It's one of the perks of the job. If you're interested, tomorrow I could show you some of my favorite spots.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to twist my arm.  Say now, that gumbo has quite a kick.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Claude. That'll be all for tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodnight, Mr. Wilkins. Mr. Pike.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pike nods coldly. Claude steps back into the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Goodnight, Claude.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you don't mind my saying, you seem mighty familiar with your house boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I believe in treating the convicts with respect, if that's what you mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Respect? Well, isn't that progressive.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pike curls his lip with disdain before taking a healthy spoonful of gumbo.</context>
      <utterance>If somebody deserves respect, Mr. Pike, they receive it from me, convict or no convict.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="36">
   <speaker>WILKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pike pulls a gold watch from his pocket and releases the face plate. A familiar mechanical tune floats on the gathering breeze. Ray turns around slowly. His eyes fall on the watch in Pike's hand. His daddy's watch. In Pike's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Well, that's a pretty good haul. What do you say, Mr. Pike? Ready to call it a day?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it's getting late. I could sure use a bath.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a real nice watch you got there, sir. Fancy old thing even plays a little tune.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it's special. They don't make 'em like this anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure don't. Mind if I ask where you got it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude looks at the watch, then at Ray. Uh oh.</context>
      <utterance>Why, my wife gave it to me on our anniversary some years back.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Must have been some time ago. Maybe forty years?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something like that, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pike thrusts the barrel of his gun up under Ray's chin.</context>
      <utterance>She give you that scar, too?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I oughta shoot you for that comment, boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wilkins turns to see Pike holding Ray at gunpoint.</context>
      <utterance>Like you shot Winston Hancock?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on here?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid I'm gonna have to teach this uppity nigger a lesson in manners.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray grabs the barrel of the shotgun and slams it into Pike's face. Pike rolls over and freezes, staring down the barrel of his own gun now in Ray's hands. Confused, Wilkins points his gun at Ray.</context>
      <utterance>That's Mr. Uppity Nigger to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cool it, Ray. You're gonna get us in a lot of trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's right, Gibson. Put down the gun and we'll work this out.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna work this man's brains out the back of his head.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shoot him, Wilkins!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't shoot, sir. I can deal with this.  Ray, buddy, you don't want to shoot this white man. See, you do that, they'll kill you for sure. And it's not that I like you or anything, but I've kinda gotten used to having you around.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got my daddy's watch, Claude. I always knew whoever took that watch killed Winston Hancock. And that was you, Mr. Pike.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's crazy. Don't listen to him, Wilkins.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you realize what your saying, Gibson?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That watch was the only thing my daddy ever gave me. It meant the world to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamn it, Wilkins, would you please just shoot the nigger!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He shoots me, I swear I'll take you with me! I just want to hear you say it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there any truth to what he's saying, Pike?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What difference does it make? Natchez was better off without Winston Hancock! Who cares if a couple of no- account bootleggers went to jail for his killing? At least the state of Mississippi got 40 years of cheap labor out of the deal!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude grabs for the gun.</context>
      <utterance>Forty years of cheap labor! Gimme that gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm gonna kill him --</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude yanks the gun free and points it right in Pike's face. Wilkins trains his gun on Claude. But the moment passes. Claude lowers the gun. Bewildered, Wilkins does the same.</context>
      <utterance>No, believe me, I'm gonna kill him!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's because you're soft. Gimme the gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said you're soft.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray mouths the word -- "soft." Claude clenches his jaw, points the gun and pulls the trigger. Click. Pike smirks and pulls a small gun from his boot. But as he raises it -- BLAM! Pike is hurled backward by a shotgun blast. Shocked, Ray and Claude look at Wilkins, his gun still smoking in his hands. After a significant beat, Ray reaches down and gingerly retrieves his daddy's gold pocket watch.</context>
      <utterance>Don't call me soft, I hate it when you call me that.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I believe this is mine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WILKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I was drawing a bead on a bird when Mr. Pike just stepped into my line of fire.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where were the two convicts when the shot was fired?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were busy loading up the truck. We got him back here as quick as possible, but... I just feel terrible about this...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't he just tell 'em the truth?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of the deputies pats Wilkins sympathetically on the back. Then he and his partner put away their notebooks and head for their vehicle. Wilkins heads up the steps and into the house.</context>
      <utterance>He knows nobody wants to hear the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Visibly shaken, Wilkins takes a seat, wiping the sweat from his brow with a handkerchief.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I think they bought it. One of the deputies belongs to my church.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wilkins winces and swallows a couple of pills from his box.</context>
      <utterance>I realize there's no way... There's nothing I can say to make up for forty years... I'll have Charlotte prepare those pardon papers right away.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Claude, mind helping me to the bathroom?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not your boss. Not anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So Ray and Claude got their pardons, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, they didn't get their pardons, you dumb shit! If they'd got their pardons way back then, we wouldn't be burying them today, would we?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, right. Well, why didn't they get those pardons?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Old man Wilkins' never came out of that bathroom. Died right there on the crapper.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just like Elvis.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course nobody believed Ray and Claude.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That musta messed 'em up pretty bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to 'em after that, Willie?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After that? Well, let's see. After that they got old. We all got old.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nurse Humphries was checking my prostate this morning. I got an erection.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An erection, huh? Haven't had one of those in a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the radio, the announcer voice rises in pitch as the Yankees score. Ray and Claude share a satisfied look.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me about it. Scared me at first. Then, before I could figure out what to do with it, it was gone. Imagine my disappointment.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure would like to see the house that Ruth built one more time.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Ruth shoulda built it a little better. Damn thing's falling to pieces. Gonna hurt somebody.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you expect? It's almost as old as we are.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They oughta tear that shit down and ship them Yankees cross the river to Jersey.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TWO ORDERLIES push a DEAD BODY past on a squeaking gurney.</context>
      <utterance>Remember what that place looked like on a sunny spring day? More beautiful than any church I was ever in.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray tips his flask in a simple salute.</context>
      <utterance>Looks like old Jonesy finally got his walking papers.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Over to the morgue and up the hill to the cemetery. Never thought I'd admit it, Claude, but you were right.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Course I was right. About what?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray closes his eyes and settles in for a nap. Claude turns to watch Jonesy squeaking away. Something about what Ray just said has given him an idea.</context>
      <utterance>You're the one who said that boneyard's the only way we're getting out of here. We're gonna join all the rest of 'em soon enough. Jangle Leg, Biscuit, Goldmouth, Poker Face, Cookie, Radio -- yes sir, pick a plot and start digging...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>GANG BANGER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two Percodan.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll raise you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANG BANGER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck are those?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keeps your cholesterol down.</utterance>
   <speaker>GANG BANGER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>GANG BANGER 2 takes a quick hit of cocaine from a bullet. He notices Ray staring at him.</context>
      <utterance>I look like I give a shit about my cholesterol?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANG BANGER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want a bump, G?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray pushes his bet to the center of the table. The shaky junkie folds. Willie tosses in some pills and turns to Gang Banger 2.</context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't be putting that shit up my nose. That came in in somebody's ass. It's like you're sniffin' ass. Maybe that's your thing, but it ain't mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Glaring, Gang Banger 2 flips a big pill into the pot.</context>
      <utterance>Looks like it's up to you, stinky ass sniffer.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tosses down his cards. The shaky junkie attempts to light a cigarette. The match slips from his trembling fingers and falls into his lap.</context>
      <utterance>Thorazine? Well, that's a little rich for my blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gang Banger 1 folds. It's back to Ray.</context>
      <utterance>Damn fool gonna set this place on fire one of these days.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The remaining players match the pot. Gang Banger 2 reveals his cards. Willie frowns. Ray lays down his cards and victoriously sweeps his winnings into a paper cup. Across the room, Nurse Humphries enters with a tray of snacks. She, too, is showing the years.</context>
      <utterance>I got three stool softeners left.  That oughta be right up your alley.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE HUMPHRIES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The magic word. The poker players join a stampede of oldsters in a clatter of canes, walkers and artificial limbs. Ray and Claude are left alone at the table.</context>
      <utterance>Who wants Jell-O?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude glances around to ensure that he's not overheard.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, where you going? We got money on the table here!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray gives Claude a long look.</context>
      <utterance>You know, Ray, I've been chewing on what you said this afternoon. I think I got a plan.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you trying to tell me after all this time you finally have a plan for busting out of here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shh! Is that so hard to believe?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't tell me, I don't want to hear it. It's probably all fucked up, anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't want to hear it, you don't want to hear it. There's no shame in that.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's too late for plans.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray turns away as Claude walks off. A DODDERING INMATE stands nearby slurping on Jell-O. His robe hangs open.</context>
      <utterance>Never thought I'd hear Ray Gibson say that. Hell with you then. You'd only slow me down anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Disgusted, Ray discards his own Jell-O. He pulls out his daddy's pocket watch and checks the time. The little mechanical tune nags at him. He snaps the lid shut and considers the watch resting in the palm of his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, man, cover that shit up!</utterance>
   <speaker>OMITTED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NURSE HUMPHRIES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is everyone here?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, where's Claude? I don't see Claude!</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE HUMPHRIES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay calm, Ray. We'll find him. Claude! Has anyone seen Claude?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grimly, Ray starts toward the burning infirmary. Nurse Humphries holds him back.</context>
      <utterance>He must still be in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE HUMPHRIES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait for the firemen!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll be too late.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE HUMPHRIES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't go in there, Ray! You'll never make it!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray shakes her off and runs up the steps, disappearing into the burning building.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going in for him. He'd do the same for me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did it start?</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRE INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably old wires. The place was a tinderbox just waiting to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess we should have torn this old building down a long time ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRE INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burke watches solemnly as the coroners wheel the bodies past him.</context>
      <utterance>Gibson made it this far before he was probably overcome by smoke. From the look of things, Banks never even made it out of bed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, you really bummed me out. That's a terrible story.  Nigger, you crying?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell, no! I just got something in my eye.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's alright for a man to cry once in awhile. Just don't make a habit of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Willie, what was Claude's plan, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The young inmates share a look, then glance into the graves, then look back at Willie.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing to it, really. Claude figured they could steal a couple of bodies from the morgue. They got a couple of crackers working there don't know their asses from their elbows. Then they was gonna set fire to the infirmary and make it look like those bodies was them that got stuck inside. Claude figured during the commotion, it wouldn't be too hard to slip onto one of the fire trucks and hang tight until it rolled right on out of here in the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What makes you think it didn't work?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leon and Jake do the arithmetic. You can almost hear the gears grinding under the strain.</context>
      <utterance>I never said it didn't work.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Willie starts to chuckle and sets his electric wheel chair on auto-pilot, leaving the young inmates to guess at the truth.</context>
      <utterance>You trying to tell us that's not Ray and Claude in those boxes?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think about that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They pick up their shovels and go back to work burying the caskets.</context>
      <utterance>I think that old man lost his marbles about a hundred years ago. Come on, let's get this over with.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't eat this.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why the hell not?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray and Claude glance around confused as the wave rolls through their section of the bleachers. What the fuck? Claude inspects his hot dog.</context>
      <utterance>I saw that hot dog guy in the bathroom urinating. He didn't wash his hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just put some mustard on it and eat it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't get ketchup?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray snatches back the hot dog.</context>
      <utterance>Gimme that damn thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray is suddenly young again.</context>
      <utterance>What am I gonna eat?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude takes the ice cream. He, too, is suddenly young again.</context>
      <utterance>Have my ice cream.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at each other and share a laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell of a day for a ballgame, huh, Claude?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claude pops the top on his ice cream. Suddenly, they are both old again.</context>
      <utterance>Hell of a day, Ray. Yankees are on fire.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, this ain't gonna work either. It's half chocolate, half vanilla.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CAMERA begins to pull back.</context>
      <utterance>They're touching.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you don't eat that ice cream right now, I'm gonna strangle you until you are completely dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? You and what army?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Next thing, you're gonna be complaining about the seats.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if you must know, they could be closer.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>"Pipe downs" etc. from the people around them.</context>
      <utterance>Damn, I shoulda let Spanky Johnson drown you in the river when I had the chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you're not talking to me...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CAMERA PULLS BACK as the arguing continues, just like the old days. MUSIC UP.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, he's on medication...</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
