<movie id="354" title="Little Nicky">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>PEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see a young mother walk into the room outside the Peeper's window. She is wearing business attire.</context>
      <utterance>Showtime!</utterance>
   <speaker>PEEPER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The mother sits on the bed and pulls off her shoes, rubbing her feet.</context>
      <utterance>Rough day at the office Mrs. Dunleavy?  Well you'll feel better once you slip off those work clothes and get into some sweats.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEEPER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The mother starts to unbutton her blouse. She takes it off, revealing a nice bra.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my G-D, yes! I wish you would let me rub those feet. Of course I wouldn't use my hands. Heh heh heh heh... He sips some wine.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEEPER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The peeper frantically writes in a dirty notebook. Mouthing the words as he goes.</context>
      <utterance>Looks like Victoria just told me her secret.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEEPER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The mother starts to unbutton her pants. Her young son walks in wearing a scouts uniform.</context>
      <utterance>Thursday the ninth, eight-thirty p.m., first brassiere sighting...  I will pleasure myself to this image for months. MONTHS I TELL YOU!</utterance>
   <speaker>PEEPER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The son talks to his mother excitedly.</context>
      <utterance>Young Scottie Dunleavy. What unfortunate timing. You mother was just getting comfy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEEPER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, yes, I'm sure you tied many great knots today or whatever. Now get out. The son, not going anywhere, sits in a chair.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEEPER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The peeper takes out a cell phone and dials. The son answers.</context>
      <utterance>Now what. This simply won't do.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>PEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Scottie. Why don't you go downstairs like a good boy and let your mother freshen up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>PEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a little birdie. A birdie who wants to see if your mother's panties match her bra.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The peeper gets nervous.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my G-D Scottie. Is there a man up our tree?</utterance>
   <speaker>PEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The peeper starts flapping his arms and making bird noises. We SEE Scottie with his sling shot. The mother nods yes. He shoots it. It hits the peeper square in the head. He falls to the ground with a thud.</context>
      <utterance>Tell her no. Tell her it's just a big bird.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEEPER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The peeper looks up. He sees Scottie pushing a television out the window. It lands on top of the peeper. He's dead.</context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Dunleavy, please come help me. And wear your bikini.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GATEKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The peeper looks left to see the GATEKEEPER standing at his station greeting the new SOULS with mock cheer.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome!</utterance>
   <speaker>PEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I in hell?</utterance>
   <speaker>GATEKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A GIANT BIRD appears and bites the peeper's crotch area. We leave the peeper in the pit and tilt up to...</context>
      <utterance>What do you think?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY THE DEMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your father wants to see you and your brothers in the throne room.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, but Jimmy, when the house is rockin', don't forget the knockin'!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="46">
   <speaker>CASSIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew it. He's finally retiring.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He throws a dart that hits one of the heads in the forehead.</context>
      <utterance>I've been waiting on this day for ten thousand years.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUMAN DARTBOARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aaaah!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If the old man picks me to take over Hell, I'll keep the torture going twenty four seven. No breaks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cassius whips a dart which hits one of the HUMAN DARTBOARDS in the eye.</context>
      <utterance>Well Dad says it's the breaks that make the torture. You have to let people feel a sense of relief.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUMAN DARTBOARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aaaaaaaaaaaah!</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cassius pulls out the dart. The eye comes with it.</context>
      <utterance>Then again, the beauty of Dad retiring is what he says doesn't matter anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cassius throws the eye on the ground and stomps it. THWACK! It splatters like a grape.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUMAN DARTBOARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky enters sheepishly.</context>
      <utterance>Was that really necessary?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, how's Daddy's little girl doing today?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cassius snaps his fingers in Nicky's face.</context>
      <utterance>Good, thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cassius' eyes start glowing red.</context>
      <utterance>Hey. Hey. Hey. Wanna mind wrestle?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky is slammed into a nearby desk as if by an invisible force.</context>
      <utterance>Actually, I'll take a rain check on0</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got ya!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky's head slams back down again.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, you got me...</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got ya, again!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs a lamp off the desk and cracks himself over the head.</context>
      <utterance>Got me for sure, yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky frowns as he finds his own right hand heading for his own crotch.</context>
      <utterance>Got ya! Now here's the big finish...</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky's hand is being possessed. It gets closer and closer until it latches on to Nicky's crotch.</context>
      <utterance>Oh no. Please Cassius...</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cassius concentrates even harder, making Nicky twist his own hand. Nicky screams even louder. Adrian smiles. They don't notice that DAD, wearing a sweatsuit (and with very small devil horns), enters behind them.</context>
      <utterance>Aaaaah.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cassius releases Nicky's hand.</context>
      <utterance>What are you boys doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing, Dad. Just re-arranging the furniture.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cassius, didn't I tell you to stay out of your brother's mind?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I forgot.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dad's eyes flash red and Cassius punches himself hard in the nose, sending him back against the wall and down to the floor. Dad gives Nicky a wink. Nicky smiles. Dad has an air of confidence and power.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe this will help you remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now everybody sit down.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Dad, I'm almost finished laying down my monsters of metal compilation tape. I really think it's a masterpiece.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leads the boys to the throne area. We see outside the window the peeper staring in sexily. Dad looks, shakes his head. Just then, THE BIRD appears and attacks him. Dad closes the curtains. Nicky, Adrian and Cassius sit on little stools at the foot of his throne. Dad lights a cigarette with his finger, the tip of which glows red like a cigarette lighter and looks down at his three sons.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, kid, we'll listen to it later.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Confused, Nicky sheepishly raises his hand.</context>
      <utterance>My dad, your granddad, Lucifer, was thrown out of Heaven by G-d and rules here in hell for ten thousand years. And after this ten thousand years had passed, he decided to abdicate his throne...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jimmy the Demon walks in.</context>
      <utterance>...to step aside.  ...and let me become the ruler of hell. This, as some of you might know, is my ten thousandth year as Prince of Darkness. So I think the time has come to discuss who will succeed me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY THE DEMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Knock, knock.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He whispers in Dad's ear.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Jimmy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, that's not what I said. He can keep his thumbs, but the fingers gotta go.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This was a very difficult decision, because I have three wonderful sons. I mean, Adrian, so smart, so ruthless. And Cassius, so strong, so tough. And Nicky, so...so...</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about coming up with anything. It's cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Such a sweet boy. But after much thought and careful consideration, I've decided that the ruler for the next ten thousand years is going to have to be...me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIUS AND ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What!?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all look at Nicky.</context>
      <utterance>Hallelujah.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean...tough break.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The important thing for the stability of our rule is to maintain the balance between good and evil. And I don't think any of you are ready for that responsibility yet. You need the wisdom that comes only with the passage of time.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dad glares. Cassius goes FLYING BACK. One of the Human Dartboards laughs. Cassius whips a dart and hits him in the tongue. Jimmy enters and points at his watch.</context>
      <utterance>Dad! This is Hoyashit.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky, Cassius and Adrian start filing out. Adrian stops.</context>
      <utterance>Right. Right. Send him in.  I'm sorry, boys. I've got to get back to work.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure about this decision, Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HITLER (in a French maid's outfit), is being brought in by Jimmy. They head towards the closet. Inside the closet is a crate of pineapples. Hitler picks out a relatively small one. Dad shakes his head "no." Dad walks over to the closet. Hitler picks out a really big pineapple. Dad nods "yes." Hitler sadly hands it to Dad. Jimmy bends Hitler over and as Dad raises the fruit...</context>
      <utterance>I'm telling you, pal, it's the right thing to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON HITLER'S EYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As the pineapple's jammed up his ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>HITLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy schnit!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>CASSIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You work your ass off for ten thousand years, hurting people, helping others hurt people, then you get a decision like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And he's dead serious.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adrian turns to the Monster.</context>
      <utterance>It's just such a slap in the face.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um, excuse me, we're having a private conversation here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cassius insanely snaps his fingers in the Monster's face. The Monster shrugs and walks off.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, get out of here! Beat it!</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cassius throws a rock at the Monster. He yelps, then turns around, motioning like he's thinking about coming back. Cassius sees this and gets enraged.</context>
      <utterance>Twenty-thousand years ago, Grandpa Lucifer said, "It is better to rule in hell than serve in heaven." Well, I'm getting tired of serving in Hell. We need a place where we can rule.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Monster, upon further reflection, throws his hands up in an "aw phooey" gesture and continues walking away.</context>
      <utterance>Oh you wanna be a big man? Bring it on!! Let's see what you got!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIUS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I thought!</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could you concentrate for five seconds?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am concentrating. Where can we rule?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think about...Earth? Cassius seems to think this isn't a bad idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We could create our own hell there.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You saying we go up there and kill everyone?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eventually, Cassius. But first we corrupt as many as we can so that when we do destroy them...</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...their damned souls will be ours.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two look at each other. They start running toward the fire wall. Knocking souls out of their way.</context>
      <utterance>It's our time, brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>GATEKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They get closer to the fire.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, what are you doing?!?</utterance>
   <speaker>GATEKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>They dive through the fire wall. It FREEZES.</context>
      <utterance>You can't go through there. The fire flows in, not out.</utterance>
   <speaker>GATEKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Sirens go off. Dogs start barking. Lights flash. And we hear the sound of DAMNED SOULS hitting the back of the firewall hard.</context>
      <utterance>You know something? You guys suck! You really suck!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now that was an experience. "You are only coming through in waves." That line blows my mind every time.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Definitely.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care what kind of mood you're in at the start of that song. When it's over, that mood has been altered. Wow. Great shit. What's next?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I thought that after messing with your head, I'd give you a little kick in the keester. Hits the tape player. "Enter Sandman" blasts.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is this, Metal-lick-a?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Metallica, Dad. Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dad and Nicky dance to the song.</context>
      <utterance>I was just playing with you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, man, I'm just asking for one Superbowl ring.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marino.</context>
      <utterance>In exchange for eternal damnation of your soul? You're too nice of a guy for me to want to do that to you, Mr.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did it for Namath.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but Joe was coming here anyways. Just go back to Earth and enjoy your records and the Hall of Fame and the beautiful family and all that.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is bullshit, man.  I'm gonna win the Superbowl this year, with or without you!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dan exits.</context>
      <utterance>Now you're talking.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a good devil, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky and Dad share a laugh which is interrupted by faint sirens. The Gatekeeper enters in a hurry and falls to his knees.</context>
      <utterance>And I also happen to be a Jets fan.</utterance>
   <speaker>GATEKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your highness, Cassius and Adrian have escaped from hell. They went through the fire, and they broke it. I think they took the New York tunnel. I tried to stop them, but they overpowered me, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Gatekeeper stands up.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, boy. Oh boy. Calm down. Get off your knees.</utterance>
   <speaker>GATEKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dad's EYES GLOW RED as the Gatekeeper stands up. Two huge boobs grow out of either side of the Gatekeeper's head. We only see them from the front for a second. From behind the gatekeeper, we see the boobs but not the nipples as he talks to Nicky.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for being so understanding, your worship. You're the man. You've always been the man.</utterance>
   <speaker>GATEKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm lucky to get away with just the head boobs, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coulda been much worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>GATEKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dad is staring off. He looks shaken.</context>
      <utterance>That's what I'm thinkin'...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is bad, Nicky.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>GRANDPA LUCIFER enters.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna die, Nicky. If the gates are broken, no new souls can get in, which means I'll start to deteriorate into nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's with all the whoo-whoo noises?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything's fine, pop.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last time you said that the renaissance happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, pop, just go back to your room.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I take him with me and have sex with his head?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The gatekeeper walks towards Lucifer.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, pop. Whatever you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>GATEKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, this is gonna be a whole new lifestyle for me, isn't it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>DAMNED SOULS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>We keep HEARING people hit behind the frozen fire with loud thuds.</context>
      <utterance>What's going on? Where are we?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY THE DEMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing's getting through that. The fire is solid as a rock.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We gotta get this bad boy burning again. Ideas?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To do that Cassius and Adrian have to come back through the other way.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So go get 'em, Dad!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dad holds up his hand. His pink is hanging by a thread. We see the bigfoot MONSTER grunt disgusted by the sight.</context>
      <utterance>I'm too weak. The process has already begun.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So go get 'em, Jimmy!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY THE DEMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just a demon, Nicky. I don't got devil blood in me. I'd last two minutes up there with your brothers.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The MONSTER puts his hands over his eyes shaking his head as if to say, "oh no."</context>
      <utterance>You're not saying it's up to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never been to Earth. I've never even slept over at some other dude's house!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY THE DEMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the spawn of Satan. You got it in you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nicky, the worst thing that could happen on Earth is you get killed, in which case, boom, you end up back here.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you telling me I have to go to Earth and kill my brothers?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY THE DEMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dad takes an ornate flask from his robe.</context>
      <utterance>Not go. They left together at the exact same time. They gotta come back together at the exact same time.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dad's pinky is hanging. Jimmy pulls it off and examines it. The Monster gags.</context>
      <utterance>Here. Get them drunk from this. One sip and they'll be trapped inside. Once you've got both of them, you bring the flask back through the gate.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY THE DEMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky looks petrified.</context>
      <utterance>Your ol' man's got less than a week.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. This can't be happening.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky looks teary eyed. The moment is broken by the Monster, who runs in and pushes Nicky through the fire. Nicky goes through the solid fire wall. PAUSE. The Monster taps his own wrist and looks at Dad as if to say, "gotta get a move on."</context>
      <utterance>Son, just do your best.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JIMMY THE DEMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were gone ten seconds. What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got hit by a big light that was attached to a lot of metal.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a train, son. Don't stand in front of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I guess I'm going to have to take a mulligan on this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky climbs up and heads back toward the fire wall.</context>
      <utterance>Please, Nicky, get back up there.  Try to hurry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beefy drops the sign from his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Nicky.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, terrific!! Now get off the track and come with me, shitstains.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name's Beefy. I'm an old friend of your father's. He's asked me to help you out.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just need to find my brothers and be on my way, Beefy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky looks at Beefy warily for a beat.</context>
      <utterance>It's not gonna be easy. Your brothers can possess people. So they probably won't look like themselves. You have to be suspicious of everyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, "bro," this jig is up...  Just get in the bottle. Just slide right on in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not me, moron.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PREACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see Nicky and Beefy walk up from behind. The PREACHER sniffs.</context>
      <utterance>Oh how the Lord loves you. All his children.  He thanks you for your kindness.  God bless, Ma'am. The Lord loves you... The Lord loves you...</utterance>
   <speaker>PREACHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He runs off screaming, wildly bumping into people.</context>
      <utterance>The Lord does not love you. I sense...pure evil.  You make the Lord very nervous.  I'm burning...ahhh.  The Devil walks among us!</utterance>
   <speaker>PREACHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He gets off course and runs right into a subway entrance. He disappears. Beefy turns to Nicky.</context>
      <utterance>Oh Lord, save us from Hell's beast!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Makin' friends already.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's freezing up here, Beefy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're on Earth now, kid. Gonna have the same physical needs and limitations a human has. We'll stop by K-mart. Get you some warm clothes.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I also have this odd pain in my mid section. Kind of a hollow feeling...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That pain is hunger.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So far, so good. Now what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky puts it in his mouth. Holds it there.</context>
      <utterance>Put it in your mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Nicky does. He chews for a long time.</context>
      <utterance>Move your teeth up and down.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Nicky does. He gets a looks of complete joy on his face.</context>
      <utterance>Now you gotta swallow it. Tilt your head back and let the meat slide down your throat-hole.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey...Popeye's chicken is ass kickin'!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It sure is. Now eat it up. You're gonna need your energy.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>NICKY stands with a drumstick and jogs off the curb right into the path of a moving bus.</context>
      <utterance>I got energy up the ying-ying. Let's get cracking!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GATEKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a pretty brassiere.</utterance>
   <speaker>GATEKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could you maybe not tell anyone about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>GATEKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got it. Could you maybe not tell anyone about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky turns and walks toward the firewall. As soon as his back is turned, the monster pantomimes to the Gatekeeper, "I love your boobs." The Gatekeeper gives a flirtatious laugh (we don't see him morph back through the wall here.).</context>
      <utterance>You got it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From now on. I'm just going to avoid all moving metal objects.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great. Now your father gave me some deposit money for a nice pad on the Upper East Side. But I misplaced it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, friend, my name is Nicky. I understand you're seeking a roommate, as per your advertisement in the Village Voice. Would it be possible for me to fill the slot?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky looks down at Beefy. Beefy looks up at Nicky. Both nod imperceptibly.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, don't you want to know what the rent is?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. What is rent?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eight-hundred, split down the middle. Tuesdays and Thursdays I rehearse with my scene partner so the living room will be off limits.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Off limits.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. And as far as household items: we can share the soap, but we'll split the cost 60/40. Cause the person who physically goes out and buys the soap shouldn't have to pay as much as the other guy.  Aren't you boiling in that outfit?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's like eighty degrees in this hallway. You from the South?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky laughs a little too hard.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. The deep South.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why is that funny?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd turns and goes into the apartment.</context>
      <utterance>And sorry, man, but no dogs allowed.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll be alright. Go on. Big day tomorrow. Don't forget to do that sleep thing I told you about.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got ya.  Is it okay if I do the sleep thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door closes. Beefy looks down at the welcome mat. It reads: I "heart" METHOD ACTING. Beefy raises his leg over it.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, your bedroom is right over there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARDINAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd stares dumbfounded. We see that the Cardinal is standing on a steaming hot pizza which is still in the box with the top open.</context>
      <utterance>In today's gospel, the Lord tells us who we are to live if we wish to attain the splendor of Heaven... or something like that. Jesus sure says a lot of stuff in the Bible. Moses this. Moses that. Abraham hit me with a whiffle ball bat.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARDINAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A MIDDLE-AGED WOMAN stands up.</context>
      <utterance>Yep, the Lord sure did say a bunch of hibbity-jibbity. But has he ever really done anything for us? Has he ever put a Jaguar XJR in my driveway? Has he ever given any of my enemies the herpes? No. He hasn't done a damn thing for any of us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CARDINAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A YOUNG MAN and his PREGNANT WIFE stand up.</context>
      <utterance>Ma'am, I know your son, and believe me, he was better off on drugs. He's a bore. At least when he was smoking hashish, he made me laugh occasionally.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After we tried for many years, the Lord finally helped my wife conceive a baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARDINAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fitzie, who's sitting on the other side of the Wife, starts to "raise the roof." Then thinks better of it. The Cardinal points to a well-dressed man in the front pew.</context>
      <utterance>No, your best friend Fitzie helped your wife conceive a baby. He helped her conceive it all night long.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARDINAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Mayor has tinfoil on his feet.</context>
      <utterance>How about you, Mr. Mayor? The Lord ever do anything for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I wish I could think of something, Cardinal, but to be honest with you, I can't. Kind of makes you wonder if there even is a Lord. If there is any ultimate punishment for our so-called "sins." Maybe we should all just have fun and do whatever the hell we want. A hubbub is raised by the crowd. Fitzie raises the roof again, this time energetically.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARDINAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The hubbub grows to a roar. Several PEOPLE start fighting over the money in the collection plate. The Cardinal smiles knowingly at the Mayor. We hear the Cardinal's thoughts - in Adrian's voice.</context>
      <utterance>Amen to that. Let the sin begin!</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, this is delicious.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIUS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Let the sin begins" - that was a good one.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we must get people sinning if we want to fill up our New Hell. How are things going down at City Hall?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIUS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I lowered the drinking age to ten.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brilliant. This is so much fun. I never want it to end.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIUS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The Mayor/Cassius laughs. As he does, his eyes slowly cross.</context>
      <utterance>Why should it end? Who's gonna stop us?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is intense! And it happens every day? Sometimes twice? I gotta tip my hat to you people!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, it's okay for me to shit the street. But you gotta use a toilet.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, just point me in the right direction next time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, there's like ten million people in this city and the clock is ticking.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky looks at the next person walking by. It's a CHINESE DELIVERY GUY on a bicycle. Nicky clotheslines him, taking him off the bike in a sleeperhold/headlock.</context>
      <utterance>Well, let's rock and roll.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Nicky puts the flask to the Chinese Guy's lips.</context>
      <utterance>Get in the bottle. Dad's falling apart. You froze the gate and you're killing him. Drink!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINESE DELIVERY GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not thirsty! I'm not thirsty!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Chinese Guy breaks loose, gives Nicky a roundhouse kick to the head and runs away. Nicky gets up.</context>
      <utterance>just get in the flask!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Beefy shakes his dog head and sighs as we see Nicky hold the bottle up to a few more PEDESTRIANS.</context>
      <utterance>Adrian and Cassius! You think a kick to the head is gonna make me throw in the towel? Well, in the immortal words of Judas Priest, "You got another thing comin'."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GATEKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bus?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Monster laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Beast.</utterance>
   <speaker>GATEKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Gatekeeper swirls his tassels.</context>
      <utterance>You like that? You think that's funny?</utterance>
   <speaker>GATEKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Monster howls with delight.</context>
      <utterance>How about that? You like that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All that running and chasing is making the sleep thing want to come early.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beefy hears Nicky's strange terrible snores. He's asleep. Beefy sighs.</context>
      <utterance>I think we have to work on narrowing down our list of suspects. Now I'm going to go check in with some of my contacts uptown.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Beefy walks away.</context>
      <utterance>Kid's got a lot of evil in him, just begging to come out...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds like our devil dance actually worked this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky snores. It sounds like "I will eat your hearts." The worried people run away. Nicky snores. Children on the Carousel, going real fast, upset. Nicky snores. Peter and John walk over to a position near Nicky's bench.</context>
      <utterance>'Bout time...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's our man.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A sleazy STREET VENDOR shuffles over towards Nicky. He eyes the flask which is half hanging out of Nicky's pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Sleepyhead must have some major ties to the dark side.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's with that guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, the Vendor grabs the flask (and Nicky's half-eaten drumstick) and runs off.</context>
      <utterance>Gotta be one of his disciples or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo, man, I think that devil guy just got ripped off.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should we wake him up?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Peter gets up and shakes Nicky who comes to with a loud</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. You do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky feels for the flask. It's gone.</context>
      <utterance>Rise and shine, devil guy. Some dude just stole your shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fire shoots out of Nicky's mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Oh nooooo....</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which way did he go?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky is about to run off. Looks at John's shirt.</context>
      <utterance>That way.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs off.</context>
      <utterance>Iron Maiden live double disc is simply phenomenal.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you check out the dragon mouth?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Dark Prince is here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="53">
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey...</utterance>
   <speaker>STREET VENDOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See something you like, my man?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The street vendor stands, very angry.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. I would like my flask back.</utterance>
   <speaker>STREET VENDOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You callin' me a thief, my man?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm just calling you... a guy who has my flask.</utterance>
   <speaker>STREET VENDOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if that is your so-called "flask," how would I have it unless I was, in fact, a thief?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A YUPPIE JOGGER is checking out the flask.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, how much for the silver flask there?</utterance>
   <speaker>STREET VENDOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's a very special item. The cap itself is one hundred percent plappium. It's a value is over three thousand dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really. Where's it from?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was handcrafted in hell by Satan himself and is only to be used for the capture and containment of my blood brothers so that the firefall of Hades will burn brightly once again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks away.</context>
      <utterance>Really. I think we'll let you keep it then.</utterance>
   <speaker>STREET VENDOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, now you gone and done it. You done messed with my business bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see that Nicky's eyes are starting to glow red.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, I would prefer if you didn't raise your voice. It's making my muscles tighten.</utterance>
   <speaker>STREET VENDOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The vendor makes an even crazier face at Nicky and starts swinging his fists around. Nearby, VALERIE, an unsure, sweetly unstylish young woman, is selling clothes off a spread out blanket. She notices what's going on. Nicky's eyes widen in panic. Just then, Valerie steps in.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, you gonna go all crazy eyes on me? I'll show you some crazy eyes. Let's get busy.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, does that flask belong to this man?</utterance>
   <speaker>STREET VENDOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you callin' me a thief? Damn.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I know you come out here and sell stolen stuff all the time. But today, the guy you stole from just happened to walk by and bust you. So why don't you admit today's not your day and give him his flask back?</utterance>
   <speaker>STREET VENDOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or what're you gonna do about it? Ugly me to death?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valerie points to a cop across the street. The Street Vendor ponders this for a second, then...</context>
      <utterance>No, but maybe that cop over there might have something to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>STREET VENDOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The vendor does crazy eyes again.</context>
      <utterance>Aw, take your dumb-ass canteen, goofy.  And you, take your raggedy-ass clothes and find a new corner. Before I show you what real crazy is.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky picks up the flask and the drumstick.</context>
      <utterance>Fine. I will.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valerie gathers her blanket, starts walking away and Nicky follows her.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, mister. I'll be seeing you in a few years.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was amazing. Thanks so much. You didn't have to do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's okay. I get messed with all the time and when I saw him doing that to you I just lost it. I hate when people take advantage of tourists. It ruins it for the rest of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I'm a tourist?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I just assumed. Your accent maybe. Where are you from?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The South.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Deep south.  She laughs along with him, not sure why.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you laughing?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, but I like it. Say. Your glasses are nice. They make your eyes look sparkly and big. It's fun to look at them.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My dad's an optometrist.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My dad's in hell, and he's falling apart.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. It's really tough when your parents get older.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I don't save him, I don't know what I'm gonna do.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky is experiencing new sensations as he looks at her. He hands her the half-eaten drumstick.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm sure a nice southern boy like you will figure something out.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here, have a Popeye's. This drumstick ain't for beatin' it's for eatin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's alright. I already ate lunch. I actually wouldn't mind getting a Gelati.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could I come with you to getting a Gelati?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you want to.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want to? A million angry octopus people couldn't hold me back!</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Octopus people?"</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, it's a deep south expression.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's freezing my hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valerie takes a few napkins and wraps it for Nicky. Just then the PREACHER walks by. He quickly turns his head, sensing Nicky.</context>
      <utterance>It's not that cold. Here, let me wrap it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you taunt me with your darkness?! Your evil is stinking up our streets! We're all gonna die! He takes off running right into a lamp post.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This town is really going to hell lately.  So what part of the city do you live in?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have an apartment. I don't remember exactly where. My dog knows, though.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have a dog? What kind?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure. I'd ask him, but he's uptown talking to his contacts.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember, it's not the size of the boat, it's the motion of the ocean.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL DOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just finish.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd love to have a dog. But I go to school full time. It wouldn't be fair to the dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>School?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Parsons School of Design. I knew growing up I wasn't much to look at, so I put my energy into making things that are pretty.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that pleasant smell coming from, your skin?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes her wrist to his nose. He stares at it, licks it.</context>
      <utterance>My perfume?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Nicky stops and looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>It's called "Comptoir Sud Pacific." Which I think is the French word for coconuts.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Valerie, it feels like there's a bunch of butterflies flapping around in my stomach. Is that normal?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes, sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. I was concerned.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I was the one who created Hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>GATEKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, your wickedness.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Monster laughs really hard.</context>
      <utterance>I started slow, though. For years, I was just giving people hot foots. Actually, you can give all the credit for Hell to my first wife; she was the inspiration. She was an ugly one, too. One day, she asked me if I wanted super sex. I said I'll take the soup.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Monster laughs even harder.</context>
      <utterance>Take it easy there, Chewbacca. In fact, you look like her mother, except she had more hair.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what was in Hell when I came down here, Cassius?</utterance>
   <speaker>GATEKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Stanley, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing. No mountains. No castles. Looked like a giant parking lot. It wasn't even called Hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>GATEKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was it called, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boogerland!</utterance>
   <speaker>GATEKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's nice, Grandpa. Why don't you just enjoy the fishing?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear the Monster laughing again as we PAN DOWN Grandpa's fishing line to:</context>
      <utterance>I can't enjoy anything. I go fishing. I catch nothing. I go to orgies, I catch everything...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>PEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I deserve this!</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just stole twenty-five bucks off the bar.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many beers did you have?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID # 3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eight sips.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both high five, throw up and fall. PAN over to ADRIAN sitting on top of a mailbox laughing as he sips from a bottle of PEPPERMINT SCHNAPPS.</context>
      <utterance>I had five! I'm so wasted.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adrian looks across the street and sees Nicky walking with Valerie. He's shocked. Valerie is holding up a pair of drawstring pants from her collection.</context>
      <utterance>When an adult goes to Hell, that's terrific. But when a child goes... that's why I'm in this business.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're saying, make all pants with a drawstring, then heavier set gals don't have to feel humiliated by telling their waist size in front of the whole store?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Basically, yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valerie laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Wow. Maybe you should make drawstring socks for gals with fat ankles.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what's nice about you? You just seem happy being yourself. You don't try to act cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks much. You know what's nice about you, Valerie?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Up the street, Adrian's eyes redden. NICKY looks like he's been stunned by something.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your juicy, heart-shaped ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I meant to say that...</context>
      <utterance>I...I don't know why I just said that.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I've always wanted to have sex with a gross pig. What do you say we go behind that dumpster, pull our pants down and see what happens? Valerie's very hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns and walks away. Nicky looks over and sees Adrian. His inner voice speaks to him.</context>
      <utterance>You're a jerk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shouldn't have come here.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Adrian's eyes flash.</context>
      <utterance>Please, get out of my mind!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She stops and turns. Nicky RAISES his fist to resist Adrian's force. It's too much. His middle finger comes up, giving her the "finger."</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Valerie!</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She runs away crying. Nicky turns to Adrian who's still across the street.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell's your problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Dad's sick.</context>
      <utterance>Adrian, you gotta come back to Hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's sick?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Adrian processes this.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, he needs souls to live. When you guys left, you broke the gates. We gotta get the gates burning again before he dies.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He should have thought of that before he denied me my birthright.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well maybe you should go back and talk it over with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Nicky's body jerks around.</context>
      <utterance>How about this? I stay here enjoying my Schnapps and you go back.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Nicky, fighting control over his body, walks slowly and crazily into the middle of the street where he sees a large truck bearing down on him. JOHN and PETER get blood splattered on them. Peter looks down to see the "666" forms in blood on their clothes.</context>
      <utterance>Adrian, please...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They laugh and hi-five.</context>
      <utterance>Check this out. The number of the beast.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DAN RATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...But even that does not come close to what happened today on Live with Regis and Kathy Lee.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIDEO FOOTAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The set of Regis and Kathy Lee.</utterance>
   <speaker>REGIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I was driving to work today, and some bozo in a Cadillac cut me off...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHY LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, that's terrible, Reege...</utterance>
   <speaker>REGIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I followed him...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHY LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You followed him?</utterance>
   <speaker>REGIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I followed him all the way downtown, and when he gets out of the car, I reach under my seat and pull out an aluminum bat.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHY LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You keep a bat under your seat?</utterance>
   <speaker>REGIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Recently, yes! So I run up behind this guy, and start bashing his brains in with this bat, and it made me feel happy! Did you ever see THE</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>KATHY LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, great movie...</utterance>
   <speaker>REGIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The blue haired lady AUDIENCE is crying. The TV turns off. We PULL BACK to see that we are in.</context>
      <utterance>I was DeNiro!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your brothers are upsetting the balance of good and evil.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can I do about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't do jack shit... unless you learn your evil powers.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody's as evil as my brothers. Those dudes put the wick in wicked.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go get a soda out of the fridge.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But those are my roommate's sodas...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have the power to change the cola in that can into any other liquid - engine oil, bat's blood, moose piss. You just have to release the evil within you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Release the evil?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky stares at the can.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just saying, there's wickedness in you... I can tell from your snores.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Nicky frowns and bites his lip. The can rattles a little.</context>
      <utterance>Release your evil...</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd is standing in the doorway. Beefy runs to the fire escape.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BILL WALTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A Globetrotter makes a fancy pass to another player, who makes a fancy pass to CORNROWS who starts doing some VINTAGE GLOBETROTTERS FANCY DRIBBLING. The REF blows the whistle and makes the travelling signal.</context>
      <utterance>What an odd game, folks. The powerhouse 85-0 Harlem Globetrotters, who normal run circles around the 0-85 Nationals, seem to be struggling to find their groove in front of their hometown fans.</utterance>
   <speaker>REF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's walking, get him a bus!</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL WALTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ref takes ball from Cornrows, who gets in the Ref's face.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, another awful call. There is no way that was travelling.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNROWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's with all these crazy calls? You gotta watch that shit, we haven't lost a game in 53 years.</utterance>
   <speaker>REF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ref snaps just like Cassius in the players' face.</context>
      <utterance>Technical foul!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It looks like the work of a brother...</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A black guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky races for the door.</context>
      <utterance>If it's Cassius, yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GLOBETROTTER FAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get your head out your ass, ref! The kids came to see the Globetrotters win.</utterance>
   <speaker>REF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Globetrotter's score on the board goes from 46 to 36.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, so you wanna lip off to me? Unsportsmanlike conduct on the big mouth in the Globetrotter's shirt. Take ten points off for the Globetrotters.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BILL WALTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A spotlight points to an announcer at mid-court.</context>
      <utterance>In all my years of basketball, I was never so happy to hear a halftime buzzer. Folk, I'm afraid if the second half doesn't get any better, I expect a full scale riot.</utterance>
   <speaker>COURT ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A brick lands at the announcer's feet.</context>
      <utterance>It's time for the Globetrotter's halftime half-court heave throw, where one lucky fan will have a shot at ten thousand dollars!</utterance>
   <speaker>COURT ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if he makes it, everyone in attendance today will receive a free pizza.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MIGUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't goin' out there and taking the shot. These people have gone crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take the shot.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look who's back from the dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They high-five. The only happy fans in their section.</context>
      <utterance>Six, six, six, pick up sticks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's Nicky doing down there?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trying to capture his brother in a flask and preserve the balance of good and evil on Earth. Todd looks over, suspicious.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you just talk?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes get red. Staring at the ball, it explodes.</context>
      <utterance>Release the evil.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Bill Walton's hair is on fire.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, too much evil..</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL WALTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think that ball just blew up. And yes, my hair is aflame.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The court announcer throws out another ball. Nicky stares at it again with red eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Could I get another ball?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Nicky throws an underhand shot. The ball arcs through the air and is about to go in when the ref comes out of nowhere and swats it away.</context>
      <utterance>I command you not to blow up and go into that metal circle.</utterance>
   <speaker>REF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd BOOS! Nicky and the ref stare at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Get that crap outta here!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you're having fun, Cassius, but you gotta come back to Hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIUS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The New Hell.</context>
      <utterance>Look around you, Nicky. We're in Hell.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky gets hit by a hot dog.</context>
      <utterance>Listen up, New York. Your souls are in great danger...</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The crowd is silent.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, how about this? I get one more shot. The ref will cover me. I miss it, the Globetrotters forfeit the game. I make it, he doesn't ref the second half and we all start conducting ourselves like decent human beings again.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The crowd roars.</context>
      <utterance>And we get free pizza.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL WALTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bill Walton reaches over to an old lady sitting near him. He takes off her wig, leaving behind her bald head, and puts her wig on his head in order to cover his burnt hair. The crowd starts YELLING.</context>
      <utterance>I think it's safe to say we're all rooting for this bizarre and hideous looking man.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROWD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nicky! Nicky! Nicky!</utterance>
   <speaker>STANDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John and Peter are yelling the loudest.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, Dad got very sick when you left.</utterance>
   <speaker>REF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky's eyes get red, he starts dribbling.</context>
      <utterance>I heard. I'm glad he's dying. It's my turn now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd looks at Beefy, terrified.</context>
      <utterance>Take him to the hole, Nicky.  I mean, woof! Woof!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>REF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's nuts. When'd you learn that shit?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Cassius. Maybe it was the super devil juice Dad gave me. HE thought I might need it for just such an occasion.</utterance>
   <speaker>REGIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Super devil juice? Give it over. Let's go best two out of three.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COURTSIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nicky peers into the flask.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIUS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Nicky caps the flask. Nicky waves to the stunned, but appreciative crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Damn you, Nicky! There ain't no super devil juice in here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So your father's the devil, you're a talking dog sent from Hell, and you guys are who?</utterance>
   <speaker>PEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a couple of big fans of Nicky and the work his Dad does.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He spins his Black Sabbath backwards.</context>
      <utterance>By the way, Nicky. Check this out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's Ozzy trying to say there?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky gets up and we see his is sitting on a hibachi. He pus on a James Taylor album and plays it backwards.</context>
      <utterance>Absolutely nothing. The Blizzard always came straight with his messages. But wrap your minds around this one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No wonder your uncle's so weird...</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta say this cake tastes a little funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I dumped a fat sack of reefer in the mix. Tried to spice up the bash. Nicky takes a big bite of cake.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's reefer?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on. One more time.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not again, fellas. It kind of hurts.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. You got to.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky loosens up his neck and makes his head go around 360 degrees. Everyone cracks up, high fives. Even Todd LAUGHS. PAN OVER to Beefy, who has bloodshot eyes.</context>
      <utterance>All right...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I used to get baked like this with my first girlfriend, Heather. We'd get so stoned she would forget I was a dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was human?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, she was a sewer rat. Man, that pissed my parents off.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dated a Japanese girl once. My parents disapproved. Not cause she's Japanese, but cause she was only fifteen.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone cracks up.</context>
      <utterance>I'm only fifteen...thousand years old.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was in love one time but she said I wasn't financially reliable enough. And she needed that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By she, do you mean he?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(laughs)</context>
      <utterance>Busted.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you feelin' over there, Satan Abdul Jabar?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little strange. I can't stop thinking about this girl, Valerie.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? Did she hurt you? Do you miss her? Need a shoulder to cry on?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy, Liberace.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, would you grow up.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We had the greatest afternoon of my life until Adrian made me tell her she had a heart-shaped ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm baked out of my mind.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe you love her. But what do I know?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me, too. We're gonna get going.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys want to stay? I have a futon in my bedroom.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a big pass, Elton John.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to see Ozzy play at the Meadowlands, right now. Wanna come, Nicky?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No thanks. I'm afraid I wouldn't be able to give Ozzy the focus he deserves.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa, that chick must be the real deal, then. Later on.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They leave.</context>
      <utterance>See ya, fellas.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>He falls asleep and starts snoring. We hear the SOUND of THREE LITTLE GIRLS singing "Ring Around The Rosie" as he exhales.</context>
      <utterance>You better snap out of it soon, kid. Cause we're going after Adrian tomorrow. Seven AM. Nighty, night.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky stands and moves to the window. He looks out longingly over the sleeping city... achingly. RACK FOCUS behind him, we see Todd nodding encouragingly in the reflection.</context>
      <utterance>That is the most frightening thing I have ever seen.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Todd. Which way to the Parson's School of Design?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky goes to the fire escape and starts to climb. His nose leads him. He reaches the window, sniffing heavily.</context>
      <utterance>Coconuts...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>STUDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You smell like coconuts.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's "Comptoir Sud Pacific." Makes me feel like a hula girl. Which is kinda what I'm going for. Wanna come in?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No thanks. I'm looking for a girl named Valerie who also smells like coconuts.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Valerie Doran? Two floors up, one window over.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, much. Good luck with the genital tucking.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky floats away. A few seconds later, he floats back, holding up the flask.</context>
      <utterance>I don't need luck. I'm good.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Adrian?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky nods and floats off.</context>
      <utterance>Andrew.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. Valerie opens the window and sprays a can of mace right in Nicky's face.</context>
      <utterance>Nicky? Oh my G-d. Stay right there.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky stands up and stumbles around.</context>
      <utterance>Oh that stings! My eyes are on fire!</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What were you thinking coming here?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bounces off the front rail, stumbles backward and goes flying over the back rail.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure, but it didn't involve getting blinded with poison.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly he stops. Suspended above ground. Valerie doesn't hear the expected thud.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my G-d, I'm so sorry!</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He floats up, but he can't see.</context>
      <utterance>Nicky?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Valerie?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I'm floating.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would you be floating?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Maybe it's because of your sweet voice.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's floating up. He slows down.</context>
      <utterance>Am I supposed to not be freaked out right now? Because I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CUT TO REVEAL he's floating outside the student's window. The student's dripping candle wax on his belly.</context>
      <utterance>I can't see you but I can smell you. And you make me feel alive in a way I've never felt before.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got the wrong window again, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky resumes floating up.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Sorry, Andrew. Valerie?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky is parallel with her. He hovers in front of her, eyes still watering. She punches Nicky in the face, and he flies back ten feet.</context>
      <utterance>I'm over here, Nicky! To the left.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, just because you're floating doesn't mean I'm gonna forget about you giving me the finger.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That wasn't me. I was being possessed by my brother, Adrian. He's the one who call you a gross pig.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, "possessed?"</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember when I told you my Dad was in Hell?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's because he's the Devil. And he wants to keep his throne for another ten-thousand years. Which is fine with me, but not with my brothers, so they broke out of Hell, causing my dad...</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... "The Devil?"...</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His vision is clearing and he can start to see her. She is totally in shock but still here.</context>
      <utterance>...to decompose. And I love my Dad very much. So I came to Earth to save him but then crazy eyes stole my flask and I met you and...well, my dog tells me I just might be in love with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky laughs. Valerie joins in.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, now I get that "deep south" joke.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Nicky starts to drop.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know if I should believe you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta believe me. You gotta believe in the butterflies.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He floats up to her holding out his hand. Nervously, she takes his hand and suddenly she is lifting off and they are flying.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, I do. Get back up here.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They soar past some more buildings.</context>
      <utterance>This is amazing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's kind of ruining the mood.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me take care of that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we go fly over Central Park?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Next time. Tonight, I want to share the most beautiful thing I could possibly imagine.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to Jersey?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>East Rutherford.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never thought I'd ever see Ozzy live until he was dead.  Please tell me you like metal.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Mister Crowley, what's inside of your head..." Nicky's jaw drops as he stares at her.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They slow dance tighter. The music swells. John and Peter look up from their seats far below. Nicky sees them while he's holding her tight. They give thumbs up.</context>
      <utterance>My dog was right. I'm in love with you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ow...what was that for?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The bum holds up a NEW YORK POST. It reads "MONSTER WANTED!" And has a picture of Nicky. Nicky is shocked. Nicky turns to run out of the alley, but the mob is there blocking the entrance. He's trapped. They start running right at him. He closes his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Fifty million dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky's body splits into about five-hundred horrifying insects, all with a miniature NICKY HEAD. The Nickysects run right at the crowd, and the crows immediately starts running the other way, completely freaked out.</context>
      <utterance>Release the evil.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I seem to be in trouble, Beefy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The shit has hit the fan, kid. Take a look.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Been breaking all morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN RATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>holding up a picture of Nicky taken at the Basketball arena.</context>
      <utterance>At a news conference earlier today, Chief of Police Andy Shaifer gave this beleaguered city its latest dose of bad news. He revealed that the man who caused a sensation at basketball arena last night is no hero... he is, in fact, a mass murderer. We see the chief of police behind a bunch of mics. He's</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't murder anybody</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look. You were really high. Things happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was with Valerie, I swear. This is Adrian's work. I've got to find him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you're looking at him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CUT TO FOOTAGE on "SCARFACE"</context>
      <utterance>My name's Nicky, and I'm gonna kill all you suckers for no reason!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF OF POLICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Difficult to watch, I know. In response to this vicious crime, I am authorizing the largest reward in law enforcement history: fifty million dollars to the person or persons who bring this man to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is baloney!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He superimposed your head onto "Scarface."</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...which is by far DePalma's best work...</utterance>
   <speaker>A LOUD KNOCKING AT THE DOOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The pounding increases.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not Nicky. I'm not home! I don't live here!</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky opens the door. Peter and John stumble in.</context>
      <utterance>Dude, it's us. Let us in.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear VOICES of an approaching crowd coming outside.</context>
      <utterance>There's like a total mob scene coming this way.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd i s looking out the window.</context>
      <utterance>I thought for sure I gave 'em the slip.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like they're following a giant trail of bug shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'll we do now, Beefy?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, this is a little out of my league.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>VOICES</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on. Let's get 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What would your dad do, Nicky?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good idea...kill me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dude. Seriously?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I'll meet you at Grand Central at noon. Okay. Do me. I command you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN AND PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John takes Nicky's head and slams it hard into the kitchen counter. Nicky is dazed.</context>
      <utterance>Alright!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That just hurt a lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've always wanted to kill someone. Can I do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at Queen Latifah steppin' up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Demons and Gatekeeper are sitting around playing strip poker. The Gatekeeper takes off his bra. From behind, we see his breasts flop out.</context>
      <utterance>Royal flush, you lose. Off with the bra.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Gatekeeper throws his hand down and storms out. The Monster laughs uproariously. Nicky enters and moves to what's left of his dad. Arms, torso, and a head (with one ear).</context>
      <utterance>Last time I saw a pair of jugs that big, two hillbillies were blowing on them.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, Adrian's got the whole city after me. He's always a step ahead. What am I gonna do?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dad's remaining ear falls out.</context>
      <utterance>What are you gonna do? Look at me, Nicky! I got no legs, I got no hips, I got one ear...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got no ears! I can't hear!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY THE DEMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Your father's got no ears!</context>
      <utterance>Now he's got no ears! You happy, Nicky?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, I'll do my best, Dad. Do you have any advice at all for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't hear you, Nicky. I can't hear anything! Jimmy picks up the ear. Jimmy speaks into it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY THE DEMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Check one-two. Check one-two.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put it back on my head. I'm falling apart here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY THE DEMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky looks very upset.</context>
      <utterance>He's got 'til midnight tonight, Nicky.  You get your ass back up there. You save your father!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure you're down with this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They approach the cops guarding the door.</context>
      <utterance>Little nervous. Wanna puke.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looking for the chief.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COPS grab John &amp; Peter and drag them inside.</context>
      <utterance>We know where to find Nicky.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CHIEF OF POLICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have what I want?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure do. You got what we want?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods to a DEPUTY who gives them a briefcase of money.</context>
      <utterance>Fifty million bones, bro.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF OF POLICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's half of it. You get the rest when I get Nicky.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's not human.</context>
      <utterance>Excellent. But I gotta warn you, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF OF POLICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PAUSE. The chief LAUGHS, then everyone else does. He walks over and picks them up by their throats.</context>
      <utterance>We think he's the son of Satan.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF OF POLICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, then I guess I'll have to be extra careful. Now where is he?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BAG LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, watch it! Who do you think you are?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF OF POLICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They march through onto the platform for Track 33.</context>
      <utterance>Emperor of the New Hell.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="41">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is he? He's late.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hear FOOTSTEPS. They turn and see the chief of police backed up by the huge police force.</context>
      <utterance>He'll be here. Just keep your cool, kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Beefy and Todd turn to see John and Peter looking sheepish.</context>
      <utterance>We've been ratted out.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys. That was so uncool.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Peter and John high-five.</context>
      <utterance>We thought the son of Satan would understand a move like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF OF POLICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The police grab Todd and put a leash on Beefy. The cops lead their prisoners away down the tunnel, leaving John and Peter alone with the chief.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, take these two outside. I can handle this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF OF POLICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The chief inserts a finger into his nostril. Then he fits his hand up there. Soon his whole arm is up his nostril as he searches for something. John and Peter are impressed. The chief grabs something and starts to pull. Then out of his nose comes Adrian, who fully forms as the shell of the chief's body slumps to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Wanna see something cool?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ta-da. So what time is my brother expected back?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at the clock. It's noon.</context>
      <utterance>Noon...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Peter is sweating, kinda nervous.</context>
      <utterance>...ish.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So even though you're not really the chief, we still get the rest of the cash, right bro?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what you'll get? An indescribably horrific torture administered by demons for the rest of eternity.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what about the cash? Can we keep it or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They high five. Adrian smiles and waits. It is real hot down there. We hear a train coming in the distance. A fan circles slowly. They all wait for him.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see the HOMELESS LADY down the platform stumbling her way towards them, drunk. Adrian scowls at her.</context>
      <utterance>Food stamps? They should call 'em "dude stamps." Cause ever time I get one, some dude takes it away...</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, studs. I'll let you make out with me for a dollar!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(grabs the bottle, laughs)</context>
      <utterance>No thanks...but we'll take that bottle of booze.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Peter pushes her away.</context>
      <utterance>Hey...that's mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John and Peter high five and John swigs from the bag.</context>
      <utterance>Beat it, ya freak.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Schnapps...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adrian raises his eyebrows. We see that the homeless lady is actually VALERIE in disguise. She looks back, tense. John offers Adrian the flask.</context>
      <utterance>Peppermint...alright.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hands it to him. He takes it.</context>
      <utterance>Wanna hit?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drink up. Here's to fifty million clams.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To the defilement of Earth and the corruption of its people.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adrian smiles at John, then raises the bag. He stops just before it hits his lips. He looks at John curiously.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever. Knock it back, grab Nicky and let's get outta this hell-hole.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is awfully hot down here. How do you manage to stay so cool?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adrian stares at John. He raises the bag again.</context>
      <utterance>Weed lowers the body temperature.  I read that...in, uh...er, science magazine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This liquid will probably quench my thirst. Cool me off.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Definitely.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And give you a good buzz.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or maybe it will trap me inside for all eternity.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John starts to tremble a bit.</context>
      <utterance>Uh. No it won't?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Nicky, I've missed you. Come on out and say hello...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Urr...uggg...errr...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adrian is mentally pulling Nicky out of John. Nicky/John wages an epic battle with himself as Adrian smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I'm calling you out, brother...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN/NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oww. Adrian, this is very painful. Nicky comes flying out. John's body slumps to the floor next to the chief's. Adrian looks in the "Schnapps bottle" to see the flask wrapped in paper. He peeks inside.</context>
      <utterance>Urrr...uggh...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Cassius.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIUS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. Let me out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, New Hell really only needs one new Satan.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIUS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Adrian hands Nicky the flask.</context>
      <utterance>You mother...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts the Flask in Nicky's hands.</context>
      <utterance>But Cassius could use some company for the rest of eternity. So get in the flask.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A thick, yellow smoke shoots out of Beefy, enveloping the group. Beefy escapes and bolts back down stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, he's gotta pee.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Run, Beefy! Run!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adrian looks over at Valerie. Suddenly she comes flying over to him. He grabs her by the throat. We hear a train coming in the distance.</context>
      <utterance>I won't drink. You can't make me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course I can. Drink or she dies.  Unlike you, she won't come back from where she's going.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let her go.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The train sound is coming CLOSER. Valerie looks at Nicky. Nicky raises the flash to drink.</context>
      <utterance>I hear a train coming. Drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see Beefy skid to a stop, raise his leg and a full size archery arrow shoots out of his penis and tracks right into</context>
      <utterance>I have to, Valerie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahhh!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valerie is able to escape momentarily. Adrian reaches for her, grabbing her. They both spin and fall down onto the tracks. Right into the oncoming train.</context>
      <utterance>Now that hurt the both of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky leaps down onto the tracks, wrestles Valerie away from Adrian and tosses her off the tracks. Adrian looks at Nicky.</context>
      <utterance>Valerie!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WHAMM! The train comes by, hitting both Adrian and Nicky.</context>
      <utterance>See you in Hell!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. My. G-d. I can't believe you're here. Welcome. Can I just tell you, I am so excited right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So excited.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She really is.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky trails off as he sees the Angels laughing at him.</context>
      <utterance>That's terrific. Now could you ladies point me to the Black Palace? I should check in with my dad...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, you're just so cute.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have any idea where you are right now?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The home of eternal damnation, house of Hades, H.E. double toothpicks...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Angel and two friends laugh and high-five. Nicky's confused.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe try the opposite of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>What do you know about your mom?</context>
      <utterance>Okay, can I just ask you something?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My brothers told me my mother was a mountain goat. Which would explain my chronic halitosis.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A mountain goat? That's really sweet.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My mom wasn't a goat?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try an angel.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An angel?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky is floored.</context>
      <utterance>Unh-huh. Which would make you half angel.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. What...what did she look like?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The GIRLS start laughing.</context>
      <utterance>Well, she was about six-three, only spoke Portuguese and had really long grey hair.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Nicky is even more floored. FLASH. Jenna has taken a picture of Nicky.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, I'm totally busting on you. I'm your mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, but you just had the sweetest look on your face.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gonna be so happy she did that.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come you're not older?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Angels don't get any older, son.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe you just called him "son."</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They laugh. Nicky is quite baffled.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my G-d. This is so wild.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="48">
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adrian enters. They all cheer.</context>
      <utterance>I can't see shit. You're all still here, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY THE DEMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Adrian's here. You'll be back to normal in a jiffy, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD LIPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yea! I can't believe little Nicky came through.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Nicky?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY THE DEMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He came with you and Cassius, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I came through that gate alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY THE DEMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, sir, false alarm.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boooo.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Puts the Gatekeeper in a headlock.</context>
      <utterance>Somebody explain what's going on.</utterance>
   <speaker>GATEKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll get nothing out of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He twists a breast. The Gatekeeper babbles out the information immediately.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps a titty twister will loosen your lips.</utterance>
   <speaker>GATEKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The only way to save your dad is for you and your brothers to pass through the gates at the same time before he deteriorates completely.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adrian twists hard.</context>
      <utterance>How much time does Dad have before that happens?</utterance>
   <speaker>GATEKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adrian throws him down.</context>
      <utterance>Thirty minutes. And then whoever claims his throne will have unimaginable power.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All boobs and no balls.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves to the throne and throws the lips off.</context>
      <utterance>Thirty minutes. Hmmm. I hope you don't mind if I take a seat while I wait for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD LIPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pushes Lucifer out of the way.</context>
      <utterance>Ahhh!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't get no respect.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sits on the throne and it starts to shake a little. He grins as two horns grow out of his forehead.</context>
      <utterance>Ten thousand years. And I never once got to sit here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. And this is just a little taste of my power.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The demons approach.</context>
      <utterance>Hell's gonna bust wide open. Demons, get him out of the chair!</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The demons stop. Now loyal to Adrian. All except Jimmy.</context>
      <utterance>Ah-ah. Not so fast, demons. There are a couple of million evil souls on Earth ready to be harvested. Anyone interested?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you Adrian and Cassius' mom, too?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, their mother's weren't angels.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a knock on the door. It opens and in comes Carl Weathers dressed as Chubbs from Happy Gilmore.</context>
      <utterance>I think they were hookers or strippers or something really porno like...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holly, Jenna, Christa. Time for your Mambo lesson.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Chubbs. I totally spaced. I'm so sorry. I have company. It's my son, Nicky. My son. Can you believe it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow, that's terrific.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nicky, this is Chubbs. He used to be a golf pro, but up here he's the dopest dance instructor.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mambo?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chubbs dances as he leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Remember, it's all in the hips. It's all in the hips.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did you meet my father?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was a long time ago, at some Heaven and Hell mixer.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I remember that night, you had like four daiquiris.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try four and a half. At first I totally didn't like him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was really conceited.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I don't know, he was funny, he made me laugh, and I hate to say it but he had a really nice body.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Angels laugh.</context>
      <utterance>And that made you want to make a baby with him?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her cell-phone rings. She answers it.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I really wasn't thinking about making a baby at the time!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello....yes, he's here with me now... I don't know if he's hot, he's my son, you perv! I'll call you back...  Oh my G-d, I will call you back, goodbye.  That was my friend, Michelle, she says "hi."</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angel makes a motion towards the phone, then stops.</context>
      <utterance>Well tell her I said "hi" back.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll call her later.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, we saw you save your girlfriend's life.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was so cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why you came up to Heaven instead of Hell. Self-sacrifice automatically gets you here.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you see me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angel and the girls clear the junk from the glass table in front of them. Angel touches the glass and it turns into a reflection of Earth below.</context>
      <utterance>We can see what's going on anywhere on Earth. Look.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All these good people have totally been led astray.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Show him Central Park.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Then suddenly we see the ground start to break up and Adrian on his throne start to be thrust upwards. Demons swarm around him.</context>
      <utterance>There's like a three day rave goin' on down there. No on is going to work anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome to the party. It's so nice to see all of you here.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, that's Dad's throne! How did Adrian get that? Is Dad okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's see...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DAD LIPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was a good Devil, wasn't I?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY THE DEMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were the best Devil, boss, the best Devil!</utterance>
   <speaker>GATEKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD LIPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tried to do some interesting stuff...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY THE DEMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did amazing stuff!</utterance>
   <speaker>GATEKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know how you came up with some of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD LIPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? That means a lot to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my G-d. He looks gross.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She touches the pool again and the reflection changes to:</context>
      <utterance>I can't believe I did it with him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd cheers.</context>
      <utterance>I'm very proud of you. You've taken to sin with minimal prompting.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The crowd cheers.</context>
      <utterance>You're acting as if there is no Heaven or Hell.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I have some news. Adrian morphs into the Cardinal from earlier.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARDINAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is most definitely a Hell! And you're all going there when you die! Which will happen in about fifteen minutes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This don't look good.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't Beefy use his penis powers to get us out of this?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They castrated him. He can't shoot arrows, he can't piss smoke.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valerie's crying.</context>
      <utterance>I can't screw.  I can't screw.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Valerie's crying!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's so nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She goes to Parson's, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would totally love to go there. But I hear it's really hard to get in.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta help her. I gotta help Dad. I gotta help everybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you do...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adrian motions to some of his guards. They nod.</context>
      <utterance>Not that horrible, but still pretty bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A frightened HENRY WINKLER is lead onto the stage prodded by two DEMONS.</context>
      <utterance>So while we wait, for your enjoyment, I bring you a dear sweet man and an international icon...Henry Winkler!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see Henry Winkler is suddenly covered head to in a swarm of bees.</context>
      <utterance>Covered in bees!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But how can I win? Adrian is stronger and smarter than me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But you have something he doesn't have.</context>
      <utterance>Stronger, yes. Smarter, definitely.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girls laugh.</context>
      <utterance>A speech impediment?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives him an ornate, jewelled ball.</context>
      <utterance>No, you have the inner light. You can totally use it. It's the best power of all.  And in case you get in real bad trouble, G-d told me to give you this.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not a hundred percent on that. G-d said when the time comes, you'll know what to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>G-d's so smart.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The smartest.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She licks her finger and wipes some dirt off his forehead.</context>
      <utterance>Well, goodbye...for now.  Can I just do this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was such a Mom thing, wasn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIEND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Totally.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, nice meeting you, Jenna, Christa.  Would it be okay if I called you Mommy?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky hugs his Mom.</context>
      <utterance>It would be so okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Mommy, get me to the big apple cause I'm gonna rock that town like a hurricane.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're already there...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When he opens them, BEAUTIFUL BUTTERFLIES are floating around the head of five of the DEMONS. They stop approaching. THEIR EYES TURN FROM WHITE BACK TO NORMAL. And their facial expression changes to happiness. They wave at the butterflies.</context>
      <utterance>Release...the good.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Five more are stopped by something. They look down and see fluffy white BUNNY RABBITS at their feet. They start petting them. The REMAINING DEMONS advance on Nicky.</context>
      <utterance>Release the good...</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>...then stop, their path blocked by a very large bucket of POPEYE'S FRIED CHICKEN. The Demons consider the bucket of chicken. One Demon takes out a piece.</context>
      <utterance>Release the awesome.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Demon bites into it. He can't help but grin a little.</context>
      <utterance>Put it in your mouth and let it slide down your throat-hole.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The OTHER SOULS dig into the bucket.</context>
      <utterance>Popeye's chicken is ass kickin'!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One thing I really regret is never having experimented sexually.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean, like, experiment with a Bunsen Burner? What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He means getting it on with someone like that freak.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His name is Andrew. I know that guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course you do, Tommy Tune.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, from this angle, you're kind of cute.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves a little closer, and she spits on him. He smiles. Opens his mouth and catches her spit. He swallows.</context>
      <utterance>You think so? Why don't you come a little closer and I'll show you a better angle.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone is grossed out.</context>
      <utterance>Yummy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my G-d, he just opened his mouth and swallowed that spit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That turn you on there, RuPaul?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep it up and I just might make you my Queen for a night or two.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John points at Todd. They laugh. Adrian gets closer to Valerie. Just then a big butterfly appears on his shoulder. He looks down to see: Nicky standing there with his army.</context>
      <utterance>You want a queen? Got one right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Little Nicky.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Adrian, I'm asking you nicely, in the name of all that is good: release my friends and get in the flask.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this a joke?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. It's the inner light. And with it we can defeat anything you've got.</utterance>
   <speaker>REFORMED DEMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adrian glares down at the REFORMED DEMON. His eyes shoot out an evil ray. The Reformed Demon explodes into a million pieces. His golden insides splatter on the crowd. The Army of Good is shaken. Another Demon lowers his chicken.</context>
      <utterance>It's true!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER REFORMED DEMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The BUCKET OF CHICKEN sprouts legs and runs away. Nicky steps forward bravely.</context>
      <utterance>It's not true?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicky leaves frame and he flies up towards Adrian.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, Adrian, you've left me with no choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Love lifts me up where I belong.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I totally had to do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL THE GIRLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHUBBS is there, too.</context>
      <utterance>Yah you did.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adrian grabs a pillow and hits Nicky hard in the face, sending him flying off the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Now I'm asking you nicely, get in the flas...</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Nicky is an expert pillow fighter. He lands a series of awesome, almost Matrix-like pillow moves. Adrian is dazed. Nicky finishes him off by tossing the pillow high in the air to him. Adrian looks up to catch it and just before it lands, Nicky steps up and pops him in the face. Adrian goes down hard. Nicky towers over him.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, you wanna a pillow fight, do you?!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now will you get in the flask?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adrian turns to his demons.</context>
      <utterance>Absolutely not.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A bunch of Demons advance.</context>
      <utterance>A little help over here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Henry!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY WINKLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is covered in bees again.</context>
      <utterance>Oh no.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear CASSIUS banging against the walls.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Nicky.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIUS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Nicky can't hold his breath and opens his mouth. Adrian jams the flask in his mouth and Nicky starts to get sucked in. Adrian smiles. But just before Nicky is gone, he manages to grab Adrian's coat tail and yank him into the flask with him. As the flask hits the ground, we HEAR:</context>
      <utterance>Come on in, bro.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIUS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Nicky. Cause now I'm gonna bust Adrian's head wide open.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was going to let you out, eventually, Cassius. I swear.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>All the Demons and all the people of NEW YORK form a large circle around the flask. Valerie and the gang make it down off the stage. We HEAR crazy sounds as the FLASK starts to jump. The crowd REACTS. A big dent pops out from the inside, followed by a horrible thud.</context>
      <utterance>Sole ruler of Hell and Earth is what I heard him keep saying. We HEAR the sounds of a struggle.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nicky!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The FLASK starts rolling over and over on the road. People get out of the way as if it were real people fighting in the street. They root for their side.</context>
      <utterance>That was Cassius!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John and Peter start beating up the Demon.</context>
      <utterance>Kill him, Adrian.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd a sweet Southern boy learn to fight like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She laughs and kisses him on the mouth. The crowd CHEERS. But Nicky won't stop kissing her. She starts to struggle for air. Nicky presses harder and starts to laugh. The crowd stops CHEERING. Valerie is waving her arms for help. Nicky turns into Adrian during the kiss. Adrian lets her go. And we hear ADRIAN'S familiar laugh.</context>
      <utterance>From my dad's side of the family.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adrian pulls his head back, his tongue is huge and he turns into a GIANT BAT. He lets out a huge roar, then flies around, laughing, scaring people. Valerie runs over and picks up the flask. She looks inside.</context>
      <utterance>What? No tongue?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No response.</context>
      <utterance>Nicky. Nicky.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A long beat, then:</context>
      <utterance>You gotta fly out...I know you can do it.  Do it for the butterflies.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>And Nicky shoots right out of the top of the flask and lands on his feet. Adrian lands and stares down Nicky. The clock is one minute from midnight. Adrian swoops down. Nicky thinks quick and pulls out the BALL his Mom gave him and smashes it on the ground. Out of it forms metal G-d: OZZY OSBORNE.</context>
      <utterance>Butterflies...</utterance>
   <speaker>OZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, New York.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN AND PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bat's eyes go wide in fear. Ozzy grabs the bat, his mouth grows big, and he bites the bat's head off. Valerie hands Ozzy the flask.</context>
      <utterance>Ozzy. They faint.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ozzy spits the bat head into the flask.</context>
      <utterance>Put him in, Ozzy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grand Central, Nicky. Start running.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'll never make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta kill yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll just go to Heaven.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PAUSE. Everyone looks around. Nicky spots Henry Winkler.</context>
      <utterance>No if you do something bad right before you die.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY WINKLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, man, not again.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry is covered in bees once again.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Henry.  Release the Evil.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do me.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valerie smashes the rock on Nicky's head, killing him.</context>
      <utterance>I love you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone cheers.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, you just saw my son save the universe. Right?!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You came through, Nicky.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I came through for you, Mom and the butterflies, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're back in Hell now, kid. There's no butterflies here. If you want butterflies, you need to be on Earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about you and Grandpa and everyone in Hell?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nicky, I let my butterflies die once upon a time and it's never stopped hurting.  That's right, you heard me, Holly. I'm still in love with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my G-d. He's totally talking about me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>FRIEND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That guy is still a horn dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, I got down low. Your mom's got up high. You take care of the middle.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pats him on the back.</context>
      <utterance>I will, Dad. But in the words of Motley Crue, this will always be my...home sweet home...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY THE DEMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry to interrupt guys, but it's time for Hitler's punishment.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lucifer walks over to the closet.</context>
      <utterance>Let me handle that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I'm not using a pineapple this time. He pulls out the flask.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADRIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASSIUS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>He shoves the flask up Hitler's ass. Hitler's face tightens.</context>
      <utterance>Don't do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>HITLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FREEZE FRAME, then:</context>
      <utterance>Holy Schnit!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh...what an uncommonly beautiful baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALERIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank yo.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Such a little angel.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEFY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tickles the baby. It giggles and a small stream of fire shoots out of his mouth and singes the Old Lady's eyebrows.</context>
      <utterance>Only a quarter, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zachariah, say you're sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY ZACHARIAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Lady scurries away. Nicky and Valerie laugh and continue walking in absolute bliss. They pass the Preacher who runs towards us.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Preacher runs straight into the camera. BLACK.</context>
      <utterance>He has spilled his seed! He is multiplying! Beware the progeny of the unholy union! We're all gonna die!</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
