<movie id="359" title="Lord of War">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FADE UP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Late-thirties, maybe the wrong side of forty, cigarette dangling from his fingers, wearing a conservative suit and tie. Black smoke wafts in front of his face. He speaks matter-of-factly, directly into camera.</context>
      <utterance>CLOSE UP on the face of YURI ORLOV.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri alone on a battlefield surrounded by the charred carcasses of armored military vehicles and other equipment, discarded weapons and ammunition, desert floor stained with what appears to be blood. The faint sound of gunfire, some distance away, carries to us on the wind.</context>
      <utterance>There are over 550 million firearms in worldwide circulation. That's one firearm for every twelve people on the planet. The only question is...  ...how do we arm the other eleven? The camera zooms away from his face, revealing:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A YOUNG COMMUNIST sits in the shadow of a statue of Trotsky in the Soviet-style plaza, jacket and neckerchief removed in the summer heat, poring over a Communist text. Yuri approaches, pretends to be interested in the statue, glances to the Young Communist's book.</context>
      <utterance>I was born Yuri Orlovitch in the city of Odessa in a country that no longer exists. You might have heard of it - a little place called the Soviet Union.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Young Communist nods at this kindred spirit. Yuri pats his comrade on the back, taking the opportunity to steal the boy's red neckerchief and Lenin pin.</context>
      <utterance>All property is theft.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>RADIO ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anatoly, deep in thought, switches off the radio. IRINA enters, puts Yuri's "feast" on the table. They speak Ukrainian, subtitled.</context>
      <utterance>--Finally, in response to human rights protests and in an effort to encourage the United States to sell grain to the Soviet Union after two successive crop failures, it is reported that the politburo has consented to permit a limited number of Jews to emigrate from the Soviet Union to Israel.  And that concludes this edition of news from the BBC World Service.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANATOLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trading Jews for grain.</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's good P.R. - for the Moscow Olympics.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good for the Jews.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And us. All eyes to Yuri, family confused. YURI   We're Jewish.</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not Jewish.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANATOLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri and the family drink to their new identity.</context>
      <utterance>Mazeltov.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Under his father's watchful gaze, Yuri takes a rubbing from one of the headstones - "ORLOV".</context>
      <utterance>There have been few occasions in the twentieth century when it's been an advantage to be a Jew.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We reveal he is standing in a jam-packed, standing-roam-only "TRANSIT" lounge.</context>
      <utterance>We Russian Jews were supposed to be headed for Israel but I didn't see much of the country on that first trip.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The Pan American destination board reads: "PA 447 to NEW YORK".</context>
      <utterance>Real Jews or fake Jews, eighty-five percent of us ended up in that other "promised land".</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>YURI, older, as we now know him, studies school work. Long-haired VITALY watches "Band Aid" on TV. IRINA puts a plate of mussels in front of Anatoly.</context>
      <utterance>I had no idea my father would take his assumed identity so much to heart. I guess he just stayed in character.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANATOLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many times--I can't eat shellfish. It's "treyf".</utterance>
   <speaker>IRINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not Jewish.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANATOLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like it.  I like the hat - to remind us there's something above us. I like that. Anatoly dons his hat. ANATOLY  I'm going to temple.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vitaly begins eating his father's plate of mussels. Yuri watches his father exit.</context>
      <utterance>You're not going to temple. You go to temple more than the rabbi!</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We focus on orientation booklets from a careers fair. Yuri shuffles between the eagle of the CIA and the dove of the U.N.</context>
      <utterance>I was suffering an identity crisis of my own.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My gift for languages made me highly sought after. The C.I.A. and U.N. were both heavily recruiting Russian immigrants. Yuri settles on the dove.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A tatty pile of weapons - some from World War II - sits in front of a long negotiating table. YURI, blue beret, observes the CHIEF U.N. ENVOY at the table opposite warlord ANDRE BAPTISTE, leader of the National Revolutionary Front of Liberia (NRFL). Baptiste, 40's, is an imposing figure. In full uniform despite the heat, he wears a jacket one size too small as if he cannot admit his extra few pounds. His THIRD WIFE stands next to him, wiping the sweat from his brow like an intermittent windscreen wiper.</context>
      <utterance>West Africa's Liberia, or "land of the free", was originally established in the 1800's as a homeland for freed American negroes. It's been enslaved by one dictator or another ever since. They even copied their masters' Southern architecture.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Baptiste has a U.N. document in front of him, awaiting his signature, clearly enjoying his moment in the sun.</context>
      <utterance>It was my first meeting with the American- educated Andre Roosevelt Baptiste. While the warning signs were all there, no one had any idea what a monster he would eventually become. I certainly didn't think he would become my friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>U.N. ENVOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baptiste smiles.</context>
      <utterance>--With all due respect, Mr. Baptiste, you don't seriously expect us to believe that this represents your entire arsenal. Baptiste shrugs. U.N. ENVOY  This is making a nonsense of the embargo ratified by all five permanent members of the Security Council. The escalation in the build up of arms jeopardizes not only order in the region but ultimately world order.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAPTISTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am only going to the restroom.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They reach the door marked, "MEN".</context>
      <utterance>Orders.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAPTISTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri winces at the remark.</context>
      <utterance>This is what they mean by U.N. Observer?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BAPTISTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't you going to help me hold my cock?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The BODYGUARDS stiffen at the insult. Baptiste stares Yuri down for a moment, then suddenly bursts into laughter. The TWO BODYGUARDS also start to laugh - cautiously. Baptiste washes his hands, stares at Yuri in the mirror, smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Doesn't look like a job for two men.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAPTISTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know you are fighting a losing battle, my young friend. War is nature. If you take away the guns, we will kill each other with knives. Take away the knives, we will kill each other with sticks. Take away the sticks, we will kill each other with your peace treaties.  You cannot stop this bath of blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not "bath of blood". It's, "blood bath".</utterance>
   <speaker>BAPTISTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baptiste smiles and exits, leaving the words ringing in Yuri's head.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you. But I like it my way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>U.N. PEACEKEEPERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ava steps up to the microphone.</context>
      <utterance>Take it off, baby! Take it off!</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Baby blue. My favorite color! A roar of approval from the men. AVA  I suppose I could give you the speech about "my hope for world peace" but I have a feeling you don't want to hear that today.</utterance>
   <speaker>U.N. PEACEKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They roar again.</context>
      <utterance>My hope is for a piece of your ass!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>U.N. PEACEKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the young man reaches out to her, a slick, handsome BUSINESS MANAGER shoves him aside.</context>
      <utterance>Ava! Ava!</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Manager slips into the car beside Ava. The U.N. Peacekeeper and Yuri watch the car roar away.</context>
      <utterance>Don't touch what you can't afford.</utterance>
   <speaker>U.N. PEACEKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's get drunk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MONROVIAN GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri exits alone. The Liberian Man, across the street, follows.</context>
      <utterance>For the smile.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Liberian appears more interested in the gun than the hold-up.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck, no, no, no, no--fuck, no. Money? You want money?  Fuck, no. Don't shoot. Don't shoot me. Fuck. U.S. dollars.  President Lincoln. The Liberian puts his finger to his lips to hush Yuri.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIBERIAN MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Liberian produces a crisp U.S. twenty dollar bill of his own, offers it to Yuri. LIBERIAN MAN (cont'd) (referring to the face on a twenty dollar bill) Jackson.</context>
      <utterance>Glock .45.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri stares at the money, bewildered.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIBERIAN MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>President Jackson.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIBERIAN MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands Yuri a second twenty.</context>
      <utterance>You are driving a hard bargain.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, keep it. Keep the money. Keep the gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIBERIAN MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Demand and supply.  There is more I am thinking where this comes from.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want more Glocks?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIBERIAN MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the Heckler &amp; Koch G-3 assault rifle.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What makes you think I'll do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIBERIAN MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri stares at the man.</context>
      <utterance>I will come back and shoot you with the Glock.  By the way, do you have the hollow point cartridges?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got any color preference for that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIBERIAN MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Liberian walks away, still admiring his new weapon. Yuri stares after him.</context>
      <utterance>Kelly green.  I will find you.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'd come to the right place - peacekeepers are armed to the teeth. And nothing but premium product. The U.N. mostly buys from Switzerland - where else?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are we doing here, Yuri?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what I mean. Here, in this country. Are we doing any good?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Satisfied with the answer, she completely gives in to the throes of passion - pulls him to her.</context>
      <utterance>Would nothing be better?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Yuri kisses father and Maitre d', ANATOLY, who is adding more Jewish decoration to the window. He bear hugs mother, IRINA, nearly causing her to drop the plates she is carrying.</context>
      <utterance>The starting salary for a U.N. interpreter back then was $32,000. I made fifty K on "misplaced" weapons on that one trip alone. I doubt the Secretary General noticed. The U.N. spends more on lunch.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Irina notices the change in her son's appearance.</context>
      <utterance>My tour as a peacekeeper was the perfect preparation for war.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>YURI plonks a glossy arms brochure in front of Vitaly. He takes in the contents.</context>
      <utterance>You know who's going to inherit the earth? Vitaly looks at him blankly. YURI  Arms dealers - because everybody else is too busy killing each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a hell of a fucking career move.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the point. I've seen how the world's coming apart.</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you want to help with that?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vitaly is still skeptical.</context>
      <utterance>You can't stop it.  It's a basic human need - we eat, sleep, sleep with each other and what else? Fight. The oldest human skeletons have spearheads in their rib cages.</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you know about guns?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know which end I'd rather be on.  Every day there are people shooting at each other. I think to myself, what guns are they using? Why not mine?</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vitaly, I've tasted your borscht, you're no fucking chef. I can eat here for free and I still don't eat here. You're doing nothing with your life.</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri puts his arm around his brother's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe doing nothing's better than doing this.  Yuri, I've actually fired one of these things.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vitaly smiles, looks sold.</context>
      <utterance>That's why I need you.  Brothers in arms.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ANATOLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finally getting in touch with what's important, my Son?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>However, instead of the synagogue, he is fixed on another distinguished Jewish man, ELI KURTZMAN, on a street corner also on his way to temple.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Anatoly introduces Yuri to Eli, who regards Yuri warily.</context>
      <utterance>It wasn't God I was trying to get close to.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad's contacts at synagogue landed me my first Israeli-made Uzis and an introduction to the biggest of the big guns.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was the eighties and the Cold War was far from thawed. Most of the deals were government-to-government. There were some go- betweens - freelancers - but it was a mostly private club with a lifetime club president. Yuri drags Vitaly away from the sales girls.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's him. The guy Eli told me about. Simeon Zaharoff. Brokered deals in the Iran/Iraq war - both sides, sold missiles to Argentina in the Falklands. Hets a fucking legend. I've got to talk to him. Yuri pushes past Zaharoff's entourage.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A BODYGUARD tries to step between Yuri and Zaharoff.</context>
      <utterance>Simeon! Simeon!</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're talking. Zaharoff, irritated, nonetheless humors Yuri.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A mutual friend, Eli Kurtzman from Brighton Beach Import-Export said to contact you. I have a business proposal. Perhaps we can discuss it - over a drink. Simeon looks him up and down.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simeon walks away without another word. Vitaly shrugs. Yuri fumes.</context>
      <utterance>You're in the wrong place my young friend. This is no place for amateurs.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yob tvayu mat.  Yuri watches Simeon go, surrounded by flunkies.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Curious how you always revert to your native tongue in moments of extreme anger...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>YURI and VITALY are getting it on with two SALES GIRLS. We pan from one couple in the living room, Vitaly, to the one in the bedroom, Yuri. We focus on Yuri, in the midst of the act - hears his brother's moans in Ukrainian.</context>
      <utterance>...and ecstacy.</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>Yuri smiles at Vitaly's cries. Something catches Yuri's eye on TV.</context>
      <utterance>Boh...Boh. Oh, Boh!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We track with them, only getting occasional glimpses through the holes as they make their way through the war-torn streets of Lebanon.</context>
      <utterance>The job wasn't so different trom the U.N. I was just as neutral working for the ununited nations. An equal opportunity "merchant of death", I supplied every army but the Salvation Army.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>They enter a building carrying a crude rendering of a Coke sign - "Taste Life." The model drinking the Coke is Ava Cordova.</context>
      <utterance>We got our start in Lebanon after the suicide bombing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>YURI and VITALY usher the CUSTOMER over to an industrial scale loaded with assorted weapons.</context>
      <utterance>When the United States leaves a war zone, they generally don't take their munitions. It costs more to bring it back than buy new stock.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CUSTOMER checks the combined weight of the weapons. YURI (cont'd) (shrug) They're second-hand weapons but they're still okay. Both men pullout calculators and start haggling over the price.</context>
      <utterance>I sell by the kilo.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Money is finally exchanged. Yuri and Vitaly leave the Customer with his munitions pot-pourri.</context>
      <utterance>For all my language skills, I soon discovered that what talks best is money. As long as you can speak dollars, dinars, drachmas, rubles, rupees, pesos, escudos, lira, krones, kwanzas, trancs, guilders, deutshmarks, yen and pounds-fucking- sterling, you can communicate anywhere in the world.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is bullshit money, Vit - small fucking potatoes.</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do we do, go more legitimate?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vitaly nods thoughtfully.</context>
      <utterance>No. More illegal.</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri and Vitaly drop to the ground, money flying. The machine gun fire subsides, a shower of dust, fragments of brick and hundred dollar bills still floating to the ground. Vitaly, first to recover, draws his own handgun, sneaks a look through a shell hole. On the other side of the wall, a firing squad of MILITIAMEN has executed one group of MEN, lying contorted, slumped against the wall. Their bound hands and feet give the bodies a macabre awkwardness. Yuri is scrabbling in the dust for the cash. The Militiamen prepare to execute another six men. Men? We focus on one HANDSOME YOUNG LEBANESE BOY, barely in his teens. Vitaly, gun poised, goes to intervene. A HAND, stuffed with cash, stops him. Yuri. The brothers' eyes meet.</context>
      <utterance>What I'd give right now for a plate of red cabbage and potatoes. The wall explodes with gunfire.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After one look back to the teenage boy, Vitaly reluctantly complies - running with Yuri, heads down, away from the scene. As they run, the wall explodes again with gunfire.</context>
      <utterance>It's not our fight. Vitaly's eyes well with tears.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON RONALD REAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>YURI and VITALY carry a crate from a taxi onto the desert floor in Somalia. A group of MUSLIM FREEDOM FIGHTERS eagerly surround the crate - Yuri hands the Leader an Uzi machine gun.</context>
      <utterance>- a cardboard cut-out planted in a sand dune.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The Muslim Leader tests it - shooting up the cardboard REAGAN. His fighters applaud, Yuri and Vitaly slightly embarrassed.</context>
      <utterance>I sold Israeli-made Uzis to Muslims.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>INDIAN TROOPS, unseen at first due to their white camouflage uniforms, descend on the chopper - eager to unload the new guns and ammunition. Yuri gasps for breath in the thin air. An INDIAN SOLDIER gives Yuri a hit of oxygen as Vitaly supervises the unloading.</context>
      <utterance>I sold to both Pakistan and India in their fight tor the most inhospitable land on earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's it going?</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIAN COMMANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're making terrific progress - most casualties from avalanches and frostbite.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Up the street, a celebration is taking place - a band, balloons, confetti, dancing. Finally, a Congolese man, JOHN "CANNIBAL" NGAWE, appears at the warehouse. The conversation is in French.</context>
      <utterance>We had our set-backs. It's not called gunrunning for nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cannibal, what's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>CANNIBAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cease fire, man. Cease fire. It's over.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?! What do you mean it's over?</utterance>
   <speaker>CANNIBAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Truce. We're friends, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Friends?! You can't be fucking friends. Last week I spoke to you on the phone. You said you would not rest until every last rebel was dead. You called them vermin. You said would piss in their mouths, you said you would exterminate them like cockroaches. Just last week, you said this!</utterance>
   <speaker>CANNIBAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cannibal starts to walk away.</context>
      <utterance>That was last week, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cannibal, don't you fucking walk away from me! Cannibal flashes Yuri a peace sign.</utterance>
   <speaker>CANNIBAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peace, man!</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri looks to Vitaly.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you, Cannibal!!</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe we can offload it - the Balkans.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least when they say they're going to have a war, they keep their word.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I even shipped cargo to Afghanistan when they were still fighting fellow Russians. But I never sold to Osama bin Laden. Not for any moral grounds. Back then he was always bouncing checks.</utterance>
   <speaker>AFGHANI OFFICIAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope you're not thinking of selling these, Mr. Orlov.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Personal use.</utterance>
   <speaker>AFGHANI OFFICIAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a hundred thousand bullets here.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vitaly hands the Official his documentation - clipped to it, a thick wad of bills. The Afghani Official smiles. He returns to his mud-brick border station beside the confiscated merchandise. Yuri focuses on a swimsuit calendar hanging on the mud wall - Miss May is AVA CORDOVA.</context>
      <utterance>I'm kind of trigger happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And everywhere I went, Ava Cordova kept following me around. We were as international as each other.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>VITALY holds onto a railing trying to stave off seasickness, not helped by standing downwind from Yuri's cigarette smoke.</context>
      <utterance>Operations like mine provided the only way for certain regimes to conduct a respectable war.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The freighter I was standing on carried 113 tons of weapons and ammunition for delivery to one of the poorest nations in Latin America in direct contravention of half a dozen international arms embargoes. Yuri makes a call on his cell phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To keep authorities in the dark, I often spoke in code. Rocket launchers were "mothers", the rockets "children". Assault rifles were "apples". The AK-47 was "the Angel King".</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do we run?</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to get out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri swings into action, frantically dials another number on his satellite cell phone. YURI (cont'd) (barking an order to a CREWMAN, referring to the Panamanian flag) Get that fucking rag down! The CREWMAN hastily complies. Yuri's call is answered. YURI (cont'd) (trying not to sound too desperate) It's Yuri. I need another handle for this tub...something in our weight class. (to an elderly Latin PAINTER, pointing to the stern) You, over the side! (the painter hesitates) Now! The terrified PAINTER makes for the stern where he's hurriedly winched over. Yuri returns to the phone call. YURI (cont'd) Yes, it's got to check out...you got a shorter name!...what?--Kono? How do you spell that?...K-O-N-O. That's good! He hangs up. YURI (cont'd) (to the PAINTER, already blacking out the name, KRISTOL) Kono! K-O-N-O. The PAINTER, nods nervously from his precarious perch, starts to paint. Yuri sneaks another look through his binoculars. The Customs Boat is closing fast. YURI (cont'd) (back into phone) What are we flying?...Dutch? Later. (hanging up, to Vitaly) Vit, get me a Dutch flag! Yuri checks the Customs Boat again. YURI (cont'd) Damn, they're hauling! He checks the Painter's progress. YURI (cont'd) (agitated, grasping the line of the scaffold) Faster! Or I send you in! (checking the binoculars again) Faster...and better! The Painter's hand is shaking.</context>
      <utterance>No, no-one's going anywhere.  Slow--dead slow. Buy me time.</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>Vitaly is frantically rummaging through a trunk containing dozens of national flags. VITALY (cant' d) I don't have Dutch.</context>
      <utterance>Yuri!</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got Belgium.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck use is that?!  He's painting a name registered in the fucking Netherlands! Vitaly winces. YURI   You got France?!</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, why?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vitaly turns the flag sideways - now a makeshift Dutch flag. Vitaly nods, impressed. Yuri looks forward. The Customs Boat has almost reached the bow of the freighter. The flag is hoisted. The Painter, barely completing the last "O" of "KONO", is hauled back on deck. YURI (cont'd) That's it! Everybody look innocent--now! The CREW resume their normal duties as the Customs Boat slows to a crawl itself, at close quarters with the freighter. The heavily-armed INTERPOL AGENTS eyeball the rusted vessel. YURI focuses on the senior agent - JACK VALENTINE. While the other agents wear sunglasses, long hair, tattoo or personalized uniform, Valentine is completely by the book. His Interpol windbreaker clean and zipped to the neck.</context>
      <utterance>Turn it on its side.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The Customs Boat ominously circles the freighter like a hungry shark.</context>
      <utterance>They say every man has his price - but not every man gets it. Interpol Agent, Jack Valentine, couldn't be bought, at least not with money. For Jack, glory was the prize.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not exactly "The Love Boat". Another AGENT hands him a phone. VALENTINE   It's clean?...It doesn't look clean. I'm boarding.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, pay before you play.</utterance>
   <speaker>NARC LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Leader smashes the box on the concrete - bullets spilling everywhere.</context>
      <utterance>You're late.</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, fuck you!</utterance>
   <speaker>NARC LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri tries to play peacemaker.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you!</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Narc Leader turns and shoots Yuri in the side. Yuri shudders with the impact. The enraged Vitaly lunges towards the Leader but Yuri, despite his wound, holds him back. YURI (cont'd) No, Vit. No. (to the Leader, referring to the bullets) Help yourselves. Free sample. Vitaly nurses Yuri to the ground. The GUERRILLAS ignore them, frantically re-load just in time, immediately start shooting at the approaching government vehicle. The government vehicle throws a vicious 180, almost toppling over. The Guerillas, now back in business, take off after the government troops. Yuri lies on the dock, genuinely surprised by the sight of his own blood.</context>
      <utterance>No, you don't fuck him--</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The first and most important rule of gunrunning is never get shot with your own merchandise.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The second rule is always ensure you have a foolproof way to get paid. Credit card, check, cash. Preferably in advance, ideally to an off-shore account. It's why I choose my customers so carefully. Say what you like about warlords and dictators, they tend to have a highly developed sense of order. They always pay their bills on time. The Narc Leader nods his approval.</utterance>
   <speaker>NARC LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I apologize for earlier.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WORKERS start loading the crates into a truck. The Narc Leader hands Yuri the suitcase.</context>
      <utterance>I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>NARC LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri snaps open the suitcase - inside six kilos of cocaine.</context>
      <utterance>It's all there.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>NARC LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six keys of pure.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't hand this to my fucking bank teller at Chase Manhattan.</utterance>
   <speaker>NARC LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should be thanking me.  Have you checked the street price today? With the seizures at the border last week, it's jumped thirty percent.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I sell guns. I don't sell drugs.</utterance>
   <speaker>NARC LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Narc Leader walks away.</context>
      <utterance>Diversify.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Narc Leader ignores him, climbs in his Jeep and drives off. The truck, loaded with munitions, also exits. Yuri and Vitaly are left alone in their warehouse.</context>
      <utterance>I've got standards.</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri shrugs, slices open one of the packs of cocaine. He takes a bill from his pocket, rolls it into a tube. He goes to hand Vitaly the tube but his brother has already rolled his own. Vitaly dips his tube into the coke - snorts, keeps snorting - a longer inhale than should be possible for a human being.</context>
      <utterance>Now what?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I found Vitaly twelve days, two thousand miles and 150 grams later in a Bolivian boarding house.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>Vitaly, absorbed with the task at hand, appears not to notice. Yuri breaks in the door.</context>
      <utterance>Vitaly! Open this fucking door!</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri stares at the cocaine map.</context>
      <utterance>Yuri!  It's my brother, Yuri. He's my big brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ukraine.  I start in Odessa, work my way to the Crimea--</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vitaly freaks out, slams the window so hard it shatters. (The Hookers still don't rouse.) VITALY (cant'd) You fucking fuck! Vitaly desperately tries to snort the cocaine out of the shag pile carpet - the straw constantly clogging with carpet fibers. Blood oozes from Vitaly's nostril. Yuri gazes down at his pathetic brother.</context>
      <utterance>You fuck!</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get out of the car. Vitaly doesn't budge. YURI  I promised our parents.</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vitaly, you're going to have a good time. This is a top place. Two Ford models checked in last week and that cute weather girl's been here since July.</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri relents, pours a gram onto the dashboard. Vitaly snorts it off the dash.</context>
      <utterance>Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two ORDERLIES open the car door, escort Vitaly away. Yuri watches his brother in the rearview mirror - shepherded up the path.</context>
      <utterance>You're a good brother. Vitaly kisses Yuri.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never understood what separated the recreational drug user from the habitual, the functional addict from the dysfunctional. But for the grace of God, it could have been me snorting lines as long as the Belt Parkway.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vitaly never got completely clean despite the prayers of my mother...</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and father. In fact, my younger brother was the only reason my father ever had to question his new religion.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>He exchanges a collegial smile with YURI who has similar entrepreneurial paraphernalia in front of him.</context>
      <utterance>After Colombia I became a one-man-operation. A sole proprietor as you say on your tax return - that is if you're foolish enough to fill one out.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The businessman's smile dissolves when he catches a glance at the brochure lying next to Yuri's "Day-Runner" - glossy photos of</context>
      <utterance>By then I'd mastered my craft. Selling arms is not so different to selling vacuum cleaners. You advertise, pound the pavement, take orders.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course, a good arms dealer also has to be a political scientist. I go by a seven-step approach. YURI gets off a plane.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>YURI immediately picks up a newspaper, eager for the latest news.</context>
      <utterance>One: identity a government and an opposition where the opposition is ignored.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>YURI is buoyed by the front page news, over-tips the NEWSPAPER</context>
      <utterance>Two: Wait for a radical group to break away from the opposition.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>YURI meets a group of REVOLUTIONARIES in a backstreet bar, shows them an arms catalogue.</context>
      <utterance>Three: Immediately approach the radical group and offer them arms.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>YURI meets a GOVERNMENT OFFICIAL in the parliament buildings, shows him the same catalogue.</context>
      <utterance>Four: Whether they buy or not, inform the government that the radical group approached you and offer the government arms.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>YURI meets the REVOLUTIONARIES a second time in the same bar - this time they are more enthusiastic and Yuri has his calculator out.</context>
      <utterance>Five: Whether they buy or not, re-approach the radical group and offer them more arms but now at a higher price. Increasing tension is a means of generating demand and the ideal situation is to sell to both sides.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>YURI, now accompanied by bodyguards, is escorted into the government buildings, where he's given a fat envelope. Back at the bar, YURI is given an even fatter envelope.</context>
      <utterance>Six: If they start shooting at each other, the escalation is underway.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>YURI stands at his hotel window, sneaking a look through grimy venetian blinds. A street battle is taking place. However, in Yuri's mind the sound of the gunshots is gradually replaced by the sound ot a cash register. Each time a gun is fired, the register rings. Yuri shuts the window.</context>
      <utterance>They are consuming small arms and ammunition and the cash register is well and truly ringing.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Yuri boards a plane, taking off for a new conflict zone.</context>
      <utterance>Seven: Don't forget that the success of a radical group in one country can inspire a radical group in a neighboring country.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The product? Er,...Colt .45.  The beer.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It cost me twenty for the fake booking, another twelve to buy out the hotel. You can't force someone to tall in love with you but you can sure make ita damn sight easier.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Popular hotel, huh? Yuri smiles. Ava approaches, extends a hand. AVA  Ava Cordova.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yuri Orlov. What brings you to St. Barts?</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A photo shoot. At least, that was the plan. But the photographer's plane got stuck in Miami. Hurricane - though there was nothing in the news.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those things can come out of nowhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The job's cancelled and there's no flight back to New York 'til Tuesday. Yuri pretends to ponder her predicament.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ava regards him cautiously - likes what she sees. YURI (cont'd) (picking up his own camera) In the meantime, why don't I take your picture? Ava smiles, poses playfully for him.</context>
      <utterance>You can hitch a ride with me if you like.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In my experience some of the most successful relationships are founded on lies and deceit. Since that's where they usually end up anyway, it's a logical place to start.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>CLOSE ON the tail of the jet - the name "ORLOV AIR".</context>
      <utterance>I nearly went broke trying to convince her I was anything but. I knew Ava was not the kind of woman to be seduced by a ride in a private jet unless you owned the jet.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is your plane?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They enter the plane.</context>
      <utterance>That is my name.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>As the plane picks up speed on the runway, the name "ORLOV" smears.</context>
      <utterance>Of course I was lying. The plane was a rental, like the car and even the suit I was standing in. At the last minute, I bribed the crew for the paint-job.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luckily, by the time we landed, Ava wasn't looking anywhere but in my eyes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had no idea. He hands her back the magazine. YURI  I'm sorry I didn't recognize you. You must think me very rude.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't apologize. I put on clothes for a living.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least you aren't taking them off.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would be if half the photographers had their way.  But I can't complain. I'm paid to say, "Cheese".  What about you?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing so glamorous. I'm in transport - international air freight mostly.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, like UPS or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Business is good.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both drink. A thought occurs to Ava.</context>
      <utterance>Like you, I can't complain.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But if you did?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's just that I travel all around the world but I can't help feeling sometimes that I'm going nowhere. Ava regards him closely. He's echoed her thoughts. Yuri pours Ava another drink. YURI (cont'd) Here's to... (raising his glass) ...a hurricane. They toast. YURI (cont'd) Without it, I'd never have met you. She meets his eye.</context>
      <utterance>Well...I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is no accident, is it, Yuri? Yuri freezes - doesn't answer. AVA  It feels like fate.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe in fate.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri gazes at her a moment - he answers her question with a kiss. Ava does not pull away.</context>
      <utterance>What do you believe in?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>As the happy couple reaches the limousine, VITALY - out of rehab and out of his mind - fires an AK-47 into the air as a salute. The GUESTS drop to the ground - the only ones left standing are Yuri and Vitaly. Yuri stares daggers at Vitaly, helps Ava to her feet.</context>
      <utterance>We married in a synagogue to make my father happy. In the eyes of my Catholic mother, it was worse than living in sin. Yuri and Ava kiss his parents, ANATOLY and IRINA.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's traditional.</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Traditional. The guests nod, uncertain. YURI  One more time, Vitaly. Vitaly lets go another burst. YURI   I'm sorry. I should have said something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANATOLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Always remember, son, there's something above you.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Irina takes Anatoly's arm, they walk away. Yuri, alone for a moment, opens the package - a small Roman Catholic Bible, conveniently bookmarked at the Ten Commandments.</context>
      <utterance>You need this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A family Christmas - Anatoly, Irina and Ava open gifts. Baby Nicolai wriggles on a blanket, trying to reach a piece of tinsel.</context>
      <utterance>I was still living way beyond my means, mortgaged to the hilt, using one credit card to payoff another. Anything to keep Ava in the style to which she had, thanks largely to me, become accustomed. Then suddenly all my Christmases came at once.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANATOLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Irina ignores him. She regards a gift - a silver goblet set from Tiffany's.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus was Jewish. You're worshipping a Jew.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ava, this is too much.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicolai crawls an inch. AVA beams proudly.</context>
      <utterance>Yuri likes to spoil you.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nicki! You did it. Good boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANATOLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ava looks around for Yuri.</context>
      <utterance>That's my grandson.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>Ava scoops up the baby. With Anatoly and Irina, they go to investigate. On the television, MIKHAIL GORBACHEV, is making his famous speech, officially ending the Cold War. Yuri kneels in front of the TV as if it is an altar.</context>
      <utterance>Tak! Tak! Tak-fucking-tak!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANATOLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's over! It's over!</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's over?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri kisses Ava, Nicolai, Anatoly, Irina, kisses the TV.</context>
      <utterance>The Cold War, the Soviet Union, the Evil Empire. Mikhail's saying "no mas". He's throwing in the towel. It's over.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gazes at the TV, revelling in the plan taking shape in his head.</context>
      <utterance>That's nice.  Your son is crawling. Yuri's too busy kissing Gorbachev's birthmark.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ANATOLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least there'll be religious freedom.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I'll go back for a visit.  Do you stay in touch with Uncle Dmitri?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANATOLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dmitri Volkoff? Now and then.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANATOLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The luckiest man alive. You know he was one of the first men at Chernobyl. Off-duty, at his daughter's wedding, he was roaring drunk. He was the only one who survived. Later they found that alcohol in your blood resists radiation.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's still a General in the army?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANATOLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Major General. He got promoted. Two of his rivals were also there that day. I told you - he's the luckiest man alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri goes to pour himself a drink. Anatoly grabs his son's hand the way he did many years earlier.</context>
      <utterance>He may be luckier than you think.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANATOLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A crash. VITALY and a call-girl, ANGEL, dressed in a low-cut fairy dress, stumble through the front door - both the worse for drink and drugs.</context>
      <utterance>It's not kosher.</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angel laughs. The family gazes at Vitaly and his friend, appalled.</context>
      <utterance>Merry fucking Christmas!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANATOLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vitaly, who is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Angel.</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri firmly escorts Angel to the door and pays her off.</context>
      <utterance>Her name really is Angel. She's a fairy.  Let's stick her on top of the Christmas tree. Vitaly and Angel laugh. No one else does. Vitaly collapses on the floor. Nicolai cries. VITALY   I love you all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vitaly snorts it off the dash.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going back to Ukraine.</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I miss Odessa. I miss you.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two ORDERLIES open the car door, escort Vitaly away. Yuri stares after Vitaly.</context>
      <utterance>I miss you too. Vitaly kisses Yuri. VITALY   Be careful, Yuri. Those things you sell, kill...  ...inside.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>He produces several passports from the locker, shuffles the passports like playing cards.</context>
      <utterance>There's no problem leading a double life. It's the triple and quadruple lives that get you in the end.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Back then I carried a French, British, Israeli and Ukrainian passport and a student visa for the U.S., but that's another story. The locker also contains five identical briefcases - presumably he can tell them apart.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I also packed five different briefcases depending on the region of the world I was visiting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The end of the Cold War was the beginning of the hottest time in arms dealing. The Wall had fallen. The arms bazaar was open. Those forty-five years had generated the highest weapons build-up in history. The Soviets had tanks and guns coming out the demon hole - huge stockpiles and now no enemy. A Border Guard approaches Yuri's car window.</utterance>
   <speaker>BORDER GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri hands the Guard his passport. Inside, a credit card emblazoned, "VISA". The guard smiles. BORDER GUARD (cont'd) Cash or check only. Yuri smiles, hands him several U.S. bills. Yuri's passport is promptly stamped. He is waved past the line of cars.</context>
      <utterance>Visa?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's good to be home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DMITRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The General gives him a great bear hug. Dmitri registers the apprehensive look on Yuri's face. DMITRI (cont'd) What? Did you think I'd be glowing? Don't worry. You can't catch it. Yuri kisses Dmitri on the cheek to reassure him. Over his shoulder, Dmitri notices the car.</context>
      <utterance>Nephew, come here and hug the luckiest man alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>DMITRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the SLK?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dmitri is impressed.</context>
      <utterance>0 - 60 in 4.8.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DMITRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't just sell you government property, Yuri. I have to report--</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--Report to who? Moscow? As of last week Moscow is in a foreign country.</utterance>
   <speaker>DMITRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>New flag, new boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dmitri hesitates, knocks back his vodka, then opens the safe - produces a document.</context>
      <utterance>There is no new boss yet. They're too busy squabbling over who gets the presidential holiday home at the Black Sea. Dmitri can't deny it. YURI   It's beautiful. The ones who know don't care any more. The ones who care don't know.  Show me your inventory.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that a "4"? It doesn't look like a "4" to me. It looks more like a "1".</utterance>
   <speaker>DMITRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's a "4".</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is too much for Dmitri. He stops, confronts Yuri - takes back the AK-47 Yuri is inspecting.</context>
      <utterance>It's whatever we say it is because no one else knows the difference. Dmitri finally gets it. Yuri examines a Kalashnikov. YURI  10,000 Kalashnikovs for a battalion. Your stocks are dangerously depleted, Dmitri. You should order more from the factory.</utterance>
   <speaker>DMITRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone will work this out, Yuri. What happens then?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll cut them in. Anyway, what could happen - you're the luckiest man alive.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>DMITRI puts on his cap, about to investigate. YURI stops him.</context>
      <utterance>Of course my idea was not entirely unique. I had rivals. Simeon angrily confronts the SOLDIER at the gate.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dmitri shrugs and complies. Yuri strides towards the gate.</context>
      <utterance>He's a friend of mine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SIMEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know who the fuck I am?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the fuck cares who the fuck you are?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I demand to see your commanding officer.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simeon reconsiders his position.</context>
      <utterance>You don't demand shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just give me back my papers.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Officer turns on his heel and returns to his guard station with the passport, starts watching TV. The Bodyguards make to follow but the Soldiers close ranks, barring their path. Simeon fumes.</context>
      <utterance>What papers?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>YURI breezes past the Soldiers with an easy familiarity. He enters the guard station as if he owns it. From beside his car, Simeon watches as Yuri jovially discusses the situation with the Young Officer. After a moment Yuri slips the Officer money in exchange for Simeon's passport. Yuri emerges from the station and returns the passport to the veteran gunrunner. YURI (cont'd) I invited you for a drink once before. Perhaps now you will accept my invitation.</context>
      <utterance>You're late, Simeon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BARMAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sell guns?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simeon is clearly disquieted by the change in the balance of power or maybe it's the bad early-nineties pop music. His BODYGUARDS sit at the table behind.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe you'd like to come to my room and see my bazooka. The Barmaid giggles and exits.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look a little lost, Simeon. Is the world changing too fast?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am here, aren't I?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simeon shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Not all of you, I think. Simeon's look begs explanation. YURI  You've gotten so rich selling for the CIA, you can't get that ideology completely out of your head. The empire was evil for too long.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't deny, it takes some getting used to. Last week we were trying to beat their brains in and now we're going into business together.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simeon regards the young man with a mixture of fear and admiration pours himself another drink.</context>
      <utterance>There's no place in gunrunning for politics anymore, Simeon. I sell to leftists, rightists. I'd sell to pacifists but they're not the most regular of customers. Yuri leans forward. YURI  Of course, you're not a true internationalist until you've supplied weapons to kill your own countrymen.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri smiles - the proposal is the victory he has been seeking.</context>
      <utterance>I understand you have Ukraine in your pocket but there are the other satellite states. Bulgaria, Hungary, Poland, Belarus. Instead of cutting each other's throats, it may be more profitable to work together. What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you are the amateur now. I think you suffer from a philosophical disadvantage - you have a philosophy. I think you should go with your instincts - your first instinct. Simeon is confused. YURI  I am the same man who was not good enough for you before. I am not good enough for you now. Simeon blanches. Yuri gets up. Simeon holds his rival's arm.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The problem with gunrunners going to war is there's no shortage of ammunition. Yuri departs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>DMITRI, flask in hand, and YURI are given a tour of the surplus hardware by one of Dmitri's brother officers.</context>
      <utterance>Helicopters, torpedo boats, armored personnel carriers, whole tank divisions.</utterance>
   <speaker>UKRAINE MAJOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--I'll tell you what I'll do. Buy six, you get one free.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about tech support?</utterance>
   <speaker>UKRAINE MAJOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri and Dmitri come upon an oily-faced BOY, perched on the cockpit of a helicopter gunship - he wears an ill-fitting uniform, several sizes too big.</context>
      <utterance>No problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son, get off there before you get hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>UKRAINE MAJOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's the tech support.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's twelve.</utterance>
   <speaker>UKRAINE MAJOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirteen. Almost fourteen.</utterance>
   <speaker>DMITRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kids grow up fast around here.</utterance>
   <speaker>UKRAINE MAJOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri shrugs, shakes the Major's hand.</context>
      <utterance>He can take it apart in his sleep.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>YURI, on his belly to avoid detection, slithers back to the roadway - hands the binoculars to a YOUNG SOLDIER. DMITRI stands beside the convoy of trucks parked barely out of view of the checkpoint, including Yuri's Mercedes and a huge open-bed tractor-trailer carrying a Russian Hind helicopter gunship. YURI (cont'd) (angrily to Dmitri) I thought we were supposed to be watching for these checkpoints.</context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DMITRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can I? You keep selling my helicopters. You're too greedy, Yuri.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dmitri regards the trucks, each one longer than the road is wide.</context>
      <utterance>We have to go back.</utterance>
   <speaker>DMITRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll be going in reverse. We can't turn around for a mile. The YOUNG SOLDIER on lookout calls to them.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri grabs the binoculars. Sure enough, Valentine and his agents are climbing into their Interpol Jeeps and driving towards them.</context>
      <utterance>They're coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>DMITRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We shoot it out?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And start an international fucking incident - no, no, no.</utterance>
   <speaker>DMITRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So we run.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I've got paperwork.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri turns to the Boy referred to as "tech support". YURI (cant' d) Get to work, Son. The boy pulls a wrench from his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>It's not a military helicopter. It's a rescue helicopter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In reply, an Interpol Agent unceremoniously slams Yuri into the side of his truck.</context>
      <utterance>Yuri Orlov.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again Yuri waves off Dmitri and his men, about to come to his aid. Yuri courteously hands over his passport and other documentation to the skeptical Valentine. VALENTINE (cont'd) (regarding the photo closely) Mr. Orlov, always in the wrong place at the right time. We've met before. Off the coast of Colombia. (feigning memory loss) What was the name of that freighter - I can't remember. Was it the Kono or the Kristol?</context>
      <utterance>Papers.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The end-user certificate for this aircraft states Burkina Faso. Nice. Did you type it yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's for humanitarian missions.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a humanitarian? Yuri shrugs - why not? VALENTINE   This is a killing machine.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not any more.</utterance>
   <speaker>DMITRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's true. Yuri has had the armaments detached.</context>
      <utterance>Listen to the nephew.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't you get the memo? The war's over. What can they do with military hardware but convert to civilian use?</utterance>
   <speaker>DMITRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Also going to Burkina Faso?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valentine, incensed, throws Yuri up against the truck himself.</context>
      <utterance>But to a different client at a different address.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you take me for? A complete fucking fool?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not complete, Sir. And while I hesitate to tell you your job, I must point out that when shipped separately the weapons and the aircraft both comply with the current Interpol trade standards and practices.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You expect me to believe this is a coincidence?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valentine regards Yuri closely - this foe is more formidable than he imagined. Valentine looks to the gun in his hand, contemplating crossing the line. He finally holsters his gun.</context>
      <utterance>I can see how certain people might interpret it as suspicious but thank God we live in a world where suspicion alone does not constitute a crime.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yuri Orlov. You and I are going to be seeing a lot of each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can hardly wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri looks to the boy, askance - a Yuri in the making.</context>
      <utterance>What an asshole.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was he doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dmitri's face lights up. Yuri hands him the keys to the SKL.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. There're more VCR's. I left them in your new car.</utterance>
   <speaker>DMITRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dmitri hands his hip flask to Yuri. Yuri watches Dmitri walk to the car and climb in for a test drive. A look of realization on Yuri's face.</context>
      <utterance>Even your enemy was admiring that car. I am the luckiest man alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The car erupts as if it has been punched by a fist beneath the earth. Recovered from the blast, Yuri runs up to the burning car but is beaten back by the flames.</context>
      <utterance>Dmit--!!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We cut between the two sides of the conversation.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I'll accept the charges.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ava--</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, baby.  You forgotten what time it is?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. I, er...  How was your audition?</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're going in another direction. The direction of someone who can act.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't say that. You're good.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ava grabs her robe - goes to the balcony so as not to disturb Nicolai.</context>
      <utterance>And you're biased.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you? Is everything okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rough day at the office.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come home. We miss you.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soon.  How's Nicki?</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From a bar down the street comes the sound of gunfire - MOBSTERS firing at other MOBSTERS escaping in a car. Yuri tries to cover the phone but Ava overhears. AVA (cont'd) Yuri, what's that?</context>
      <utterance>Asleep in our bed. It's lonely without you.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A party.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More gunfire interrupts.</context>
      <utterance>It's always a party where you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd better go. I just wanted to call--hear your voice. Kiss Nicki for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Yuri has gone.</context>
      <utterance>I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In Ukraine since 1992, $32 billion worth of arms have been stolen and re-sold. One of the greatest heists of the 20th Century.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Continental convertible comes flying around a corner - stereo blaring, deliberately terrorizing the locals on the dock. The car slides to a stop beside Yuri. It contains ANDRE BAPTISTE JNR., a handsome young man with sunglasses, a mirror for an earring and a facial tattoo. Also in the car, two BODYGUARDS and a pair of LIBERIAN TEENAGE GIRLS dressed in Dallas Cowboy cheerleader uniforms.</context>
      <utterance>My best customer was self-declared president of Liberia, Andre Baptiste. Even though we'd met before, I was in no hurry to meet him again. He'd gotten a reputation for routinely hacking off the limbs of those who opposed him. His seven-year civil war has been described as "a relentless campaign of sadistic, wanton violence unimaginable to those unfamiliar with the details of man's capacity to visit the abyss." That kind of sums up Andy for me. As the final truck door is secured, a customized Lincoln</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE JNR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Yuri, I am Andre Baptiste Junior. My father would like to meet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank him but I have other business. A busy schedule.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE JNR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri ponders for a moment. The machete in the Bodyguard's hand makes up his mind.</context>
      <utterance>It is not optional. My father is easily offended.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A bodyguard takes Yuri's suitcase. Yuri is barely in the car before it screeches away. As the car roars along the highway on the edge of control, we hear Yuri's thoughts.</context>
      <utterance>What do you know? My schedule just freed up.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Andre announces his arrival in the main street of Monrovia with a burst of gunfire. The city, a violent clash of cultures. Goats and Gucci.</context>
      <utterance>But if I thought I was scared of Andre Senior, I knew I was scared of Andre Junior. Like father, like son. The guava doesn't fall too far from the tree. He was a heavy- drinker, a womanizer with a penchant for cheerleaders and a lover of fast American automobiles which he drove recklessly and with total impunity around the streets of the capital. Oh yes, he was also a cannibal. They say Andre would eat a victim's heart while it was still beating to give him superhuman strength. I could've told him he'd get the same effect from a pastrami sandwich at Carnegie's Deli.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The car pulls up to Monrovia's premier hotel. A DEAD BODY on the ground attracts no attention whatsoever.</context>
      <utterance>Monrovia itself was like being on another planet. Planet Monrovia. From the temperature it was obviously a planet close to the sun. I rarely saw another white man even at my hotel that was soon dubbed the "Little Kremlin". And I never left town alone. Outside town, was the edge of hell. I didn't want to even gaze into it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE JNR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A PORTER, carrying Yuri's suitcase, steps over the dead body. ANDRE JNR. (cont'd) (to Yuri) Can you bring me the gun of Rambo?</context>
      <utterance>This is your hotel.  Two stars.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Part One, Two or Three?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE JNR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have only seen Part One.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The M60. You want the attachable grenade launcher?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE JNR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri nods, uncertainly.</context>
      <utterance>Please. And the armor piercing bullets.  I will be back to get you in an hour...or two. It's Liberia.  We left a welcoming present in your room.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOTEL PORTER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God, he nearly cut off her head.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the most AIDS infested region of the globe, where one in four is infected, Andre's idea of a joke was to put a young Iman and a young Naomi naked in my bed and no condom within a hundred miles.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Mr. Yuri.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two goddesses drape themselves around him.</context>
      <utterance>We'd be happy to make you happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, we don't have anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do we look like it?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gloria's lips gently touch his.</context>
      <utterance>What if I have AIDS? Don't you worry?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Faith begins to unbutton his shirt.</context>
      <utterance>You worry too much.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With great reluctance Yuri reaches behind him and opens the door.</context>
      <utterance>How can we make you happy?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By leaving.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BAPTISTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri, staring down the barrel of the Beretta, recovers fast.</context>
      <utterance>What did you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baptiste is taken aback. He suddenly bursts into laughter.</context>
      <utterance>Now you're going to have to buy it.  It's a used gun. I can't sell a used gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAPTISTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other Officers laugh uncertainly. The Lieutenant's body is dragged out - leaving a smear of blood across the marble floor. Baptiste, seemingly oblivious to the carnage he's wreaked, resumes talking to Yuri, in a measured way as if he's discussing the sad state of punctuality in contemporary society. BAPTISTE (cant'd) (confiding in Yuri) There's no discipline with the young boys. I try to set an example but it's difficult. I blame the MTV. Yuri nods, disguising his terror. Baptiste, checking his Rolex Oyster, rises from his desk. BAPTISTE (cont'd) Let me show you something.</context>
      <utterance>A used gun. That's a good one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>ANDRE BAPTISTE haggles with YURI as he inspects his troops ranging from twelve to fourteen. Yuri, averts his eyes from the boys, uncomfortable reviewing soldiers a head shorter than he. OLDER SOLDIERS fill the ranks behind.</context>
      <utterance>I had heard of the "Boy Brigades", "Small Boy Units", "Kalashnikov Kids". The theory was that a bullet coming from a fourteen year old is just as effective as one trom a forty year old.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAPTISTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't pay your asking price, Yuri. We are not a rich people and the market is already flooded with your Kalashnikovs. In some places you can buy one for the price of a chicken.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't just look at the unit price. You forget the ancillary costs. End user certificates need to be forged and notarized, shell companies set up, insurance purchased, pilots and crews hired. Not to mention the bribes. You can't get a nut and bolt out of the Eastern bloc without a bribe. There's one bribe for the nut. Another for the bolt. This is an expensive proposition. Andre interrogates Yuri's eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAPTISTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baptiste produces a handful of uncut diamonds from his pocket. Yuri's eyes widen at the sight of the very precious stones.</context>
      <utterance>I pay in timber...or stones.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andre smiles. He turns to his new Lieutenant.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take the stones. It's hard to get a tree trunk in my hand luggage.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAPTISTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very professional, Lieutenant.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri and Andre watch the troops disperse.</context>
      <utterance>Dismissed!</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andre nods, grateful for the free tactical advice - regards Yuri in a new light.</context>
      <utterance>I know you're planning a new offensive. If you delay a week I can get you the armored personnel carriers we talked about. They would give you a significant strategic advantage.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAPTISTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They say I am the lord of war. But perhaps it is you.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not "lord of war". It's "warlord".</utterance>
   <speaker>BAPTISTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andre smiles again. They are going to be fast friends. He leaves Yuri alone to examine his uncut diamonds in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>I like it my way.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Diamonds are far less bulky than hundred- dollar bills. You can get a million dollars into a cigarette box.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri and Vitaly greet each other with a nod.</context>
      <utterance>Yuri, I just got off the phone with the dealer. I sold my first painting.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fantastic. Who bought it?</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone important. They want to remain anonymous.  How was your trip?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know. Same old, same old.  Where's Nicki, in bed?</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. Poor darling. He tried to stay up.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll kiss him goodnight.</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This calls for a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What doesn't?</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He watches Ava showing off more of her paintings to Vitaly and the latest girlfriend.</context>
      <utterance>My first painting. I'm officially an artist!</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I figured I was a patron of the arts and of everything else Ava had tried and failed at after modelling. Acting, her own cosmetics line. I didn't sabotage her careers but I can't deny it was convenient for me in maintaining a low profile. She was a beautiful bird in a gilded cage.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you, brother?</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, still the resident family fuck-up.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They watch Ava in the living room sharing a joke with Vitaly's girlfriend.</context>
      <utterance>Someone has to do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She knows, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't talk about it. Vitaly looks askance. YURI   How many car salesmen talk about their work, how many executives at cigarette companies? And both of their products kill more people every year than mine. At least mine has a safety switch. If those guys can leave their work at the office, why can't I?</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit, you're good. You almost had me convinced.  We're going, baby.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ava grins, goes to drink when she notices two huge diamond earrings laying at the bottom of the glass.</context>
      <utterance>To Manet, Monet...and Ava Cordova.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yuri!</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The trip went better than expected.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yuri, they're beautiful.  But what am I going to wear them with?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They kiss.</context>
      <utterance>I know just the outfit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>In the cockpit, an American PILOT and CO-PILOT keep an idle watch on their instruments as they fly over the endless plains of Sierra Leone. YURI sits in the jump-seat, reading the Wall Street Journal.</context>
      <utterance>I was now the best merchant of death alive. I didn't own my own plane. I owned a fleet - running guns into Liberia, Sierra Leone or the Ivory Coast at least once a week. Unfortunately, my friends at Interpol were also starting to find West Africa on the map. Most trips I had phoney paperwork. If the deadline was tight, I had no paperwork at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--Even taking into consideration the pay-off to the parents, a week with a girl in Burkina Faso is cheaper than a night with a girl in Jersey.</utterance>
   <speaker>CO-PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Plus, they're cleaner--</utterance>
   <speaker>PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--and a lot of them speak better English.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>The Pilot picks up the radio, looks to Yuri. Yuri shakes his head, dialling his satellite phone. Yuri's call is answered.</context>
      <utterance>--Charlie, Echo, India. Descend for landing on heading zero...two...nine.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Colonel Southern, it's Yuri. Sorry to call you on this number but I've got an Interpol jet and-- The jet outside the window falls back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>COL. SOUTHERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Southern hangs up.</context>
      <utterance>I can't know you right now. It's not a good time.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly machine gun fire strafes the Ilyushin - bullets tearing through the fuselage, perilously close to Yurirs very combustible cargo.</context>
      <utterance>Not a good time!</utterance>
   <speaker>CO-PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The jet appears again at the window.</context>
      <utterance>Motherfucker!</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That was your last warning.</context>
      <utterance>--Charlie, Echo, India. Comply immediately.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where was the first fucking warning?!</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rock your wings if you intend to comply.</utterance>
   <speaker>PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm putting us down.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You land and we're all going away! I don't have paperwork!</utterance>
   <speaker>PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're in a flying fucking bomb! They're firing bullets at our bullets! Forget about going away! They shoot again, we're going away for good! I'm putting us down.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pilot responds on the radio.</context>
      <utterance>Okay! Okay!--Fuck!!</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not the airport. There. The highway. It's our only fucking hope.</utterance>
   <speaker>PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A pothole could set us off.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pilot doesn't buy it but reluctantly changes course anyway.</context>
      <utterance>Don't underestimate yourself. You're the best, Tony.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INTERPOL PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't land there.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He can't get far. I want a truck waiting on the tarmac.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The PILOTS are already halfway out of the plane door, grabbing supplies as they go. YURI (cont'd) (calling out from the window) Where are you going?</context>
      <utterance>We're going to be okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pilots start running down the highway.</context>
      <utterance>As far from the evidence as I can.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>YURI is left alone. He turns a lever marked, "CARGO BAY".</context>
      <utterance>Wait, you idiots! There's not going to be any evidence! Stay with the plane! The pilots ignore him - run for their lives.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri sees the pilot seats being stolen.</context>
      <utterance>What a fucking disaster.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Glancing up the highway, Yuri sees an approaching cloud of dust - VALENTINE and two truckfuls of heavily-armed Interpol Agents. Too late. The last of the guns and ammunition are being carted away on the back of a thin cow. Valentine's truck fishtails to a halt beside the stripped plane. Valentine is first off the trucks and into the plane's cargo bay - empty. Other INTERPOL AGENTS fan out - futilely questioning locals. Miraculously the weapons have vanished into the bush. Valentine calls out to the last fleeing local - a BOY with a lifevest.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, not those! You don't touch the plane!  Not the fucking seats...</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy stares back, defiantly inflates the life preserver. VALENTINE (cont'd) (exasperated) Forget it. The entire cargo has gone. An errant bullet falls off a shelf in the plane and rolls down the floor - Valentine picks it up. YURI sits innocently on his soda crate. A frustrated African Interpol Agent, MBIZI, wound-up by the chase, rushes Yuri - slams him to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, you!</utterance>
   <speaker>MBIZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valentine rushes over, pulls Mbizi off Yuri.</context>
      <utterance>You run from us.  Can you run with no legs?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valentine drags Mbizi out of Yuri's earshot. Mbizi still wants a piece of Yuri - Valentine preventing him getting to the gunrunner.</context>
      <utterance>No, Mbizi. No, no, no.</utterance>
   <speaker>MBIZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me disappear him, Mr. Valentine. He is a devil. Let me disappear him.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MBIZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look where we are. Who will know?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mbizi stops struggling against Valentine.</context>
      <utterance>We will.</utterance>
   <speaker>MBIZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turn your back, Mr. Valentine. I will go to hell to stop him.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mbizi and another Agent reluctantly head off in a truck. Valentine returns to Yuri who is dusting himself off. Valentine handcuffs Yuri himself, picks up the soda crate and sits Yuri back on it. VALENTINE (cont'd) I've spent my whole career on the right side of the line. You're the first man I've encountered who makes me seriously consider crossing it.</context>
      <utterance>No.  Find the pilots.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the charge?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing in Sierra Leone?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm on safari.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shooting wildebeests with submachine guns?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you with the park service? Hunting without a license - is that the charge?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're trafficking arms.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trading. But without evidence who can say?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri remains handcuffed, sitting on the soda crate - dwarfed by the cargo plane. Valentine paces beside him. VALENTINE (cont'd) (ignoring him) There are more prestigious assignments, you know. Keeping track of the nuclear arsenals. You would think it more critical to world security. It's not. Nine out of ten war victims today are killed by assault rifles and other small arms - like yours. Those missiles just sit in their silos. Your AK-47 - it's the real weapon of mass destruction. Yuri regards his interrogator curiously. Despite the sun beating down, he feels obliged to give him his version of the facts of life.</context>
      <utterance>Trade or traffic, you make a fortune by keeping the poorest people on the planet killing each other.  Do you know why I do what I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He regards Valentine with something approaching pity. YURI (cont'd) I realize the unspeakable things that are done with my weapons. I also understand the unspeakable things that are done with Williams Sonoma carving knives and Wilson baseball bats and they aren't taking those off the market any time soon. People will always buy guns. Why not mine? Valentine appears to have no answer. YURI (cont'd) Can I go? You've got nothing on me-- (unable to resist) --but cuffs. Now Valentine smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want people dead, Agent Valentine. I admit, a shooting war is better for business. But I'd prefer people to fire my guns and miss. Just as long as they're firing.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see time lapse photography of Yuri waiting out his twenty-four hours, under armed guard on the highway - stretching his legs, eating a suspicious-looking sandwich, going to the bathroom, the sun arcing across the sky - all the while his plane is being cannibalized by the locals. Finally the time lapse slows back into real time. Valentine returns in a Jeep with Mbizi and other Agents.</context>
      <utterance>I am legally permitted to hold you for twenty-four hours without charging you. Yuri looks away, knows where this is going. VALENTINE  You may ask, why do I bother to do that? I can assure you, it is not because I enjoy your company. And you may be surprised to learn that it is not for any vindictive motive. No. The reason I delay you for every second of the permissible twenty-four hours, is that I am delaying your deadly trade and the deaths of your victims. I don't think of it as taking a day from you but giving a day to them. Some innocent man, woman or child somewhere has one more day on this earth because you are not free. Valentine looks to his watch. VALENTINE  See you in twenty-three hours and fifty five minutes. Valentine walks away. Yuri is left to ponder the notion.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valentine opens the back of the Jeep. Lying in the back, the bodies of the two PILOTS shot and stripped. VALENTINE (cont'd) The locals got to them before we could. Yuri turns away from the sight. His handcuffs are removed. Returning Yuri's documents, Valentine notices a photo of AVA and NICKI in the wallet. VALENTINE (cont'd) Handsome family. Valentine and the Agents get back in the truck and drive away.</context>
      <utterance>You'll be pleased to know your colleagues were no more co-operative than you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yuri! Yuri Orlov!</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vivian...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know. Fighting the good fight.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An aid program?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, yes. In fact, I've just had some transport problems. You couldn't give me a ride to Monrovia, could you?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri steps back into a vehicle with which he is very familiar. VIVIAN (cant' d) We're pulling out. It's too dangerous. It's a shame. We were really doing some good things. Yuri nods in understanding.</context>
      <utterance>Sure. Climb in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANDRE JNR., a FLUNKY and his CHEERLEADERS appear from behind the door, laughing at his shocked reaction. YURI (cont'd) Andre! What in heaven is he doing here?</context>
      <utterance>Jesus! Simeon!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE JNR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri stares into the old gunrunner's terrified eyes. ANDRE JNR. (cont'd) You got here just in time. I was afraid he would die before you got a chance to kill him. He offers Yuri a Beretta.</context>
      <utterance>A gift for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE JNR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who do you think informed on you - cost you your plane? He came to meet my father, hoping to take your place. Yuri spits on Simeon.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You stupid old fuck!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE JNR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andre again offers Yuri the Beretta.</context>
      <utterance>He killed your man when he tried to kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE JNR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want us to let him go?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andre offers him the gun a third time. Yuri refuses it.</context>
      <utterance>No. No. I...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE JNR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andre grabs Yuri and presses the gun into Yuri's palm, clasping his own hand over Yuri's.</context>
      <utterance>So you do want him dead. You just don't want to kill him yourself? I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE JNR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andre forces Yuri's finger onto the trigger as he aims at the terrified Simeon - eyes pleading. Yuri attempts to pull his hand away but Andre is too strong.</context>
      <utterance>We'll do it together. A bonding experience.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE JNR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri opens his mouth but no word comes. Andre presses Yuri's finger onto the trigger. The gun goes off. A splash of blood across the sofa's green upholstery. The gunshot echoes around the room. Simeon is very dead.</context>
      <utterance>You can stop if you want - but you do. Just say the word. Andre stares at Yuri not Simeon. ANDRE JNR.  Say, "stop".</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andre smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE JNR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll get you another room with a nicer view.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The Barman nods to a patron at a corner table - a SEASONED FIGHTER - no more than eighteen years old.</context>
      <utterance>I started doing a lot of cocaine in West Africa. I wasn't medicating myself. I was simply playing catch-up. I was constantly dealing with people who are chemically imbalanced without the aid of chemicals. It's just a matter of etiquette. It's rude to act sane in a room full of lunatics.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He bought you "brown-brown", Mr. Yuri.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Brown-brown".</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A mixture - cocaine and gunpowder.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does the gunpowder do?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's magic. They give it to the small boys before battle - they do anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some other time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to try it at least once, Mr. Yuri. The Barman starts chopping another line.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going for a walk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't fuck you, did I? Did I fuck you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PROSTITUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The prostitute tosses a couple of bills back to him. Yuri ignores the money, staggers after her.</context>
      <utterance>It's not what I would call a fuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri staggers to his feet - wanders aimlessly across a field.</context>
      <utterance>Are you sick? She ignores him. YURI   Are you sick?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GIRL #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They will!</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They won't!</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They will!</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They won't!</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They will!</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The GIRLS approach Yuri - no older than seven, formal white dresses, hands politely behind their backs.</context>
      <utterance>Ask the foreigner. The foreigner will know.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of the girls shows Yuri a healed stump where her hand should be. Yuri runs away.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, will my fingers grow back?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simeon turns and walks away - revealing a large exit wound in the back of his head. YURI (cont'd) Simeon!! Yuri pokes his head through the hole but Simeon has vanished. Yuri turns back to find himself trapped by TWO MEN in flip-flops, shorts, Gap T-shirts and AK-47's. Through Yuri's eyes the two men look like four. The two/four men go through Yuri's pockets, take his watch, shoes. Yuri is oddly compliant - clumsily helping one of the thieves fasten the watch. One of the men, tired of Yuri's antics, aims his gun at Yuri's head. His colleague stops him.</context>
      <utterance>Simeon.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't. He's Andre's.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck Andre.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man fires at Yuri. The gun jams. Yuri looks almost disappointed. The man tries again. Again the gun jams.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, fuck Andre.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. They don't usually do that. Let me have a look. Maybe I can fix it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man whips the gun across Yuri's face.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck off!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANDRE BAPTISTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yuri, you fucked up! I am going to shoot your face off with your own gun. Yuri doesn't flinch.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man's face falls. The real ANDRE BAPTISTE emerges from the car with</context>
      <utterance>Not bad. Andre's latest double?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ANDRE BAPTISTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's too eloquent.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE BAPTISTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baptiste brandishes a copy of the New York Times.</context>
      <utterance>You have no heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE BAPTISTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE ON the headline, "U.S. SUPREME COURT REVERSES RECOUNT RULING". ANDRE BAPTISTE (cont'd) --now the U.S. must shut up forever. Yuri just smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Have you seen the news? They accuse me of rigging elections, but after this in your Florida with your Supreme Court of kangaroos--</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andre shrugs. He regards the inactivity at the dock.</context>
      <utterance>More good news. That's the last aid shipment. The war is so bad, the U.N. is pulling out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE BAPTISTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why is nothing happening?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE, JNR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No trucks. They are trapped on the front lines.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri gestures down the dock where food is being loaded into trucks marked, "HUMANITARIAN AID" Andre Baptiste and Andre Jnr. are clearly taken with the idea.</context>
      <utterance>There are trucks. You just have to get all that food out of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE JNR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andre Baptiste hands Yuri his payment - a slim briefcase containing a pouch of uncut diamonds.</context>
      <utterance>Killing certain humans can be considered humanitarian.  Isn't that right, Mr. Yuri?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After surviving the last few days I'd started to feel like I was invincible. But there was a weapon that could hurt me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hush, Nicki.  I don't believe you. Valentine is unfazed. AVA  Can you prove any of it? Where is your evidence?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was hoping you could help us with that.  I understand your parents died tragically in EI Salvador.  That regime has startling similarities to several of the regimes supplied by your husband.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valentine rises to leave. Ava holds Nicolai, her mind reeling.</context>
      <utterance>Get out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>YURI, still carrying his suitcase, appears in the doorway. He drops the case.</context>
      <utterance>Ava?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ava, what's wrong? Where's Nicki?</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri senses something very wrong.</context>
      <utterance>He's with your parents.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He finds a robe from the closet - gently places it around her. She pulls it off her shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>Why aren't you dressed? I thought we were going out.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri pulls the robe back onto her shoulders, walks to the window.</context>
      <utterance>I can't wear the clothes. I can't wear the jewelry. I can't drive the car. I can't live in this house. Everything1s got blood on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ava pulls the robe to her, follows Yuri to the window.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be so melodramatic.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course I'm melodramatic. I'm a failed actress, remember? We need to talk about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? We never have before.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri notices the Interpol business card on the bedside table.</context>
      <utterance>Now we do.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These people - you can't trust them--</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--I've talked to your parents. Why do you think they don't want your money? They know where it comes from. We all know. Yuri sighs, resigned.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I sell people a means to defend themselves, Ava. That's all. I don't hold a gun to any one's head and make them shoot--</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--Yuri, I see the news. Sierra Leone--</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--I don't sell machetes.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--What do you think is pointing at the victims when they use those machetes? I see the pictures. Yuri, the guns are bigger than the boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's nothing illegal about what I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri looks away.</context>
      <utterance>I don't care if it's legal, it's wrong. Ava meets his eye. AVA  I can accept the drugs. I can even accept the other women. I can't accept this.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It makes no difference if I stop. Someone will take my place the next day.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let them. We have enough. You're not that little boy in Odessa anymore, lining up for a loaf of bread--</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--It's not about the money.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't answer - perhaps he doesn't have one. Ava looks out of the window at their expensive view. AVA (cont'd) I feel like all I've done my whole life is be pretty. All I've done is be born. I'm not just a failed actress. I'm also a failed writer, failed artist, failed businesswoman. I'm not much good as a mother. Come to think of it, I'm not even that pretty any more. I've failed at everything, Yuri. (turning back to him) But I won't fail as a human being. I'm leaving. The words finally register with Yuri.</context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She interrogates his eyes for the truth.</context>
      <utterance>You can't leave. I'll stop.  I'll stop. Ava is skeptical. He holds her, reassures her. YURI  I've been thinking about it for a while. A lot, lately.  I'm making more from the oil and timber anyhow.  I'll stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will? You promise?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns back and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.  Now get dressed. We'll go out. Ava picks up the dress off the bed. Yuri gazes at her. YURI  By the way, you're wrong about not being pretty any more.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The van door opens to reveal VALENTINE and other INTERPOL AGENTS, wearing headsets, monitoring a scanner device. The agents read porn to keep themselves amused - except Valentine.</context>
      <utterance>For the next month I stopped running guns. I went legitimate.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No wonder Valentine was confused.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>With the cordless phone to his ear, Yuri wanders to the kitchen. He tosses the pendant down a trash chute. Back in the den, Yuri punches a calculator as he continues his phone call.</context>
      <utterance>Thank God there are still legal ways to exploit developing countries.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But the only problem with an honest buck is they're so hard to make. The margins are too low. Too many people are doing it. Finally we are privy to the conversation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ANDRE JNR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--You should come to Liberia with me tomorrow. It is beautiful this time of year.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEENAGE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>YURI, ashen-faced, hurriedly exits the elevator into the ornate lobby - strides up to Andre Snr.</context>
      <utterance>Liberia. Is that on Long Island?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE JNR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yuri!</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck are you doing here, Andre?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE BAPTISTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're here for the peace talks at the U.N.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So at the same time you thought you'd drop in on your arms dealer?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE BAPTISTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that what you still are? You're a hard man to get hold of all of a sudden.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ANDRE BAPTISTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--But now you mention it, we are doing a little shopping while we're here - that is if you open for business.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They've got to be watching.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE BAPTISTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course they blame me. They always blame me. They are on a--</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--hunt for a witch?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE BAPTISTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Witch-hunt". But I have been granted diplomatic immunity due to the escalation in hostilities.  That is why I need you. They are making life difficult to re-supply. It will require a man of your unusual ingenuity.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't help you. I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE JNR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andre Baptiste and his son breeze out of the lobby.</context>
      <utterance>You still haven't brought me the gun of Rambo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was that about the oil or the timber?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri looks to his hand - we rack focus to the uncut diamond. Yuri gets up.</context>
      <utterance>Both. Everything. Ava smiles, carries on reading.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, not even waiting to say goodbye? I'm leaving in ten minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicolai kisses his father.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Nicki has swim practice.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLAI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bye, Papa.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ava kisses Yuri.</context>
      <utterance>See you, big guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Personally, I'm glad you're going. You've been here so long you're starting to get on my nerves.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We'll go somewhere - the sea.</context>
      <utterance>This oil concession should be wrapped up by Thursday. I'll be back for the weekend.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A thought occurs to Yuri.</context>
      <utterance>That would be fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri's turn to interrogate her eyes. Ava smiles.</context>
      <utterance>You trust me, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She looked me directly in the eye the way I've looked in the eyes of a thousand customs officials, government bureaucrats and footsoldiers from every law enforcement agency in the world - and she lied without flinching.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I trust you.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Ava gives Yuri a final kiss, hurries Nicolai out the door.</context>
      <utterance>She'd learned from the best.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>We reveal AVA and NICOLAI in the car. Yuri's car pulls away and Ava's car follows.</context>
      <utterance>That's him.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLAI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are we going, Mama?</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a game.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLAI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like hide and seek?</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Returning to his car, Yuri fails to notice that AVA has witnessed his routine from her own car. Instead of following the car, Ava exits with Nicolai.</context>
      <utterance>I can always sense when I'm being tailed. I know what to look for. But then I'd never been tailed by the woman I love.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Ava looks to Nicolai, tries one more combination, reluctantly. CLOSE ON the numerals on the lock - "10...6..."</context>
      <utterance>I can put myself in Ava's place. She might have understood if the combination was the last four digits of my social, my birthdate, even her birthdate but not Nicolai's.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My son's birthday unlocked what the government would later describe as, "a catalogue of carnage". "90". The lock opens.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ava opens the storage room door - at first struck by the exhibition of her paintings inside the locker. Shaking the image from her head, she turns her attention to the briefcases and other documents. She shuffles through the passports in horror - different photos of Yuri, different names: "George Eagleman", "Georges D'Aigle", etc. Who is her husband? Is he any of them?</context>
      <utterance>Not that. Not that, Yuri.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come to see how the other half lives?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I miss your borscht. Mom and Dad say you're clean.</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You too. They said you went legitimate - hard to believe.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri glances to his parents, ANATOLY and IRINA, at the restaurant counter, folding napkins - observing their two sons. They avert their eyes.</context>
      <utterance>That's because it's not true. Vitaly is hardly surprised.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only you know. I'm leaving tonight - on a job. I want you to come.</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't. I'm thinking of opening my own place.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe this trip will help. It's good money.</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've given my word.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't have to know. We'll tell them we're going for a little "r" and "r".</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you need me all of a sudden?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More than usual. I can't trust anybody. I need someone to watch my back. The notion touches Vitaly. Yuri closes the deal. YURI (cant'd) "Brothers in arms". Vitaly looks to his PARENTS. They stare at him until he averts his eyes. Vitaly can't refuse his brother.</context>
      <utterance>West Africa's fucked-up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are we going?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE JNR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri stares out of the window.</context>
      <utterance>RUF - "freedom fighters".</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The truck passes a checkpoint marked by two skulls.</context>
      <utterance>Every faction in Africa calls themselves by these noble names - "liberation-this", "patriotic-that", "democratic-republic-of- something or other". I guess they can't own up to what they usually are - "federation- of-worse-oppressors-than-the last-bunch-of- oppressors". Often the most barbaric atrocities occur when both combatants proclaim themselves "freedom fighters".</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vitaly comes to a horrific realization. He hurries to Yuri, still negotiating with the Rebel Leader.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yuri, I need to talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not now.</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vitaly draws Yuri out of earshot.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't do this deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The fuck we can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look over there. As soon as we leave, they're going to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not our business.</utterance>
   <speaker>REBEL LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the hold up?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is no hold up. I'll be right there. Yuri draws Vitaly further away. YURI  Vitaly, it's what we always know - we can't control what they do.</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Today we can. They're right there - close enough to touch.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think they'll do if we back out - they'll kill us.</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Rebel Leader approaches again - this time he's not leaving.</context>
      <utterance>And if we go ahead - they'll kill them.</utterance>
   <speaker>REBEL LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is he saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vitaly realizes the futility of the discussion, backs down.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ANDRE JNR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>VITALY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something for Yuri.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDRE JNR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vitaly closes the lid - a ruse. He picks up the hammer and in one sudden, violent motion swings it across Andre's face, smashing his jaw, teeth flying, Andre's body flopping like a rag doll. Vitaly grabs two grenades from the box, pulls the pin from one and bowls it into the truck. He runs. The truck explodes in a fireball - instantly incinerating Andre Jnr. Yuri's head whips around. The Rebel Leader's head whips around.</context>
      <utterance>Step away - slowly.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vitaly dashes for the second truck. The REBEL LEADER opens fire, raking Vitaly with machine-gun fire - still trying to run with legs torn to shreds. YURI (cont'd) No!! A second hail of gunfire - all REBELS firing. Vitaly's legs betray him. He collapses to the ground in a pile of blood and dust. We focus on Vitaly's still FACE - he has taken enough bullets to kill him three times over. But he is not quite dead. Agonizingly slow, he raises the grenade hand to his mouth - pulls the pin with his teeth. CLOSE on Vitaly's HAND, trying to summon the strength to throw the grenade. A hand appears, grasps Vitaly's hand - gently but firmly removing the grenade.</context>
      <utterance>Vit!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We pull back to reveal the makeshift coffin sitting at Yuri's feet.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know which is worse, Jewish guilt or Catholic guilt. My parents were like God's tag-team.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I could not deny them the chance to say goodbye to their eldest son.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For twenty Monrovian dollars a doctor removed the lead from Vitaly's body and wrote a bogus death certificate. I should have paid more. The OPERATOR of the machine, stops the conveyor belt.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>In Vitaly's chest, a bullet.</context>
      <utterance>I've smuggled millions of rounds of ammunition and the bullet that lands me in jail is found under my dead brother's rib.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yuri Orlov, we're with the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Believe it or not, I only use the first two. The agents are not amused - handcuff Yuri.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have the right to remain silent. Use it. They march him away.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANATOLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Crimean Restaurant".</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>Anatoly looks at the telephone receiver in his hand - without another word he passes the phone to IRINA. ANATOLY walks away.</context>
      <utterance>Papa?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Both my sons are dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri doesn't take the bait. Two other AGENTS sit at the back of the room observe the interrogation. VALENTINE (cont'd) (referring to a document) Curiously, the death certificate says he died of heart failure.</context>
      <utterance>One of yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>If I saw one of those coming at me, l'd have heart failure. The flippant comment gets under Valentine's skin but he keeps his temper in check.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe he did.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We performed the autopsy and released your brother's body to your family. You tried to do something decent, Yuri. You went against your nature. And now it's cost you.  Your brother's funeral is looking a lot like your funeral.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Falsifying a death certificate? That's not going to hold me.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri not so cocky now - waits to see where this is going. VALENTINE (cont'd) (putting a copy of the New York Times in front of Yuri) Have you seen today's paper? A front photograph of VALENTINE posing beside Yuri's documents including his five BRIEFCASES. The headline reads, "MERCHANT OF DEATH IN CUSTODY". Caption - "Catalogue of carnage." VALENTINE (cont'd) (pacing, lauding it over Yuri) Fake end-user certificates, cut-out companies, all meticulously catalogued. There's hardly a dictator, warlord or despot anywhere in the world you aren't on first name terms with. (producing another evidence bag containing Ava's diamond earrings and an engagement ring) Your trophy wife gave us the prize. She also provided us with these - which we suspect are conflict diamonds. Yuri takes all this in. VALENTINE (cont'd) She has agreed to testify against you. Yuri nods - picks up the newspaper. But instead of reading about his own front page news, he opens the paper, turns to World Affairs - various items on the warzones at the end of the millennium. Yuri reads, takes his time. Valentine cannot believe his audacity. Finally Yuri reacts. A broad smile - his killer smile.</context>
      <utterance>You're right, as usual.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enjoy it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>despise, that I am the personification of evil, that I'm responsible for the breakdown of the social fabric of society and world order, that I am a one man genocide. Say everything you want to say to me now - because you don't have long. Valentine is infuriated by Yuri's casual demeanor.</context>
      <utterance>This. Tell me that I am everything you</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri is looking away, apparently completely unconcerned. His attitude further angers Valentine. VALENTINE (cont'd) You don't seem to fully appreciate the seriousness of your situation!</context>
      <utterance>Are you not paying attention or are you delusional? You've broken every arms embargo written. There's enough in those briefcases to buy you consecutive life sentences. You'll spend ten years going from a cell to a courtroom before you even start doing your time.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valentine laughs derisively.</context>
      <utterance>My family has disowned me. My wife and son have left me. My brother is dead. Trust me, I fully appreciate the seriousness of my situation. But I promise you I won't spend a single second in a courtroom.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri is still unfazed. He leans forward to close the deal.</context>
      <utterance>You are delusional.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A montage of scenes - Yuri's prediction plays out accompanied by his commentary.</context>
      <utterance>I like you, Jack. Well, maybe not. But I understand you. You feel your loyalty to your badge has finally been rewarded. But you haven't counted on the people who gave you that badge. Valentine's turn to hesitate. YURI   Let me tell you what's going to happen so you can prepare yourself. Yuri nods to the interview room door. YURI  Soon there's going to be a knock on that door and you're going to be called outside.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>We observe valentine's reaction - vigorously arguing with his superior.</context>
      <utterance>First, he will compliment you on the fine job you've done, how you're making the world a safer place and then he is going to tell you that I am to be released.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>The Officer, still turned away from us, tries to calm Valentine.</context>
      <utterance>You are going to protest, you will probably threaten to resign.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>We return to the present.</context>
      <utterance>But in the end I will be released. Yuri exits the cell to freedom.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valentine turns on his heel. He is at the door when Yuri finally replies.</context>
      <utterance>I would tell you to go to hell. But I think you're already there.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valentine doesn't look back, exits. Sure enough, the Officer is in the hall as Yuri predicted - COLONEL SOUTHERN.</context>
      <utterance>What if I'm not? What if I sleep fine at night? What if I sleep better than you? I think that's what truly scares you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Most people are happy just to get out of jail. I expect to be paid to leave. Yuri opens the case - BALES OF CASH.</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not a fool. I know that just because they need me one day doesn't mean they won't make me a scapegoat the next. But I was back doing what I do best.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BORDER OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Umbrellas - to Saudi Arabia?</utterance>
   <speaker>YURI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yuri hands the Officer a plain, brown paper bag. The Officer looks inside - a wad of cash.</context>
      <utterance>Sun umbrellas.</utterance>
   <speaker>BORDER OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Officer waves the convoy through.</context>
      <utterance>Have a safe trip.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
