<movie id="361" title="Lost in Space">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>West activates his targeting computer.</context>
      <utterance>Hell. And we're going to send them back screaming.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TARGETING DISPLAY-CLOSE. The fleeing Attack Ship jogs in and out of the crosshairs on West's holographic array. West fires.</context>
      <utterance>Last one to kill a bad guy buys the beer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TARGETING:DISPLAY-CLOSE. The Attack Ship flashes, captured in the targeting hatchmarks. The display expands into a tactical grid.</context>
      <utterance>I can hear her. Oh, yes, oh yes. She's gonna sing.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMPUTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Target lock.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXT.-SPACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Imminent collision.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INT.-JEB'S CRAFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Attack ship is right behind him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Weapons are off line. Jettisoning main drive core.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>COMPUTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Warning. Failure in redundant drive systems. JEB-POV. The surface of Mars is rushing up fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMPUTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Impact on in 90 seconds.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mars Control. . .</utterance>
   <speaker>EXT.-SPACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeb's ship is barreling toward the planet.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEB</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>. . .this is Ranger One.</utterance>
   <speaker>INT.-WEST'S FIGHTER</speaker>
      <mode>ON RADIO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Engines will not respond. Require assistance. Repeat...</utterance>
   <speaker>BASE</speaker>
      <mode>ON RADIO</mode>
      <context>Rescue craft have been dispatched.</context>
      <utterance>Ranger One this is Grissom Base.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXT.- MARS MINING COLONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three small rescue craft race skyward.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grissom, this is Eagle One. Those Pugs Will never reach him in time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASE</speaker>
      <mode>ON RADIO</mode>
      <context>DON takes a beat. Then he spins his chair towards Mars, begins working the controls.</context>
      <utterance>Eagle one clear this frequency and return to base.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Eagle One. I'm going after him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASE</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Negative Eagle one, your craft is not equipped West hits his thrusters.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>INT.-JEB'S FIGHTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mars is coming up fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMPUTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Impact in 30 seconds.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeb, do you have navigational thrusters?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context>Mars fills the windscreen. Jeb checks his status display.</context>
      <utterance>It's a yes or no question.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marginal. But in the green.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMPUTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Impact in 15 seconds.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Head towards the canals.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context>The canal streaked face of the Mars is all Jeb can see. He grabs his throttle, engages his navigational thrusters and pulls.</context>
      <utterance>Saving your ass. Read towards the canals. Now!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>INT.-WEST'S SHIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>West is accelerating toward Jeb.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASE</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context>West slams a switch, deactivating his radio.</context>
      <utterance>Major West, your ship is not equipped for rescue. You are not authorized to jeopardize this asset. That is a direct order. Acknowledge!</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He BLASTS into the canal, walls rushing up on either side of him.</context>
      <utterance>Never liked that station, anyway.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INT.-3EB'S FIGHTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The canal floor is rushing up fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMPUTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Impact in five seconds.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COMPUTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Warning. Proximity alert.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeb, I'm going to give you a little kiss. Don't take it the wrong way.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXT.-MARTIAN CANAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>West angles his ship directly under Jeb.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JEB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don, abort. Abort.</utterance>
   <speaker>INT.-WEST'S FIGHTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>West going up. Don angles the throttle.</context>
      <utterance>Jeb's fighter is visible overhead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>INT.-WEST'S FIGHTER</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context>West pulls his throttle all the way back.</context>
      <utterance>Does this mean we're going steady?</utterance>
   <speaker>EXT.-MARTIAN CANAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>West shoots up and out towards the dark of space.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context>The rescue craft converge on Jeb's ship as Don heads for base.</context>
      <utterance>You weren't getting out of buying those beers that easy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>VO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INSERT IMAGE-A dashing hero, wind in his hair. JOHN ROBINSON.</context>
      <utterance>Imagine an end to world hunger. What if ample food and clean drinking water were the birthright of all our planet's children?</utterance>
   <speaker>VO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INSERT IMAGES -Airbrushed faces of a perfect family. THE ROBINSONS.</context>
      <utterance>This man, professor John Robinson, inventor of the faster than light hyperdrive can make that timeless dream a reality.</utterance>
   <speaker>VO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INSERT IMAGE-A towering launch dome glints in the morning sun.</context>
      <utterance>John Robinson and his family have been extensively trained to take a ten year journey across the galaxy in the world's most advanced spacecraft, The Jupiter.</utterance>
   <speaker>VO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INSERT IMAGE-A satellite photo of a planet. Closer on continental patches, enhanced to show deposits of a diamond like powder.</context>
      <utterance>From a distant world, the Robinsons, Will bring back a miracle...</utterance>
   <speaker>VO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INSERT IMAGES - Sun dappled, swaying wheat. (OVER) Music crescendos.</context>
      <utterance>Dimondium can turn even worthless sand to fertile soil. Earth WILL be a garden. What kind of - future can our children look forward to?</utterance>
   <speaker>V0</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INSERT CORPORATE LOGO.-A Coke bottle hurling towards the stars.</context>
      <utterance>A future without hunger. A future without suffering. Heaven on Earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>V0</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This mission sponsored by the US Army and the Coca-Cola corporation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The room lights suddenly dim. The Principal flickers, revealed as a holograph, her head now sitting on Schwartzenegger body. Maureen LAUGHS, then realizes the Principal has no idea her image is being distorted. Maureen begins moving about the room, surreptitiously glancing behind couches, into cabinets.</context>
      <utterance>He hacked our main power grid to run his experiment. The school was in chaos. We didn't even have lights.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context>The Principal's body has become Twiggy's. Now that of an ape. Maureen pulls open a closet. Will sits inside. Grins.</context>
      <utterance>This is no laughing matter, Mrs. Robinson. Will is terribly gifted. His little time machines, though pure fancy, are the products of a truly brilliant mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The changing shape of education.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will shrugs, adjusts his deck. The Principal returns to normal.</context>
      <utterance>No more monkey business.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The boy is starved for attention. Was there no way his father could have attended the science fair?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON SCREEN a hi-tech orbital gate is highlighted and expanded.</context>
      <utterance>Once we have landed on Alpha Prime our on board robot will begin construction of a hypergate.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON SCREEN an image of an orbital gate now under construction.</context>
      <utterance>By then, technicians here on Earth will have completed a companion hypergate in our planet's orbit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Once both gates are complete, ships will be able to pass instantaneously between them. The Jupiter can bring the Dimondium back to Earth without the ten year delay of a return trip.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why can't you just use the Jupiter's hyperengine to zap straight to Alpha Prime?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON SCREEN a graphic spaceship appears randomly in the corner of a turning schematic of the galaxy.</context>
      <utterance>As you know, hyperspace exists beneath normal space. If you try to enter hyperspace without a gate</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your exit vector is random. There's no telling where you'd come out.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John glances to the doorway where a uniformed GENERAL stands.</context>
      <utterance>Professor, how is Captain Daniels recovering from the flu? Will we still be able to pilot the mission?</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John hits a button and the room darkens. A giant monitor reveals...</context>
      <utterance>Ladies and Gentlemen, you came to get a look at the Jupiter One. Don't you think you've waited long enough?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Professor, how does your family feel about leaving the Earth behind....</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context>CHAPTER 3: Goodbye!</context>
      <utterance>They couldn't be more excited.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes a beat, blinking away the tears. Lifts her wrist and turns on a video camera watch. She begins down the hall. VIDEO-POV. Penny's face in the monitor screen.</context>
      <utterance>I Don't want to stay home for dinner. I want to see my friends for the last time.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... On the eve before she is torn from her friends, kidnapped, hurled into deep space against her will, what thoughts fill the mind of the young Space Captive....</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What will I wear?</context>
      <utterance>Will there be boys on Alpha Centuri?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Penny shows the camera her arm, covered by strings of ribbons.</context>
      <utterance>When we wake up in ten years the video journals of Penny Robinson, Space Captive, will be devoured by millions. I will be world famous. You on the other hand, will have been totally forgotten.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Space Captive has decided to wear ribbons of support for fellow sufferers as she is dragged into deep space, green for the ecological issues, white for human rights</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Penny seems about to speak, instead just smiles, goes to his bed and pulls off the sheets, begins knotting them together.</context>
      <utterance>You'd probably gag if I described the secondary infections loss of circulation can cause.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you grinning at?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Penny knots the sheets into a rope, ties it to the bed-post. Will lifts several palm-sized gold-plated stars. Each reads: 1st prize.</context>
      <utterance>I just found an upside to this mission. The thought of jettisoning your body into deep space.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad says Don't bring them. Like anything I do matters to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He never showed, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe if I had actually broken the time barrier he would have paid attention.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Penny tosses the rope out the window, prepares to climb.</context>
      <utterance>Don't let him get to you, kiddo. He just gets busy with work is all.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, that's a no to family dinner?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>you do the math.</context>
      <utterance>Let's see, do I spend my last night on Earth watching Mom and Dad pretend not to be fighting again or get in ten years of making-out at the mall ...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom's gonna go thermal.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHAPTER 4: Major West</context>
      <utterance>What's she gonna do. Ground me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>INT.-SPACE COMMAND-CORRIDOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John and the General walk the metal passageway.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're lucky they didn't press on Daniels, condition.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I figured a chance to look at the ship would keep the dogs at bay.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben, I'm worried about jamming in a replacement pilot at the last second. My family' a on this mission. I need someone who's more than just spit and polish.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The General palms an access panel. A door hisses open to reveal...</context>
      <utterance>I've got your man. He just doesn't know it yet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At ease, Major.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, why was I pulled off active duty? I salvaged my craft and Jeb's. I'll fight a court martial, General.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know Professor Robinson?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By reputation only.  Your father's battle strategies were required reading at the Academy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much do you know about the Jupiter Mission, Major?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Jupiter is fully automated. The pilot flies the ship out of the solar system and lands on Alpha Prime. It's a baby sitting job, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Major, you are aware Earth's resources are severely limited.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every schoolchild knows our recycling technologies will save the environment. Sending a family across the galaxy is a publicity stunt to sell soda to people of all ages.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I am about to tell you is classified. Every schoolchild has been lied to. The recycling technologies have failed. In less than two decades Earth will be unable to support human life.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We spun the ad campaign to give the mission a friendly face, keep people from panicking in the streets. We partnered with Coke because the 900 billion this mission cost would have bankrupted the government. The SinoJordanian Alliance knows the truth as well as we do. They hope to reach Alpha Prime first - And if they do, I guarantee you, they will not share the Dimondium with Western Demons like us. our crops will wither. We will be left to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Captain Daniels doesn't have the flu, does he sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Daniels was murdered in his apartment last night. The flu story is a cover we fed the press.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dan was a good pilot. A good man.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your rescue stunt over Mars was foolhardy. Explain yourself, Major.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had a friend in trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You endangered a one billion dollar spacecraft, disobeyed a direct order because of a friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir. And I'd do it again. Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(stepping forward)</context>
      <utterance>He'll do.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHAPTER 5: Dr. Smith</context>
      <utterance>Congratulations Major, you're the new pilot of the Jupiter mission.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>My work is done.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps a brief jaunt down memory lane is required. I was contracted to provide Daniels, apartment code.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSINESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They found a replacement pilot, the mission is going ahead on schedule.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How tragic. For you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSINESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We require more direct intervention.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(OVER) a KNOCK. The man reaches forward and presses a button. The businessman, the desert disappear, only holographs. Room lights. Lights come up to reveal...</context>
      <utterance>I see. Well, that will cost you. And, I'm afraid my price has just become ... astronomical.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Doctor moves to a circular overhead light board around which are displayed the faces of the crew of the Jupiter craft. Removes the micro-files, hands them to the technician.</context>
      <utterance>Control hasn't received the results of your final pre-flight exams, Doctor Smith.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles, so sweet you can barely see the malevolence behind it.</context>
      <utterance>The Robinsons are checked out at one hundred percent. They are in perfect condition and ready to fly.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHAPTER 6: Welcome Aboard!</context>
      <utterance>Wish them good luck for me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context>The figures have come to the saucer entry-port.</context>
      <utterance>The mission protocols are simple. Professor Robinson is in command unless you encounter a military emergency. In that case, Major West, you will assume command.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome aboard, Major.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some of this technology might be new to you. I'll be happy to explain.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don strides to a pedestal in the center of the bridge. Flicks a switch and a holographic Jupiter craft appears on the launch pad.</context>
      <utterance>Cold fusion drive  Rambler-Krey Life Sciences stations.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don points to a row of man-sized glass cylinders on the back wall.</context>
      <utterance>Holographic navigational interface.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He approaches the blast doors that lead off the back of the bridge.</context>
      <utterance>Cryosleep array. Fully monitored.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don hits a wall panel which opens to reveal an immense ENGINE ROOM.</context>
      <utterance>Sick bay, remote Ops, engineering and living quarters are below decks. Hyperengine should be in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then the ELEVATOR rises from the lower decks. On its circular platform stands a DOCTOR in a lab coat. She walks to the General.</context>
      <utterance>If you have to baby sit, it's not such a bad nursery, wouldn't you agree, Major?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The cryosleep systems are running at ninety five percent.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doctor Smith approved the specs-</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doctor Smith is base physician. I am responsible once this ship is in flight. These tubes have to keep the crew in suspended animation for ten years. They will be perfect or this ship will not launch. Is that clear?</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely, Doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Judy, I'd like you to meet Major West. He's taking Mike's place.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's heavier than Mike. We'll have to re-calibrate.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd be more than happy to discuss my dimensions perhaps over dinner?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>West - I've read about you. Something of a war hero, aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, yes, actually.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She heads toward the readouts. West turns to John.</context>
      <utterance>Those who can't think, fight.  Well, nice to have met you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's one cold fish I'd love to thaw.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>West turns to John. Dad?</context>
      <utterance>I'm not going to make it home for dinner, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's going to be a long flight.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXT.-ROBINSON HOME-NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lights burn in the windows.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context>Maureen descends the steps in a bathrobe. Joins John.</context>
      <utterance>He won first prize again. He practically brought down his entire school. But he won first prize.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maureen is silent.</context>
      <utterance>A non-working prototype for his time machine. Sharp stuff for a midget.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry about dinner. I had to work late. The new pilot-.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you had to do was prioritize your family over the mission</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maureen. This mission is about our family. So we can stay together</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John stares at his wife. Then he reaches forward, touches her hair.</context>
      <utterance>The perfect nuclear family. The most stable social unit, ideally suited for the isolation of a long journey into space. It's all just PR, John. You're never home. Judy is becoming a ghost just like you. Penny can't see past her own navel and Will has to black out-his school, just to get his father's attention. The perfect nuclear family in ruin.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Then she moves to him. And he holds her close.</context>
      <utterance>I know, Maureen. I'm scared too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LOADING TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything else?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOADING TECHNICIAN #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HOLD on a canister that reads: BIOLOGICAL MATERIALS: Do Not Open, as it passes on the loading belt. FOLLOW THE DRUM as it winds along the conveyer, up a gantry towards the Jupiter One. PUSH IN...</context>
      <utterance>I'm showing a late shipment from Mission Medical. Smith's authorization. Here it is now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith hits a switch on the panel and the Robot's system indicators light into life. Smith types several keys on the keypad.</context>
      <utterance>You'll forgive me if I forgo the kiss, my sleeping behemoth.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But the time has come to awake.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Robot is on-line. Reviewing primary directives. One, preserve the Robinson Family. Two, Maintain ship systems. Three</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith taps the keypad. The Robot is silenced. Smith types again.</context>
      <utterance>Spare me the chatter.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith completes his re-programming. Hits a switch.</context>
      <utterance>What noble charges my steely centurion. Sadly I fear you have far more dire deeds in store for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith smiles. Removes the re-programming module.</context>
      <utterance>Robot is on-line. Reviewing primary directives. Two hours into mission destroy Robinson family. Destroy all systems.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith climbs into a chute marked WASTE DISPOSAL.</context>
      <utterance>Now that's more like it. Farewell my tin-plated pal. Give my regards to oblivion.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you never to call me here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSINESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly the tiny module in his hand OVERLOADS, the flesh on his palm smoking as Smith is engulfed in an electrical charge. He goes out, his body perfectly still. CHAPTER 8: Launch!</context>
      <utterance>I see you have completed your mission on schedule Good work, Doctor. And goodbye. The Businessman smiles. SMITH-CLOSE. Puzzled.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>EXT.-SPACE COMMAND-MORNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INT-JUPITER ONE John and Maureen face will and Penny who stand now in their freezing tubes. All wear silver flight suits. Maureen moves Penny's hair from in front of her face.</context>
      <utterance>The giant dome shines in the early sun.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't, mom. Vogue says this will be the style in ten years.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will she wake up less annoying?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does he have to wake up at all?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maureen kisses her children. John moves to will who reaches to shake at the same moment John tries to hug him. A beat. Then John tries to a shake as Will goes for the hug. A total miss. Will backs into his tube.</context>
      <utterance>Alright you two, enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John kisses his wife, already in her tube.</context>
      <utterance>You get a C in paternal expression, Professor. But an A for effort.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You always get an A in that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't let me shatter this unbridled display of affection, but we are running behind.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Major, she's all yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Judy walks the row, checking their bio-monitors. Enters her tube.</context>
      <utterance>I'll try to give you a smooth ride.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We are in the green.</context>
      <utterance>Mission control this is Dr. Robinson.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISSION CONTROL</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context>Don walks to Judy's tube.</context>
      <utterance>Roger, Doctor, you are go to initiate cryostasis.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One question, Doctor. in there room in these tubes for two?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The tubes rotate closed around the Robinsons. Suddenly each crew member is surrounded by a shimmering blue glow, brightening like a star and then subsiding. All stand fixed in suspended animation. Don stares at the family a beat. He goes to the main console. Straps himself in.</context>
      <utterance>Barely enough for you and your ego, Major. Drive carefully.  initializing cryostasis tubes.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mission Control, this is Jupiter One. The Robinsons are asleep. We are ready to fly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NOAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MONITOR-CLOSE. The dome begins to part.</context>
      <utterance>Jupiter Two this is Mission Control. You are at T-minus two minutes and counting. We're opening the dome.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXT.-JUPITER ONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Giant gantries retract. Fueling lines disengage.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>West reaches for a glowing panel.</context>
      <utterance>Roger, Houston.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're outta here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks to the center of the bridge and activates the navigational holograph, images forming in mid-air over the pedestal. HOLOGRAPH- CLOSE. The Jupiter Two is visible, backed by the planets of our solar system.</context>
      <utterance>Houston, diverting all spacecraft controls to the main computer.  Eight years of flight training.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don touches buttons and a highlight indicates the ship's trajectory past mercury, around the Sun in a slingshot and into space beyond.</context>
      <utterance>Navigational holographics on line.  Fifty combat missions.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don walks to the freezing tubes. He zips up his silver flight suit.</context>
      <utterance>Course confirmed for slingshot exit of the solar system.  Just so I can take the family camper on an interstellar picnic.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>West climbs into his tube.</context>
      <utterance>Ten world series. My, nephews' high school and college graduations. A decade's worth of Sports Illustrated swimsuit editions.  Noah, ten years in a lifetime.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith turns, slaps the burned out programming module on the Robot.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No response. The Robot continues to power up. Smith engage interface. Initiate system shut-down.</context>
      <utterance>Disable program.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Robot disengages from the service bay, begins rolling forward.</context>
      <utterance>Robot is on line. Implementing prime command directives.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Robinson family, destroy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Robot rolls towards the bridge.</context>
      <utterance>No. Cease. Desist.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith grabs a wrench from a tool bracket, leaps for the Robot. The Robot swings once, sending Smith flying into a flaring console.</context>
      <utterance>All operating Systems, destroy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jupiter Two, destroy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He fires, a blast of electricity hitting the cryosleep controls. (OVER) ALARMS sound as the tubes begin to descend, electricity sparking across the sleeping Robinsons.</context>
      <utterance>Robinson Family, destroy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context>Smith, wrench in hand, rushes the Robot, is again hurled across the room. The Robot turns towards the navigational computer.</context>
      <utterance>Mechanical moron. You'll kill us all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NOAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Techies begins working the controls.</context>
      <utterance>This mission's over. Wake them up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No response, sir. I'm sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="32">
   <speaker>INT.JUPITER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE FREEZING TUBES are quickly being engulfed in flames. Smith stumbles toward their control station. Begins typing madly.</context>
      <utterance>The Robot is rolling toward the com.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He SMASHES a glass panel that reads EMERGENCY DEACTIVATE. The figures inside the lowering tubes glow. All except Judy. The Robot is before the Com, electricity arcing between his claws.</context>
      <utterance>Wake up, damn you. I can't stop this infernal contraption on my own.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Robot FIRES at the main Com, controls EXPLODING everywhere. The freezing tubes begin to open, the Robot spinning to face them. John blinks to life first. Emerges, ducking a BLAST of electrical energy from the Robot, hitting the deck and rolling.</context>
      <utterance>Hurry up. Hurry up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maureen grabs Will and Penny, pulls them down just as the Robot blows away their tubes. John pulls a laser pistol from a wall mount.</context>
      <utterance>Maureen. The children.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Disengage safety.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Robot spins towards John, FIRES an electrical charge - John dodges at the last instant, the grazing blast burning his silvery suit, singeing his side, sending into the wall, his gun flying.</context>
      <utterance>Voiceprint confirmed.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will ducks under his mother's arm, scrambles across the bridge.</context>
      <utterance>Dad!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Robot FIRES at the scrambling boy but misses, Will disappearing down the gunny hatch leading to the lower decks. DON leaps from his tube atop the Robot's back, trying to grab the Robot's power source. The mechanical monster electrifies his shell, sending the Major flying. The Robot turns to Penny and Maureen. Extends his arms toward them. Electricity arcing between his claws. The two are done for. Maureen puts her hand over Penny's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Will, wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Robot is about to fire. Suddenly the Robot freezes, his claws deactivate, his power lights go to stand-by and he stands immobile. WIDER. Will stands in the b.g., his tiny hacking deck in his hands.</context>
      <utterance>Look away, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Robot. Return to your docking bay and power down.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Robot turns and begins heading for the elevator. All watch in amazement. Will grins, a familiar mischievous gleam in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Command accepted.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An EXPLOSION rocks the ship.</context>
      <utterance>If the family won't come to the science fair, bring the science fair to the family.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context>Penny stands over Smith who lays crumpled in the corner. Maureen grabs an emergency medi-kit from a wall clamp, tosses it to Penny.</context>
      <utterance>Mom, look, it's Doctor Smith.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pulse, respiration and bleeding-</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John is standing, helps Don to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>Basic triage, lock down and stabilize. I know the drill.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don moves fast to the helm. The main view screen is still closed, covered by giant metal blast shields.</context>
      <utterance>NEXT picnic, no robots.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maureen is at the life sciences console.</context>
      <utterance>Communications links are down.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VIDEO MONITOR-POV. Penny is bandaging Smith's head, her bravado barely masking her fathoml4ss terror.</context>
      <utterance>Life support is at ten percent. Trying to bring secondary systems on line. It's not working.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A console FLARES. Penny fights back tears, terrified.</context>
      <utterance>Explosions rock the ship. Danger is everywhere, 'Yet the Space Captive is fearless as she...</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don is at the navigational system.</context>
      <utterance>I want to go home now.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rerouting power from the secondary couplings. Try it again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly the lights go on, the air compressors begin to Hiss.</context>
      <utterance>Finding a power tap....</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Life support is back on line.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Penny in working ever Smith, bandaging his head. She runs stimulator under his nose. Smith begins to stir, COUGHING.</context>
      <utterance>I can't get the blast shields open. We're flying blind.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>West turns, spots Smith for the first time.</context>
      <utterance>I've got life signs.  Boy, somebody could use a breath mint.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don moves to the fallen figure, lifts him up against the bulkhead.</context>
      <utterance>Try the emergency back-ups.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smith, what the hell-</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don almost buys it. Then he notices Smith's hand, grabs it. BURN-CLOSE. The reprogramming module's distinctive, foreign signature seared into his flesh.</context>
      <utterance>I was making a last minute check ... someone hit me from behind.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don slams him against the bulkhead, begins dragging him towards the airlock. The pilot hits a switch. The inner hatch opens.</context>
      <utterance>Sino-Jordanian technology. You're a Goddamned spy.  You did this.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop. What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dropping some extra weight.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Help, somebody. Please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="32">
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith uses the distraction to palm-slam Don in the chin, knocking him backwards. Don staggers, goes again for Smith.</context>
      <utterance>The thawing engine in broken. can't get her out. She's dying.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don freezes in his tracks.</context>
      <utterance>Touch me and the girl dies.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your mission physician is indisposed. I can save her life. But only if you spare mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I Don't deal with dead men.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don's decision is lighting fast.</context>
      <utterance>Kill me, I kill the girl. How much is your revenge worth, Major? I will, of course, need your word as an officer that you will let me live.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Help her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly the radio SQUAWKS into life.</context>
      <utterance>I've got a com signal.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jupiter Two this is</context>
      <utterance>...Is Mission Control. Do you read?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VIEWSCREEN CLOSE. The blast shields part to reveal a giant fiery orb in their path. They are heading directly for the sun.</context>
      <utterance>Emergency power's on line. I think I can get these blast shields open.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>INT.-MISSION CONTROL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Noah stands over the Com. The room is a madhouse.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Noah looks up at the main monitor. The graphic of the Jupiter Two is heading towards the graphic of the sun.</context>
      <utterance>Give me a telemetry projection.</utterance>
   <speaker>INT.-JUPITER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John and Don stand over the Com.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOAH</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're way off course. We show you in the sun's gravitational pull.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long do we have?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOAH</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context>DON straps himself into the pilot's chair.</context>
      <utterance>We count seven minutes before your outer hull begins to melt.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SMITH stands at the freezing tube, Penny and Maureen assisting him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to try for the Mercury Mines.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will need Dr. Robinson's portable gurney. I believe it is stored in-</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Penny races off. Smith begins working the controls to Judy's freezing tube.</context>
      <utterance>I'm on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We trusted you.  You tried to kill us all.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Existence offers us nothing if not the opportunity for an endless series of betrayals.  There's a world behind the world, Professor Robinson. Lie once, cheat twice and everything becomes clear. Do not mistake my deception for a character flaw. It is philosophical choice, a profound understanding of the universe. It is a way of life.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a monster.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Penny reappears, a case in hand. She presses a button and the case unfolds into a hovering, gyroscopicaly-leveled gurney.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps. But I am also the only one who can save your daughter's life.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Will?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's futzing with that Robot.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, Penny dear, I need you to short the power on my command.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does he have to call me dear?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith hands Penny a wrench.</context>
      <utterance>Professor, if you will assist me in lowering the body.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maureen nods. Penny SLAMS the wrench into the power circuit. The freezing field FLARES and deactivates, the tube swinging open. LIFESIGN MONITOR-CLOSE. Flatline.</context>
      <utterance>Penny, dear. Now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith and Maureen lower her onto the gurney.</context>
      <utterance>She's dying.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Penny, Maureen and Smith rush the gurney out the blast doors towards Sickbay just as the ship tilts madly.</context>
      <utterance>Sickbay. Move.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unable to re-route to Mercury. The sun's pull is too strong.  Noah, I need options.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No cardio-pulmonary or respiratory functions.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Body temp at 68 Fahrenheit.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Penny unzips the silver material as Smith works the console, highlighting her holographic heart.</context>
      <utterance>Get her flight suit off.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The holographic image of her heart beats once, then is still.</context>
      <utterance>Clear.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The lights flicker on the bio-console, the holograph winks out.</context>
      <utterance>Again. Clear.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Power's down.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHAPTER 10: Initiate Hyperdrive</context>
      <utterance>We're losing her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've re-routed all secondary systems to the main drive.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She won't budge. Shortest baby sitting mission I've ever done.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My family's not going die in space.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm open to suggestions.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMPUTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Outer hull breach in 30 seconds.</utterance>
   <speaker>INT.-SICKBAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smith begins pumping Judy's chest by hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith steps back, begins precise, staccato blows to Judy's chest.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, child. Fight. Put a little heart in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith stops, presses his ear to her chest - Takes her pulse. Smiles.</context>
      <utterance>The life.. .  I save ...  may be  my own.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Then Judy opens her eyes, manages a weak smile.</context>
      <utterance>Judy? Baby?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should try to look less worried. It has a tendency to spook the patients.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith holds her gaze, his eyes almost snake-like.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maureen stares at him. A beat. She pulls a laser from the wall. Points it at his forehead.</context>
      <utterance>You are a good woman, Maureen. Any man could see that. I hope I have proven the well-being of your family is of great importance to me. Perhaps, if you convinced your husband to trust me...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stabilize her, Smith. Because you only breathe as long as she does.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>COMPUTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heat seal breach in 20 seconds.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DON stares at him.</context>
      <utterance>There's got to be some way to get through this.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's it?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The hyperdrive -</context>
      <utterance>We can't get away from the sun. So we have to go through it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Engage the hyperdrive without a gate, we could be thrown anywhere in the galaxy</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anywhere but here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're getting resident radiation distortions from the space craft. She must be breaking up.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Techie hands him a sheet. Noah looks for a beat.</context>
      <utterance>Let me see those numbers, Annie.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son of a bitch. He's powering up the hyperdrive.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hyperengines coming on line.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMPUTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sun covers the entire windscreen, a furious landscape of flame.</context>
      <utterance>Warning. Heat shield breach.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hyperdrive at 100 percent. Major, you have the Com.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John takes Will's hand as West engages the hyperdrive. West, John and Will, are hurled backwards from the sudden acceleration, sticking to the walls and ceiling respectively.</context>
      <utterance>Zero to 20 million miles a second in under a minute. Let's see what this baby can do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Noah stares at the screen.</context>
      <utterance>We can't keep a fix on her, sir. She's starting to disappear.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Godspeed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is everyone okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All in one piece. Although Major West has the most puzzling definition of a smooth ride.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then Judy emerges through a door, zipping up her flight suit.</context>
      <utterance>Judy? Where's Judy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy either I cut down on the coffee or sew in a flap. It's hell getting in and out of this thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you-</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vitals are normal. Pulse and respiration seem to be-</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Baby, are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John holds her close, spared a father's worst fear.</context>
      <utterance>I'm fine Daddy really.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don turns towards Smith. Maureen steps between them.</context>
      <utterance>Will every disaster be an excuse for familial sentiment? Please tell me now so I may gather up a liberal supply of space sickness bags.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened, John? Where are we?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You had me worried, Doc. Nice to see you thawed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smart maneuver with the hyper-drive.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don makes a connection. The pedestal powers up, a holograph of the Jupiter Two appearing over its surface.</context>
      <utterance>A fighter who thinks, what do you know? You're just in time for the show.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HOLOGRAPHIC PEDESTAL-CLOSE. The area around the Jupiter Two is now filled with a holographic representation of the alien solar system.</context>
      <utterance>Computer, map our current location.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don just shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>See anything familiar?</utterance>
   <speaker>COMPUTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Searching for recognizable constellations.  Unable to locate.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This computer has star maps of the entire known galaxy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Judy wraps her arm around her sister.</context>
      <utterance>We're lost, aren't we?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VIEWSCREEN- CLOSE. The nearest planet is starting to glow. Suddenly a distortion field begins to emanate from the alien world. The edges of space seem to sear away, leaving a glowing portal.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any effect on the ship?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VIEWSCREEN -CLOSE. All the planets and constellations beyond the portal appear to be in different places.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All the planets have moved.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHAPTER 12: The Proteus</context>
      <utterance>And where did that come from?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Go back in front of it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a hole in space. A doorway.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A doorway to where?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we want to reach that ship, we're going to have to find out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>INT.-JUPITER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The giant, silver ship looms in the windscreen.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No apparent effects on the ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm hailing on all frequencies. No response.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are some markings on the starboard side. Can you throw some light on her?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE WINDSCREEN-CLOSE. Powerful spotlights hit the ship. WEST AND JOHN-CLOSE. And really surprised.</context>
      <utterance>Don't know if the exterior spots are working.- There we go.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE SPACESHIP-CLOSE. Essentially a needle covered with metal scallops. On its hull, under the legend PROTEUS, an American flag.</context>
      <utterance>If this in all a dream, why can't there be more girls?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>what are those scales on her hull?</context>
      <utterance>I've never seen a design like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How could Earth launch a ship this massive and neither of us know about it? ... It just doesn't make sense.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These scanners are damaged, I'm getting inconsistent life signs but they may be sensor ghosts.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON SCREEN-A docking ring on the giant ship comes to life, giant floods coming to life, the docking aperture rotating open.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe her computer's still up. I'm trying standard remote access codes.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>EXT.-SPACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Jupiter Two heads towards the giant ship.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A smaller docking ring is illuminated on the viewscreen.</context>
      <utterance>Can you give me some light on the secondary docking ring?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Attached to the starboard docking ring is another, smaller craft. Its snaking anthropomorphic lines are not of human design.</context>
      <utterance>What do you make of that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boys, I think we're having a close encounter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ROBOT</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context>REVERSE ANGLE. The Robot in rolling in through the doorway, arms waving wildly before him.</context>
      <utterance>Crush.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don and John are up fast. But the Robot just rolls to a stop. Will steps from behind the automaton, his hacker's deck in his hand. He pulls a tiny mic from his deck. Lifts it to his lips.</context>
      <utterance>Crush! Kill! Destroy!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crush. Kill. Destroy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will points to several jury-rigged modifications.</context>
      <utterance>Crush! Kill! Destroy!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All stare at him. Penny finally speaks.</context>
      <utterance>I hacked into his CPU, bypassed his main operating system and accessed his sub-routines. He's basically running on remote control.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Show off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Penny's VOICE trails off. Stares out the porthole. Endless space.</context>
      <utterance>And so the Space Captive finds herself helping the Robinsons by guarding the traitor. And she finds-</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then Don approaches, a silver bundle under his arm.</context>
      <utterance>She finds that out here, in the dark and cold, she's scared, and she's kind of glad they're all together.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Identify yourself, soldier.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Penny steps aside.</context>
      <utterance>West, Major, United Space Force, requesting permission to see the prisoner.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don smiles, winks at her, going through the door.</context>
      <utterance>Proceed Major West.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ouch. Could he be cuter? I don't think so.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don tosses his bundle on the seat. A silver flight suit.</context>
      <utterance>These quarters are totally unacceptable. I demand-</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to check out the probe ship. Maybe we can figure out how they got here. And how to get home.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ta-ta. Have a wonderful trip.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're coming with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out of the question. I'm a doctor not a space explorer. You and- But Don is in his face in a heartbeat.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you are is a murderous saboteur and I am not leaving you on this ship so you can do more harm than you've already caused.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I absolutely refuse-</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith stares at him a beat. Then he smiles, looks to the flight suit.</context>
      <utterance>Give me an excuse to kill you. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Silver always was my color.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John enters, removes a gun from the weapons locker.</context>
      <utterance>When boarding a mysterious spacecraft, it always pays to look your best.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Deactivate safety.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>GUN-CLOSE. A small light goes from red to green.</context>
      <utterance>Voiceprint confirmed. Rifle is active.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did a good job up there son. You saved us all.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An awkward silence hangs between them.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know I haven't around much these days.That we haven't had time to-</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context>John looks at his boy Will in silent.</context>
      <utterance>Professor, we're ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that, John walks out. Will stares after him. Faces the Robot.</context>
      <utterance>Will, you're the most important thing in the world to me. I hope one day you'll be able to see that.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will works his remote, sending the Robot towards the bridge.</context>
      <utterance>Take care of my dad, okay Robot?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The air is stale. Old.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don walks to a computer panel set into the wall. Begins typing.</context>
      <utterance>That's the smell of ghosts.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm interfacing with the on board computer... Odd.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not working?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Robot rolls deeper into the alien ship. The others follow. More lights flicker into life, illuminating the long corridor ahead.</context>
      <utterance>No, it's just, I don't know, too fast. Most of the systems are down.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Motion sensors are still working.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context>Smith, John and Judy join Don at one of the bulkhead walls.</context>
      <utterance>What do you make of this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WALL-CLOSE. A series of hieroglyphics are scrawled on the hull wall. The sketches tell a story. HIEROGLYPH-CLOSE. The alien craft docks with the giant ship. SECOND HIEROGLYPH-CLOSE-A trio of inhuman bipedal stick figures enter the giant ship. THIRD HIEROGLYPH-CLOSE. The shape of a sun or a disc, from which juts many legs. This final hieroglyph is circled in a clotted red substance. Don touches the stain. CHAPTER 13: Exploration</context>
      <utterance>Some kind of hieroglyphics.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I didn't know better I'd say this is blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know an omen when I see one. I suggest a hasty retreat.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don shoves Smith forward with the butt of his laser rifle, the group heading deeper into the quiet ship.</context>
      <utterance>Just imagine we're retreating in the opposite direction. Now, move it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ROBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Robot turns, begins heading further down the corridor. (OVER) now DRIPPING can be heard by all.</context>
      <utterance>... Hear something?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like the drip, drip, drip of blood..</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really need to shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE CEILING shows a jagged hole, covered with some kind of viscous membrane, leading to the dark of a service tunnel above. The membrane DRIPS steadily onto the floor below.</context>
      <utterance>Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That material appears biological.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing good will come of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What makes you such an expert?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trust me, Major. Evil knows evil.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's find the bridge. Maybe we can get some answers. They head off. HOLD on the dripping membrane.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maureen throws a switch. The panel lights up, then goes dead.</context>
      <utterance>Try it now, Mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell happened in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith has moved off slightly, wandered over to a STORAGE ALCOVE. Within, a row of docked Robots, larger and sleeker then ours. John and Don are powering up the Com, console lights coming on.</context>
      <utterance>Some kind of fire fight. Look at this technology. I've seen some of this before. On the drawing boards.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you bring up the Captain's log?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MAIN SCREEN-CLOSE. Fills with snow. Then a figure can be seen. It's Jab. But his hair is grey.</context>
      <utterance>The data has degraded. I'm going try and gather any fragments I can. There isn't much, but ... here we go.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeb.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hyperspace tracker seems to be functioning...  No sign of the Jupiter Two...</utterance>
   <speaker>JEB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have exceeded our mission timetable by two...  I'm not willing to give up. Don would keep looking for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>IN THE ALCOVE, Smith frees a power pack from one of the robots. Slips it into the sleeve cuff of his field suit.</context>
      <utterance>That's it. The rest of the data is totally corrupted.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Judy stands by the life sciences panel.</context>
      <utterance>This doesn't make sense. How could they launch a rescue mission for us when we've only been lost a day?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A turning holograph appears over the console panel. A degraded image of a trembling, viscous pouch. Tiny shapes move within.</context>
      <utterance>I've got something here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don notices Smith's standing in the storage alcove.</context>
      <utterance>They brought it up from the planet's surface. It's seems to be some sort of egg sack.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smith, step away from there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the corner of the ceiling, another membrane covered hole.</context>
      <utterance>Happy to oblige, Major. Although I don't think it's me you should be worrying about. But rather this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm detecting motion. Behind you...</utterance>
   <speaker>INT.-PROBE SHIP BRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A towering SHADOW shoots past the open doorway.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After it. Move.  Bring Smith.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>INT.-HYDROPONICS LAB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A jungle. John and Judy arrive behind Don.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This explains where all the plants came from.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Robot arrives through the lab door, carrying Smith in one claw.</context>
      <utterance>Growth like this would take decades.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don's eyes fix behind Smith's head.</context>
      <utterance>Unhand me, you mechanical moron.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't move.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am sick of your terrorism. If you are going to kill me, be done with it. Otherwise I will insist you treat me with the respect and-</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith is suddenly silent. Don's hand shoots out, just missing Smith's head, disappearing into the brush behind him, leaves flying, as-he pulls from its hiding place a small creature. About the size of a large stuffed bear, spiny skin going from leaf color to red, shaped like a rhesus monkey but covered with the scales of a tiny dragon and bright yellow cat's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I said don't move.</utterance>
   <speaker>INT.-JUPITER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will is watching through the Robot's eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Neat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the beast struggles in Don's hand it changes color, chameleon like, trying to hide. No luck. Don holds fast.</context>
      <utterance>Well, who do we have here?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy there, little buddy. No one's going to hurt you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don has begun stroking the creature's head. After a beat, the small beast begins to COO and emit small BLIPPING sounds.</context>
      <utterance>How do you know it won't hurt us?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like you've made a friend. You have a good bedside manner, Major.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to let that one go.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How charming. Doctor Dolittle of outer space.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do you think it came from?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The beast has moved onto Don's shoulder, is now clutching there, burying its tiny face into his neck. Don can't help but LAUGH.</context>
      <utterance>It's possible this is one of the creatures represented in the hieroglyphs we saw on the wall. It must have been their ship attached to the other docking ring.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It looks like a child.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If so, my dear Major, what do you suppose happened to its parents?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they leave, a dark shape skitters across the ceiling in the background. Ominous. Unseen. CHAPTER 14: Giant Spiders!</context>
      <utterance>Let's get back to the bridge.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>INT.-JUPITER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Penny is still hanging overhead.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sensor console comes back to life, displays lighting, status lights going green. Maureen stares at the monitor.</context>
      <utterance>I think I've got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCREEN-CLOSE. Revealed in the sensor scan, the scallops pulse with ambient heat. Penny lands beside her.</context>
      <utterance>That's strange.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those scales are giving off heat.</utterance>
   <speaker>INT.-PROBE SHIP-BRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John is at the Com.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've tapped into the internal sensor array. Besides us, this ship is totally deserted.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don is sitting with the tiny creature. He pulls a ration pack from his pocket. Turns it over in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>A ghost ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The creature stares at him intently as he tears open the foil lip, sucks a bit LOUDLY. Judy can't help but smile at him.</context>
      <utterance>And the flavor of the day is ... banana/beef. Who thinks up these combinations?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>MM. Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don glares at him, hands the tiny creature the pouch. The creature looks at it, emits a small BLIP, takes a tentative suck. Its eyes widen in delight as it begins to suck the ration pack.</context>
      <utterance>Major West, I highly recommend you never breed. That by the way is my medical opinion.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Little thing was hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(OVER) a distant, high pitched WHINE.</context>
      <utterance>Good Lord, who will - spare us the tyranny of the sentimental?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly the creature begins to SCREAM, leaping on Smith's back, clinging to his neck for dear life.</context>
      <utterance>Do you hear something?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The WHINE is growing louder. it seems to be coming from above. THE CEILING-CLOSE. There, in the corner, the membrane covering the hole seems to be trembling.</context>
      <utterance>Get this infernal creature off me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This can't be good.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have a remarkably keen sense of the obvious.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Our heroes race to a nexus, corridors leading off in all directions. Spiders are dropping from the ceiling around them.</context>
      <utterance>They eat their wounded.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which way?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INT.-PROBE SHIP-CORRIdOR</context>
      <utterance>Turn left.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The spiders are swarming, closing fast.</context>
      <utterance>Now right.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got to seal the bulkhead.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The door control is at the other and of the corridor.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Judy pulls her gun, FIRES, hitting a ceiling sensor at the end of the corridor. Blast doors SLAM, sealing out most of the spiders. DON-CLOSE. Impressed. BLAST DOORS-CLOSE. Metal teeth begin tearing through the steel. Our group has made it to the door to the docking bay. They rush in, the Robot coming through the open doorway last and holding there.</context>
      <utterance>The fire sensor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Open, damn you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's cycling a vacuum check. There is no way to speed up the protocols.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Judy throws him, hard, into the wall.</context>
      <utterance>Fools. I warned you not to come aboard this cursed craft. You've killed us. You've killed us all.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The first spiders reach the Robot, leaping onto its metal bull.</context>
      <utterance>Now that's a bedside manner.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don hits a switch just as a spider breaks free, rushing towards the dropping airlock door. Smith recoils from the swiping talon. SMITH'S BACK-CLOSE. A tiny rand and beneath, a razor thin incision. THE DOOR drops, the spider's arm, still twitching, severed inside the airlock.</context>
      <utterance>Seal it. Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>INT.-JUPITER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The inner airlock door Opens. The crew tumble in.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don is already powering up the ship's engines as Smith tries separating himself from the tiny lizard monkey.</context>
      <utterance>Get us out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He throws the beast hard across the bridge. The creature hits the wall, SCREECHING, begins racing across consoles. John has strapped in beside Don.</context>
      <utterance>Get this cloying gargoyle off of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A MONITOR shows the hull of the Jupiter Two. More spiders are leaping onto the ship, attaching themselves to the hull.</context>
      <utterance>Get me an external view.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE LIZARD MONKEY skitters up the back of Penny's chair, over her head, getting tangled in her hair before jumping into her lap.</context>
      <utterance>Prepare to disengage.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Penny in frantically wiping the hair from her face. The tiny creature on her lap begins a perfect imitation of Penny. Don releases the docking ring, glances at the Monitor. The hull of the ship is now entirely covered with spiders.</context>
      <utterance>Get it off me. Get it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LIZARD MONKEY'S EYES widen in terror as the ship SHAKES, burying its head in Penny's chest. A beat. Then Penny hugs the tiny beast.</context>
      <utterance>Initiating separation.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But she sounds anything but sure.</context>
      <utterance>It's okay. Everything's going to be alright.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're clear. Everybody hang on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>INT.-JUPITER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>ALARMS sound.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think those things were using the probe ship as a way to trap food.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That I s probably what happened to the monkey's parents. We were going to be desert.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what happened to the crew?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing good.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON SCREEN. The hull of the Jupiter Two is covered with the giant spiders, their teeth cutting through the outer hull.</context>
      <utterance>We're not out of the woods yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's see how these monsters like a hundred thousand volts.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the crowd goes wild.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON SCREEN-The spiders shoot webs from their bellies, attaching to the Jupiter, land on the hull again, re-extending their limbs, starting to burrow once more.</context>
      <utterance>Recall your nightmares from childhood, Major. Monsters are rarely so easily dissuaded.  a THUNK. Then another. A third.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Persistent bastards.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you hit them again?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every time I electrify the hull, I'm draining our systems. Once or twice more and we're going to be dead in space.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maureen emerges from the airlock holding the spider's severed limb in metal tongs. Carries it to her life sciences analyzer.</context>
      <utterance>A fate I fear may be inevitable one way or another.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MAUREEN'S MONITOR-CLOSE. A graphic of the severed spider leg. A small line begins to extrapolate to the rest of the figure. Musculature and flesh are drawn in on the screen.</context>
      <utterance>That's the same expression you had when my mother came to stay with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VIEWS CREEN -CLOSE. More and more spider are spiraling from the probe ship, all heading toward the Jupiter Two.</context>
      <utterance>DNA extrapolation - coming up. Silicone based. Admantium shell and lack of respiratory system suggest an ability to live in deep space. Tiny front brain implies communal relationships. More like bees.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are thousands of those things Maureen is working the COMPUTER.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don begins typing.</context>
      <utterance>They may be attracted to heat and light.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MONITOR-CLOSE. More spiders are hitting the bull.</context>
      <utterance>With the right command codes, I can light up the probe ship from here.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn. No response.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But they won't work until the next fleet of ships are built. That's at least two years away.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The mighty probe ship begins to power up, engines glowing red as they begin their initial BURN.</context>
      <utterance>Just do it. Don begins entering command codes.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think about it, Don. The ships's advanced technology. Your friend looking old. What if that ship is from our future?</utterance>
   <speaker>COMPUTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCREEN-CLOSE. Spiders are eating through the outer hull.</context>
      <utterance>Warning. Outer hull has been compromised.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not working.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you get the fusion drive on line?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>INT.-JUPITER TWO</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Warning. Inner hull breach in twenty seconds.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give them a little encouragement.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Electrifying outer hull ... now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don looks at John a beat, then he begins working the controls.</context>
      <utterance>Get us out of here. Fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don hits a button. On the remote control console a readout begins to flash. The message is simple: FUSION DRIVE-OVERLOAD.</context>
      <utterance>Never leave an enemy stronghold intact. One of your father's first rules of engagement.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don, stop. That's a direct order. We might need to salvage-</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a military emergency. That means I'm in command.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don, no. I'm ordering you-</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don hits a button. The panel light flashes: OVERLOAD.</context>
      <utterance>I hate spiders.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don angles the ship away, punching the thrusters as the probe ship's engines begins to glow.</context>
      <utterance>Hang on, it I a gonna be a bumpy ride.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INT.-JUPITER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ship is buffeted by the shock wave.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't hold her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INT.-JUPITER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don is struggling to keep control.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>INT.-JUPITER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The windscreen is filled with a RUSHING BLIZZARD.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't get the stabilizers on line.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pull up. Pull up.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WINDSCREEN- CLOSE. The storm clouds suddenly PART TO REVEAL ... A</context>
      <utterance>Really? No kidding? Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIANT SNOW COVERED MOUNTAIN RANGE.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don banks the controls.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INT.-JUPITER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The surface is coming up fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got to slow us down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maureen straightens, rubs her neck.</context>
      <utterance>Everybody, by the numbers.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Life Sciences, still breathing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mission medical, I'm alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me too. Robotics, I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Video Mechanics, okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm alive, Major West's poor excuse for piloting skills not withstanding.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don hits a switch, the windshield de-icing, becoming clear.</context>
      <utterance>Let's take a look.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think we're in Kansas anymore.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About half the core material is burned out. We'll never generate enough power to break orbit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you not to blow that ship's reactors and you did it anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Professor, give it a rest. I was technically still in command.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't hand me that. I'm commander of this mission.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, no offense, but you're an egghead with an honorary rank. No one ever intended you to handle combat situations. You're spouting some nonsense about- time travel while those spiders posed a continuing threat. I made a judgement call and if I have to I'll make it again. Hell, you of all people should understand that. If your father were here-</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don's face is right up in John's.</context>
      <utterance>My father is not here. My father is dead, killed in one of his combat missions you so admire. My family is on this ship And you're going to follow my orders. Whether you agree with them or not. Is that clear, Major?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two are too close to do anything but kiss or fight. Kissing seems less than likely.</context>
      <utterance>Save the speeches. I like you. But the fate of the Earth is at stake here. I'm going to do whatever I think it takes to ensure the success of this mission. With or without your help. Is that clear, Professor?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context>WIDER. Maureen stands in the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>Am I interrupting something?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Really. I think you two should go ahead and slug it out. I mean, here we are stranded on an alien world and you boys want to get into a pissing contest. So please, go for it. I'll have Judy down here in a heartbeat to declare you both unfit and I'll take over this mission. Now I don't want to hear another word from you two until you can play nice. Is that clear?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maureen- Listen-</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maureen turns on her heal and EXITS. The two men exchange a look.</context>
      <utterance>Not another word.  Better. Now if you've finished hosing down the decks with testosterone, I suggest you come with me. I may have found a way to get us off this planet.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHAPTER 18: Danger Will! (Out of Sequence in screenplay.)</context>
      <utterance>Tell me about it. They head after her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will tunes the deck. More STATIC. Then...</context>
      <utterance>Can you hear me? Robot?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Systems error. Robot unable to register neural net outputs. Unable to locate motor controls. Unable-</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Do you remember?</context>
      <utterance>Calm down. Your body was destroyed in the conflict with the space spiders.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Affirmative.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I downloaded your neural net.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Robot tried to destroy the Robinson family. Why would Will Robinson save Robot's personality? Your actions do not compute.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess sometimes friendship means acting with your heart, not your head.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Logic error. Friendship does not compute.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will turns to face a pile of pirated components from various par of the ship. He lifts a circular bubble of diodes. Smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, Robot. Im going to build you a new body. I promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHAPTER 15: Follow Orders! return to CHAPTER</context>
      <utterance>Mom always said I should try to make new friends.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The atmosphere here can sustain human life. I've located 500 Rads radioactive material a mile north.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John looks out the viewscreen at the alien night. Turns to Don.</context>
      <utterance>That's at least what we'd need to get the core functioning again.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll set off at daybreak. it'll be safer. Those are my orders, Major.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I agree with your recommendation, Professor.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dtente is a beautiful thing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the diagnosis, Doc? Is it cowboy or ballerina on Halloween?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right now she's a girl. But I think your little pal here is from a self-replicating species. At different stages of life she, or he, probably alternates sexes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The tiny creature has begun playing with an aural scanner.</context>
      <utterance>Imagine the savings on dating outfits alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I keep her?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Penny, you've never taken care of a thing in your life besides yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. She's all alone. I promise I'll look after her. She needs me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that Judy EXITS. Penny sits, stroking the tiny creature.</context>
      <utterance>...The moment you misplace her, or forget to feed her, we leave her on this planet where she can live in the wild. I'm not kidding Penny.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The creature makes a tiny BLIP.</context>
      <utterance>We're both a long way from home, aren't we little one?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blip reaches out, touches a green ribbon around Penny's wrist.</context>
      <utterance>That's what we'll call you. Blip.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Penny takes the ribbon off, ties it around Blip's wrist. Blip looks up, eyes glowing. Penny caresses the tiny creature's cheek.</context>
      <utterance>You like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The creature reaches up, touches Penny's cheek. Her tiny tongue trying to imitate Penny's words of comfort.</context>
      <utterance>Nice girl. Pretty girl. Nice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remove that lock this instant. I shall not be caged like some animal</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gave my word I'd let you live. I never said for how long.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith stares at him a beat.</context>
      <utterance>These quarters will be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me, Major West. Are you really confident in Robinson's ability to guide us? If I were set free, I would support your right to command. With minimal force, we could take this ship and assure this mission continues under your leadership.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...My God Smith, you're right. How could I have been so blind? I'll just run and get you a gun so we can hijack the ship. Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sarcasm is the recourse of a weak mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith tries the door. Locked. Then, from one cuff of his field suit, be removes the control belt he stole from the probe ship.</context>
      <utterance>I'm hiding the pain. Really. And with that West leaves.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith moves about the room, lifting small bits of metal, creating an impromptu set of tools with which to alter the control bolt. PAN DOWN. HOLD on SMITH'S BACK. Beneath the rend in his suit, the tiny tear in his flesh is now covered with tiny, alien scales.</context>
      <utterance>I assure you, Major West. Your pain has just begun.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Star light, star bright...</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don comes and sits in the co-pilot's chair beside her.</context>
      <utterance>A million strange stars and only one wish. I wish we were home.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never thought a sky could look so alien. ...We really are lost.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When the first sailors circled the globe and saw a brand new sky, they thought they had sailed off the edge of the earth. But they were really just around the corner.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We just billow our sails and let the wind blow us home, Is that it Major?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don turns on a monitor below the viewscreen. MONITOR-CLOSE. It shows the star-field above. He lifts a light-tipped stylus.</context>
      <utterance>So those sailors found familiar shapes in the stars to make the skies more friendly, to help them find their way.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don begins to draw on the screen, connecting the stars like dots in a children's book. Slowly, a familiar porcine face takes form.</context>
      <utterance>That's how constellations were born.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Judy LAUGHS. She takes the stylus. Begins to draw.</context>
      <utterance>Porky the wise and mighty Pig.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don smiles. Judy can't help but smile back. Their faces are close.</context>
      <utterance>The great bucktoothed Bunny... Bugs.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, my quarters or yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are the only single man and woman of consenting age in the galaxy. How much more of a set up do you need?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you figure just dispense with the pleasantries, get down to business?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have a way with words, Doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don moves his face to hers, only a breath apart.</context>
      <utterance>Right here? On this console?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DON-CLOSE. Lips parting. Suddenly water begins to pour down over his head. His eyes open wide. Judy holds her empty glass in hand.</context>
      <utterance>Here would be fine. Judy smiles sweetly.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rises, walks off, leaving Don mopping his brow.</context>
      <utterance>Next time, fly slower.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was I thinking, bringing us all out here into space?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The world needed saving. You were the right man for the job.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But solving the world's problems doesn't leave much time for the people you love, does it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you get any time with Will?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I've got too much to do-</context>
      <utterance>Now he's decided he can rebuild the robot. Wants to show me his designs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He needs your attention.</context>
      <utterance>Funny creatures, men. You try so hard not to be your fathers, end up making the same mistakes. Will adores you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't get off this planet much less back on course. I don't have time to...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John, just listen to him. it doesn't matter what he's saying. Just listen. Sometimes, at least in the eyes of their fathers, little boys have to come first.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maureen looks out the window. A long beat. Then she smiles.</context>
      <utterance>As soon as we get back into space, we're going to spend some real time together. I promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John presses a button, the blast shield opening to reveal the stacked orbs of three glowing moons. Maureen smiles.</context>
      <utterance>It's nice to have our family under one roof. Even if we had to go half way across the galaxy to manage it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John moves to her, begins pulling her down, out of FRAME.</context>
      <utterance>How would you feel about a little late night tutorial, Professor?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mm. That's new. What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Going for extra credit.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXT.-JUPITER TWO-NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ship sits on the alien landscape.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good night John.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good night Maureen.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good night Judy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good night Will.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good night Penny.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context>CHAPTER 17: The Core</context>
      <utterance>You guys have got to be kidding.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are those rumblings? They've been happening all morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can half the landscape have grown up overnight?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MAUREEN'S MONITOR-CLOSE. A geothermal analysis shows the giant plates that make up this world appear mismatched.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, let's get settled. Maureen?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's impossible. But this planet's geothermic plates don't match up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al1 eyes turn to John.</context>
      <utterance>I was afraid of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think these tremors are the result of opening and closing doorways.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doorways to where?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The future.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps the Professor was hit on the head when we landed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember the portal that lead us to the probe ship? What if we crossed a into a time years after Earth sent a rescue mission.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not serious? Time travel is impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No it's not. It's just improbable. Like hyperdrive was a hundred years ago. Nothing's really impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This world could be riddled with doorways to the future.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So if we walk into that forest outside, we're really just walking into this crater years from now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But doorways in time, John?</context>
      <utterance>Geological plates from different times wouldn't fit together. That would explain the tectonic mismatch.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If these portals are opening and closing, part of some cascading, natural phenomenon, they could be tearing this planet apart</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These portals are exactly what I predicted my time machine would do. What if the doorways aren't natural? A machine that bends space, like our hyperdrive, could be modified to bend time as well. What if someone on this world has built a device?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son, I appreciate your input but now isn't the time for flights of fancy.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that Will storms out. John stares after him a beat, sorely wanting to follow. (OVER) another RUMBLE.</context>
      <utterance>You never listen to me. Not ever.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no telling how long before this planet breaks up entirely. . Don and I are going to locate the radioactive material for the core. Get the ship ready to go. We may have very little time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will just shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Aren't you coming out to say goodbye?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will looks away, finally giving voice to his worst fear.</context>
      <utterance>You're always leaving. What if...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John stares at his son, unsure what to say, the boy's anguish so deep and apparent. He reaches into his shirt, takes off his dog tags.</context>
      <utterance>What if one time you don't come home...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lifts the chain and places it around the boy's neck.</context>
      <utterance>Whenever your grandfather went away on a mission, held leave these with me. For safe keeping. And when he got home I d always be waiting to give them back.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will is silent. John touches the boy's hair, then walks out. A beat. Will looks up after his father, fingering the dog tags.</context>
      <utterance>I'm coming back Will. I promise.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got a fix on the radioactive material. It's through the portal.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll just have to hope the doorways remain stable.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These crater walls are disabling the com-links. You won't be able to communicate with the ship.  the ground shakes again. Maureen Come home to me, Professor.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John kisses her. Don looks at Judy.</context>
      <utterance>I love you, wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to regret saying this, But try to get back in one piece.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is kind of a kiss for luck occasion, wouldn't you agree, Doc?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blip reaches up and touches John's face. Then her CHIRPS form a rough approximation of the words Penny taught her.</context>
      <utterance>See. I'm regretting it already.  Kisses have to be earned. Say goodbye, Blip.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice girl. Pretty girl. Nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then the two men bead off, towards the portal and forest beyond.</context>
      <utterance>You take care of her, Penny.  Take care of you too, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>PULL BACK TO REVEAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smith stares out the cabin window. PUSH IN as</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns, heads back to his table, transformed now, into a makeshift lab, the stolen control bolt in mid-modification.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, enjoy your moments of trite familial bonding.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because they will be your last.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's everything even close to nonessential. Even my bellybutton ring.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Pen.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Will just shakes his head, sulky.</context>
      <utterance>You want to come on a land survey?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She ruffles his hair. Disappears. Will activates a CPU speaker.</context>
      <utterance>Look, what does dad know? Maybe someone did build a time machine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(OVER) a KNOCKING has begun. WILL looks up, puzzled.</context>
      <utterance>Robot is on line.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chapter 18: Danger Will!</context>
      <utterance>It sounds like old morse code.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said someone is in danger.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith eyes the weapon, moving towards the boy.</context>
      <utterance>We all are. You are wise to arm yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith barely misses a beat as he adjusts, passing the child, going instead to the window and opening the blast shield.</context>
      <utterance>This gun is set to fire for me only so don't try anything funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>William, you misjudge me. I only want to help you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Help us? You tried to kill us all.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith gazes out at the exotic terrain. (OVER) an inhuman WAIL.</context>
      <utterance>But now our fates are intertwined. if your father and that idiot West fail, I will have no chance of getting home. It is in my best interests they succeed. And I always follow my best interests.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What monsters roam these alien wilds? Fools. To set off blindly across this savage land. Much as I hate to admit it, it will be harder to manage without them.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith is silent. A long, lethal beat.</context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about? They'll be back. They'll be okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone should go after them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will, I forbid it. You're a boy. A clever one, certainly, but a child nonetheless. This planet is likely full of predators. Even if you found them, what if they're hurt, ravaged, dying, what good could you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith turns away, hiding his smile.</context>
      <utterance>But you're a doctor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not really. Geologists have speculated that Dimondium might be naturally occurring in many older worlds. Part of a biosphere's way of rejuvenating itself.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Penny stands in the f.g. with Blip on her arm, taking plant samples, talking into her video recorder.</context>
      <utterance>This one is ten times more powerful then that on Alpha Prime. There's enough here to save Earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blip jumps up on Penny's arm, knocking her recorder to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>After much deliberation, the Space Captive has decided to accept her new role as member of the crew. The Robinsons, after all, can obviously use her help...</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blip stares at her, frightened by her tone, begins backing away to the edge of the forest. She looks at Penny, then disappears into the thick brush..</context>
      <utterance>Now look what you've done. Stop hanging all over me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Penny heads after the creature. HOLD on her recorder. Forgotten. CHAPTER 19: A Different Future</context>
      <utterance>Blip. Wait. I'm sorry. Damn.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dead ahead is a field of beautiful, alien flowers, their purple leaves moving in the wind like an azure sea.</context>
      <utterance>I've got a fix on Dad's suit beacon.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow, that's Mom's favorite color.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(OVER) a tremendous RUMBLING. The WIND ROARS. Suddenly, the air in the distance begins to twist, a rushing distortion sweeping towards them, flowers growing, landscape aging rapidly within.</context>
      <utterance>How droll.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith turns, begins to flee, pulling Will with him, away from the rushing warp. Smith trips, falls, closes his eyes, waiting for the distortion to overtake him. A beat. He opens his eyes. SMITH-POV. A glowing, stationary portal shimmers behind him, revealing beyond a forest ever older, darker, more overgrown.</context>
      <utterance>Run, child, run.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No sign of the boy. Then, from behind a tree, Will appears.</context>
      <utterance>Will? Will?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The field across the portal has is now a mass of giant plants, the flowers a deep red. Will rushes across the rip in space.</context>
      <utterance>Wow!</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>William, wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, over here I'm in the future.  Here I'm in the past. Don't worry. If my theories are correct, these doorways should remain stable, for a while anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can barely contain my glee. Why aren't you aging like the plants?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will takes Smith's hand, pulls him across the threshold. SMITH-POV. Where he stands is now lush, the sky overhead a glowing crimson. Yet behind him, the path in as it originally appeared. Younger. The sky, bright. Will has run deeper into the brush. Smith notices something by his feet. He clears away the brush, revealing shapes beneath the foliage. His expression darkens.</context>
      <utterance>That's just an effect of the portals forming. Once they stabilize you can cross from one time to another just like stepping between two rooms.  Dad's signal is this way. Come on, Doctor Smith.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context>Will has returned.</context>
      <utterance>What did you find?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith shoves Will on, the boy unable to see what Smith saw. PAN DOWN. Headstones. Each bears a marking, the names still legible. Maureen, Penny and Judy Robinson.</context>
      <utterance>Come, come, son, no time for distractions. Let's move on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn? Damn is not good.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(OVER) a sudden RUMBLING. The ground shakes. The ROAR of WIND. A time portal rushes towards them like a glittering maw, the side of the crater aging and crumbling in it's wake. John and Don race away from the distortion, ducking falling trees, roll clear as the portal stabilizes, now a fixed doorway to a darker, more deserted future.</context>
      <utterance>The radiation signature we've been tracking. it's a ghost. A reflection from the Jupiter Two bouncing off the ore in these walls. There's no core material here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ship's back that way. we have to go through.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXT.-BRUSH-DAY-PRESENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Penny is pushing through the forest.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She spots the tiny creature ahead in the distance. Blip SNIFFS the ground, runs a few steps. SNIFFS again. Looks up. There, before Blip is another glittering hole in time. The forest beyond is far thicker, the sky red. Blip steps through the portal.</context>
      <utterance>Blip? I'm sorry. Blip?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Penny goes to the edge of the portal, stares at the monstrously tall trees beyond. A beat. Then she steps through, following.</context>
      <utterance>Blip, wait.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE STONE-CLOSE. A series of hieroglyphs are painted on the giant rock, their images the same style as those on the probe ship. HIEROGLYPH ONE-CLOSE. A mighty battle in space is depicted.</context>
      <utterance>Blip, you can't run off like that.  What the-?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context>HIEROGLYPH TWO-CLOSE. A fiery star falls to the planet's surface.</context>
      <utterance>Some kind of fight, in space. It almost looks like the probe ship Major West blew up.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HIEROGLYPH THREE-CLOSE. Here a dark haired beauty holds a single lizard monkey aloft, her face remarkably like Penny's. Suddenly BLIP begins to SHRIEK. (OVER) RUSTLING leaves. SHAPES are moving in the trees, the vague outline of camouflaged forms dropping to the ground. Five figures suddenly de-camouflage. Lizard monkeys, two large, two smaller. Directly in front of Penny, the largest monkey de-camouflages. Fully grown, the beast is nearly twice Penny's height. Around the creature's wrist is something odd. An old, tattered green ribbon. BLIP begins to SCREAM and SHRIEK.</context>
      <utterance>That could be the Jupiter Two crash landing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Too late. Blip leaps on the giant creature, grabs the ribbon. The beast could slap Blip away like a fly. But the creature doesn't resist, just stares down at Blip with something akin to tenderness. Blip looks at the ribbon in his hand. Then at the one around her wrist. Save for their age difference., the ribbons are identical. The giant monkey moves forward, closing on a petrified Penny, paw reaching out, touching her face. The beast begins stroking Penny's cheek in a familiar gesture of comfort.</context>
      <utterance>Blip, no!</utterance>
   <speaker>GIANT BLIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Penny stares up in stunned wonder.</context>
      <utterance>Nice girl. Pretty girl. Nice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Something catches the light on the ground beside them. Don reaches down and lifts a small metal fragment in his hand. METAL-CLOSE. On it is the familiar logo of the United Space Agency.</context>
      <utterance>We should be able to see the ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could these be from the probe?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don finds another piece of wreckage, turns it over in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Corroded. This metal is decades old.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WRECKAGE-CLOSE. The fragment bears a simple legend: Jupiter Two.</context>
      <utterance>It's not possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Where the hell are we?</context>
      <utterance>What kind of nightmare is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Don is hit in the chest with a plasma charge, goes flying. John ducks and rolls, FIRING his laser from behind the cover of a rocky mound. John goes up to take another SHOT, is bit with a powerful electrical blast, falling hard. Still.</context>
      <utterance>No, Major, when the hell are we?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel like we got turned around.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just follow your father's signal, young William.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A boy of your intelligence shouldn't swear.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>REVERSE ANGLE. At the edge of the crater wall sits the wrecked hull of the Jupiter Two. The lower sections are gone, the hull scarred, open to the sun.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Shit, indeed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context>A FIGURE sits in the command chair, visage obscured by shadow.</context>
      <utterance>Well, well. All things really do come to he who waits.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this place?</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You've come home.</context>
      <utterance>Why Professor, the shock must have scrambled your brain. Look around you. Don't you recognize the spot?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But even as the words cross his lips, he knows it is.</context>
      <utterance>This can't be...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...Where's my family?</context>
      <utterance>What have you done to the ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your family is dead. Dead and in the ground.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The figure stands, light hitting his face. Late thirties. Long blond hair, a shaggy beard and moustache. Eerily familiar.</context>
      <utterance>What fickle consort in memory. Time dims certain images while others shine clear and bright as yesterday.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The figure walks to one of the burned out panels.</context>
      <utterance>I'll never forget that morning. Twenty years ago. What was it you said? I'll be back. I promise. But I knew better. You never came home.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Without you, your family never had a chance. A few spidersv survived the destruction of the probe ship. They reached the planet and attacked. I can still hear the women scream.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The figure walks forward, into the light. Stands there a moment. Then he lifts something hanging around his neck. Tarnished metal, old but familiar. John's father's dog tags.</context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you recognize me, Dad? It's me. I'm your son. Will.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The four lizard monkeys are kneeling in a circle around Penny.</context>
      <utterance>Penny? Penny?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Penny rises, steps forward, carrying Blip. The other beasts hang back, their faces genuflecting, almost reverential.</context>
      <utterance>Penny? Baby, are you alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay, Mom. They're not going to hurt us. it's like they think I'm their princess or something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But...</context>
      <utterance>Best as I can tell this whole clan was spawned by this single creature.  We've been a busy girl haven't we?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Speak, doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Each creature seems to have unique corpuscular patterns on their palms. As individual an fingerprints, no two alike. Except...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Except the prints on this giant creature and our little Blip match exactly. Don't they?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Penny and Judy stare at her in wonder.</context>
      <utterance>Because, I think Blip and our friend here are actually one and the same.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>. . .ouch. Who ordered me that last drink? What the hell is going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we crossed into our own future. We've come back to the Jupiter Two decades after we left.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will moves to a control console at the base of the giant gantry.</context>
      <utterance>Look father, what my flights of fancy have wrought. I used your hypergate to build my time machine.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will hits a button. A generator opens, revealing a glowing cylinder of core material incrementally descending into the console.</context>
      <utterance>Over the years I have struggled in vain to harness the awesome power of time. All my experiments at creating a stable doorway have been futile. Until now. Today you will witness my ultimate triumph.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The core material. if we could get that back to our Jupiter Two...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The doorways in time that led us here must be a side effect of his machine coming on line. Like streams running into the ocean....</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will turns a switch on the control console. (OVER) More TREMORS. The laser beam's intensity grown, and in the corridor cut by the beam into the bubble images begins to stabilize. Images of Earth.</context>
      <utterance>Once this core material in fully introduced into the control console, I will open a doorway stable enough for one person to take one trip through time and space as well. Today, I will change history.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will return home, to the very day you took us on this cursed mission. I'll stop us from taking off. I'll do what you never could. I'll save the family. I'll save us all.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look around. Your machine is ripping this planet apart. What if the force wave you ride home has the same effect on Earth? What if, in getting home, you destroy Earth in the process? A beat. Then Will turns away, goes back to work.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going home. I'm going to save the family.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will, I'm your father. You've got to listen to me-.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHAPTER 20: Spiders Sting</context>
      <utterance>Let me tell you about my father. My father was a walking ghost. Never there when I needed him. He dragged his family into deep dark space and lost them there. My father is not coming to the rescue.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've got to go inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Slow down, now. We can't know what waits inside that ravaged craft. But we can be confidant it is nothing good. And I for one am frightened.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But Dad's in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will, listen to me. I have crossed this world with you, found your father as promised. But I can't let you go in there unarmed.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I've got a gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will stares him. Pulls free the pistol. Thumbs the lock pad.</context>
      <utterance>If we go forward, the barer of that weapon must be ready to kill. Murder is a skill, one which I have developed and, luckily dear boy, you have not. Look inside your heart, Will. Are you truly capable of taking a life? If not, then I ask you now, put your faith in me. Give me your trust. Give me that gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enable gun for all users.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will hands Smith the gun.</context>
      <utterance>Voiceprint confirmed.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith grabs Will by the neck, pressing the barrel to his temple.</context>
      <utterance>Finally.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A brief lesson in survival on this world or any other. Never trust anyone. Remember it into your old age, should you have one.  Now move!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can go back across the portals to the past, to the functioning Jupiter Two, where your mother and sisters are still alive. We can use this core material to escape together.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don has edged his way to the descending core material.</context>
      <utterance>And then what? All of us lost in space. Don't you see? I can do what you never could. I can save us all.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid not. Through the doorway comes young Will, Smith walking behind him, hand on his shoulder, gun to his head.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never fear. Smith is here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will, I. . .</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don stares at him a beat. Then obliges, walking over to join John. Smith approaches the Robot.</context>
      <utterance>Don't move, Professor Robinson or this rather peculiar family reunion will be tragically brief.  I'll ask you to step away from that console, Major.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith goes into his tunic and removes his modified control bolt.</context>
      <utterance>Well, well, some of us just don't know when to stay dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith slaps the bolt on the Robot's CPU. The automaton's arms go up, then fall limp. Docile.</context>
      <utterance>I borrowed this from the probe ship in hopes of taking over the helm once we were in flight. But I seem to have found a better use instead.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith activates the bolt. The Robot powers up once again.</context>
      <utterance>Let's try this dance again. You are the puppet. I am the puppeteer. Do get it right this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Robot's claws begin to glow with electricity. Smith smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Robot, enable electric disrupters.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith walks to Older Will, puts the gun to his head.</context>
      <utterance>Now that's a good gargantuan.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith starts to pull Older Will away when Will comes forward, staring at the time machine, eyes wide with awe.</context>
      <utterance>Say goodbye to your past. You're future lies with me. I'm going home in your place.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Older Will's smile is bittersweet as he places his hand on his younger self. Touches his hair.</context>
      <utterance>You did it. Just like I imagined. Re-routed the hypercore. But the natural power source, the delivery system. I never thought of those.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will. The future is never what it looks like when you're ten.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith shoves the boy back to his father, turns to Older Will.</context>
      <utterance>Heartwarming. Nauseatingly sentimental but heartwarming.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Will just smiles.</context>
      <utterance>We certainly could have aged better, I must say Now, show me how your little time machine works.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An odd moment for mirth, don't you think? What are you grinning at?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SMITH-CLOSE. Puzzled. Unseen, the boulder behind him seems to be moving, shifting. A VOICE comes, alien, yet terrifyingly familiar.</context>
      <utterance>Look around you, Doctor. At this hostile world. Do you really think a boy could have survived all alone?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context>The shape behind him unfolds, coming up now, long spindled arms and legs, ten feet tall, a hybrid monster, half spider, half Smith.</context>
      <utterance>Never fear, Smith is here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith stands petrified as the creature approaches him on spindled legs, goes down on its second knee joints, coming eye to eye.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Doctor, how nice to see me again after all these years.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spider Smith flexes his three jointed arm.</context>
      <utterance>The spider's sting had some unexpected side effects.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spider Smith reaches out and caresses Will's cheek. Turns to John.</context>
      <utterance>But my unique gifts gave me an advantage in this quarrelsome world.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs Smith's arms and begins to move him about like a marionette, engaging in a bizarre dance with himself.</context>
      <utterance>After the women were savaged, I became the father Will never had.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that Spider Smith lifts Smith over his head and hurls him like torpedo through a torn hole in the hull, towards the rocks beyond.</context>
      <utterance>But you, Doctor. Your crude ambition fills me with self-loathing.  You see I have looked within me and what I see is you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spider Smith turns to face the Robot.</context>
      <utterance>I never liked me, anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kill them all.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith throws the back of one hand over his forehead in a parody of a twenties starlet.</context>
      <utterance>But my dear boy, once the doorway in time stabilizes, this planet is going to come apart at the seams.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His head comes forward, neck elongating so he faces WILL.</context>
      <utterance>I am willing to perish here on this world for the sake of your most noble mission. But your selfish father will only try to stop you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Will's gaze is impassive. Spider Smith actually SIGHS.</context>
      <utterance>Once your mission is complete, none of this will have happened anyway. So why not just dispose of them?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very well. Robot, take them inside the ship and keep them there. If they move, then kill them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns. The clearing is empty. No Blips. No Penny. Blip runs cut before them, grabs Maureen's hand, trying to pull her forward.</context>
      <utterance>We've got to get to the ship. Penny?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In Blip's hand, a mass of colored ribbons from Penny's wrists. Blip waves them in the air, then races off. A beat. The women follow.</context>
      <utterance>Where is she, girl?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SPIDER SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spider Smith starts climbing the gantry, truly like a spider, up towards the bridge and crows nest hanging over the bubble. Will walks to the control console platform, the platform now beginning to rise on the gantry, towards the bridge above. JOHN-POV. Something hangs from below the climbing Spider Smith's back. It's an egg pouch of the kind they saw on the probe ship log.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it would seem the time is upon us. Off we go, William.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Robot FIRES a charge between its claws.</context>
      <utterance>Will, it's a trick. Smith's carrying an egg sack. If he's willing to stay on this world and die, why is he about to spawn? He's going through the portal himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Proceed to the ship or be destroyed.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hurry, boy. Time waits for no man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>SPIDER SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's almost time. I really am a word-smith.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Once the core cylinder is fully injected, the planet will begin to come apart and the time doorway will stabilize. Then I jump in.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TIME BUBBLE-CLOSE. In the circle made by the laser, the images are not yet stable, but discernable. Earth the day before the launch.</context>
      <utterance>A leap of faith. How fitting.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me again, old monster, how did the girls die?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The spiders attacked the ship</context>
      <utterance>We've been over this before, son.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith stares at him. Then he smiles. A horrible sight.</context>
      <utterance>In all the years since, the spiders have never re-surfaced. Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will turns a switch. The laser generated aperture narrows.</context>
      <utterance>Let's forget the past.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Focusing the aperture. Remember, the energy around the portal will rip a man to pieces.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't the doorway too small?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...And I became you.</context>
      <utterance>Not for me.  But then I'm not going, am I? The spiders didn't kill the girls. It was you. I just never let myself see it. You kept me alive because you needed me. Because I could build this for you. You killed my family. Destroyed this world. And I helped. You became mad as the spiders.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spider Smith opens his pouch, revealing a thousand tiny spiders.</context>
      <utterance>Poor, poor boy. Did you really think I would let you go home? Let all that I have become vanish? Look at me. I am no mere man. I am a God.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His arm whips out, grabbing Will, bringing him close, opens his mouth, bearing venomous fangs.</context>
      <utterance>Your father was right. Within me roil the growing needs of a master race. We WILL descend upon helpless Earth. An entire planet to rule.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An entire planet on which to feed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll run, draw his fire. You may have time to get away with Will.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBOT</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context>The men look up. In the b.g., Will has approached the Robot.</context>
      <utterance>Halt or Robot will destroy.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you remember what I taught you. A long time ago. About friendship?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Friendship means acting with your heart not your head.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why I rebuilt you. Because I wanted us to be friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Logic error. Friendship does not compute.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget logic. Act with your heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Robot has no heart. Robot is powered by a fusion pulse generator</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Robot stares at him a beat.</context>
      <utterance>Every living thing has a heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The floor trembles again. The planet is coming apart at the seams.</context>
      <utterance>Any attempts to override command protocols may result in fused processors in my neural net.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Robot stands still a beat. Then he reaches towards Smith's control bolt attached firmly on his CPU.</context>
      <utterance>Please, Robot, if you don't let us go, we're all going to die. I'm asking you now, will you help us? Will you be my friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Robot's claws lift into attack position, an electrical charge building with dangerous intensity. He is about to fire. At the last minute, the Robot jerks his hand upward, BLOWING away a piece of the ceiling. He rips off the control bolt.</context>
      <utterance>Robot attempting to deactivate control bolt-commands overriddenattempting to reroute-dangercircuitry overloadattempting to escape-kill them, kill them...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHAPTER 21: Time to Die!</context>
      <utterance>Robot will save ... I will save Will Robinson. I will save my friend.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Penny stands in front of the Jupiter Two, beckoning them urgently.</context>
      <utterance>Penny? Penny?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did you go?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Maureen can respond the ground RUMBLES, begins crumbling.</context>
      <utterance>I came through the forest. I had a promise I had to keep.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Inside. Fast.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got find your way back to the ship. The portals may still be stable. I'll try to meet you there.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's our only chance to escape.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to get that core material.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll stay. The family needs their father</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The crew needs their pilot. No matter what happens, when the planet starts to break up you take off.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Without the core we'll never have enough power to make orbit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Then Don extends his hand.</context>
      <utterance>You've got to try. Promise me, Don.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then Will and the Robot arrive.</context>
      <utterance>Good luck. Commander.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will. Son. I want you to know-</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John bites back a bittersweet smile. (OVER) another RUMBLING.</context>
      <utterance>You'll tell me when you get back to the ship. Now there just isn't time.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Robot extends his claw. A panel opens on his arm and he tears out a hand-made component. A conduit made from Will's golden first prize medals, joined together to make a jagged star.</context>
      <utterance>I could use a weapon.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INT.-JUPITER TWO-ENGINE ROOM CONTROL PLATFORM-FuTURE Spider Smith has Will against the rail.</context>
      <utterance>Professor, I have a plan.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Time to die, son.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that Will SMASHES Spider Smith in the face with two closed lists. Smith recoils, lifts the boy aver his head.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not your son.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith hurls Will over the rail towards the time pool below. The creature walks to the end of the arm, stares at the forming aperture into the past below him. PORTAL-CLOSE. Images of the day before the mission launch swirl in the laser-generated opening, growing ever more stable.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the ground, crumpled in a heap, is Smith. Don checks his pulse.</context>
      <utterance>Look.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(OVER) the rushing WIND. RUMBLING. A portal opens before them to a far younger world. Then another portal, to a world far older. A third portal RIPS across the sky overhead.</context>
      <utterance>Damn. He's still breathing.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The time machine must be near full power. The portals are collapsing.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More portals are opening around them, others winking shut.</context>
      <utterance>Which one leads us home?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Through a new rip in time, the intact Jupiter Two can be seen in relief of the battered future craft. The ground beneath their feet is beginning to give way.</context>
      <utterance>There.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't just leave him here.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure we can.  Damn it.  Smith. Wake up. Smith.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, the pain, the pain.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The PORTAL is beginning to shimmer. The ground starts to fall away.</context>
      <utterance>Danger. Will Robinson. Danger.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don hurls Smith through, Will, the Robot and West darting across the threshold just as the portal winks closed.</context>
      <utterance>Jump!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Penny opens the air lock. Maureen holds close her son. Steps back.</context>
      <utterance>Mom, the forest.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's John?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MEE GROUND-CLOSE. A geyser of fire BLOWS into the air.</context>
      <utterance>The portal closed behind us. It was his only way back.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've got to try and lift off.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(OVER) TREMORS. More lava is rushing up towards the mercury, the walls themselves beginning to crack. SMITH opens a gate at the end of the crow's-nest and a gang plank unfolds above the doorway in time.</context>
      <utterance>We've already begun the pre-flight countdown. You have the Com.  I'm going to save as many lives as I can, Major. Now strap in. INT.-JUPITER TWO-ENGINE ROOM CONTROL PLATFoRm-FUTURE</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not so fast.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith's head moves from each impact, but the punches have no effect. It smiles. Grabs John and hurls him across the platform.</context>
      <utterance>You sabotaged our mission.  You killed my family  You stole my son. It's payback time.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The monster leans down over John. Opens its jaw.</context>
      <utterance>Spare me the fury of the righteous.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John's hand is reaching towards the fallen fighting star. At the last moment John grabs the metal weapon from the catwalk, slashes Smith across the face, silver-red blood pouring down his cheek.</context>
      <utterance>I think there's time for a snack before my trip.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, the pain. The pain.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John feints towards Smith's head and then slashes low, cutting the viscous membrane of the monster's egg pouch. SPIDER SMITH-CLOSE. Surprised.</context>
      <utterance>You ain't seen nothing yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SMITH'S EGG SACK-CLOSE. Scores of the tiny spiders are pouring out of the sack, rushing up towards Smith's face, tiny jaws chomping.</context>
      <utterance>Remember the probe ship? These monsters eat their wounded.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spider Smith tumbles backwards, falling against the rail on the side of the platform. John rises and rushes him, SHOULDER-SLAMMING him, sending Smith hurling over towards the bubble below. Spider Smith hits the bubble, missing the doorway formed by the red laser and is swept up by the tides of time.</context>
      <utterance>No. Stop. No!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spider Smith SCREAMS as he disappears and reappears in the various half-formed images within the bubble before vanishing altogether. John turns. The core cylinder has descended almost entirely into the main console. only seconds before it's too late to retrieve it.</context>
      <utterance>Take all the time you want to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXT.-JUPITER TWO-DAY-PRESENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The landscape is a sudden inferno.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maureen stares a beat out the window.</context>
      <utterance>I kept hoping somehow he'd appear.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don hits the engine switch. The.mighty generators WHINE into life.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go, Major.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHAPTER 23: Escape Velocity</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, my love.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will is still. Then, finally, his eyes open.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, son. Wake up.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought I lost you.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will turns in time to see the core cylinder sink into the control panel, the laser exploding in intensity below them as it drains the cylinder's radioactive power. The world begins to EXPLODE.</context>
      <utterance>The core.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John stares at him.</context>
      <utterance>You could have taken the core and left before it was too late. You saved me instead.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE LASER-CLOSE. Reaches full power. The image in the time pool stabilizes, becoming clear. TIME POOL-CLOSE. Mission Control the day before the launch. Father and Son stare into the past, eyes filled with wonder.</context>
      <utterance>There wasn't any choice. I couldn't let you fall.You're my boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PAN UP. Through a torn hole in the hull and a glowing rip in space, the Jupiter Two is rising into the flame ravaged sky.</context>
      <utterance>Look. They made it.</utterance>
   <speaker>INT.JUPITER TWO-PRESENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ship is shaking madly.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not getting any altitude.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly the panel EXPLODES, sending Judy flying across the bridge. Penny races to her sister. Kneels. Judy's eyes are wide, still.</context>
      <utterance>I'm reading a power build up. Markers in the red-</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will stares at his father and beyond him. There, in the time doorway, a young Will walks towards the entrance to Mission Control in the morning sun, innocent with no knowledge of the future.</context>
      <utterance>I couldn't save them.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER WILL</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context>Will reaches forward and touches the control console. The images in the laser generated doorway begin to change.</context>
      <utterance>So many years ago and I can still feel it. Our sun. Our Earth. It's all I've thought about. Going home.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TIME BUBBLE-CLOSE. Instead of Earth we now see this planet's surface, the Jupiter Two rising as it did just moments ago.</context>
      <utterance>A long time ago, you told a small boy that one day he'd understand how precious he was, how much his father loved him. Today is that day.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TIME BUBBLE-CLOSE. The Jupiter Two tries in vain to dodge the fire geysers, then EXPLODING all over again. Will enters some commands. TIME BUBBLE-CLOSE. The image in the portal begins to run backwards, the Jupiter Two reconstituting from a ball of flame, receding past diminishing flame geysers, beginning to land again.</context>
      <utterance>All I could see was your need to go forward at any cost. What you never showed me was your love. I lost that. Robbed by time. I could never see how much you cared. Until now.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father, take my hand.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maureen stares a beat out the window.</context>
      <utterance>I kept hoping somehow he'd appear.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don hits the engine switch. The mighty generators WHINE into life.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go, Major.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodbye my love.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The roof of the hull is beginning to swirl, becoming translucent, like water. There, standing above them, John and Older WILL.</context>
      <utterance>Look.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the passage through time and space is already breaking up as the world of the engine room EXPLODES in the b.g.</context>
      <utterance>Come with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't. There was only enough power for one person, one trip, remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maureen reaches up towards her son, reaching down, the two hands almost touching before Will is gone, the portal closed forever.</context>
      <utterance>It's good to see you again, Mom. It's good to see you alive.  Sorry about all the monkey business.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He sacrificed everything for his family.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maureen holds him close. A small figure walks up beside them. Will.</context>
      <utterance>He had a good example.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat, then Will reaches up, hands him his dog tags.</context>
      <utterance>Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm glad you came back.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John takes the boy in his arms, father and son finally holding close. (OVER) more RUMBLING as the ground continues to give way.</context>
      <utterance>I just want you to know I love you son. I love you very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context>John moves fast to the Com.</context>
      <utterance>The planet is breaking up around us.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John smiles a beat, then he's all business.</context>
      <utterance>Nice of you to drop in.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(OVER) A tremendous CRASH.</context>
      <utterance>Status?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>West turns, hauls off and PUNCHES Smith, knocking him out cold.</context>
      <utterance>We're doomed. We're doomed.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, that felt good.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don throws the power switches to full.</context>
      <utterance>Get us airborne.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to try to reach escape velocity. Maybe we can break the gravitational pull.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The gravity wells will drag us down.</context>
      <utterance>No. We don't have the core material.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We might-</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We've got to go down.</context>
      <utterance>We won't make it. Trust me. I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Through the planet as she breaks up.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's insane.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don and John stare at each other a beat. Then Don smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I don't have time to argue. I'm giving you a direct order, Major.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VIEWSCREEN- CLOSE. The world is breaking up beneath them, revealing a fiery maw. DON GUNS the engines, heading straight for the chasm.</context>
      <utterance>Yes Sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A window out the windscreen a portion of the planet has torn away revealing the black of space and the starfield beyond.</context>
      <utterance>There.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don banks the ship toward the opening, flying past exploding fragments of this shattering world.</context>
      <utterance>I see it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice work, flyboy.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, I earn that kiss yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DON shrugs, begins to turn away. Judy grabs him.</context>
      <utterance>You earned that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives him a long, passionate kiss. She lets him go, stunned.</context>
      <utterance>This one is on credit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Penny holds Blip in her arms, who has begun to BLIP madly.</context>
      <utterance>Cold fish, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Penny presses a button. Blast doors open on a storage hold.</context>
      <utterance>Poor thing. She's lost her whole family.  Penny, why are you looking at me like that. Penny?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Forms in the cargo hold de-camouflage. The other lizard monkeys, standing amidst glittering canisters of Dimondium.</context>
      <utterance>I promised Judy I'd take care of her. I couldn't leave her all alone.  Well I am their princess, after all.  You can come out mow.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dimondium. Now if we could only find our way back to Earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Robot projects a holographic schematic of the galaxy. The Jupiter Two is highlighted. Earth blinks at the other and.</context>
      <utterance>If I may, Professor.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your son's star charts.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(OVER) ALARMS. The shattered planet's core is turning bright red, a sudden ROARING blast wave heading towards the ship.</context>
      <utterance>It's a map home.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The planet's gravity field in collapsing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll be sucked in.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no way to get clear in time.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hyperdrive.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAUREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody hang on.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here we go again.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don throws the switch.</context>
      <utterance>Cool.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
