<movie id="367" title="Major League">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spring training starts the twelfth. How do you think the Indians will do this year?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other two shake their heads in contemplation of this sorry fact.</context>
      <utterance>They don't look too good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirty minutes late. Think she'll show?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTHEWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's got to. She's the damn owner now.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Butler tries to figure out what a guava facial is, the conference room doors swing open and a muscular MALE SECRETARY- BODYGUARD enters, clearing the way for MRS. RACHEL PHELPS, a flashy, striking woman in her early forties. Despite the designer clothes she favors, there is the hint of something less refined about her. She carries a Pekinese dog, CHA-CHA on her left hip.</context>
      <utterance>She didn't last week. She was having a guava facial.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men applaud, but their hearts are barely in it. The Secretary-Bodyguard pulls out a chair at the head of the table and Rachel sits.</context>
      <utterance>Good morning, gentlemen. Welcome to another season of Indians' baseball.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Several eyes roll up around the room.</context>
      <utterance>I know that it may not seem the same without Donald here this year, but I promise you by the end of the season this team will have made history.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unfortunately there are some in the press who feel that...  "the ex-showgirl wife of Donald Phelps has no business being the owner of a major league baseball team." Rachel crumbles the paper and throws it away.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This causes a few nervous glances in the room.</context>
      <utterance>Obviously, Donald didn't feel that way or he wouldn't have left the team to me. And I was more than showgirl. I was a dancer. Now, I know some of you have doubts about my ability to run this franchise. God help you if I ever find out about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donovan, Butler and Simmons pour over the list.</context>
      <utterance>Spring training begins in two weeks.  Here's the list of people we'll be inviting to camp this year.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could sit here and tell you what a great year we're gonna have, but the facts are we lost the two best players we had to free agency. We haven't won a pennant in 30 years. We haven't even finished in the first division for 15. Obviously it's time to make some changes. What do ya think?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never heard of half these guys. And the ones I do know are way past their prime.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Most of these guys never had a prime.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This guy here is dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cross him off then.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's not be hasty.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's time to shake things up, Charlie. Clear the board and start over.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's not the best material I've ever had to work with, but I'll do my best to see we move up a notch this year.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel sticks out her hand. Donovan shakes it somewhat feebly, bewildered by this whole development.</context>
      <utterance>I know you will, Charlie. That's why I'm movin' you up to General Manager. Congratulations.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that, Rachel gets up and breezes out of the room with her entourage, leaving Donovan and the others dumbfounded.</context>
      <utterance>Well, that should do it for today. Thank you, gentlemen. Let's get to work.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTHEWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One minute, 58 seconds.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BODY-BUILDER ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Donovan, Mrs. Phelps would like to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>OMIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on in, Charlie. Have a seat.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm glad you called me in. I'm still unclear on a couple things</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, really? Like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if I'm the G.M., who's gonna be the Manager?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was thinking of Lou Brown.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lou Brown?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is hardly an impressive credential to Donovan.</context>
      <utterance>He's managed the Toledo Mud Hens of the International League for the last 30 years.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think he'll fit right in with our team concept.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What exactly is our team concept?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I wanted to talk to you about. I want to put together a team that will help us relocate to Miami.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?  Some of these guys are furniture movers?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel bends down to give her dog, Cha-Cha, a little love pat, while Donovan tries to contain his disgust.</context>
      <utterance>I'm serious about this, Charlie. It's no secret I've never liked Cleveland much. The weather's lousy, downtown is a pit, the stadium's falling apart, and we can't draw dick. Another couple of years of this and I'm gonna have to start feeding Cha-Cha dog food.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Phelps, you can't just up and move a team on a whim...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's hardly a whim. Miami's offered to build us a new stadium -- 62,000 capacity, 45 V.I.P. boxes, and no rent for the first million at the gate. Plus a 12 million dollar media guarantee; 45 percent of the concession gross, all of the parking and they pick up the stadium operations costs. No other franchise in baseball can match that deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even so, the League'll never let us leave Cleveland. We got a lease with the city.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donovan looks at it, the paragraph highlighted in yellow.</context>
      <utterance>The lease says we have the right to move if our attendance falls below 800,000 for the year.  Paragraph 40, line 17.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we play bad enough, we should be able to come in under that.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you saying? You want us to lose?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donovan is stunned. He casts around helplessly for some response.</context>
      <utterance>No, we've been losing. What I want us to do is finish dead last.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mister Phelps would never have approved of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On Donovan's sunken face, we go to:</context>
      <utterance>He knew it had to be done. He just didn't have the courage to do it.  Hopefully, you will come to see the wisdom of it.  If this team lives up to its potential, we could have the worst record in all baseball.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's Charlie Donovan calling from his office in Cleveland. We CUT BACK AND FORTH between the two as we will in subsequent phone scenes.</context>
      <utterance>Yeh.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Jake? This is Charlie Donovan, new G.M. of the Cleveland Indians.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh...</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanted to call and say the organization remembers you fondly from the years you played here and we'd love to have you come to spring training for a shot at this year's club.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taylor struggles to get a look up at the girl on top of him.</context>
      <utterance>Is that you, Tolbert? This isn't very funny, ya know. I'm hung over. My knees are killin' me. If you were gonna pull this shit, you could've at least said you were from the Yankees.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donovan is baffled by this whole line of conversation.</context>
      <utterance>By the way, you were with me last night. Who's this girl on top of me?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taylor hangs up, leaving Donovan staring into his phone. Taylor looks up to see TOLBERT standing in the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>Tolbert? Tolbert? Screw it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tolbert.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOLBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On Taylor's reaction, we...</context>
      <utterance>Who the hell were you talkin' to?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lines three and four are waiting for you, Mr. Brown. One guy about the TR- 70's.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tire World.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For a moment there's silence on the line, then:</context>
      <utterance>Lou? This is Charlie Donovan, the new G.M. of the Cleveland Indians. Listen, Lou, I hope you're sittin' down 'cause I got an offer you probably been dreamin' about your whole life. We been watchin' your progress down there at Toledo with a lotta interest and well...  How would you like to manage the Indians this year?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know...</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do ya mean you don't know? This is a chance to manage in the big leagues.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brown clicks off. Donovan puts his head down on his desk.</context>
      <utterance>Lemme think it over, will ya, Charlie. I got a guy on the other line about some whitewalls. I'll talk to ya later.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rick, we heard about your pitching out at Portland last year...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn has been working, sweating slightly. He takes off his cap to mop his brow -- revealing a RADICAL HAIRCUT with PIGTAIL. He sports a RING in his left ear.</context>
      <utterance>I'm, ah, not with them anymore...</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'd still like to take a look at ya at our spring camp in Arizona, March first.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh, well, I'm not sure I can make it by then.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, we're gettin' you out on a sort of work furlough deal. Any questions?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh. Where's Cleveland?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Lou, you been in baseball thirty years. Don't you wanna advance some?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel rubs her fingers together, making the money sign to Donovan.</context>
      <utterance>I used to coach the unwed mothers' softball team. I have advanced some.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what are you really worried about? The money?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naw, I'm just not sure I'd be happy in a big organization like that. Owners are always on your back, tryin' to "help you out."</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think that's gonna be a problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Down here baseball's a game, not a business. I don't wanta be a babysitter for a buncha millionaires who think they know it all already.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't have any millionaires.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well then, bonus babies or whatever you got...</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't have any bonus babies either.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you have any proven major league talent?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not that I know of.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, then... I'll be up in a couple days.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brown hangs up.</context>
      <utterance>Sounds like my kinda team. Have my contracts ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guess I really put the screws to him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taylor goes to the phone in the clubhouse tunnel.</context>
      <utterance>Taylor, telephone for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jake, Charlie Donovan again.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeh, Charlie, look, I'm sorry about this morning...</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No problem. Look, Jake, camp starts on the first. Can you make it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You been stayin' in shape down there?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh hell, yeh, I work out every day.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donovan hangs up. Taylor shoots a fist in the air, and we...</context>
      <utterance>I thought so. See ya in Arizona.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>approaching his MANAGER.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go, Taylor. You're up.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luis, I'm not gonna be playin' anymore. I got a tryout in the States.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine. Leave your uniform.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I changed at the motel.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave your uniform.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brown turns around from a conversation with Temple.</context>
      <utterance>This looks like Jake Taylor.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was an Allstar in Boston, wasn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wish we had him two years ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We did.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four years ago then.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to the private rooms?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEMPLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're on an austerity program. This is what happens when you finish 24 games out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it's Cerrano. Defected from Cuba. Wanted religious freedom.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's his religion?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Voodoo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thought you didn't have any high- priced talent.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I forgot about Dorn, 'cause he's only high-priced. Got him as a free agent three years ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still hits the ball pretty well, doesn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dorn pulls his golf clubs out of the car.</context>
      <utterance>Yeh, he just can't field it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll shape him up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hayes strolls up and introduces himself.</context>
      <utterance>Don't recognize this guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say hey, Willie Mays Hayes here. I play like Mays and run like Hayes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lou Brown. Nice to meet ya, Hayes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hayes hustles off toward his car.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks. Well, I gotta get my stuff...</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A motorcycle pulls to a stop in the lot, diverting everyone's attention from Hayes. Off steps Ricky Vaughn, a hefty bag over his shoulder. He's still sporting his radical do.</context>
      <utterance>I don't remember a Hayes on the list.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at this fuckin' guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEMPLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donovan is speechless. Brown breaks into a small smile. Yes, sir, this is his kinda team.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe he's the mascot.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn whips a hard glance at Dorn, but keeps on walking, making his way along the bunks looking for his assigned bed. It's the one above Taylor. Vaughn unloads his duffel bag in silence.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, what do we have here? Guy looks like a fuckin' toilet brush. Hey, T.B., I love your pony tail. And the earring's cute too. Where's the matching bracelet?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn shakes it and nods. Says nothing.</context>
      <utterance>Jake Taylor.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, you just gonna settle for toilet brush, or you got another name?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vaughn. Rick Vaughn.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The conversation is interrupted by the arrival of Hayes.</context>
      <utterance>Forget about Dorn. He's always a little tough on rookies. You'll get a lot worse from other teams.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say hey! How ya doin'? Willie Mays Hayes here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hayes doesn't quite know what to make of Vaughn.</context>
      <utterance>Jake Taylor.  Rick Vaughn.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell league you been playin' in?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>California Penal.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never heard of it. How'd you wind up playin' there?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On Hayes' look, we...</context>
      <utterance>I stole a car.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Hayes, let's do 'em right.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, my philosophy is no pain, no pain.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How the knees holdin' up, Jake?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great. Never been better.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mobility's good? No problem gettin' off the throw to second?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need a catcher, Jake. Somebody who can keep this team together on the field. You were a helluva player when you were sound, but around the league they think you can't take the pounding anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Around the league they're wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna have to put you to the test, ya know. So, I want the absolute truth here. Are you 100 percent?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh. Would I bullshit about somethin' like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hayes gets in and takes his stance. On the first pitch, he takes a mighty cut and hits a pop-fly to the pitcher's mound. We take QUICK CUTS of the next three pitches. Hayes takes prodigious swings at all of them, producing three more pop- ups, none out of the infield. Brown calls a halt.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Hayes, this isn't the All Star Game. Get up to the damn plate.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you may run like Mays, but you hit like shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My stroke'll come back once I get warmed up.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEMPLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never did get warmed up last year. Hit .211 at Maine. I looked him up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think Mr. Hayes shows some promise. His speed could be a big asset.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For what? Running back to the dugout?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta stop swingin' for the fences though, Hayes. All you're gonna do is give yourself a hernia. With your speed you should be hittin' the ball on the ground, leggin' 'em out. Every time I see you hit one in the air, you owe me twenty pushups.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The next pitch comes in. Hayes swings and pops it up.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, no problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he gets down to do his twenty, Brown turns to Temple.</context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes you can teach a guy to hit. You can't teach him to run.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brown and Pepper stand behind Taylor for a better view. Vaughn goes into his wind-up and fires a screaming fast ball that Taylor has no chance to get out of his crouch to catch. The ball rockets an inch over Brown's head, and slams into the backstop. Brown stands frozen a second, contemplating his brush with eternity, then turns to Pepper.</context>
      <utterance>All right, Vaughn, they tell us you're a pitcher. Let's see what you got.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice velocity.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounded like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brown turns to the Clubhouse Man who's holding a speed gun.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Lou, I wasn't quite expectin' that much octane.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLUBHOUSE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>96 miles an hour.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better teach him some control before he kills somebody.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Dorn, get in front of the damn ball.  Don't give me this ole' bullshit.</utterance>
   <speaker>DORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I took one of these in the eye last year. Nearly lost my sight.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm deeply moved. Every time you play it off your hip, you give me forty sit-ups.</utterance>
   <speaker>DORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What! That's Little League shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brown strikes an effeminate fielding position, like Betty Grable shying from a mouse. Dorn burns.</context>
      <utterance>So is this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, this guy hits a ton. How come nobody else picked up on him?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEMPLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harris winds and throws a fair-to-middlin' curve ball. Cerrano swings and misses it a foot.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, Harris, that's enough fast balls. Throw some curves.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dorn approaches Brown at the cage.</context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>DORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lou, I wanna have a word with you here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit, the way I played today, I wouldn't be surprised if they red- tagged me already.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do ya mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn's hand freezes on his locker latch, afraid to open it now.</context>
      <utterance>Red tag in your locker means the manager wants to see you, 'cause you just died and went to the minors.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn is still not so sure. He sits down on his locker stool and glances over toward STEVE HARRIS a starting pitcher, whose locker is adjacent. As Harris takes off his jersey we see three SPLOTCHES OF GREASY SUBSTANCES on his chest, just inside the button line.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, they don't cut anybody the first day.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is that stuff?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn can't believe this.</context>
      <utterance>Crisco, Bardahl, Vagisil. Any one of 'em will give you another 2-3 inches drop on your curve ball.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Course if it's cold and I got a shirt on under my jersey, I just rub a little jalapeno inside my nose and get it runnin'. I need to load up the ball a little, I just wipe my nose.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You put snot on the ball?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn just looks at him incredulous.</context>
      <utterance>At my age, you put anything you can find on it. I haven't got an arm like yours.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doin' there, Pedro?</utterance>
   <speaker>CERRANO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bats. They are sick.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So are mine. Is somethin' goin' around?</utterance>
   <speaker>CERRANO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No hit curve ball. Straight ball, hit it very much. Curve ball, bats are afraid. I ask Jo-Buu to come. Take fear from bats.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jo-Buu?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe he's the pagan saint of baseball.</utterance>
   <speaker>CERRANO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cerrano pours some gin in a small cup and puts it next to the fetish doll. Harris has been listening to all this. Cerrano grabs a towel to head for the showers.</context>
      <utterance>I offer him cigars and gin. He will come.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't leave this gin sittin' around out here with this group.</utterance>
   <speaker>CERRANO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cerrano closes his locker and goes off to the showers, leaving everyone to wonder just how bad.</context>
      <utterance>Is very bad to steal Jo-Buu's gin. Is very bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>OMIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is final cut down day, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh, better get your snake ready, Hayes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hayes reveals a pair of red and cut hands.</context>
      <utterance>No, I'm goin' cold turkey today. My hands are too screwed up to hold it anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They've reached the locker room now.</context>
      <utterance>If you're gonna use that head first slide, you better get yourself some gloves or you're not gonna have any skin left on your hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't wanna go in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever happens, keep it to yourself until you're outta the locker room. Don't celebrate in front of guys who just died.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taylor goes into the locker room. Hayes and Vaughn hang back. Cerrano is already at his locker. He's got two snakes this time and some kind of voodoo head dress on. He sprays a patch of white paint on the locker door from a spray can, draws a symbol door. No tag. He kisses the snake, leaving some white paint on his lips, like a kid who's just had a glass of milk. Taylor, exhausted from the game, lifts his latch and peers inside. He's made it, too. Cerrano offers a hand. Taylor shakes it and breaks a weary smile.</context>
      <utterance>What if we're one of the deceased?</utterance>
   <speaker>GENTRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>opens locker, slumps on stool. He's a goner.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES AND VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>the two rookies, are still hanging back.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hayes strides manfully to his locker and pulls it open. This doesn't tell him much, however, because he's got his eyes closed. He stands that way a beat ot two, then opens one eye. Seeing no tag, he turns and walks double-time out of the locker room, as if he had to get to the john. He comes outside, turns a corner, and starts leaping around like a wild man.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Vaughn, let's show some nuts here. If they cut us, we'll just sign with the Yankees.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got news for you, Mr. Brown. You haven't heard the last of me. You think I'm shit now, but someday you'll be sorry you cut me. I'm gonna catch on somewhere else, and every time I pitch against you, I'm gonna stick it up your ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good, I like that kinda spirit in a player. The only problem is, I didn't cut you.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We GO TO Vaughn, his faced a mask of anger and embarrassment.</context>
      <utterance>I think somebody's been havin' fun with you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The team breaks into applause and whistles as Taylor's name is announced. Dorn is the only one who seems unhappy about it. As Taylor accepts the congratulations of his teammates, he turns to Vaughn.</context>
      <utterance>Can I have your attention, please? I counted up your ballots for team captain and I think you chose the right guy. If you hadn't, I woulda told you he won anyway. Mr. C for the year -- Jake Taylor.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget about Dorn. You got other things to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taylor gives him a wide smile. Vaughn finally allows himself one.</context>
      <utterance>Packing for Cleveland.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see the new lineup the Indians got?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never heard of most of 'em.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BUSINESS EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know the majority of these names.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONGSHOREMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are these fuckin' guys?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really got all of that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taylor is too embarrassed to reply.</context>
      <utterance>What was it? A slider?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you gonna have?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. What language is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>French.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They got patty melts over there?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three raise their wine glasses.</context>
      <utterance>Forget it. I'll order. Let's have a toast.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The glasses CLINK. Suddenly Taylor's attention fixes on something across the room -- a stunning young woman in her late twenties, LYNN WESTLAND. She's having dinner with a DATE in a three-piece suit. Hayes and Vaughn follow Taylor's eyes to the woman.</context>
      <utterance>Here's to baseball, here's to the start of two great careers, and for me, here's to at least one more good year in the sun.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it? The chick?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's my wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does she know it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean she woulda been if I hadn't screwed it up. Who's that guy she's with?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. He's not wearing a name tag.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want me to beat the shit out of him?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does she do?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's a librarian.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A librarian? Shit, I gotta start readin' again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lynn is somewhat surprised, but gets up to take the call. We FOLLOW her to the pay phone in the hall.</context>
      <utterance>Miss Wells, there's a telephone call for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Lynn. It's Jake.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jake? How did you know I was here?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is indeed. Lynn is a little unsettled by this display of clairvoyance.</context>
      <utterance>Just a hunch. I took you there when you got your masters. I figure you're probably wearing the black velvet dress with the red sash.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sensing that something's askew, she turns and looks across the way to see Jake talking to her on the pay phone on the other side of the hall, maybe ten feet away. He gives her his best grin.</context>
      <utterance>How did you know that? I didn't have this dress when we were...</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lynn, as is often the case with Jake, is both charmed and put-out. She goes with put-out.</context>
      <utterance>You look great.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. What are you doin' here? Aren't you supposed to be in Mexico somewhere?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm playin' with the Indians again. Back in the Bigs.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she is. Not so sure about herself, though.</context>
      <utterance>That's great. I'm happy for you, Jake.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta get back...</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute. What's your number. I tried calling you at home, but you're not listed...</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My life is different from when you knew me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meaning what? That I don't know you anymore?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Couldn't we talk about this some other time? I really gotta...</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, just gimme your number.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think that's a good idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not? Because of the guy you're with? What is he, a banker?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lawyer. Please, Jake, he's watching us.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not leavin' without your number. You still wear those great little tortoise-shell glasses? I always loved it when you took them off.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jake...</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The number, Lynn...</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. 555-9314.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him a beat, unsure what to say, then heads back toward her table. We go to Lynn's date. None of this has been lost on him.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you. I'm back, Lynn, and I'm gonna be around.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the number again?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this place?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Cabbie pulls to a stop and points to the other side of the street.</context>
      <utterance>Furnished apartment building owned by the Indians. We get special rates. With what we're makin' we'll need it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taylor and the others turn to see a dismal, run-down building with a neon sign that says "The Turk."</context>
      <utterance>That's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome to the Big Leagues.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VOICE ON PHONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taylor doesn't like the sound of this.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Cuyahoga Sheet Metal.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got anybody workin' there named Lynn Wells?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE ON PHONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never heard of her.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taylor hangs up, staring off into space.</context>
      <utterance>Didn't think so.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lou Brown enters the locker room.</context>
      <utterance>Take it easy. We got 162 of these to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The players turn their attention to Brown.</context>
      <utterance>All right, let's gather 'round.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cheers all around.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not much for inspirational addresses. I just wanta point out that every newspaper in the country has picked us to finish last. The local press thinks we'd save everybody a lot of time and trouble if we just went out and shot ourselves. Me, I like to waste sportswriters' time so I'm for hangin' around and seein' if we can give all these guys a nice big shitburger to eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't we gonna have a prayer? I mean we're not all savages like Cerrano.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys go ahead. I belong to the church of three-run homers.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Many of the players follow suit. Suddenly the silence is shattered by a loud explosive SOUND, scaring the hell out of everybody. All eyes turn to Cerrano, who has just set off a charge of gunpowder on his locker altar.</context>
      <utterance>All right, let's bow our heads.</utterance>
   <speaker>CERRANO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Disgusted, Harris and the others turn back to their prayers.</context>
      <utterance>Have to wake up bats.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harris never gets to finish. The smoke rising from Cerrano's gunpowder explosion sets off the automatic sprinklers in the ceiling. As Harris and the faithful look up into the downpour, we...</context>
      <utterance>Dear Lord, we ask...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You read the Plain Dealer today? They said this is gonna be the worst Indian team we've had in years.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody laughs at the Indians now, but there were other times. Even won the Series in '48. Then Willie Mays made that catch on Vic Wertz in the '54 Series and Cleveland's never been the same since.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As the Indians go so goes Cleveland, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we ever lost the Indians, Cleveland would die.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, everybody, Harry Doyle here, welcoming all you Friends of the Feather to another season of Indians baseball.  A lotta new faces for the tribe this year, as they take on the defending American League champs, the New York Yankees. And listen to the roar of the crowd as the Indians takes the field! Doyle leans out the press box window with his mike, trying to pick up the sound of a couple guys CLAPPING down below.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doyle takes a hit of his spiked Coke.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir, they love this club here in Cleveland.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bottom of the first, Willie Mays Hayes to lead it off for the tribe.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>going through his warmup routine at the plate.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Hayes is in the batter's box now. The Yankee pitcher winds and fires. Hayes swings and hits a little dribbler toward the second baseman, who races in and scoops it up bare-handed.</context>
      <utterance>A lotta people say you can tell how a season's gonna go by the first hitter of the year. In the last fifteen years, the Indians have never had the season lead-off hitter reach base.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Doyle leans out the window again trying to pick up some cheering.</context>
      <utterance>Hot shot toward the hole. Rudia knocks it down, gets up, fires to first. Too late! Hayes beats it!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And so the string is broken. Maybe things will turn around a little for the Indians this year.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>FIRST BASEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Showed some real power on that one, Slugger.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hayes reaches in his back pocket and pulls out one of the pairs of black leather gloves he bought earlier.</context>
      <utterance>I plan to get at least a double out of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And now Hayes is putting on a pair of black gloves, sending a little message to the Yankees.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hayes takes his lead-off and crouches, ready to steal.</context>
      <utterance>Bought a hundred of these, one for each base I plan to steal. Excuse me, here, I gotta take my first step toward the Hall of Fame.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST BASEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hayes looks down at his shoe. It's not untied. He notices too late that the PITCHER is throwing over to pick him off.</context>
      <utterance>You look real sharp, but you'll never steal second with your shoe untied.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Hayes dives back for the bag, but never gets there; his face smashing up against the First Baseman's glove, which is already holding the ball.</context>
      <utterance>Brewster, quick move to first...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He got him. Hayes is picked off.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST BASEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hayes lies in the dust humiliated.</context>
      <utterance>Nice base running, dildo. Hard to get your thumb out of your ass with the gloves on.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doyle takes a long pull on his Coke and we GO INTO A MONTAGE depicting the Indians' progressive disintegration in this game. We see: A) THREE FIELDERS converging on a short pop fly into left field. They all collide and go down in a heap as the ball drops untouched. B) DORN playing a grounder off his hip. He fumbles it, picks it up, fumbles it again. No play. C) TAYLOR crouched behind the plate, but up off his haunches, ready to throw. We hear the voice of his thoughts.</context>
      <utterance>Well, so much for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The runner on first takes off as the pitch comes in. Taylor catches the ball and fires down to second. The ball sails three feet over the second baseman's head and on into center field. Taylor stands there, disgusted.</context>
      <utterance>Guy's goin'. Gotta be goin'... get the throw up. Don't bounce the damn ball.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D) CERRANO striking out on a curve ball. He bawls his bat out on the way to the dugout. E) THE THREE FIELDERS we saw before, converging on another pop fly into short left. This time all three dive off at the last instant to avoid a collision. Once again the ball drops untouched.</context>
      <utterance>Nice throw, dickhead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn stands on the mound rubbing up the baseball with the same intensity we saw in the locker room.</context>
      <utterance>Top of the sixth. Rookie sensation, Ricky Vaughn, on to pitch now. You can close the book on Winters...</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy does it, Ricky. We're only four down. We're still in this thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn nods and continues to grind the ball as Pepper and Taylor leave. The Yankee Hitter steps in. Vaughn winds and fires a screamer. Taylor has to leap high to come down with it.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry if you're off the plate on a few pitches. Doesn't hurt to put the fear of God in a hitter.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The Yankee Hitter is slightly unnerved by this pitch.</context>
      <utterance>First pitch is a little high...</utterance>
   <speaker>YANKEE HITTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This guy kinda wild?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANOTHER PITCH to the Yankee hitter. It's outside.</context>
      <utterance>I figure you got a 30% chance to survive this at bat.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>ANOTHER PITCH to a SECOND YANKEE HITTER. It's low.</context>
      <utterance>Ball four.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>ANOTHER PITCH to a THIRD YANKEE HITTER. He has to jump over it.</context>
      <utterance>Ball eight.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Low, and Vaughn has walked the bases loaded on twelve straight pitches. By the laws of probability, you'd think one of those coulda drifted over the plate.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pepper has reached the mound...</context>
      <utterance>Wild thing, You make my heart sing, You walk everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn nods. He's plenty upset with himself.</context>
      <utterance>Okay kid. I think we got 'em scared enough now. Time to get a few of 'em out.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives Vaughn a pat on the butt, and goes back to the dugout. The Yankee hitter, HAYWOOD, stands in. He's the first baseman who tagged Hayes out.</context>
      <utterance>Just relax, and keep the arm up on top. Gotta throw strikes. No place at the inn for this guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Taylor, what you doin' back up here?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn, determined to throw a strike, winds and delivers. The ball is a perfect strike, right down the middle. Haywood crushes it to deep left field. Vaughn drops his head, not even bothering to look.</context>
      <utterance>Couldn't cut it in the Mexican League.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ball lands in the second deck; a grand slam home run.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, shit...</utterance>
   <speaker>PEPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looked like a strike anyway. You want me to go get him?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn paces around on the mound, rubbing up the ball. The next hitter, COLEMAN, steps in. Vaughn gets up on the rubber, his face set. He winds up and fires one right into Coleman's back. Coleman goes down in a hurry.</context>
      <utterance>No, let's see how he reacts.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Interesting.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least he hit what he was aimin' at.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both benches are up on the dugout steps ready to come out. The only thing holding them back is that Coleman is being tended to by the trainer. The home plate umpire thumbs Vaughn out of the game. Vaughn comes down to protest, but Pepper quickly grabs him and hurries him off the field.</context>
      <utterance>I think you can go get him now.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Coleman finally gets to his feet, still a little shaken. He looks around for Vaughn, but he's already disappeared into the dugout. Coleman walks down to first under his own power. Brown signals for a new pitcher and the players on both sides begin to return to the benches.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, kid. As soon as Coleman gets up, he's gonna be lookin' for you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, I was horse shit tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only thing you got to be sorry about was hittin' Coleman.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn nods slowly.</context>
      <utterance>If you wanted to send a message, it shoulda been to Haywood. He hit the damn homer. Coleman was just picking his nose in the on-deck circle.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget the other stuff. It coulda happened to anybody. Besides, Haywood didn't hit it that good. That ball wouldn't have been out of a lotta parks.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeh, name one.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn just looks at Taylor a second and then smiles in spite of himself.</context>
      <utterance>Yellowstone.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="42">
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jake, you shouldn't have come here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was wonderin' why you'd give an old friend a bum phone number.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's talk in my office, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lynn starts to walk. We'll FOLLOW them as they make their way through the library. Lynn tries to keep the conversation hushed. Taylor could give a shit.</context>
      <utterance>I don't wanna talk in your office.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you I don't think it's a good idea for us to see each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't have anything in common. Sometimes I wonder if we ever did.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talkin' about? We were both athletes, world class, hot for each other. What more can you have in common?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jake suppresses a smile.</context>
      <utterance>I stopped bein' an athlete three years ago. Books are my life now.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you dare laugh, Jake. In two years I've put together one of the best special collections departments in the country.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what is it? You're still sore I never read Moby Dick?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You never read anything I asked you to.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not like what's-his-name at the restaurant?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His name is Tom, and keep your voice down.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do ya see in this guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's stable. He's intelligent... and I've never found him in bed with a stewardess.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's 'cause no stewardess would have him. Wouldn't you rather be with somebody who's in demand?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just like always, you don't take anything seriously. Everything's a joke to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lynn stops and turns to face him.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Lynn, for Christ sake, I'm just tryin' to loosen things up a little. I'm gettin' frostbite here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taylor is momentarily floored by the revelation.</context>
      <utterance>Tom and I are getting married in the fall.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? That's crazy, Lynn. I got plans for us.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What plans?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was gonna play another a year or two, then we go to Hawaii, and have a couple kids who grow up to be Olympic champions.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you think stuff like that? I haven't seen you in two years. You never even wrote me a letter.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Lynn, but I wasn't exactly proud of my situation. C'mon, you didn't think about me at all since I been gone?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not so loud, Jake.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember the three nights we spent on the beach in Vera Cruz? You have nights like that with Mr. Briefcase?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're in the large reading room now.</context>
      <utterance>What about the night you had in Detroit with Miss Dairy Queen?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was I supposed to do? She bet me fifty bucks she had a better body than you. I had to defend your honor.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With this the whole reading room turns around and stares at her. Lynn is mortified by her outburst. Taylor tries to smooth it over.</context>
      <utterance>What a bunch of bullshit!  I have a much better body than she does.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nice job, Jake. Lynn is still mortified.</context>
      <utterance>She's right. Take it from me, she really does. I mean Miss Dairy Queen has quantity, I give her that, but the, ah, quality just isn't there.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Most of the hands in the room shoot up.</context>
      <utterance>How many think Lynn oughta give me another shot?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ayes have it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You haven't changed at all, have you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid I have or I wouldn't be here. C'mon, Lynn, I don't wanna do time for things that happened years ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lynn starts off for her office door.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Jake. You'll always be the little boy who wouldn't grow up.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lynn continues on into her office. As the door closes, we GO TO Taylor's forlorn face.</context>
      <utterance>Lynn, wait...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A quarter of the season's gone, we're 15 and 24, seven games out of first. Our attendance is just below 180,000. That's bad, but not bad enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Projected over the whole season, we stand to wind up 36 games under .500 and 28 out of first. That should be bad enough for anybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We finished 24 out last year and still drew 890,000. When school's out for the summer, attendance is liable to rise. Plus, this team is showing signs of improvement. I didn't think we'd win 15 games all year. Any ideas?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On how we can get worse?  How about a series of fines for good play? Maybe a $30,000 bonus to the guy chosen Least Valuable Player.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Donovan wonders what she means by that, we...</context>
      <utterance>This is no laughing matter, Donovan.  I think maybe the problem is we're coddling these guys too much.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's with this? We never leave from this terminal.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They come through the gate where they see two American Airlines jets on the tarmac.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe the other one's jammed up.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which one is ours?</utterance>
   <speaker>GATEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The gateman points off-screen. Suddenly, an old DC-3, with the Indian logo on it, pulls into frame.</context>
      <utterance>That one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this, Lou?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Front office says it's an economy measure, 'cause we're not drawin' good.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We PICK UP Cerrano crossing himself. Harris sees it.</context>
      <utterance>Well, they certainly have spared every expense.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hayes sits petrified in his chair, his knuckles whitening on the arm rest.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, so now you come around.  He's not fooled.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call the stewardess, Vaughn. I need one of those bags.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There aren't any stewardesses.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wonder if there's any pilots.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bouncing ball to second. This should be it. Collins up with it, on to first, and the game is over.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>in the press box again.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, the Sons of Geronimo, still suffering a bit from propeller lag, are nipped by the Tigers tonight, 7 to 0. The only excitement for the tribe provided by Rick Vaughn who set an American League record by throwing four wild pitches in one inning. Congratulations, Rick. For the Tigers, 5 runs, 9 hits, and no errors. For the Indians, one run, and let's see, one hit.  Is that all we got, one fucking hit?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAT MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't say "fuckin'" on the air.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about it. Nobody's listening anyway.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HARRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who you got lined up tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>DORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are we? Kansas City, right? Gotta be Arlene</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You call her?</utterance>
   <speaker>DORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't have to. She knows when I'm in town.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A GUY from the bar approaches the table.</context>
      <utterance>I'm about ready to turn in. I've anesthetized my knees enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, Mr. Vaughn, can I have your autograph?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah... yeh... sure.  My first autograph. I couldn't give these away a couple weeks ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw your record on the news. You made their Hall of Shame. Congratulations.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a celebrity now, Vaughn.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you had to do somethin' good to be a celebrity.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not if you do it colorfully.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>DORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We GO TO the door to find ARLENE standing with two friends, RENE and VICKI. ARLENE is a looker alright, 27, and seriously built. She cases the room, spies Dorn and comes over to his table.</context>
      <utterance>What'd I tell ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARLENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Rodger. This is Vicki and Rene.</utterance>
   <speaker>DORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, doll. This is Steve Harris.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARLENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's your buddy Gant?</utterance>
   <speaker>DORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They cut him to make room for bristle boy over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARLENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that Vaughn, the guy they call Wild Thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>DORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARLENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's kinda cute. They say he could be a big star.</utterance>
   <speaker>DORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talkin' about? He couldn't find the plate if it was magnetized. He won't last the year.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARLENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He struck out five in a row before the wild pitches.  Maybe I'll check him out.</utterance>
   <speaker>DORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taylor watches this exchange from across the room.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute, you're with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARLENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't remember you makin' any date.</utterance>
   <speaker>DORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since when do I have to make a date? Who's been showin' you this town the last three years?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARLENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ARLENE pulls away and heads for the jukebox as Dorn seethes. She punches a button and we hear X's version of "WILD THING." ARLENE sashays right up to Vaughn in time with the music.</context>
      <utterance>Ancient history, Rodger. I gotta look out for myself now. I don't have to be a slave to no .235 hitter.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARLENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ARLENE knows how to make the big entrance. Vaughn's slightly overwhelmed.</context>
      <utterance>Wild Thing, you make my heart sing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guess we're over with, eh, Dorn?</utterance>
   <speaker>DORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Speak for yourself, Taylor. I got a couple good years left.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Moby Dick?" What is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's one of the masterpieces of American literature, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lynn put you on to this?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Long time ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we're goin' to a club tonight. You wanna come along?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taylor indicates a stack of Classic Comics next to him.</context>
      <utterance>No, I got some more reading to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, you got a test or somethin'? Why don't you just go over and see her? Maybe she'll let you slide on a couple of these.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I might if I knew where she lives.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy. Tail her home from the library.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean sit in a car and wait for her to come out? That's kinda juvenile, don't you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="44">
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Lynn, I'm sorry I followed you home but I wanna...</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't my place...</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Lynn can answer, Tom appears at the door.</context>
      <utterance>Whose place is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's there, love?  Oh, Mr. Taylor, right?  I remember you from the restaurant. Lynn's told me a lot about you. Why don't you come in for a while?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah, that's o.k., I got some things to do...</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh, he's gotta be goin'...</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Taylor can beg off further, Tom ushers him inside and closes the door. In the room are two other couples: ARTHUR HOLLOWAY, a senior partner in Tom's firm and his wife CLAIRE, and BRENT BOWDEN, another lawyer in the firm and a contemporary of Tom's. His wife is JANICE. This is a very upscale group.</context>
      <utterance>No, really, come on in for a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Polite nods from the group, except for Janice, who seems somewhat intrigued.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, everybody, this is Jake Taylor.  Jake, Arthur and Claire Holloway Brent and Janice Bowden. Jake is a professional baseball player.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, Jake, what brings you here this evening?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I, ah, just had a couple books I wanted to discuss with Lynn. I thought this was her place.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it soon will be.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taylor sticks out his hand. Tom's not sure whether Taylor's putting him on or not. He shakes anyway.</context>
      <utterance>Yeh, I heard you guys were engaged. Congratulations.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. What can I get you to drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tom goes off to get the beer.</context>
      <utterance>Beer'll be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What team do you play for, Jake?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Indians.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here in Cleveland? I didn't know they still had a team.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh, we have uniforms and everything. It's really great.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm told that baseball players make very good salaries these days.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That depends on how good they are, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lynn is irritated by Janice's directness.</context>
      <utterance>How good are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tom and the others react as if Taylor's just announced a death in the family.</context>
      <utterance>I make the League minimum.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone is somewhat surprised by Lynn's quick defense of Taylor, including Lynn herself.</context>
      <utterance>He was one of the best in baseball until he had problems with his knees.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you going to do when your career ends? I mean you can't play baseball forever, can you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somethin'll come up.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, I was thinkin' of goin' to Hawaii, and having a couple of kids who grow up to be Olympic champions.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh really. In what event?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack just nods. He never heard of it.</context>
      <utterance>Swimming. Maybe the two hundred meter Individual Medley. I figure it oughta be big by then.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got the girl picked out?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lynn's eyes drop to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>I did, but I wasn't smart enough to hold on to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You used to be an athlete, didn't you, Lynn?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two Hundred Individual medley.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A tense silence settles on the group.</context>
      <utterance>Alternate on the '80 Olympic Team.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taylor exchanges a quick glance with Lynn and heads for the door.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I gotta be goin'. Nice to have met you all.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tom accompanies Taylor to the door, out of earshot of the others.</context>
      <utterance>Let me walk you out.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the beer.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't mention it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll let you know if I land a good job. I know you're concerned about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tom sticks out his hand. The two men shake to keep up appearances for their onlookers across the room.</context>
      <utterance>Yeh, well, I just wanted Lynn to know what she would've had ahead of her.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay away from her.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Suck my dick.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn comes in and takes a seat. He's worried.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon in, Rick.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn nods contritely.</context>
      <utterance>Rick, I'm not gonna beat around the bush here. You got a great arm, one of the best I've ever seen, but your control hasn't come around like we hoped it would.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn looks at the picture on the wall. He squints slightly. Brown notices it.</context>
      <utterance>Now, there are a lotta pitchers that started out wild and, after workin' it out in the minors, for a while, went on to great careers.  Take Sandy Koufax there...</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Koufax?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brown quickly prints some big letters on a legal pad and goes to stand about fifteen feet from Vaughn.</context>
      <utterance>Never mind Koufax.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn balks a second and then concentrates on the pad, squinting. Unsettled, he squints harder. He even tries closing one eye.</context>
      <utterance>Read these letters, starting at the top.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn shakes his head no.</context>
      <utterance>Can't read it, can you?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gonna send me to the minors?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nope.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These things make me look ridiculous.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meanwhile, Cerrano is sharpening a long knife at his locker.</context>
      <utterance>Drop in the bucket, Vaughn.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that for?</utterance>
   <speaker>CERRANO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gin and cigarettes not enough for Jo- Buu. I still can no hit curva ball for sheet. I hafta make a sacrifice to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sacrifice? You mean like something living?</utterance>
   <speaker>CERRANO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Si. I kill unborn children.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cerrano pulls the unborn chicken out of his pocket -- a common store bought egg. Harris is a little embarrassed at his outburst. Cerrano touches the egg to his forehead, then places it on his altar. In one swift motion he slams the knife down on it, cutting it into two perfect halves. Taylor and the others are agape at a knife sharp enough to do this. As the yolk spreads out on the altar, Brown emerges from his office.</context>
      <utterance>Not while I'm here you're not. That's murder.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The locker room quickly empties, leaving one man behind -- Harris. He looks around to make sure everyone is gone, then tiptoes over to Cerrano's locker. Screwing up his courage, he picks up Jo-Buu's cup of gin.</context>
      <utterance>All right, let's hit the field.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bolts it down, then backs into the middle of the room, waiting at the ready, as if half-expecting a bolt of lightning. When nothing happens, he gloats at the fetish doll in triumph.</context>
      <utterance>Here's looking at ya, Jo-Buu.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're in the ninth, two down, man on first and the Indians clinging to a one run lead. VAUGHAN, one out away from his first major league victory...</utterance>
   <speaker>OMIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Vaughn stomps around on the mound, obviously upset. He glares at Dorn a beat before getting back on the mound. Dorn's face is non-commital. Brown paces in the dugout.</context>
      <utterance>Bouncing ball, Dorn can't get to it, into left field, base hit. Clarke digging around second, he'll make it to third, and the A's have runners at the corners.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want me to go get him?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doyle downs a little more rum and coke in the press box.</context>
      <utterance>No, he's come this far. Let's see if he can finish it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doyle imitates the sound of a crowd cheering with his own voice, punctuated by whistles and clapping.</context>
      <utterance>Vaughn in a little trouble here, but I'll tell ya, these Cleveland fans are great. Listen to them get behind Vaughn.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need some defense here. Maybe we oughta do a wave.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Indians don't do waves. Let's keep this thing pure.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What harm could it do?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Taylor walks out in front of the plate to throw the ball back to Vaughn.</context>
      <utterance>Runner goes, high, Taylor has no play. The go-ahead and potential winning run is in scoring position.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taylor goes back behind the dish. Vaughn gets up on the rubber. He winds and comes to the plate. Way high this time.</context>
      <utterance>Forget the runners, Ricky, get this guy at the plate.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doyle imitates the sound of a crowd booing. Taylor, meanwhile, has gone out to the mound.</context>
      <utterance>High ball two, and the crowd doesn't like that call one bit.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, let's get nasty here, Rick. You know he's lookin' for this pitch. Gotta come up with somethin' studly.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuckin' Dorn. Game shoulda been over by now. Dorn coulda had that ball. He tanked it on purpose.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn nods.</context>
      <utterance>This isn't the California Penal League, Vaughn. We're professionals here. We don't tank a play for personal reasons, so cut the crybaby shit. You've pitched a helluva game. You wanna finish it, don't ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you give me a strike on this pitch?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh, but I don't know if there'll be much on it. My arm feels like jello.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just make sure it's over the plate. I want him to swing.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The last time I did that, the guy hit one that hasn't landed yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taylor starts back toward the plate, and then stops.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, I'll take care of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By the way, I been meaning to ask you. Why'd you steal that car?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was bored.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn permits himself a little smile and release from the tension. Taylor smiles back, and trots off toward the plate.</context>
      <utterance>Next time you might think about takin' in a movie or somethin'.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rexman shoots Taylor a wicked glance.</context>
      <utterance>Helluva situation we got goin' here, huh, Rexman? Two on, two out, you're down by a run in the ninth. You got a chance to be a hero on national television, so whatever you do, don't blow it. They'll be callin' you a gutless choke artist all over America.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a free agent at the end of the year. Not much demand for gutless choke artists. What are you hittin' now? .230? .240?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rexman, slightly irritated, backs out of the box.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, nice average. Uh oh, on second thought, that still means you got a seven outta ten chance of goin' in the dumper.</utterance>
   <speaker>REXMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up, will ya, Taylor?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rexman gets back in the box.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, I can understand not wantin' to talk about baseball when your nuts are in a vice like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rexman is trying to ignore Taylor, but failing badly. Taylor flashes a sign to Vaughn. Vaughn goes into his windup.</context>
      <utterance>By the way, I saw your wife at the Capri Lounge last night. Hell of a dancer. You must be very proud.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn releases his pitch.</context>
      <utterance>But that guy she was with... I mean I'm sure he's a close personal friend of yours and all, but tell me...</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rexman, completely unnerved, takes a feeble swing and hits a high pop-up out in front of the plate.</context>
      <utterance>...Why was he wearing her panties on his head?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taylor moves out two steps and makes the catch easily, ending the game. Taylor rushes out to congratulate Vaughn. The players exchange handshakes and high fives, as Brown watches from the dugout.</context>
      <utterance>Uh oh, Rexie, I don't think that one's got the distance. Maybe if the wind comes up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's startin' to come together, Pepper. It's startin' to come together.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SUZANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh hi, Jake, how are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine, Suzanne, can I have a quick word with Rodger?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We FOLLOW Taylor into the luxurious den, where we find Dorn watching his wide screen TV in a smoking jacket.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, c'mon in, he's in the den. I'll get some coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>DORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Jake, old boy, what brings you out here?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just wanta tell ya somethin', but I didn't want to do it in front of the whole team.</utterance>
   <speaker>DORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what your problem is, but...  ...if I ever see you tank another play like you did tonight, I'll cut off your nuts and stuff 'em down your fuckin' throat. Dorn looks at Taylor for some sign that he's kidding. He doesn't get one. Taylor turns and walks on out, as we go to Dorn's stunned face. Suzanne walks in with a tray.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coffee anybody?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why the hell are we havin' practice during the All-Star break?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard the Big Lady upstairs ordered it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's hotter than shit in here. What happened to the air conditioning?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh man, this old body can use a soak.</utterance>
   <speaker>DORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brown flips on a switch. The whirlpool makes some grinding noises and then quits altogether.</context>
      <utterance>Forget it. It's not workin' again.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harris shouts over from the showers where he's just turned on the water.</context>
      <utterance>Damn it, I thought they were gonna replace this thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, there's no hot water in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brown is stopped short by the sight of Rachel Phelps standing in the middle of the locker room as various unclad players dive for cover.</context>
      <utterance>She's at it again. I've had it with this nickel and dime stuff.  I'm gonna get the Bitch on the phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanted to see the Bitch?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you think you oughta cover yourself with a towel first, Mr. Brown?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There aren't any towels, and I'm too old to be diving under benches.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I can take it if you can.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to the new whirlpool we were supposed to get?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Revenue problems have forced us to cut back on equipment. We'll simply have to fix the old one.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You fixed it six times already. And now there's no hot water in the showers.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The pipes in this building are old and rusted. We're replacing them, but it's a long, expensive process.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How am I supposed to keep my players healthy with cold water and no therapy equipment?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Immediately, 30 arms shoot up behind her in the Italian "up- yours" gesture. She turns around, but by then the players have quickly returned to normal positions.</context>
      <utterance>Your players will just have to get a little tougher. What are they, a bunch of pansies?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Over 162 games even tough guys get sprains, sore arms, muscle pulls...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that, Rachel turns and walks out. Brown and the others can only watch her go.</context>
      <utterance>It's only temporary. Besides, these guys weren't playing that good when the equipment was workin'. If I could get anybody to come and watch this team, none of this would be necessary. You oughta be grateful I can still pay your salaries.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OMIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
   <speaker>OMIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SPORTSCASTER ROSS FARMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On the air.</utterance>
   <speaker>FARMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In case you haven't noticed, and judging by attendance, you haven't, the Indians, that thought-to-be hopeless collection of has-been's and never-will-be's is actually approaching the .500 mark, and with it, semi-respectability. Nothing to write home about, to be sure, but at least we don't have to cover our eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya know, they could be a lot worse.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BUSINESS EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya know, I may have underestimated this team a bit.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONGSHOREMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya know, these guys aren't so fuckin' bad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GROUNDSKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're still shitty.</utterance>
   <speaker>OMIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
   <speaker>OMIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah shit, here comes Lou. Gimme a break, Mel. I gotta get outta here.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, kick some dirt on me. The Commissioner'll buy that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taylor begins kicking dirt on Wingo's shoes, ala Billy Martin. Wingo takes a dramatic hop, skip and jump and gives Taylor the heave-ho thumb just as Brown arrives. Wingo turns away.</context>
      <utterance>Right. Good idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brown grabs Taylor and pulls him aside.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, don't you go anywhere. I wanna have a few words with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are we arguin' about here?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fucker called that a ball.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean the one that was a foot outside?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taylor breaks away and starts back to the dugout. Playing it to the hilt, he throws his glove and mask to the ground on the way. Meanwhile, Brown is going jaw to jaw with Wingo, outraged at the call. Brown pulls a carrot out of his back pocket, and offers it to Wingo, who immediately thumbs him out.</context>
      <utterance>Yeh.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taylor comes up the stairs from the locker room, still in full uniform. He emerges onto the box level to see Lynn disappearing down the ramp toward the parking lot.</context>
      <utterance>leaving her seat and starting up the aisle.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You still got that great kick. Just like the first time I ever saw you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You follow me here too?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh, what did you want to see me about?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wouldn't have been at the game if you didn't want to see me about something.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just wanted to see you play.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How was I?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You looked good, but you oughta open your stance a little. They're pitching you inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll try that. You wanna have some dinner?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, I already ate.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. I forgot your life is different now.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the race.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anytime.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="40">
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whose place are we at this time?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mine. You follow me again?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh. When I saw you at the game, I figured you wanted to see me about something.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just wanted to see you play.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How was I?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You looked good, but you oughta open your stance a little. They're pitchin' you inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taylor gives a perfunctory nod. They look at each other a second. There's still plenty there. Taylor begins to come toward her. We hear his cleats on the floor. She backs off, but not with real conviction.</context>
      <utterance>I'll try that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I oughta tell you that I'm moving in with Tom.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goin' uptown, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not goin' uptown, I just want to lead a regular life. You know, like an adult maybe. With a house and a garden and normal hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I can't lead a regular life?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like the life you've had, Jake. You like hangin' out with the boys, livin' in hotels, eatin' dinner at midnight, having girls send you their underwear in the mail. Remember the surprise party I threw for you when you made the All-Star team? You never showed up, but the doorbell rang once and we all got quiet and hid behind the furniture. It was a guy to serve you with a paternity suit.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was a hoax. The girl was just trying to get some publicity.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, but you had obviously been with her. And it happened in front of all our friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lynn looks at him a long beat.</context>
      <utterance>I was drownin', Lynn. The endorsements were dryin' up, my knees were goin', they were talkin' about sendin' me down. I was just trying to hold on to somethin', prove to myself I was still an All-Star. I don't care about that anymore. I know I don't have much time left in baseball. I'm just a guy trying to put his life back together. Thinkin' about you was the only thing that kept me goin' in Mexico.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lynn is backed up against a desk now. She could move out but doesn't.</context>
      <utterance>I've come back to you too many times, Jake. I can't afford to believe you anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess this is our last hurrah then.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess so. Did you really read "Moby Dick?"</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taylor comes forward to kiss her, tentatively at first. Their conversation is interwoven with the slowly deepening intensity of their kissing.</context>
      <utterance>Cover to cover.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When's the wedding?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>October third.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your mom and dad like this guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're unbuttoning each other's shirts now.</context>
      <utterance>You're still their favorite.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gonna be a big wedding?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tom doesn't like big weddings. You coulda read Plot Outlines of 101 Great Novels.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At any library.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean the wedding.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All Saints on Euclid.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice church.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh. Who saved Ishmael at the end?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody. It was Queequeg's coffin. Am I invited?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To the wedding.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their shirts are off now.</context>
      <utterance>If you want. Maybe you really did read it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This doesn't change anything, you know. We were always good at this.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lynn?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The zipper on your skirt is stuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taylor's spikes come down across her skirt, catching in the material, ripping it from her body and pinning it to the wood floor. Taylor steps out of the shoe and whisks Lynn OUT OF FRAME. We hold on the skirt, nailed to the floor by the cleats.</context>
      <utterance>Use your imagination.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, my worst fears have been confirmed. We're 60 and 60, nine games out of first, and only two out of the first division. Who do those guys think they are?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you just have to accept the fact that they're not as bad as you'd hoped.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have to accept anything. Our attendance is only beginning to rise. If we can force a losing streak for a week or two, we can still turn this thing around. The fans are used to losers here. At the first sign of a slump they'll give up on this team.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's left to do? You've taken away everything you can.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not everything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TEMPLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Memo says we'll only be usin' this for short trips.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good thing we don't play anybody in Europe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I borrow one of those, man? They don't have any magazines on this bus.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, go ahead. I think my reading days are over.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Macbeth. This a good one?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hayes is impressed.</context>
      <utterance>These are all Hall of Famers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll trade you Song of Hiawatha for The Deerslayer.</utterance>
   <speaker>DORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naw, I'm not into Song of Hiawatha.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right then, how about Crime and Punishment?</utterance>
   <speaker>DORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh, that sounds pretty good. That's a detective story, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The players all crowd to the window to get a glimpse of their hotel. Hotel is actually overstating it. This place is one cut below the YMCA.</context>
      <utterance>This is it. The Sheffield Arms.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know if we can survive any more of these economy measures.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Vaughn finishes his warmups. As Taylor pumps the ball down to second, Vaughn hears a voice from the Yankee dug-out.</context>
      <utterance>So, Ricky Vaughn, roughed up in his only other appearance against the Yankees, will see what he can do with the Bronx Bombers this time. Vaughn, after a slow start, has come on lately and now leads the American League in strikeouts with 221.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn glances over and sees that one of the Yankees is dressed in a striped prison uniform. He also wears long earrings, high heels, and of course, glasses. Vaughn tries to ignore the guy, but his concentration is broken. Vaughn steps up on the rubber for his first pitch. He winds and fires. The Yankee LEADOFF HITTER rips a one-hopper to the wall in right center. Hayes runs it down and guns it back to the infield to hold the guy to a double. The convict whoops it up. Vaughn gets back up on the rubber. As he comes to the stretch, he catches sight of the convict again. The guy is doing a pantomime, sneaking up to a car and picking the lock, much to the delight of his teammates. Vaughn throws his pitch in the dirt and all the way to the backstop. The runner on second goes to third.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, jailbird!</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn gets ready again. The convict finishes picking the lock and then is suddenly arrested. He puts his hands against the wall and spreads his legs for a weapons check, cracking up the whole bench. Vaughn is getting a little steamed. His next pitch is hammered into left for a single, scoring a run.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Rick baby, settle down.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREE SHOTS OF VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>throwing pitches, followed by:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the problem, Rick? You're throwin' basketballs up there. That guy in the dugout botherin' you?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naw, I'm all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn nods as Taylor trots back behind the plate. Vaughn gets set again as his old nemesis, Haywood, steps into the batter's box. Haywood has a sly smile on his face. As Vaughn comes to his stretch, the convict goes back into his act. He's in jail now, struggling against the bars. Finally he bends over and grabs his ankles, while one of his teammates humps up against him, pretending to bugger him. This sends the Yankee bench into hysterics. Vaughn has lost it now. He fires to the plate and Haywood creams another tape measure job into the upper deck. Hayes doesn't even bother to run back to the wall. He just watches it go. 6-0 Yankees.</context>
      <utterance>Forget him. Worry about the guys carryin' bats. C'mon, Ricky, let's get nasty.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought now that Vaughn had some control, he was ready for the Yankees.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brown makes his way to the mound to take Vaughn out.</context>
      <utterance>Not quite yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, Vaughn pitches in some tough luck here as the Yankees put together as few squib hits and take a 6-0 lead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mind if I join you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Donovan. Hell no. What are you doin' here?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just wanted to get out on the road. You damn near pulled one out today.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someday we'll figure out how to beat those guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya know, you've done a helluva job this year.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sixty and sixty-one is hardly a helluva job.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With this club it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya know, when I first got to camp I figured this team had no chance. I was just hopin' we'd win enough that I could stay on and really start to build something here. But there's a lotta talent on this club, Charlie. The veterans are starting to play back to form and the rookies are developing faster than I thought. There's two or three potential all- stars in there. I think we're a first division team right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really believe that, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know it. All we need is something to bring it all together.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rachel Phelps would never allow that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On Brown's incredulous face, we...</context>
      <utterance>She doesn't want you in the first division. She doesn't even want you in Cleveland.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We take several CUTS OF FACES around the room.</context>
      <utterance>I got somethin' I think you oughta know about. I wouldn't have known about it myself if Charlie Donovan hadn't told me, although I shoulda guessed it from everything that's happened. It seems that Mrs. Phelps doesn't think too highly of our worth.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taylor, Vaughn, Hayes, Dorn, and the others can hardly believe what they're hearing.</context>
      <utterance>She put this team together because she thought we'd be bad enough to finish dead last, knockin' attendance down to the point where she could move the team to Miami.  And get rid of all of us for better personnel.</utterance>
   <speaker>DORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence descends on the room.</context>
      <utterance>Even you, Dorn.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In other words, Phelps thinks we're all dinks. That we don't belong in the big leagues.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if we don't finish last?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taylor surveys the bowed heads around the room. He stands to address the group.</context>
      <utterance>She'll replace you with somebody who will. After this season, you'll all be sent back to the minors or given your outright release.  So, all we're gonna get is this one year.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eyes dart around the room, then come back to Taylor. No hands are raised...</context>
      <utterance>I don't know about the rest of you, but I've been playin' baseball since I was five years old. I've had some good years and some years to forget. I've burned out my knees... I don't think I have three fingers that work right... I've lost most of the money I made and baseball has messed up my personal life from time to time. But I know one thing... I can still play this game a little. And I'd like to know who in this room thinks they're the kinda bum Mrs. Phelps is lookin' for?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, then, I guess there's only one thing to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>DORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We take CUTS of the startled faces of the players. As the idea sinks in, they begin to come to life. MUSIC begins and we're into a...</context>
      <utterance>Win the whole fuckin' thing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FARMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You remember bra burning in the '70's, well, the newest thing in Cleveland is doormat burning as Indian fans are standing up and saying "We won't be stepped on anymore".</utterance>
   <speaker>THREE QUICK SHOTS OF VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>blowing fast balls by hitter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OMIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
   <speaker>OMIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TEAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, do you know us?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're a Major League baseball team, but since we haven't won a pennant in thirty years, nobody recognizes us, not even in our own hometown.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why we carry the American Express card. No matter how far out of first we are, it keeps us from getting shut out at our favorite hotels and restaurants.</utterance>
   <speaker>CERRANO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So if you're looking for some big league clout, apply for the little green home run hitter.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look what it's done for us. People still don't recognize us, but...  ...we're in the first division now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, not bad for a has-been and a never-will-be.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dorn comes by Taylor's locker.</context>
      <utterance>We haven't won anything yet. We still got one more to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>DORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Taylor, there's a coupla drop- dead Annies outside. One of 'em says she used to know you pretty good. Brunette, great rack...</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Darla.</utterance>
   <speaker>DORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh. What doya say we chat 'em up?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know...</utterance>
   <speaker>DORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We leave Taylor thinking it over.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, you're not gonna keep moonin' over that library chick, are you? Forget her, she's gone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You still got that black Corvette? The one that the sound system took up the whole trunk?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I had to sell it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought they gave them to ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not after your knees go bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Darla is down to her bra and panties. She puts her leg up on the bed to unhook her stockings. Taylor is about to take off his pants, but stops.</context>
      <utterance>That's all right, you'll be gettin' a new one now.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Darla, I don't think I can do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean? We did this between innings once.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Darla looks at him a long beat.</context>
      <utterance>I guess I'm just not that guy anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Happens to the best of them sooner or later. What's her name?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Darla gives Jake a goodbye peck, the elevator door opens across the hall, and out steps Lynn. She's obviously rattled by the sight of Taylor and Darla together.</context>
      <utterance>So long, Jake. Too bad. I was gonna devote a whole chapter to you in my book.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that she quickly steps back into the elevator and the doors close.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me. I was in town for a conference and thought I'd drop by, but I can see you're busy...</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taylor leaps to the elevator door, but it's too late. He then sprints to the end of the hall and down the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Lynn, wait...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanted to see me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn says nothing, but he's clearly disappointed.</context>
      <utterance>Yeh, Rick. I just wanted to tell you that I'm startin' Harris tomorrow against the Yankees, even though it's your turn in the rotation.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got more experience and a little better record against the Yankees.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh, sure. Whatever's best for the team.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't read anything into it, Rick. You're one of the guys that got us here.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn turns and walks back up the aisle. Brown watches him go, knowing he's still upset.</context>
      <utterance>Yeh, okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn turns around to see Suzanne Dorn. She's dressed to draw blood, looking better than we've ever seen her. She slides into the booth.</context>
      <utterance>You mind if I join you?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think I'd be very good company tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn falls silent. Suzanne stares at him with a devastating combination of sexual heat and tender admiration. She's pulling out all the stops. Vaughn's a little flustered.</context>
      <utterance>Nothin'. Job problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm, ah, a ball player.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, but that's not why I came over. I don't chase ball players.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did you come over then?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We GO TO Vaughn. Forget it. He's a goner.</context>
      <utterance>Because you're the sexiest man I've ever laid eyes on, and you look like you could use a... friend.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you goin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've gotta get home.</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't even get your name.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Suzanne. Suzanne Dorn</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Suzanne Dorn?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that she walks on out, leaving Vaughn dazed by the knowledge of who he's just slept with.</context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Suzanne Dorn.  So long. You're a great kid.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SUZANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Jake.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taylor is amazed by what he's just seen. As soon as Suzanne is out of sight, he goes to Vaughn's room and opens the door.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Suzanne.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn is sitting on his bed in a state of disbelief.</context>
      <utterance>Vaughn?</utterance>
   <speaker>VAUGHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taylor nods that it's all right even though he doesn't believe it.</context>
      <utterance>I swear to God I didn't know who she was.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. I didn't think you'd come.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't stay.  We gotta get to the park.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good luck today, Jake.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh, you too.  Tell me one thing. The night you came up to my hotel -- was there really a library conference?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I came to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too bad it didn't work out better. I just wanna say I'm sorry for all the things I've put you through over the years.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even for last night?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He says this with absolute conviction. Despite herself, Lynn senses that he's telling the truth.</context>
      <utterance>Can't be sorry for that. Nothing happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you weren't defending my honor again?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lynn smiles. He gives her a kiss and watches as she goes inside. He stands there a long beat, then turns and walks slowly down the steps past his teammates.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't have to. She knew she was outclassed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door is opened by a Male Secretary and in steps Lou Brown.</context>
      <utterance>Come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Lou, what can I do for ya? Lou puts a folded piece of paper on her desk.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanted to hand in my resignation before you had a chance to fire me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know what you been tryin' to do with this team. After the season, I want no part of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I knew I could count on Charlie to tell somebody. I was just afraid he might take too long.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would you want him to tell somebody?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you'd tell the team, hopefully getting them mad enough to knock themselves out trying to prove they belonged in this league. I think it worked.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel nods.</context>
      <utterance>You tryin' to make me believe you wanted us to win all along?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bullshit. What about the plane, the bus, the bad hotels...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were broke. We couldn't afford anything better. Donald left the team nearly bankrupt. If we'd had another losing season, I would have had to sell the team. I knew we couldn't win with the team we had, so I decided to bring in new players and see how they'd do with the proper motivation. There was never any offer from Miami. I made it all up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why should I believe any of this? Now that we're winnin' it's easy for you to jump on the bandwagon.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brown has no comeback for this. He knows now that she's telling the truth.</context>
      <utterance>If I'd really wanted you to lose, all I had to do was send the best players back to the minors. But I didn't, did I?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brown can only shake his head at this whole thing.</context>
      <utterance>You think this was all an accident? I personally scouted every member of this team, except Hayes, of course. He was a surprise. They all had flaws which concealed their real talent, or I wouldn't have been able to get them. But I knew if anyone could straighten them out, you could. And if you tell them any of this, I will fire you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two shake hands. Brown looks at Rachel a beat, still looking for some sign of duplicity. Finally he gives her a grudging smile of respect.</context>
      <utterance>I love this team, Lou. Go get 'em tonight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn nods.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know what Dorn's wife is up to, but I think it'd be best if you dressed early and got out to the bullpen before Dorn comes in.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got a problem. Cerrano wants some extra power for tonight. He's lookin' to sacrifice a live chicken. We can't have people pukin' in the locker room before the game.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell him not to worry, I'll take care of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bye bye, honey, wish me luck.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUZANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uh oh, we know what this is all about.</context>
      <utterance>Before you go, there's something I wanta tell you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the press box.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's your bourbon.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Won't need it tonight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know where Vaughn is?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nope. Haven't seen him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dorn moves off.</context>
      <utterance>Let me know if you do. I wanna have a little talk with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CERRANO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's my chicken?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see a Bat Boy enter with a bucket of fried chicken. Cerrano looks at it in bewilderment.</context>
      <utterance>It's comin' in now.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One whole chicken, like you said.</utterance>
   <speaker>CERRANO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it no alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Cerrano hefts the bucket somewhat skeptically and takes it to his altar, we...</context>
      <utterance>Believe me, Jo-Buu will like this. He's gotta be gettin' tired of raw chicken.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Down in the dugout, the players are lined up ready to take the field. They exchange words of encouragement, hand slaps, clenched fists, but all at a very low key level. This is tension time.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, everybody, Harry Doyle bidding you a Wahoo welcome from beautiful Municipal Stadium, where tonight before a capacity crowd of 75,000 screaming featherheads, the braves of the Cuyahoga will leave their teepees in search of Cleveland's first League Championship in over 30 years. Standing in the way, their long time nemesis, the New York Yankees, the Big Boys of Broadway, who have beaten the Indians like a tom-tom all year long.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Indians charge onto the field to a standing ovation. In the center field bleachers Thelma's victory blanket containing the scores of every Indian game for the season, hangs from a railing. Bobby, Vic and Johnny pound the tom- toms leading the stadium in a monster version of "In the Land of Burning Waters." Even the groundskeepers join in. Two down in the first. Harris looking sharp so far... Bouncing ball to third. Dorn up with it.</context>
      <utterance>All right, guys, let's take it to 'em.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE SCOREBOARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>0-0 in the 3rd.</utterance>
   <speaker>CERRANO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>striking out on a curve ball.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>picking a Yankee runner off first.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE SCOREBOARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>0-0 in the 5th.</utterance>
   <speaker>OMIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harris comes set and delivers. The Yankee hitter, BURTON, (L) swings and gets all of it.</context>
      <utterance>Still nothing -- nothing, top of the seventh, two down. Harris has been in trouble all night, but has battled his way out with the help of some great defensive plays.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Hayes climbs up on the wall, but it's long gone. Home run.</context>
      <utterance>Uh oh, this one's tagged. Deep center field. Way back. Way back.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's off the reservation, home run. And the Yankees lead it 2-0.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Dorn swings at the first pitch and lines a sharp single to left. The crowd and the Indian bench suddenly come alive. Cerrano moves to the plate.</context>
      <utterance>Dorn up now, two down, bottom of the seventh. The Indians running out of chances.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The crowd and bleacher band begins to clap as Dorn takes his lead. Cerrano swings at the first pitch and misses. An audible groan goes through the crowd. The Yankee pitcher gets set again, and throws Cerrano a big, roundhouse curve. He misses it a foot. Strike two.</context>
      <utterance>That'll bring on Cerrano, hitless tonight. As a matter of fact, he hasn't touched the ball yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn, havin' trouble with the curve ball again.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cerrano steps out and begins to talk to his bat, gesturing and pointing as if arguing with his wife.</context>
      <utterance>We should've gotten him a live chicken.</utterance>
   <speaker>CERRANO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cerrano gets back in the box and digs in. The Yankee pitcher comes to his stretch and delivers. Another big breaking curve ball. Cerrano swings and knocks the crap out of it. Everyone in the stands and on the bench jumps to their feet, rooting for the ball to get out.</context>
      <utterance>I pissed off now, Jo-Buu. I good to you, I stand up for you. If you no help me now, I say fuck you, Jo-Buu. I do it myself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HARRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>on the mound, looking like he's out of gas.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Harris comes set and fires to the plate. It's way high.</context>
      <utterance>Activity continues in the pen, as Harris is really digging himself a hole now. He got the first two hitters, and then gave up a single and a double and has now gone 3-0 to Cheevers.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Brown has seen enough. He makes his way to the mound.</context>
      <utterance>High, ball four and they're loaded for Haywood, the biggest Indian killer of them all.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brown signals to the bullpen with his left hand.</context>
      <utterance>You pitched a hell of a game, Steve. Take a seat and we'll see if we can get this guy for ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me Vaughn.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want Vaughn?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know he hasn't done real well against this guy, but I got a hunch he's due.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn nods, but we can tell he's too nervous to have digested any of that.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, Ricky, Haywood likes the hard stuff in. Curve him on the hands, bust him away, and don't get up with anything. You listenin' to me Rick?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>O.K., kid, you're my man. Let's go get him.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brown and Taylor leave Vaughn alone on the mound, the SINGING of the crowd ringing in his ears.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon Ricky, this guy is the out you been waitin' your whole life for.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No sooner has Taylor settled in behind the plate, than Dorn starts toward the mound. Vaughn watches him come with fear and trepidation.</context>
      <utterance>O.K. Vaughn has finished his warmup and we're ready to...</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dorn arrives at the mound, and holds out his hand for the ball. Vaughn gives it to him. Dorn rubs it up, staring long and hard into Vaughn's eyes. Vaughn is sweating bullets. Finally Dorn speaks.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>DORN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles and hands Vaughn the ball back. Vaughn returns the smile and accepts the ball. While Dorn trots back to his position, Vaughn turns his back to the plate for one last moment of concentration. As he turns around to face us, we see a new man as the wicked opening CHORDS of X's "Wild Thing" are heard on the TRACK, only louder and more savage than before. Vaughn steps up on the rubber, his face hardened into fierce resolve. There's nothing nervous about him now. This kid is gonna make somebody pay.</context>
      <utterance>Let's cut through the crap. I only got one thing to say to you. Just rear back and strike this motherfucker out.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Taylor sets down a sign. Two fingers for the curve ball. Vaughn shakes it off. Taylor puts down another sign. Vaughn shakes it off. Finally, Taylor puts down one finger -- the fast ball. Vaughn nods with steely purpose.</context>
      <utterance>Haywood steps in, the American League triple crown winner. .341 average, 48 homers, 121 R.B.I.'s. He's homered the only two times he's faced Vaughn.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn winds and delivers a hissing blur toward the plate. Haywood takes a ferocious swing and misses. Strike one. We see the number 97 come up on the digital readout of the SPEED GUN which a club employee holds behind the screen.</context>
      <utterance>All right, Ricky, let's get nasty.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, looks like the boy is pumped. Sucker was movin', wasn't it? Ever hit ya, it'd leave a two foot hole comin' out. Taylor gets ready to flash another sign. The convict jumps up and down trying to distract Vaughn. No way.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The fans are going wild. They're all standing now, yelling for a strikeout. Vaughn gets back up on the rubber with the look of an animal sighting prey. Taylor gets down to give the sign.</context>
      <utterance>Nice swing, Haywood. Good follow- through. Keep it up, I'll show you the ball sometime.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget the curveball. Go with the heater.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taylor wiggles his fingers around and then puts down the big No. 1. Vaughn gives him a quick nod.</context>
      <utterance>Well, shit, all these pitches to choose from. Maybe we'll try somethin' different this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vaughn goes into his windup and unleashes a screaming bullet toward the plate. Haywood pulls the trigger, but it's already by him. Strike three. 101 on the gun. Taylor leaps up and gives Vaughn the fist. The fans are going berserk. MUSIC ends.</context>
      <utterance>And if I don't see you again, Haywood, have a nice winter. Okay, buddy?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Doyle turns the mike off.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Lordy, three straight heaters and the Yankees are blown down. No runs, two hits, three left on, and, are you ready, Cleveland? We go to the bottom of the ninth, still tied at two.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monty takes a big swig straight from the bourbon bottle.</context>
      <utterance>Can you believe this, Monty?</utterance>
   <speaker>OMIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER INDIAN HITTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>grounding out to short.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>walking up to the plate.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Taylor and the others yell encouragement to Hayes as he digs in at the plate. The Yankee pitcher delivers and Hayes hits a high bouncer toward short. The shortstop waits for it to come down and then fires to first. Too late. Hayes streaks across the bag, beating the throw by a hair. Once again the CROWD comes to life. The Yankee Manager comes to the mound and waves for a new pitcher.</context>
      <utterance>Two down in the ninth, Hayes steps in hitting .291, trying to get something going for the Tribe.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Out of the pen comes BILLY DUKE, a good facsimile of Goose Gossage only Duke is bigger and meaner.</context>
      <utterance>And Horton is wasting no time. He's goin' to the Duke.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Duke finishes his warmups and stares over at Hayes. Hayes smiles, snaps his black gloves out of his hip pocket, and carefully pulls them on over his hands. The Duke does not care for this kind of showmanship. Brown comes over to talk to Taylor, who's been watching Duke from the on-deck circle.</context>
      <utterance>Duke leads the league in saves, strikeouts per inning and nose hairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya know I'd be an ass not to pinch- hit for you here. You're 0 for 18 against Duke. Plus you're beat to shit you can hardly walk, there's no way you can get around on this guy's fast ball. So I want the absolute truth here. Can you beat this guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taylor starts for the plate, as Duke finishes his warmups. Brown comes down the dugout steps.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brown flashes a sign out to Hayes. A hint of a smile comes over Hayes' face as he dusts himself off. Taylor steps back in as Duke gets up on the rubber. Taylor digs in his back foot, then points to the left field bleachers ala Babe Ruth.</context>
      <utterance>Flashing some signals. That's a hell of an idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The crowd, electrified by Taylor's gesture, remains on its feet. Duke stares in at Taylor, comes to his stretch and then lets go a steaming fast ball right at Taylor's head. Taylor goes down in a swirl of dust, the ball missing him by inches. The stadium explodes with BOOS, but as soon as Taylor picks himself up, the crowd begins to ROAR again. Bobby, Vic and Johnny are pounding out a heavy beat on the TOM-TOMS. Everyone in the stadium begins to CLAP in unison with the DRUMS. Taylor steps back in and once again points to the bleachers.</context>
      <utterance>What's this? Taylor is pointing to the bleachers, calling his shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unbelievable. They're on their feet here, stomping, clapping. C'mon, join in wherever you are out there. Let's hear you, Cleveland.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pandemonium breaks loose in Municipal Stadium. Rachel hugs Donovan, dances around, punches the air, then hugs Donovan again. Everywhere people are hugging and kissing each other. Bobby, Vic and Johnny are going berserk in the bleachers. Thelma sits quietly, a tear rolling down her cheek.</context>
      <utterance>...Safe. The Indians win it. The Indians win. Oh my God, the Indians win it!!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUICK CUTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A) The Business Executive stand up and yell "Yes!" in the middle of the opera. Several other men stand up and express their excitement as well. B) The Longshoremen whoop it up in their bar -- exchanging fives and hugs with the punkers and heavy metal kids. C) The various apartment dwellers dancing, clapping, yelling out the windows. D) The two Korean Groundskeepers just shaking their heads in amazement. E) Elsewhere in the stadium, the joyous exultation continues unabated. The crowd pours onto the field as Hayes runs toward Taylor and literally leaps into his arms. F) The two spin around throwing their fists in the air. G) Cerrano and Harris embrace. Dorn gives Vaughn a hug, then steps back and decks him with a right hand. H) Dorn pulls Vaughn back to his feet, and they hug again. I) Up in the stands, Rachel watches all this with tears in her eyes. Taylor starts off the field when he sees something that catches his eye. Standing by the field rail is Lynn. She holds up her left hand and smiles. There's no ring on it. Taylor races over to her as she jumps down from the rail and hugs herself to him. We HOLD on the celebration as it swirls all around them, and...</context>
      <utterance>of our other fans. We see...</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
