<movie id="374" title="Man on the Moon">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>AS FOREIGN MAN</mode>
      <context>Andy puts a needle on a phonograph, and swelling CLOSING CREDITS MUSIC starts to play. FINAL CREDITS roll. Andy stands frozen, awkwardly looking at the audience. Every time the music ends he picks up the needle and restarts the music. He does that as many times as the credits require. Finally, CREDITS END. And then--a sly smile. He leans in. DROPS HIS ACCENT and WHISPERS.</context>
      <utterance>Hallo. I am Andy. Welcoom to my movie.  I hoped the story of my life would be nice...but it turned out terrible! It is all LIES! Tings are mixed up... real people I knew play different people. WHAT A MESS! So I broke into Universal and cut out the junk. Now it's much shorter. In fact, this is the end of the movie. So tanks for comink! Bye-bye!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>AS REGULAR VOICE</mode>
      <context>Andy turns to a primitive 16mm PROJECTOR and turns it on. WHIR! He smiles at the flickering light.</context>
      <utterance>Okay! Just my friends are left. I wanted to get rid of those other people... they would have laughed in the wrong places.  I was only kidding about the movie... it's actually PRETTY GOOD! It shows everything... from me as a little boy until my death --  Oops!! I wasn't supposed to talk about that! Oh. Eh, uh, we better just begin. It starts back in Great Neck, Long Island...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We PUSH INTO the white light. It fills our frame, blazing whiter, whiter...</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes. I remember it well...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's my boy! Good swingin', kiddo.  Hey -- Michael... where's your brother?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Instantly -- Stanley's mood turns black. He frowns angrily, then snatches his briefcase and marches in.</context>
      <utterance>He's inside.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he in his room?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stanley glowers. He huffs upstairs.</context>
      <utterance>Of course he's in his room.  All his "friends" are in there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>(now as BRITISH</context>
      <utterance>But professor, why are the monsters growing so big?</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stanley rolls his eyes. He opens the door...</context>
      <utterance>It's something in the jungle water. I need to crack the secret code.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>as BRITISH</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR)</speaker>
      <mode> PROFESSOR)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I should talk to the natives.  Shoom boom boo ba! Shoom boom boo ba --</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andy!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy suddenly turns off, becoming introverted... awkward. Frustrated, Stanley stares at his son.</context>
      <utterance>Oh!</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andy, this has to stop. Our house isn't a television station. There is not a camera in that wall. Andy glances over at the wall. Hmm. STANLEY   Son... listen to me. It isn't healthy. You should be outside, playing sports.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Championship wrestling, at five.</context>
      <utterance>But I've got a sports show.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know that's not what I meant! Look, I'm gonna put my foot down! No more playing alone. You wanna perform, you GOTTA have an audience!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>B-but I have them.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy thinks, considering his options. Then, he nods.</context>
      <utterance>No! That is NOT an audience! That is PLASTER! An audience is people made of flesh! They -- live and breathe! Got it?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>as KIDDIE SHOW</utterance>
   <speaker>HOST)</speaker>
      <mode> HOST)</mode>
      <context>(he makes an</context>
      <utterance>And now, boys and girls! It's time for... TV Fun House!</utterance>
   <speaker>APPLAUSE SOUND)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, everybody! Are you ready for a singalong? I'll say the animal, and you make his sound! Okay...? Okay!  "Oh, the cow goes........." Carol stares, unblinking. Then --</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Moo.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"And the dog goes......"</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy waves and bows. There's faint scattered applause. Andy sighs. An irritated MANAGER steps onstage. He shoots Andy a disgruntled look, then takes the mike.</context>
      <utterance>"And that's the way it goes!"  Thank you. Goodbye!</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the b.g., Andy starts packing up his props: Hand puppets, conga drums, a phonograph... it all goes into a big bulky case.</context>
      <utterance>The comedy stylings of Andy Kaufman, Ladies and Gentlemen!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, Mr. Besserman, same slot tomorrow...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>thinkin' of letting you go...</context>
      <utterance>Eh, I dunno... Andy. I'm...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're firing me??  You don't even pay me!</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A stunned beat. Andy is hurt.</context>
      <utterance>Look -- I don't wanna seem insulting. But... your act is like amateur hour: Singalongs... puppets... playing records...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want? "Take my wife, please"??</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure! Comedy! Make jokes about the traffic. Do impressions. Maybe a little blue material...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't swear. I -- I don't do what everyone else does!</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An uncomfortable beat -- and then Andy starts crying. The manager is dumbfounded. He doesn't know what to do. Tears are rolling pitifully down Andy's cheeks. The manager is confused -- totally disoriented. Shamed, Andy covers his face, then runs out. Silence. The manager stares after him... having no idea what just happened.</context>
      <utterance>Well, everyone else gets this place cookin'! Pal, it's hard for me to move the booze when you're singin' "Pop Goes The Weasel." Andy stares, disheartened. MANAGER  I'm sorry. You're finished here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>THUG #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy stares fearfully. An anxious moment. He thinks... considering his options. Then, he suddenly stammers in a thick FOREIGN ACCENT.</context>
      <utterance>Give us your wallet.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>AS FOREIGN MAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I -- doo not unterstand!!</utterance>
   <speaker>THUG #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give us your money!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>AS FOREIGN MAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?? What mooney? Abu daboo! I do not have mooney! The thugs glance at each other. ANDY   Pleaze! I just move to America yezterday! I do not know!</utterance>
   <speaker>THUG #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's in the case?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>AS FOREIGN MAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>NO! Eeet, eet is just perzonal trifles from my homeland --</utterance>
   <speaker>THUG #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guy snatches the case. He impulsively BREAKS the lock... and clothes, congas and records fall out. The thugs are dismayed.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up! Gimme that thing!</utterance>
   <speaker>THUG #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamn immigrants!</utterance>
   <speaker>THUG #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harsh glances. They angrily turn and leave. Andy takes a nervous breath, then starts picking his things off the street. He shouts after the guys:</context>
      <utterance>This guy's pathetic. Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>AS FOREIGN MAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tank you veddy much...!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WISEASS COMIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The comic waves and exits. APPLAUSE. George politely claps. A PIANO PLAYER jumps in with an upbeat show tune. We think there's a break... when Andy suddenly, awkwardly steps on stage. He is in character as Foreign Man. Pink jacket, tie, hair slicked back, frightened like a deer in headlights. He puts down his big case, pulls out various junk, and arranges it on chairs. The room hushes, uncertain as to who the hell this guy is. Andy tentatively grabs the mike. The stagefright is agony.</context>
      <utterance>So I'm getting my mother-in-law a special Christmas present: A pre- paid funeral! The mortician asked me if I wanted her buried, embalmed or cremated. I said, "Make it all three! I'm not takin' any chances!"  Thank you. Good night!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>AS FOREIGN MAN</mode>
      <context>(looking around) Tank you veddy much. I am very happy to be here. I tink -- this is a very beautiful place. But one ting I do not like is too much traffic. Tonight I had to come from, eh, and the freeway, it was so much traffic. It took me an hour and a half to get here! Andy chuckles, as if this were a punchline. Silence. The crowd is baffled. ANDY (AS FOREIGN MAN) (cont'd) But -- talking about the terrible things: My wife. Take my wife, please take her. Yikes. A few NERVOUS LAUGHS. Andy gestures, as if they got the joke. ANDY (AS FOREIGN MAN) (cont'd) No really, I am only foolink. I love my wife very much. But she don't know how to cook. You know, one time, she make a steak and mashed potato. Ehh, and the night before, she make spaghetti and meatballs. Her cooking is so bad... is terrible. People are embarrassed. Some avert their eyes. A couple hipsters laugh mockingly. George leans forward. Andy wipes the sweat from his brow. ANDY (AS FOREIGN MAN) (cont'd) Right now, I would like to do for you some imitations. So first, I would like to imitate Archie Bunker. (no change in his voice) "You stupid, everybody ees stupid! Ehh, get, get out of my chair Meathead... go in the, eh, Dingbat get into the kitchen, making the food! Ehh, everybody ees stupid! I don't like nobody, ees so stupid!" Tank you veddy much. (pleased, he proudly bows) Now I would like to imitate Jimmy Carter, the President of the United States. (no change in his voice) "Hello, I am Jimmy Carter, the President of the United States." Some people BOO and walk out. A few giggle, getting into the groove. George is intrigued. ANDY (AS FOREIGN MAN) (cont'd) And now... I would like to imitate the Elvis Presley. A woman LAUGHS caustically. Andy grins stupidly, then turns his back to us. He presses "Play" on a CASSETTE RECORDER... and the THEME FROM 2001 starts playing. House lights dim dramatically. With a flourish, Andy pulls tape off his pants -- revealing rhinestones. He removes his pink coat -- putting on a white jeweled jacket. He combs his hair. Then he brushes his hair. Then he combs his hair some more. Finally he picks up a guitar, strikes a pose -- and spins around. He is ELVIS. CONFIDENT. SEXY. LIP CURL. DEAD-ON PERFECT. The crowd is blown away. Vegas Elvis INTRO MUSIC suddenly blasts. Andy/Elvis swaggers stage left and takes a bow. Then he goes stage right and takes a bow. Then he returns stage left for another bow. Music STOPS.</context>
      <utterance>Now? Now...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>AS ELVIS</mode>
      <context>Wow. Flabbergasted, people APPLAUD. This man is Elvis. Suddenly -- "JAILHOUSE ROCK" guitar kicks in. ANDY (AS ELVIS) (cont'd)</context>
      <utterance>Thank you very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>SINGING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Warden threw a party In the county jail! Prison band was there And they BEGAN to WAIL!"</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pst. What's the story with this guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George nods admiringly.</context>
      <utterance>I think he's Lithuanian. None of us can understand him.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He does a hell of an Elvis.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I really enjoyed your set.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>AS FOREIGN MAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tank you veddy much.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I understand you're from Lithuania?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>AS FOREIGN MAN</mode>
      <context>George is puzzled.</context>
      <utterance>No. Caspiar.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Caspiar? I haven't heard of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>AS FOREIGN MAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a veddy small island in de Caspian Sea.  It sunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George hands him a BUSINESS CARD. Andy reads it -- then his eyes pop. He DROPS the accent.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Hm. I'm uh, sorry.  Well, look, I'm probably out of my mind -- but I think you're very interesting. If you ever need representation... we should talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George realizes it's all been an act. He laughs heartily.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Shapiro, it's an honor!!</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Caspiar, huh?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George is surprised at this hubris.</context>
      <utterance>You see, I want to be the biggest star in the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People love... comedians.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George looks up at Andy -- and inexplicably there is a giant MOIST BOOGER hanging from Andy's nostril. George cringes. He doesn't know what to say. A waitress brings over two plates of awful 70's HEALTH FOOD -- seaweed, beans, stringy paste. George frowns. Andy beams. ANDY (cont'd) Mmm! I particularly recommend the Lotus root. Andy pulls out a little Handi-wipe and cleanses his hands. Then he starts arranging the food in compulsive little piles: Beans in pinwheel shapes. Sprouts in piles. George peers at the bizarre food behavior.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not a comedian. I have no talent.  I'm a song-and-dance man.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You show a lot of promise... but... my concern is I don't know where to book you. You're not a stand-up... your act doesn't exactly translate to films... help me... where do you see yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George is unsure if that's a joke.</context>
      <utterance>I've always wanted to play Carnegie Hall.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy dips his silverware in the water glass. Two dunks, then he dries it with his napkin. George stares, perplexed. He looks back up -- and Andy's booger has suddenly switched nostrils. Huh?</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, ha-ha. That's funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy's about to eat -- but first bows his head in silent prayer. George raises an eyebrow. Andy snaps his head back up. ANDY (cont'd) I want gut reactions! I want that audience to go through an experience. They love me! They hate me! They walk out -- it's all</context>
      <utterance>See, I don't want easy laughs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're insane.  But -- you might also be brilliant. Alright, Andy... let's do it. George warmly extends his hand. Andy slowly smiles, then takes George's hand. The men shake. A moment of supreme importance.</utterance>
   <speaker>EST. BEVERLY HILLS - DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The glitz strip of Los Angeles. Money. Beauty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O.S., a SECRETARY shouts out.</context>
      <utterance>Sammy, opening for David Brenner is a fine gig. You'll be on the road... get some exposure...</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tony Clifton on the phone!</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He says he's an associate of Andy Kaufman's.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the phone, a STACCATO, ABRASIVE NASAL VOICE blares.</context>
      <utterance>Oh.  Sammy, think about it. I gotta go.  Hello? George Shapiro here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY CLIFTON</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, yeah. Is this GEORGE SHAPIRO?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Er, yes. Speaking.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY CLIFTON</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>George is baffled.</context>
      <utterance>"Speaking"! Reeking, seeking, creaking... Freaking!</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I help you with something?</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY CLIFTON</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah! You stay away from that Andy Kaufman, if you know what's good for you!</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY CLIFTON</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You -- you know damn straight who it is. Tony Clifton! A name to respect. A name to fear.  Beer. Gear. Deer. Ear.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look... I don't know what your problem is...</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY CLIFTON</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>CLICK. Clifton hangs up. George is bewildered.</context>
      <utterance>Kaufman's a lying bastard! If you sign him, I'll RUIN YOU!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>LITTLE WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The students all open their eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Now, while continuing your deep breathing, slowly open your eyes. You should feel rested, relaxed, and alert.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOGI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do any thoughts come...?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUDENT #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My mind is clear. I feel great.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOGI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good...</utterance>
   <speaker>STUDENT #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Yogi's eyes go to Andy. Andy smiles sweetly.</context>
      <utterance>All the tension is gone from my body.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Yogi nods kindly.</context>
      <utterance>I want to thank you, your Holiness. My heart is radiating with pure energy.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOGI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You always had a good heart. But I'm proud of the progress you've made in your discipline.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh. The Yogi peers intently.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. TM got me focused. In fact, my manager got me a TV gig! It's just some new show with no budget, but I'm still excited.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOGI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you at peace with your family?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um, yes. I haven't fought with them, since I started here.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOGI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goals are important.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I stopped drinking. I gave up drugs. And I'm meditating three hours a day. It's the center of my life...</utterance>
   <speaker>YOGI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy smiles beatifically. This means a lot.</context>
      <utterance>We are all impressed.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Anyone else --?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Huh? The Yogi thinks hard... squinching up his face. Then... he finally speaks.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, wait! I have a question.  Is there... is there a secret to being funny?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOGI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Silence.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CAROL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still can't believe my brother's gonna be on TV...!</utterance>
   <speaker>JANICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope he doesn't get nervous.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The commercial ends, and the "APPLAUSE" sign blinks. The crowd APPLAUDS. An "ON THE AIR" sign lights up.</context>
      <utterance>What's the difference? This thing's on in the middle of the night -- no one's even gonna see it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome back to Saturday Night Live! And now, as a special treat on our first show... musical guest ANDY</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MIGHTY MOUSE THEME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The audience is puzzled. The Kaufmans are alarmed.</context>
      <utterance>"Although we are in danger, We never despair, Because we know where there is danger He is there!"</utterance>
   <speaker>LORNE MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God, he's doing nothing. It's dead air...!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MIGHTY MOUSE THEME</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Then SUDDENLY -- Andy comes to life and triumphantly LIP</context>
      <utterance>"We're not worrying at all. We're just listening for his call..."</utterance>
   <speaker>SYNCS.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then instantly -- Andy resumes his blank expression. MIGHTY MOUSE THEME (V.O.) (cont'd) "That means that Mighty Mouse is on the way!" The audience SCREAMS with glee. The tune ENDS, and the audience APPLAUDS CRAZILY. Delighted, Andy grins and bows. The Kaufmans clap the hardest. Stanley locks eyes with Andy... and the beaming father smiles the proudest of all.</context>
      <utterance>MIGHTY MOUSE THEME   "Here I come to save the day!" Shocked, the crowd HOWLS with LAUGHTER.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andy, c'mon IN! Thanks for flyin' out here!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The stewardess let me keep my headphones.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's... terrific! But I got something better. This is BIG...  You are getting a once-in-a- lifetime, unbelievably lucrative opportunity to star on... a</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sitcom...?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And this is a CLASS ACT! It's the guys who did the Mary Tyler Moore and Bob Newhart shows! It takes place in a taxi stand! And you're gonna be the Fonzie!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm -- Fonzie?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>NO! The Fonzie! The crazy breakout character! The guy that all the kids impersonate and put on their lunchboxes!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>George, I hate sitcoms.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Long pause. Then -- Andy responds.</context>
      <utterance>HANG ON, you ain't heard the best part! ABC has seen your foreign man character, and they want to turn him into --  "Latka," a lovable, goofy mechanic!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"No"? "No" to which part??</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George is flummoxed.</context>
      <utterance>No to the whole thing. None of it sounds good.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andy... this is every comedian's dream.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you, I'm not a comedian. And sitcoms are the lowest form of entertainment: Stupid jokes and canned laughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>B-but, this is classy... they did Bob Newha--</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. George glares.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not interested. I want to create my own material.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I refuse.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Fine, I'll do it.  But I have a few terms.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course! That's what negotiations are for. Andy starts to write on a piece of paper. GEORGE  What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy clicks his pen, done. George smiles and takes the list. He scans it... then his face gets totally befuddled.</context>
      <utterance>Writing down my terms. George watches patiently.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you makin' fun of me --? This is RIDICULOUS!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those are my terms.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're IMPOSSIBLE!! Jesus!  I mean -- "two guaranteed guest shots for Tony Clifton"??! Who is this TONY CLIFTON?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George gets a look.</context>
      <utterance>He's a Vegas entertainer. I used to do impressions of him. We sorta... got in a fight over that.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This Clifton called me up. He's a loon! He HATES you!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(a sarcastic FONZIE</context>
      <utterance>Nah, he just talks tough. But I owe him one. Andy smiles ingenuously, then turns stern. ANDY  If I'm the new Fonz... ABC's just gonna have to give me what I want.</utterance>
   <speaker>IMPRESSION)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George winces. He stares at the list.</context>
      <utterance>Heyyyyyy!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tony Clifton.</utterance>
   <speaker>NETWORK GUY #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is he?!</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Long pause. The execs stare at George like he's lost his mind. GEORGE (cont'd) But Andy says he's fabulous. (awkward) He also says, these are the terms. The execs' leader, MAYNARD SMITH, shudders hopelessly.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>NETWORK GUY #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Couldn't Kaufman ask for more money, like everyone else? George slowly, sadly shakes his head: No. Maynard glances at his team -- then frowns. MAYNARD  George, we don't book phantom performers. The deal's off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andy?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi George!</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eh, hi, Andy. Look, this Tony Clifton... is he performing anywhere?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course.  But only on Monday nights.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's alright. Where...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The DRUMMER starts a drum roll. Patrons APPLAUD. A LIGHT SPOT hits the entrance area... and nobody enters. The spot is waiting... waiting... still waiting... until the drum roll slows down and stops. The announcer BOOMS again. ANNOUNCER (V.O.) (cont'd) Ladies and Gentlemen, out of respect for Mr. Clifton's vocal demands, could everyone please extinguish your cigarettes and cigars. The crowd GRUMBLES angrily -- then irritably complies. One ANGRY GUY thrusts his cigar into a water glass.</context>
      <utterance>And now, Mama Roma's is proud to present International Singing Sensation... a man who has sold more records than Elvis and the Beatles combined... George is skeptical. ANNOUNCER   Ladies and Gentlemen, Mr. Entertainment... TONY CLIFTON!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGRY GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamn, I paid five dollars for this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The band starts playing lounge standard "VOLARE". And then, obnoxious TONY CLIFTON swaggers out. Tony has a rubbery face, black wig and moustache, sunglasses, a padded belly, and a peach tuxedo with blue shirt and velvet piping. Tony stops, smirks at the audience, and sucks on a cigarette. He blows smoke rings at them.</context>
      <utterance>And now! A man who needs no introduction... TONY CLIFTON!</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY CLIFTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd is furious.</context>
      <utterance>Heh-heh. How ya all doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGRY GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>People light back up and start talking. Tony ignores the ruckus. He starts SINGING, pinched and off-key.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you!</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY CLIFTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he approaches a</context>
      <utterance>"Volare! Whoa, whoa. Cantare, Whoa whoa whoa whoa." George winces. He's horrible. TONY CLIFTON   "I got the wings of your love, I got the wings of a dove. I got the... uh...  ... the chicken wings from Eh, Kentucky Fried..." The band is lost. TONY CLIFTON  Oh. Whoop do doo, Whoop de di, Stick a needle in your eye... The band gives up and stops. TONY CLIFTON  Eh, the hell with that song. One person CLAPS. Most BOO. TONY CLIFTON  So how ya doin'!  How ya doin' over here? How ya doin' over there?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's that pasta carbonara?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave me alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY CLIFTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tony approaches a LONELY SAD SACK sitting at the bar. Tony thrusts his mike at the guy.</context>
      <utterance>Okay!  So, you havin' a good time, sir?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SAD SACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure...</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY CLIFTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAD SACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bob.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY CLIFTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Bob"? BOB! Bob bob bob.  Bob what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAD SACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bob Gorsky.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY CLIFTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Gorsky"? What is that, Polish?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAD SACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tony gets indignant.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY CLIFTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you tryin' to do some of that Polack humor? Well if that's so, you can just get the hell out of this restaurant!</utterance>
   <speaker>SAD SACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's my name.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY CLIFTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>SHUT UP! I hate them Polish jokes! People are embarrassed. TONY CLIFTON  I do a clean show! Like, I wouldn't do that one... oh, you know it... "What do you call a pretty girl in Poland"?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAD SACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A -- a tourist.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY CLIFTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tony snatches Bob's water glass and POURS IT over his head! George is appalled. The crowd is aghast. Bob is wet. People BOO AND HURL THINGS. Bob starts weeping, then bolts up and runs from the building. TONY CLIFTON (cont'd) And stay out, Fatso! The room erupts, outraged. George covers his face, looking ill. Suddenly, Tony snaps at him.</context>
      <utterance>See, that's EXACTLY what I'm talkin' about!  Here! I'LL give you a little humor!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George is rattled.</context>
      <utterance>And YOU. I wanna see you backstage!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tony puts down his fork. He pauses... slowly turns around... and is Andy. George GASPS. His eyes bulge. Andy smiles innocently. He gestures to an empty seat.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, I'm here. What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George is breathing heavily, like someone about to have a heart attack. His brain melting, he shakily reaches for a chair and sits. George glances down. Lying alongside the food is Tony's rubber face.</context>
      <utterance>Are you hungry?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... I-I don't understand this act.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's good old-fashioned entertainment. Everyone loves a villain.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat -- then Bob strolls over. His real name is BOB ZMUDA.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Well tell that to the poor schlub who you humiliated!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Andy, good show.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George gapes. On closer inspection, Bob is cocky, aloof, and conniving. He and Andy grin naughtily at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Oh George, this is Bob Zmuda. Bob and I have been buddies for years.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was a really hot house!</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So your name's not Gorsky.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George thinks about this -- then laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Don't believe everything you hear.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andy!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George grins crazily, ecstatically.</context>
      <utterance>What's up?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>EXPLODES, but he doesn't notice. He turns to George... and slowly smiles sweetly. Genuinely.</context>
      <utterance>Andy... THEY SAID YES! They agreed to it all! They thought your terms were a shining example of your "irreverent wit" -- and precisely why they want you!  You're getting EVERYTHING! Whoa. Andy looks up, astonished. His space station</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well thank you very much...!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TONY DANZA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One producer stands. This is tightly-wound ED WEINBERGER.</context>
      <utterance>Man, this is bullshit!  Where's Kaufman? Why isn't he here??</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An angry beat. The actors resume...</context>
      <utterance>You'll see him on Friday when we shoot. Now run the lines with Rodney.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JUDD HIRSCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm taking bets we do the show with the stand-in.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILU HENNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Judd is surprised.</context>
      <utterance>No, I hear Andy arrived. Rumor is he's locked inside his dressing room.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna quit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Each show is worse than the next.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you nuts?! 40 million people watch you every week!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So? What do they know?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hmm?! Andy raises an eyebrow.</context>
      <utterance>Absolutely nothing! That's the beauty!  It's credibility. You make them love you... and then later, on your special, you'll screw with their heads!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care! Travolta signed a contract, he's a Sweathog for life!... Oh yeah? Just try to sue us. He HANGS up. His ASSISTANT peeks her head in.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maynard is baffled.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, they're having a problem down on the Kaufman Special. They say he's not following the... technical requirements.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Technical"???</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andy, I hear fabulous things about the Special...  Eh, I understand we've hit a teeny speedbump?</utterance>
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maynard doesn't exactly understand.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Kid Genius told me to mess with the horizontal hold! He wants the picture to roll!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The technician pushes a button. ON THE MONITOR - Andy's image briefly appears.</context>
      <utterance>Show me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>ON-SCREEN</mode>
      <context>At that moment, Andy's image starts rolling across the screen, until it disappears into a blur of static...</context>
      <utterance>And now... in her television debut, the incredible Chubby Rosalie!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll be great. The viewer will think their TV is broken. They'll get out of their chair, they'll twist the knobs, they'll hit the TV, but they won't be able to fix it! Maynard stares at the monitor. The totally indecipherable picture still rolls. A glum pause.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andy... we don't want the viewer to get out of their chair. They might change the channel.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy beams giddily. Maynard gazes dully, struggling to reason.</context>
      <utterance>But it's funny! It's a practical joke. They'll get frustrated!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andy... uhh... this network has a long-standing policy: The viewer must be able to see the program.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>But it's only for thirty seconds!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both men quickly extend their hands and shake. Maynard nods and leaves. Beat. Then, Andy pulls out a Handi-wipe and cleans his palm. A STUDIO PAGE walks over. He has a huge MAIL BAG.</context>
      <utterance>Deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUDIO PAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy looks up -- and his face lights up like Christmas.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Kaufman, do you want your mail?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MIMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A disinterested beat.</context>
      <utterance>... so after I finish junior college, I'll go to work for my dad's accounting firm. Unless, I decide to live with my friend Valerie, but she wants to move to Anaheim, and I don't want to do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Another beat. ANDY  So do you wanna wrestle?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me -- ?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mimi is bewildered, and offended.</context>
      <utterance>Do you wanna wrestle? It's a good way of breaking the ice.  That instant physical intimacy really brings two people together.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?! We just met an hour ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No no no, it's not sex! I mean -- it can lead to sex... but really, it's just wrestling.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An awkward silence. They continue walking. She points up. MIMI (cont'd) The sunset is really beautiful.</context>
      <utterance>I don't wanna talk about it!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean -- uh -- the colors in the sky are so vibrant. I love this time of day.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never understood that. It's just... getting dark.  But I like you! Hey! Why don't we fill the car with gas, drive to Tijuana, and GET MARRIED???</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGLE - MIMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fear. She shivers, then hoarsely speaks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I wanna go home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>ON TV</mode>
      <context>Very gently, Andy touches Howdy's cheek and starts weeping. THE EXECS -- are horrified.</context>
      <utterance>You know... I was once in your gallery. I was just sitting there and I wanted to touch you. I was kind of depressed because I could see what everyone was like, and I was wondering if, now, maybe I could... touch you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>ON TV</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Howdy, I've been watching you ever since I was a little boy...  You're the first friend from television I ever had. I always wanted to meet you... and now ...I finally am.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXEC #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is NOT funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXEC #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Artsy Fartsy shit"...</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment, the picture turns to FUZZY SNOW. Maynard scowls.</context>
      <utterance>No... eh, the Special isn't all like this... just wait... it will be hysterical.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maynard angrily jumps and POUNDS on the TV. BANG, BANG! George winces -- then mutters awkwardly.</context>
      <utterance>Christ! We're the Number One Network -- can't we afford decent TVs?!</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maynard is embarrassed. Finally -- he explodes.</context>
      <utterance>No, um... it's part of the snow. An awful beat.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell Kaufman we will NEVER air this program!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BLUE COLLAR GUY 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, could I please have more coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guy nods. Andy hurries over with the coffeepot and starts pouring.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, yeah, in a sec'.  That was decaf, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLUE COLLAR GUY 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, you look just like Andy Kaufman.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy hurries off. The guy's buddy leans in, whispering.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I get that all the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLUE COLLAR GUY 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm telling you, it's him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLUE COLLAR GUY 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna bet?? If that was him, he wouldn't be workin' here, pouring my coffee!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Could you clear this table and bring me a piece of poundcake? Andy turns. They stare down each other. GEORGE  Andy, this is ridiculous. Take off that apron.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy hurries off with a water pitcher. George chases him.</context>
      <utterance>NO! I'd rather work here, than at ABC. There's no lying in a restaurant. They don't promise you a job as a cashier, then suddenly make you a frycook!</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I'm sorry. They're assholes! But we work in a creative business. You can't predict what people are gonna like --</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ONLY reason I did Taxi was so I could have my own Special!</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell you what. I'll book you on some concerts, and meanwhile, we'll show the Special around... see if somebody wants to buy it --</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, we can have a garage sale. "Hey look, I got a floor lamp and a network TV Special for only fifty cents!" A glum moment. Andy fills water glasses. ANDY  How long is left on my Taxi contract?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You signed for five years --  So four years, seven months.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay... I'll go back. But just let them know, first they ain't gettin' Latka. They're gettin' Tony!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy angrily hurries offstage.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me one moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me the book.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! Andy, don't do it --</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy fiercely GRABS a small book from Zmuda. Zmuda cringes.</context>
      <utterance>They're asking for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he goes into a</context>
      <utterance>Since you're such a special audience... I'm going to reveal, for the first time ever, the real me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>AS LATKA</mode>
      <context>The audience APPLAUDS enthusiastically. Andy waits until the applause dies and goes back to the book.</context>
      <utterance>Tank you veddy much!!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>BRITISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"When I came back from the East last autumn, I felt that I wanted the world to be in uniform and at a sort of moral attention forever; I wanted no more riotous excursions with privileged glimpses into the human heart..." People start BOOING. Andy looks up. ANDY   Please, let's keep it down. We have a long way to go.  "Only Gatsby, the man who gives his name to this book, was exempt from my reaction - Gatsby, who represented everything for which I have an unaffected scorn..." The crowd is incredulous.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PROMOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he ever going to stop?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. When he reaches "The End."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>BRITISH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Tom was evidently perturbed at Daisy's running around alone, for on the following Saturday night he came with her to Gatsby's party. Perhaps his presence gave the evening its peculiar quality of oppressiveness..." A weak VOICE feebly shouts:</utterance>
   <speaker>WEAK VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy looks up, shocked. Insulted, he "blows his temper."</context>
      <utterance>Do Latka.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>BRITISH</mode>
      <context>He slams the book shut. People CHEER. Andy starts to storm off -- then turns. ANDY (BRITISH) (cont'd) No, no, I'm only fooling. The audience GROANS. ANDY (BRITISH) (cont'd) I'll tell you what. Would you rather have me continue reading or would you like to hear the phonograph record? The audience ROARS for the record. Andy smiles, puts the needle on and to everyone's horror more "Gatsby" comes out.</context>
      <utterance>Look! I don't have to tolerate this impoliteness! Forget it -- I'm gonna stop the show. GOODBYE!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>BRITISH-FROM THE RECORD</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"His presence gave the evening its peculiar quality of oppressiveness - it stands out in my memory from Gatsby's other parties that summer..."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy nods uncomprehendingly.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody likes anarchy more than me... but this is science fiction!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's get some breakfast.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy mumbles in a pipsqueak whimper.</context>
      <utterance>What kind of show was this??!  There were three-hundred walkouts! The promoter wants a refund!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, George...</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You should be watchin' out for him!</context>
      <utterance>You're DAMN RIGHT you're sorry!  And you -- you're the road manager!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George paces furiously.</context>
      <utterance>We might have lost our focus...</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When you play the Midwest and South, you DON'T MINDFUCK THESE PEOPLE! It's not postmodern -- it's rude.  If you wanna perform in Texas, you give 'em Mighty Mouse! You give 'em Elvis!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But George, I like to push the boundaries...</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hmm. Andy thinks.</context>
      <utterance>And that's great. But do it in LA and New York! There you experiment! Show up with a sleeping bag and take a nap on stage! I don't care!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long would they let me sleep?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know!  Andy... you need to look inside: Who are you trying to entertain? The audience... or yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGLE - ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He doesn't know the answer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm worried about Andy. His stress level is affecting his work.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't Tony Clifton going on Taxi soon? Maybe that'll chill him out.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zmuda mulls this over.</context>
      <utterance>Bob, Andy needs to RELAX. See if you can get him away from all this. Take him to Hawaii, or Bali... Find something special. Something nice...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dunno about this...  What will my mother think?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She'll say, "Now my son is a man."</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's so dirty.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy nods.</context>
      <utterance>Nah. The girls sponge off between johns.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat -- then Andy becomes GERMAN, with a monocle and stiff walk.</context>
      <utterance>Which one?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>GERMAN</mode>
      <context>The two chosen girls take Andy's hands and lead him off. He reaches the door -- then gives Zmuda a nervous look. Zmuda smiles reassuringly. Andy gulps, and goes in... Beat. Zmuda turns to the older, jaded MADAM.</context>
      <utterance>I vill haf both! I vill haf dat fraulein... unt... the vun vith the big strudels!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a big day. It's my friend's first time with a prostitute.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zmuda's jaw drops, stupefied.</context>
      <utterance>What're you talking about? Andy comes here almost every weekend.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're talking about... Andy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Disbelief -- then Zmuda LAUGHS sharply. He's been conned.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, he doesn't always call himself that. Sometimes he's Tony, and wears a tux.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You let me win.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy grins and leans down...</context>
      <utterance>What if we did...?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. If I give you three-hundred dollars, will you come to LA and help me destroy a TV show?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TONY DANZA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He just arrived.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROL KANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's an hour late.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly -- the door SLAMS open. Tony bounds in, filthy drunk, clutching a bottle in a brown bag.</context>
      <utterance>Look, I'm told this Clifton guy is a little eccentric. You're all just gonna have to roll with the punches this week.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY CLIFTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maxie! Them's all the words that rhyme with taxi!... Right, girls? Little Wendy and the Hooker sashay in, dressed as tarts. Tony feels them up, and they SQUEAL. The cast stares in horror. TONY CLIFTON (cont'd) Eh, why the blue faces? You musta read the script! (he chuckles) Well, don't worry! Your pal Tony stayed up all night, writin' some fixes on it. (he pulls out some</context>
      <utterance>Taxi! Laxy! Just the factsy,</utterance>
   <speaker>SCRIBBLED PAGES)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed's expression goes ashen.</context>
      <utterance>I added me a musical number, cut out Judd Hirsch, and changed the location to Mardi Gras!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TONY CLIFTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And now, the new theme song!  "Oh yes, we drive a taxi, And we're havin' fun. Yeah, we work together, And we get the freakin' job done."</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>George, we've lost two days. Filming is on Friday. We HAVE to let him go!</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure how Andy's gonna take this...</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points at Tony, swaggering around on the set. George shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>So we'll go downstairs and tell him!</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed glares.</context>
      <utterance>But that's Tony down there. That's not Andy. Trust me, it's like "Sybil" -- Andy's nowhere on the premises!</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well whoever the fuck that is, I'm firing him!</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Heh? Ed raises his eyebrows.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. But we'll have to warn Andy first. I think he's up in San Francisco, doing a concert.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode>INTO PHONE</mode>
      <context>Ed glances down at the stage... and suddenly Tony is no longer there. He's magically vanished. Beat. George turns on the SPEAKERPHONE, then CLICK! Andy's happy voice pops on the line.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Diane, this is George. I'm trying to reach Andy up in San Francisco.  Yeah, I'll wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, George! Good to hear from you!</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Andy. How's the weather up there?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Ed looks totally off-balance. George winks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, you know the Bay Area! Always foggy!</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's been some trouble with Tony.</context>
      <utterance>I'm here with Ed over at Taxi.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no! Did he get hurt?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>burlesque.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, Andy, nothing like that.  But... Tony's not fitting in. His style of performance is too...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andy, I'm calling you up like this because I have the utmost respect for your artistry. But -- I need your permission to fire him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh dear!  George, this is gonna kill Tony. He's waited his whole life for this break.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There'll be other shots.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy thinks about this.</context>
      <utterance>Andy, I have to do it. He's a terrible actor.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess I understand. But Ed -- please... let him down gentle.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Andy, I will. Andy hangs up. A relieved Ed turns to George. ED  Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We had a deal!!</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY CLIFTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You musta talked to someone else --</context>
      <utterance>I don't know what yer talkin' about.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah!! I talked to Andy Kaufman!</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY CLIFTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed is livid. He gazes harshly at Tony -- Tony's burning eyes piercing through the rubber features.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know nothin' about no Kaufman. He's been ridin' my coattails, smearing my reputation. Been usin' my good name, to get places.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get off my stage! You're fired!</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY CLIFTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly -- FLASH! Ed looks over. A REPORTER has a camera.</context>
      <utterance>I GOT A CONTRACT!! I'm gonna take you to the DEPARTMENT OF LABOR!</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who're YOU?!</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>UP IN THE BLEACHERS - George enters. He looks down at the growing debacle, and winces. Uh-oh. ONSTAGE - Enraged, Ed blows up.</context>
      <utterance>I'm from the LA Times. We're doing a little puff piece on Mr. Clifton.  Mr. Kaufman arranged it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ONSTAGE - Studio SECURITY GUARDS run over. They GRAB Tony.</context>
      <utterance>Security! Escort this man off the lot!!</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY CLIFTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TONY CLIFTON (cont'd)</context>
      <utterance>Stop! GETCHER HANDS OFF ME! Tony scuffles. The camera FLASHES.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want those pictures getting out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zmuda takes the camera. He casually starts to make his way for the exit... when Ed suddenly HOLLERS.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take care of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zmuda gasps. Two guards go running for him. Zmuda barrels away, trying to escape. The guards chase. Zmuda races by George, and suddenly palms off the camera into George's arms. The guards whip by, oblivious. George grimaces, unclear about his loyalties. He sweatily peers at the timebomb in his hands. And then -- George thrusts it under his jacket. He bolts for the door and feverishly scampers out.</context>
      <utterance>Wait -- he's one of THEM!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TONY CLIFTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George slowly smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Hey. Good hustlin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That asshole! That FUCKING</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um, Ed... you have a phone call --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Heh??! Shaking with fury, Ed stares at the telephone... then slowly picks it up.</context>
      <utterance>Well, um... it's Andy Kaufman...</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long pause... then Andy's voice calmly speaks.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah???</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A flabbergasted beat.</context>
      <utterance>You were brilliant.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were in the moment. You became a producer losing his mind.  It was the best improv I've ever seen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>Well -- thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. See you next week. Andy hangs up. Ed just sits there, astounded.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zmuda reads one paragraph.</context>
      <utterance>This is great! It makes Tony REAL - - three-dimensional! It's very good for his career.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Was this in actuality Andy Kaufman? And if it was Andy Kaufman, is Andy Kaufman crazy?"</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he shouts to a</context>
      <utterance>Boy, they totally fell for it! I'm only acting crazy! Hmm. A few awkward glances. Then -- Andy grins at his meal. ANDY  Boy, this is tasty.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITER)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, can I please have some more seaweed?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ehh -- Andy doesn't really like playing casinos. The audiences don't work well for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOKER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Disappointed beat. The booker thinks. BOOKER   What about Tony Clifton?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?! You want Tony Clifton to headline Harrah's Tahoe??</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOKER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>George winces.</context>
      <utterance>Eh, sure. We're trying to expand our audience base -- and I know the college kids really love Andy Kaufman.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tony Clifton is NOT Andy Kaufman.</context>
      <utterance>Look -- I gotta be clear with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOKER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, yeah, yeah. I know!  Wink wink! Nudge nudge!</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm serious. If you book Tony, do NOT EXPECT TO GET ANDY.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOKER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>George rolls his eyes in annoyance. Finally, he shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take my chances!!</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine, be my guest! Book him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ONLY!"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>George is flabbergasted.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gene, you misunderstood!! You're not getting BOTH of them!  It's physically impossible!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOKER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why's that? You said over and over and over, Tony Clifton is not Andy Kaufman --</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I KNOW what I said! But -- trust me, it's not gonna happen!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOKER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>George is stupefied. He looks at his watch.</context>
      <utterance>Sure it is. Tony called me himself. He yelled at me, insisting that his dressing room be bigger than Andy's. They're both going on tonight, believe me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PUSHY MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not listenin'! It's a VERY simple concept.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE OF PUSHY MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're making no sense. How can they be the same person --?</utterance>
   <speaker>PUSHY MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The onstage ORCHESTRA hits a fanfare. LIGHTS DIM. Sharp SPOTLIGHTS meet at the foot of the stage. Suddenly -- Tony swaggers out, hands over his head in a gesture of triumph. Thunderous APPLAUSE. Tony beams. The music stops. George leans in, curious as to how Andy will wiggle out of this. Tony bows theatrically, turns back to face the orchestra, and waits. The NOISE LEVEL slowly drops -- but not entirely. Tony waits, and waits, and waits... until suddenly he turns towards the audience and SCREAMS</context>
      <utterance>Trust me! You'll never see them on stage at the same time!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PUSHY MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George grins stupidly. The silence is now deafening. Slowly, very slowly, Tony raises his arms. Slowly... the musicians get their instruments ready. Tony stands there, and stands, and stands, waiting for something... anything... to disturb the silence. In vain. Somebody COUGHS. The whole scene repeats itself. Finally -- finally -- Tony is surrounded by total silence. Then, (only a moment before the length of this scene would become unbearable), he begins to move. Tony pivots around, looks at the audience... And the entire room looks like Tussaud's Wax Museum. Tony starts LAUGHING hysterically. The audience's reaction is mixed: Some people LAUGH. Some BOO. Some ask perplexed questions. Some SCREAM OBSCENITIES. Some even APPLAUD. Tony is very happy. He turns to the orchestra, raises his baton -- and commences the downbeat! The MUSIC BEGINS. A SPOTLIGHT hits the wings... and then ANDY STRIDES OUT. George's jaw drops.</context>
      <utterance>He's never gonna start! Kaufman thinks this is funny!  We've paid forty bucks for a show that's never gonna start!</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE OF PUSHY MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The whole audience BURSTS INTO APPLAUSE. Life is back to normal. Andy bows shyly and takes his place in front of a prepared row of congas. He starts to play. Tony Clifton grabs the microphone.</context>
      <utterance>You see! I told you! They're not the same person!</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY CLIFTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George squints his eyes, trying to figure out who this is. TONY CLIFTON (cont'd) "Whether I'm right Or whether I'm wrong Whether I find a place in this world Or never belong! I gotta be me! I gotta be me! What else can I be, but what I am?" Tony's singing is awful. Andy happily accompanies on congas. The audience doesn't know what to think. Tony's SINGING reaches the end... aggressive and off-key. TONY CLIFTON (cont'd) Let's bring it on home -- (he hits his screeching CLIMAX)</context>
      <utterance>Thank you! Thank you! I wrote this tune for my friend Frank Sinatra. He had a nice little success with it... but forgot to thank me on the album. He starts to BELT "I Gotta Be Me".</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're so proud. You're like some retarded kid comin' home from school: "Look, Dad, I got an F!"</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But wasn't it funny?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy excitedly jumps up and down.</context>
      <utterance>"Funny"? I dunno. But "intriguing"... "mindboggling"... perhaps "headache-inducing"... sure.  Like, that moment, when you both came onstage...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George is dazed.</context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh! See, with all these articles, people think they're insiders. They see Tony Clifton, and they say, "Ah, that's really Andy Kaufman." But that spoils it. So NOW, Tony denying being me is the truth! Tony's not me! But maybe he is! The audience will never know...  They'll think they're laughin' at me -- but actually I'll be laughin' at them, because they're wrong and I'm right!</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you've got this big elaborate joke, which is really only funny to two people in the universe.  You... and you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure! But WE think it's kickass! Now I get to be Tony. I get to dump the glass of water on someone else's head!</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hmm. Andy contemplates this.</context>
      <utterance>But what's the POINT? How will any of this make you the biggest star in the world?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>George... I'm at a stage where the audience expects me to constantly shock them. But short of faking my death, or setting the theater on fire, I don't know what else to do.  'Cause I've always got to be one step ahead of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A perplexed beat.</context>
      <utterance>But I feel you're extending this philosophy to real life. It's obsessive. Nothing's ever on the level anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>George, it never was.  Didn't you know that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at this! An evil Russian! Ooo, here's an evil Nazi -- he likes to fight dirty! Hey, here's an evil Japanese guy!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this, World War Two...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I always wanted to be a bad-guy wrestler...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat -- then Andy notices an issue of Sumo Magazine, with a picture of a wrestler and his cute little fianc&amp; 1081;e on the cover. He slowly lifts it up, intrigued.</context>
      <utterance>No offense, pal, but I just don't think you're built for it. These he- men'll kick your ass!! They're huge! Andy's face drops. He realizes Zmuda's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I'll pick on someone smaller than me...!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... And I vow to continue wrestling until I am BEA TEN, in a three- minute match, with my shoulders pinned to the mat!!</utterance>
   <speaker>MERV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By a woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm doing this because I feel that a woman cannot beat a man in wrestling. Even if they train with weights... it requires a certain mental ability -- (a clumsy pause) And, uh -- I just don't feel they have that... The audience MURMURS uncomfortably. Andy laughs and backpedals. ANDY (cont'd) No no! Women are superior in many ways. When it comes to cooking and cleaning, washing the potatoes, scrubbing the carrots, raising the babies, mopping the floors, they have it all over men. I believe that! An appalled silence. Merv winces. Some people start BOOING. We can tell Andy is pleased. ANDY (cont'd) But when it comes to wrestling, forget it! If there's a woman that can prove me wrong, come up here. I'll shut my mouth and pay her 500 dollars. Merv baitingly turns to the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Yes! BY A WOMAN!</utterance>
   <speaker>MERV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any... volunteers...?</utterance>
   <speaker>WIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We move through the crowd, finally picking out... a feisty woman, LYNNE. She mutters, half hateful, half laughing --</context>
      <utterance>All the WOMEN'S hands angrily shoot up!</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanna kill that jerk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode>AS REFEREE</mode>
      <context>Lynne extends her hand. Andy fakes a shake -- then snidely refuses and struts away. The crowd HISSES. DING! It's the bell. The match begins. Lynne barrels at him, craving a victory, but terribly unprepared for this experience. Andy immediately grabs her by the legs and flips her over. WHUMP! She's down. Andy has trained for this. Zmuda gets on his knees, watching, trying to look official. Lynne struggles and slithers away. She grabs Andy's arm and forces him down. People CHEER. His torso hits the mat. LOUDER CHEERS. But suddenly he rolls over and pulls her hair! Her head snaps back. The crowd is INCENSED. Zmuda hurries over and pantomimes a stern warning. Andy nods, and they separate. They do a little dance around the ring, Lynne looking for a hole. Suddenly, Andy spins her into a Half-Nelson. Her arms are pinned. They struggle, then he throws her down on her stomach. One! Two! Three! And DING! It's OVER. Andy jumps up and sneers at the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Will you please shake hands, go to your corners, and come out wrestling.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the winner! I've got the</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GUEST COORDINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's your complimentary photo with Merv. Here's your Turtle Wax --</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't need Turtle Wax.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUEST COORDINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lynne takes her junk and hobbles off. She passes Andy, who sees her and grins.</context>
      <utterance>Every guest of Merv gets it. And here's your dinner-for-two voucher at Red Lobster.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gosh, you scored! Look at all those goodies!</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lynne coldly hurries away. Andy chases after her.</context>
      <utterance>Buzz off. Go patronize somebody else.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I hope you didn't take that stuff I said seriously. It was just part of the show!  It's like the old days, when a carnival barker would try to rile up the crowd.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy nods, pleased.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. So you were just pretending to be an asshole.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lynne stares -- then begrudgingly cracks a smile.</context>
      <utterance>It's what I'm good at!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Merv Griffin has received 2000 pieces of hate mail. Andy, Merv Griffin doesn't GET hate mail.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he hands him a</context>
      <utterance>That means it was a success. I woke up the audience -- like punk rock!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBELL)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here, take this.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He crosses his arms. Andy frowns and lowers the weight. GEORGE (cont'd) Buddyboy, they detest you! Next time you make an appearance, women are gonna picket.</context>
      <utterance>No, I'm not gonna take it. If I take it I'll break my back.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're having a laugh...</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>WRONG! You haven't given them any clues that it's a parody!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's because they've only seen it once. But I'll do it again, and again, and AGAIN...  They'll catch on!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi...</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi... am I late?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy gives Lynne her ticket. They enter the theater.</context>
      <utterance>No, I'm sure we'll be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Popcorn?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One large tub of popcorn, please, extra butter. The CANDY GIRL makes Andy his popcorn. He pays... then heads to the exit. ANDY (cont'd) Okay. Let's go. Lynne is baffled.</context>
      <utterance>I really want one.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andy, the theater's that way!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I love movie theater popcorn... but that doesn't mean I have to sit through "On Golden Pond." Lynne stands in place. Andy smiles. ANDY  C'mon. We'll go for a walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She throws down her ticket and runs after him.</context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did you call me? The last person I ever expected to get a call from was you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gosh. Gee, Lynne... I was just so impressed with your wrestling moves.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi...</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi... am I late?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy gives Lynne her ticket. They enter the theater.</context>
      <utterance>No, I'm sure we'll be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Popcorn?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One large tub of popcorn, please, extra butter. The CANDY GIRL makes Andy his popcorn. He pays... then heads to the exit. ANDY (cont'd) Okay. Let's go. Lynne is baffled.</context>
      <utterance>I really want one.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andy, the theater's that way!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I love movie theater popcorn... but that doesn't mean I have to sit through "On Golden Pond." Lynne stands in place. Andy smiles. ANDY  C'mon. We'll go for a walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She throws down her ticket and runs after him.</context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did you call me? The last person I ever expected to get a call from was you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gosh. Gee, Lynne... I was just so impressed with your wrestling moves.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy is shocked.</context>
      <utterance>You were impressed with something. It's pretty odd when a man sports a hard-on that large on national television.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh! Uh, I hope I didn't offend you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A charged moment. Andy's eyes widen. His speech gets faster.</context>
      <utterance>I'm here, ain't I?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you wanna to go to Memphis and get married?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I wanna go to Memphis and get married?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why Memphis?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>he SPEAKS VERY</utterance>
   <speaker>FAST)</speaker>
      <mode> FAST)</mode>
      <context>Whoa. Lynne stares into his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Because Memphis is the wrestling capital of the world! I'll go in the ring, and I'll announce that I will shave my head and marry any woman who beats me! Then you'll come up, we'll wrestle and I'll let you win! Then you'll scalp me, and we'll get married on Letterman, like Tiny Tim did on Carson... right there on the show! What do you say???</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And all this will be for real?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you want...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The mob LAUGHS harshly.</context>
      <utterance>Look here, Andy Kaufman! I'll take you on -- SISSY!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ooo, the little lady's upset. Well I say -- get back in the kitchen!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy and Lynne are startled.</context>
      <utterance>STOP IT! This woman's a FAKE! She's nothing but Kaufman's girlfriend!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>T-that's not true --</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd angrily starts to HISS. Lynne whispers to Andy.</context>
      <utterance>It's a set-up! And I won't allow our great sport to be degraded by a fix!!</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andy... who is that...?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(this gets HUGE</context>
      <utterance>I'm Jerry Lawler, the KING of Memphis wrestling!!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHEERS)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So if Kaufman wants to tangle, I've brought a real wrestler! She's trained and she's READY!! Kaufman, do you think you can handle... FOXY</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TATTOOED GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy sneers. He cracks his knuckles, finally walks over... and commences a WINDMILL. Absurdly, he spins his arms around and around, daring Foxy to get near him. She rolls her eyes and waits. The REF jumps out of the way. A minute has counted down. Finally, Andy stops -- and the real wrestling begins. Foxy lunges at him and immediately goes for a choke-hold. The crowd CHEERS, relieved. Lawler motions signals. Foxy yanks -- but Andy jerks away. Andy is intrigued. She's coming to play! Andy gestures to the Ref and points UP. The Ref looks away -- and Andy SLAPS Foxy. The crowd furiously JEERS. The Ref spins around, and Andy shrugs innocence. He then runs at Foxy and theatrically pushes her into the ropes. She bounces off, stumbles back - - and Andy drops to his knees. She trips over him and hits the mat. Andy aggressively jumps onto Foxy's shoulders and pins her. The Ref counts: One! Two! Three! DING!! It's over. But Andy stays on her, shaking his ass, leering rudely. Jerry Lawler yells from the corner.</context>
      <utterance>Are you scared???</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy remains, flapping his arms like a chicken. THE BOOING grows. Louder. More emotional.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, you won. GET OFF HER!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGRY VOICES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lawler hesitates -- then suddenly climbs in the ring and lifts Andy off! Lawler angrily PUSHES Andy down. Andy is flabbergasted.</context>
      <utterance>Jerry, help her! Get in there! Do something!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lawler snickers and walks away. Completely overreacting, Andy grabs the mike. ANDY (cont'd) I'm gonna SUE YOU! (he starts RANTING berserkly) Let me tell you something, Lawler! I am not a hick -- I'm a national TV star! And I DON'T like a dumb cracker pushing me around in the ring! I never agreed to wrestle you! So you know what I'm gonna do??? (seething) I'm gonna hire a lawyer to sue you for every cent you've got! This was assault and battery! In a court of law, I'm gonna kick your Southern- fried rump!!! Lawler snatches the mike and bellows.</context>
      <utterance>W-what are you DOING? I don't fight men!</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>YEAH?! Well I got news for you, Andy Kaufman! Wrestling is a serious sport to me! I don't like anyone makin' fun of it, and I hate anyone insultin' the South! So we can settle this two ways: We can go to court... or you can get in the ring with a man, and wrestle for</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy grabs back the mike. He sticks his face in shocked Lawler's. ANDY (cont'd) (sarcastic SOUTHERN</context>
      <utterance>He -- can't get away with this.  YOU! You think I'm CHICKEN?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ACCENT)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy bears his teeth. Enraged, Lawler tries to take a swing at him. HANDLERS run in and separate the angry men.</context>
      <utterance>You wanna "wraaastle" me?! You wanna "WRAAASTLE" me??? Okay, Lawler -- let's rumble! Yeah, I've only wrestled women, but they were bigger than you! In fact, they're probably smarter than you, 'cause you're from "Maaamphis, Taaanassee!"  I'm from Hollywood. I have the brains. That's how I win. And Mr. Lawler, I'm gonna make you cry "Mama!"</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this an act -- or are you addicted to causing trouble??</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's unamused.</context>
      <utterance>I can shtop whenever I want...</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then stop treating me like a fucking prop.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shoots him a stern look.</context>
      <utterance>I-I'm sorry. I got caught up in the action...!</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy laughs.</context>
      <utterance>I'm warning you, Kaufman: One morning you're gonna wake up... and your head's gonna be shaved.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You've lost touch with reality!</context>
      <utterance>Andy, do you realize you don't do comedy anymore? Where's that sweet guy who used to do  "Here I come to save the day!"?  Please, enough with the wrestling!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, you don't think I can beat him?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy shrugs, lacking a response. He eats more cake. GEORGE (cont'd) Andy, look... there's a job I want you to take -- guest-hosting the TV show "Fridays." It's not so hot... but this is a great opportunity for you. The show's live, they'll give you carte blanche, and you can get back to the business of making people laugh. Andy gets a strange gleam. He only heard one thing.</context>
      <utterance>He is the Southern Heavyweight Champion. He'll kill you.  First, you piss-off women. Then you piss-off the South. Then you get killed!  And I did the bookings.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said -- live?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not comfortable with the last sketch. I DON'T do drug humor!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK BURNS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andy, it'll be fine! It's what we're known for!  "Maui? "Wowie!"</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not listening to me --</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK BURNS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry! The kids will love it</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I don't do drugs! And I don't enjoy making light of them!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>YELLING</mode>
      <context>Andy storms off. Eavesdropping cast shake their heads.</context>
      <utterance>I was promised creative control!</utterance>
   <speaker>ACTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a prick!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JANICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw Michael!</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SKETCH is on a French restaurant set. ANDY sits at a table with actor RICHARDS and actress MELANIE. Another actress, MARY, tiptoes back over, GIGGLING stupidly, playing stoned.</context>
      <utterance>Afterwards, I'll take you backstage. You can meet my brother. The girl smiles excitedly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She GIGGLES more. The other three play baffled.</context>
      <utterance>"Gee, restaurants are amazing, aren't they? All these strangers sitting around... stuffing dead animals in their faces! It's just incredible!"</utterance>
   <speaker>MELANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"If you say so."</utterance>
   <speaker>ACTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Excuse me, I'll be right back." Andy stands and walks out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JANICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmph! They sure didn't give Andy much to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said he's coming back!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy purses his lips, fretting. An endless pause. Uh-oh. Andy won't finish the line. The cast looks around worriedly. Live TV is beaming out... Finally, Melanie covers.</context>
      <utterance>"Gee, that bathroom is so colorf--" Suddenly he STOPS. The actors glance up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay, honey? Something wrong, Carl?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't, um... Andy shakes his head. The crowd laughs nervously. ANDY  I can't play stoned.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>TECH DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Maynard raises a calm hand.</context>
      <utterance>Shit...! What's he doing??</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay. Stay with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICHARDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just read the cue cards!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More silence. The actors are trapped and upset.</context>
      <utterance>I can't play stoned. I feel really stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Unsure beat -- then fed-up Richards jumps up and storms off the set. A CAMERAMAN hesitantly pans, confused what to do. Mary is lost. She continues giggling, "stoned." Richards returns... with the CUE CARDS. Irked, he dumps them over Andy's head. The crowd CHEERS stupidly.</context>
      <utterance>You feel stupid? What about us?! The tension is awful.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy gets enraged, grabs his prop water glass and THROWS it in Richard's face.</context>
      <utterance>You didn't have to do that!</utterance>
   <speaker>RICHARDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! CUT IT OUT!</utterance>
   <speaker>MELANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Melanie slaps her prop butter in Andy's hair. WIDE - Jack runs up from the floor. He gestures at the booth.</context>
      <utterance>You JERK!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK BURNS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go to commercial, man!  Get off the stage!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said I didn't want to do the sketch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MELANIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All the commotion stops. The audience doesn't know whether to laugh or boo. The actors are flabbergasted -- then furious. MELANIE (cont'd) He's a fuckin' psycho!</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God --!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Maynard runs out of the booth, beaming. People watch curiously. Andy seems discombobulated. Maynard shouts out to EVERYBODY assembled.</context>
      <utterance>Why didn't someone tell us???</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The audience LAUGHS and APPLAUDS wildly. The actors stare in disbelief. One laughs hysterically. Most are pissed. MAYNARD (cont'd) But we don't want to upset the folks at home. So now Andy is now going to apologize and explain that it was all a prank. Right, Andy?</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me!... I have an announcement to make! You've all just participated in a "happening." To make it real, some of you knew, and some of you didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crew members start moving things around. In the audience, Michael locks eyes with Andy. An odd, knowing moment between the brothers. Michael whispers, getting worried.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, great! So let's reset!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andy...!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JANICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Fridays JINGLE starts, and Andy's face fades in on the TV. He looks directly into the camera, nervous, stiff and serious.</context>
      <utterance>Why is Andy doing this? Why?... Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>ON TV</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>During the commercial, the people at ABC asked me to apologize... and to tell you the truth. They wanted me to explain that this whole fighting episode was staged...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maynard is suddenly very confused. The crowd laughs nervously. ANDY (cont'd) Why are you laughing? I'm not trying to be funny! They threatened to fire me from Taxi, unless I gave in to their demands! (shaken) But... I won't! Because what you saw was REAL!!</context>
      <utterance>And... um...  I can't do this.  I-I can't say it.  It's a lie! A cover-up!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cue the commercial!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>ON TV</mode>
      <context>Maynard jumps up, furious. He snaps.</context>
      <utterance>These kinds of things go on everyday at the networks, only you never see it, because they cut to commercials.  Now for sure they're gonna fire me, so if you want to see me again, you'll have to come to Memphis... And BLINK! Andy gets CUT OFF.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna STRANGLE George Shapiro!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JANICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's in Memphis?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who knows?! That kid is totally meshuga.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JANICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why is he saying these things?!</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're gonna lynch him!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy reaches in his pocket and removes... a bar of SOAP.</context>
      <utterance>Nah. He's just engaging a passive audience.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd is enraged -- rumblings of imminent violence. Andy smiles helpfully. ANDY (cont'd) And now, for your next lesson: This -- is toilet paper. Andy holds up a ROLL OF TISSUE. That's it. The crowd goes NUTS. Jerry Lawler races over and snatches the mike, trying to maintain his dignity.</context>
      <utterance>People, this is a bar of soap. Does it look familiar to you? If you wet it, it'll clean your hands. Stanley's eyes bulge.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kaufman, we've had enough!! Let's you and me do what we came here for</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Lawler's waiting for him to return.</context>
      <utterance>And Kaufman's left the ring!</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lawler disparagingly frowns. The REF checks his watch. Andy crosses to the opposite end of the ring, gauging his rival... then slowly climbs in -- Until the second Lawler moves. Then Andy leaps back out!</context>
      <utterance>Is this a strategy?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Andy struts around the floor, pointing to his brain. He smirks at various spectators... until he finds himself face- to-face with -- his parents. An unexpected moment. Andy's finger frozen on his brain. Janice shakes her head despairingly.</context>
      <utterance>And Kaufman's left the ring again! He doesn't seem interested in actually making contact with his opponent.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cameras FLASH. The paparazzi love these moments.</context>
      <utterance>Andy, please. Let's go home!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat -- then Andy gets HIT in the head with a cup. People HOOT. Disoriented, Andy returns to the ringside. Lawler is losing his patience.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, Mom. I'll make you proud...!</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy paces around, unsure of his next move. LAWLER (cont'd) Look... if you get in here, I'll give you a free headlock. Lawler leans down and offers his neck. Andy peers skeptically. People JEER. Andy looks at waiting Lawler... then tentatively climbs in. As promised, Lawler doesn't move. So Andy crosses over and grabs Lawler's head! Andy grins triumphantly. He squeezes his arms tight, muscles flexing, riding high on this moment. Until -- Lawler stands and flips him over. Andy SLAMS DOWN on his back. CRUNCH!</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Did you come down here to wrestle, or to act like an ass?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Andy lies on the mat, unmoving. Lawler doesn't care. He picks up Andy's prone body and grips it upside-down. Janice covers her eyes. Stanley is worried.</context>
      <utterance>It's a side suplex!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy's parents' reaction is a fiesta for photographers.</context>
      <utterance>Why isn't he MOVING??</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Raging Lawler promenades around the ring, arms over his head. The crowd SHOUTS CRAZILY, rooting him on. Lynne runs to the ropes, SCREAMING for help.</context>
      <utterance>Lawler has committed a PILEDRIVER, which is an AUTOMATIC DISQUALIFICATION! Match goes to Kaufman by disqualification, after two minutes, twelve seconds! Andy is splayed unconscious.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JANICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy opens his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Andy!! Are you okay?!?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A confused beat.</context>
      <utterance>I'm fine, Mom, you can calm down.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>B-but... we saw... your neck...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Total silence. Stanley stares... then a FURY comes over him.</context>
      <utterance>Nah, it's phony baloney -- I faked the whole thing.  It didn't hurt at all. It was just a yoga move. I tucked my head in. Deadpan, Andy sits up.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raging Lawler promenades around the ring, arms over his head. The crowd SHOUTS CRAZILY, rooting him on. Lynne runs to the ropes, SCREAMING for help.</context>
      <utterance>Andrew -- HOW DARE YOU!! For all we knew, you were DYING! Look at your mother -- she's still shaking! Andy is splayed unconscious.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JANICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy opens his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Andy!! Are you okay?!?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A confused beat.</context>
      <utterance>I'm fine, Mom, you can calm down.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>B-but... we saw... your neck...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Total silence. Stanley stares... then a FURY comes over him.</context>
      <utterance>Nah, it's phony baloney -- I faked the whole thing.  It didn't hurt at all. It was just a yoga move. I tucked my head in. Deadpan, Andy sits up.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andrew -- HOW DARE YOU!! For all we knew, you were DYING! Look at your mother -- she's still shaking!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stanley has a blank expression. But Janice starts to cry.</context>
      <utterance>But that's it. I needed you to believe! Our family will be in the newspapers. People will look, and they'll be touched. Because your emotions were honest!</utterance>
   <speaker>JANICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy is genuinely shocked. He looks at his quivering mother... and then his voice softens, truly remorseful.</context>
      <utterance>Andy, I love you! I love you, whatever you do...! She hugs Andy tightly.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Geez, I'm sorry. Maybe I shouldn't have put you through all that...  Well, from now on, you'll always know the rule of thumb: Anything that happens to me... IS NOT REAL.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>OLD DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't see any injury to your neck, Mr. Kaufman.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Positive.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But my neck hurts... and I have a slight cough...</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's probably just a strained muscle.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Doctor gives up.</context>
      <utterance>Doctor, I think I need a neck brace.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it makes you happy...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"... has been rushed to a nearby hospital, where doctors are checking him for possible paralysis. His parents are at his bedside. Fans will best remember Kaufman as lovable Latka on television's Taxi"...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a rave! Boy, if I ever fake my death, they'll really miss me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's working for Elvis.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, he's just laying low, waitin' for his comeback.  God, listen to this! "It was morally wrong to take advantage of such an unstable individual..."</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George rolls his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Wow, you can't BUY this kind of publicity!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somebody KNOCKS outside. Andy jumps up, puts on his neck brace, and transforms himself into a shuffling invalid. A DELIVERY BOY drags in an enormous basket of flowers and goodies. Andy takes the card. It reads "Andy, we're all praying for you. Your friends at Taxi." Andy chuckles.</context>
      <utterance>George, let's not drop the ball on this. I've made some kind of cosmic career move.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lorne Michaels squirms uncomfortably. He chooses his words.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for seeing me on such short notice.  I... I wanted to talk to you about booking Andy on "Saturday Night Live."</utterance>
   <speaker>LORNE MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>George -- I don't know if Andy works for our show anymore. That wrestling stuff... is such a turnoff.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lorne Michaels mulls this over.</context>
      <utterance>We agree completely.  Andy has to reconnect with his core audience. So I got him on Letterman tonight. He's gonna apologize to Jerry Lawler, then repent for all his bad guy shenanigans.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORNE MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's smart.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Lorne Michaels nods.</context>
      <utterance>He's very sincere.  And he needs your show...</utterance>
   <speaker>LORNE MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. It'd be good to have the old Andy back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lawler and Letterman are unimpressed.</context>
      <utterance>I apologize for all the wrestling I've ever done. I'm sorry for all the abuse I've ever given...  I was just playing bad guy wrestler. That's not me... it's just a role. But Jerry took it personally.</utterance>
   <speaker>LETTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said some pretty inflammatory things.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angst flickers on Andy's sweaty face. He stammers.</context>
      <utterance>He thinks everything's a joke -- but it's not.  Did you laugh when you were layin' in the hospital?? The crowd WHOOOOS.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>T-there wasn't a reason to purposely hurt me --</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a wimp.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father said I should've gotten a lawyer --!</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then your father's a wimp.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LETTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said some pretty inflammatory things.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angst flickers on Andy's sweaty face. He stammers.</context>
      <utterance>He thinks everything's a joke -- but it's not.  Did you laugh when you were layin' in the hospital?? The crowd WHOOOOS.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>T-there wasn't a reason to purposely hurt me --</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a wimp.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father said I should've gotten a lawyer --!</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then your father's a wimp.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is bad... I only got 28 percent! I'm like McGovern in</utterance>
   <speaker>'72...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>George sighs.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that... we reveal that SOMEONE ELSE is sitting next to Andy. But only the back of his head is visible. GEORGE (cont'd) It's like you two guys wanted to destroy Andy's career! Upsetting all those people... putting out that toxic venom... (helpless) What did you THINK would happen?!</context>
      <utterance>And this wasn't "Merv." This was the hippest audience on television.  They've turned on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were just trying to push the envelope --</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the other person is JERRY LAWLER. He feels bad.</context>
      <utterance>You're BLIND! There is no envelope anymore!!  It hurts me to say this... but there's only one solution --  I don't want you two to ever work together again. We WIDEN...</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY LAWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. We thought it was funny...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jer', it's not your fault. You were terrific.  But maybe George is right...</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY LAWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy gulps emotionally.</context>
      <utterance>That's fine. But I wouldn't have traded it for anything...  Because for one brief, shining moment... the world thought that wrestling was real.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll stay in touch. Next time I'm in Memphis, I'll stop by the house, and Noreen can make me her double chocolate cake.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY LAWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A touching beat... until Andy gets a Quixotic gleam.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, buddy...  Stay good. Andy and Jerry hug.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I can turn it into a bit. I can go back on the show, and say it was rigged. Demand a recount...</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy's face drops.</context>
      <utterance>Andy! You don't get it!  They don't want you back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy is repeating this faster and faster; the students are blinking their eyes faster and faster. The door opens. The Yogi sticks his head in.</context>
      <utterance>Open your eyes... close your eyes... open your eyes... close your eyes... open your eyes... close your eyes...</utterance>
   <speaker>YOGI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, Andy...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Yogi signals Andy to step out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, your Holiness?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOGI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is very difficult for me to say... but -- perhaps it would be best if you didn't attend the retreat.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?? I... I attend every year.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOGI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy is stunned.</context>
      <utterance>Yes -- we do not doubt your devotion to TM. But we feel that perhaps... you and the program have grown apart philosophically.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Philosophically"?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOGI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy is stupefied. He doesn't know how to respond.</context>
      <utterance>The wrestling... the sexist remarks... the foul language... these things are not becoming of an enlightened individual.  It seems you have no respect for anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Yogi shakes his head. Andy can't believe it. He looks around -- men in turbans staring at him. Andy cracks.</context>
      <utterance>Of course I do...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please! You've GOT to let me take the classes! It's how I keep myself</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>YOGI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is apparently not working.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So HELP ME! All I wanna do is</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go away.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door opens. Lynne enters, holding a carton of ice cream.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, it's open.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chocolate.</context>
      <utterance>I brought you Haagen Dazs.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't deserve Haagen Daz. I'm a horrible person.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andy, you're not horrible. You're just... complicated.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know the real me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andy... there is no real you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIGHT - ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then... he slowly smiles.</context>
      <utterance>An astonished silence.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy studies her... looking at Lynne's face, body, eyes. Pause.</context>
      <utterance>You're probably right. They both giggle.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lynne smiles slyly. She leans down and kisses him.</context>
      <utterance>Do you wanna move in together?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Our first phone call!  Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andy... it's me. I've got some crummy news.  Taxi's been canceled. Silence. Andy has no response. GEORGE   Do you want me to come over? Talk about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy hangs up. He just sits there... confused... unsure how to react. Andy scratches his head -- then feels something odd. He goes over to the mirror. On the back of his neck... is an inflamed red pimple. Andy grimaces. ANDY (cont'd) Yuck!</context>
      <utterance>Um... no. Uh, I'm sorta busy right now. Thanks. We'll get together next week.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sparse crowd APPLAUDS. Budd leaves, and Andy shuffles up.</context>
      <utterance>And now we have a treat for you late- night diehards. The star of Taxi -- here in person, Andy Kaufman!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy gives him a look -- thinks -- then continues. ANDY (cont'd) Not to mention that my wife has left me. And she took the kids. (he sighs) I don't know what I'm gonna do with myself. My options are sorta limited... (beat) This morning, I noticed I've got a cyst, or some kind of boil, on the back of my neck. It's really disgusting. Look. Andy turns. The red lump is bigger, grosser. The crowd GROANS, revolted. ANDY (cont'd) So I was thinking, since I'm sort of a quasi-celebrity, that I could charge people to touch it. (candid) Does anybody want to pay a buck to touch my cyst? A couple stoners GIGGLE and CLAP. Andy COUGHS, then frowns. ANDY (cont'd) I'm serious. A pause... then a few curious people walk up to the stage. The first taker is a GOOFY BLONDE WOMAN. She starts to reach for the cyst -- when Andy stops her. ANDY (cont'd) No, no, you gotta pay first. She nods, discomforted, and reaches for her purse...</context>
      <utterance>Actually, Budd, you're wrong. I found out today that Taxi's been canceled. The crowd AWWWWS sadly. Andy blinks. ANDY  Yeah, that's how I felt too... though I don't know why. 'Cause for years, all I wanted to do was get off that show.  But now that nobody will hire me, and nobody thinks I'm funny... I guess it was probably a pretty good job. One guy LAUGHS sharply.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Budd stares sadly.</context>
      <utterance>I made six bucks. That's good money.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy thinks. The wheels are spinning.</context>
      <utterance>This is a comedy club -- not a medical sideshow.  If you wanna perform here, take a shower, get some sleep, and pull yourself together. Come back and do the material that people love: Do the Mighty Mouse, the Foreign guy! Andy, you gotta snap out of this funk! If you can -- I'll give you the headline spot tomorrow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, what's going on here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inside, there's HUGE LAUGHTER. George's eyes widen. Piqued, he goes in...</context>
      <utterance>George, you won't believe it... I got Andy to do all the old material!  And he's killin' them!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>AS FOREIGN MAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... but one ting I do not like is too much traffic. Tonight I had to come on de freeway, and it was so much traffic...  It took me an hour and a half to get here! Foreign Man chuckles pathetically. The crowd HOWLS. Andy's rockin'. ANDY   But talking about the terrible things: My wife. Take my --</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERRUPTING JERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Take my wife, please take her."</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>AS FOREIGN MAN</mode>
      <context>A flustered pause. Andy glances down, then continues. ANDY (AS FOREIGN MAN) (cont'd) No really, I am only foolink. I love my wife very much. But she don't know how to cook --</context>
      <utterance>T-take my wife, please take her... The rhythm is thrown. A couple laughs.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERRUPTING JERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Her cooking is so bad, is terrible."</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>AS FOREIGN MAN</mode>
      <context>Uh, cooking is so bad, is terrible. The laughs are weaker. The act is getting wrecked. IN BACK - George grimaces. Who the hell's doing this?? Angry, George hurries down front, looking for the loud jerk. He scans the tables... and it's Zmuda. ANDY (AS FOREIGN MAN) (cont'd) But right now --</context>
      <utterance>H-her cooking...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode>AS JERK</mode>
      <context>A frazzled confusion, then Andy drops the accent. He glares at Zmuda.</context>
      <utterance>"But right now I would like to do for you some imitations. First, the Archie Bunker." Andy freezes up. The audience is embarrassed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, do you have a problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode>AS JERK</mode>
      <context>Andy winces.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, my problem is you're tired.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I, I was asked to do this material -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode>AS JERK</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, because your new stuff's a bunch of crap. Kaufman, people are sick of you. The wrestling... the hoaxes...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey -- that stuff gets written-up in the papers --</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode>AS JERK</mode>
      <context>GEORGE - is dumbfounded.</context>
      <utterance>Who gives a shit?! It's not funny!</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why...? Andy, why...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I used to think you were original.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was very original!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>"Andy Kaufman" has been destroyed.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, exactly -- "was"! But now, you're creatively bankrupt.  In fact, Ladies and Gentlemen, Kaufman's so desperate, he PAID me to do this tonight!! I'm a plant. It's just a fresh coat of paint on an old broken-down routine.  Isn't that true??? Andy shudders. The audience averts their eyes. A painful silence.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The world thinks Andy Kaufman sucks. So I was just giving 'em what they want...</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andy, they don't think you suck. They've just... lost a reason to love you. The guys stop walking. George gently speaks. GEORGE  You've gotta make the public embrace you again. You have to win back their sympathy...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll come up with something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at that Grand Slam! Two eggs, two bacon, two sausage, two pancakes -- $2.99! How do they do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They get you on the coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then -- Andy stiffly speaks.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me -- but could Andy tell us why we're here??? All heads turn. A long pause.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Zmuda nods.</context>
      <utterance>I have cancer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, that's good! We can make that play.  And we'll really drag it out. You get better, you get worse... you die...</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. Lynne is puzzled.</context>
      <utterance>FORGET IT. It's in terrible taste! I want nothing to do with this.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andy, are you serious?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy softly shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Serious like a heart attack! Hey, maybe I can push you around in some goofy wheelchair!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's true. I have lung cancer.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's ridiculous. You don't even smoke.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lynne's eyes tear up. She hugs onto Andy.</context>
      <utterance>I -- I got some freaky rare kind. It's called large-celled carcinoma.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Andy! Can they cure it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't know... they've gotta run more tests.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you told your family?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George and Zmuda glance skeptically at each other. Hmm... Confused, George leans in to Andy.</context>
      <utterance>No, NO! Not yet. I feel bad -- I've jerked 'em around so many times.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy gulps.</context>
      <utterance>Andy... you look me in the eye, and tell me this is true.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>George -- it's true.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I find out you're behind this, I'll kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are ya TALKIN' ABOUT?! I was the one saying I didn't believe it!</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly. That's the sort of thing you guys would work out to fuck me up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you be so casual??!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even if I'm dying -- I still need clean socks.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're NOT DYING!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He keeps working. Lynne loses it.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. You're probably right.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy finishes his socks. Satisfied... he turns on the TV. ON THE TV: It's "Lassie." Little TIMMY is laid-up in bed, with a broken leg. Suddenly LASSIE runs in, holding a book. Lassie places the book on his lap. The boy smiles gratefully.</context>
      <utterance>God, you're so detached!! Lynne storms out.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIMMY</speaker>
      <mode>ON TV</mode>
      <context>ANDY - is terribly touched. Tears start rolling down his face. Genuine sobbing. Terrible grief, until he wipes his cheeks. Andy collects himself, then reaches for a phone. He dials a long number.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, girl. You're my best friend. Timmy warmly embraces the dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The doctor leaves. A somber silence -- and then Janice bursts into tears. Stanley hugs her tightly. Carol watches the doctor with great hostility. His old tennis shoes are grabbing her attention. He leaves, and she frowns.</context>
      <utterance>The cancer started in Andy's left arm and spread to his lungs. We've initiated an aggressive radiation program... see if we can eradicate the affected cells.  Excuse me. I'll be right back.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a crock.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How dare you make light of this!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's not gettin' me again --</context>
      <utterance>Dad, I cried when he broke his neck.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A standoff moment. Carol loses it.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus! He's got lung cancer!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, that's exactly it! He picked lung cancer, because he doesn't smoke. That makes it weird! If he'd picked leukemia, it'd be totally believable, and we'd all be going, "Poor Andy, he's really sick." So he chose lung cancer, because he WANTS us to be scratching our heads, saying, "Is this real?"</utterance>
   <speaker>JANICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course it's real. We're in a hospital...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom, it's Cedars-Sinai! It's a showbiz hospital! Andy's studio friends probably run this place!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He plans these things out. He takes over, hires actors...  Personally, I didn't think that "doctor" was very convincing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you notice his costume had the wrong shoes?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We all know he's talked about faking his own death...</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure -- but what if he isn't?  My son could be dying... and we're actin' like we're on Candid Camera.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WILD-HAIRED MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to visualize. Visualize big, healthy white cells in your body. Now visualize little cancer cells. Now those big white cells are attacking the cancer cells...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the corner -- George stares. He's fighting his skepticism.</context>
      <utterance>I see them... I see the white cells...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was that all about?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Long beat.</context>
      <utterance>It's visualization therapy. He's helping me turn inward and fight the disease.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ah. Andy's eyes widen. His wheels are spinning fast.</context>
      <utterance>He's an actor. I remember him in "The In-Laws."</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>also ordained in holistic medicine. ON GEORGE - He glares, stewing. George is fed up. ON ANDY - An unspoken tension. Then suddenly, he breaks down. ANDY (cont'd) George, what am I supposed to do?! I'm sick, and I'm tryin' to get better... but everyone's lookin' at me funny! Even you come to my home and act like I'm puttin' on a skit!</context>
      <utterance>Uh, yes... that's true. But he's</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must take a little pleasure in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Of course!  But that doesn't mean I don't need everyone's support! I can't be surrounded by negative energy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andy, you're surrounded by what you create. You are the KING of negative energy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy struggles to remain composed. George sighs.</context>
      <utterance>Y-yeah? Well, then it has to stop! Because if these bad vibes get out... then everyone will be talkin' about how sick I am, and it becomes a self-fulfilling prophecy, and then -- I'm dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how can I help you...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanna go back to work and put on a happy show.  The best show anybody's ever seen!</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you wanna tour the clubs?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George gently smiles.</context>
      <utterance>No clubs. I wanna reach the TOP!  Carnegie Hall...!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>REPORTER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. The room GROANS.</context>
      <utterance>I'm working on a great cover story: I've got a guy in the lab at Cedars. He says Andy Kaufman is dying of lung cancer.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDITOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What bullshit! No. No more Kaufman stories! He's burned us too many times!</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Reporter frowns.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, he's definitely not dying. He's playing Carnegie Hall next month!</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus. Only Kaufman would use cancer as a publicity stunt.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is great. The crowd's gonna love this!  Hey... do you still think any of those cowgirls are still alive?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dunno. If they were, they'd be pushin' 80.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, call SAG. It'd be cool to get one on the show.  I want the evening to build and build. It's gonna have the most incredible ending: Singers, dancers, the "Hallelujah Chorus" -- then the sky opens, and Santa Claus comes flying down!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you say, "Santa, what am I gettin' for Christmas?" And he says, "Cancer!"</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! NO NO NO! None of that! I want this show to be positive!</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy smiles.</context>
      <utterance>That's great... but this show's gonna cost a fortune. Even if it sells out, you'll still lose eighty grand.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care about the money. I just want the show to deliver.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So who's gonna pay for it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tony Clifton.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know Tony doesn't have that kind of money.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. George considers this -- then slowly nods.</context>
      <utterance>Then he'll borrow it. I know Tony better than you do. Even if he has to work another ten years to pay it off, he'll do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Andy. Will do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crazed APPLAUSE. Frail ELEANOR GOULD, 75, comes onstage. ANDY (cont'd) It's such an honor to have you here.</context>
      <utterance>Ladies and Gentlemen! I'm pleased to announce that we have with us the one surviving cowgirl from that 1931 film, Eleanor "Cody" Gould!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEANOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andy... this is so overwhelming...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eleanor starts to protest -- but Andy hands her the HOBBY HORSE. She blushes. Andy turns away, goes to the band, and starts conducting. They begin to PLAY "JINGLE JANGLE JINGLE." Eleanor awkwardly starts dancing in circles. Andy gets excited and conducts FASTER. Eleanor is sweating. She dances faster. Andy impatiently SPEEDS UP the MUSIC MORE. Eleanor desperately skips in circles, trying to keep up... when suddenly she grabs her heart. Eleanor stops -- and collapses. She's down. A horrified GASP from the crowd. The band stops playing. CREW MEMBERS run on from backstage. One checks her heart. She's not moving. Zmuda runs out, horrified.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it's gettin' even better! 'Cause we found one of the original hobby horses! Do you -- do you think you could treat us to a few steps from "Jingle Jangle Jingle"?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd is stunned silent. Pause -- then one man stands. It's Michael. Straight-faced, he hurries out of his seat, sprints down the aisle, and goes on stage. Michael checks her pulse and loosens her blouse. He presses Eleanor's chest, trying to restart her heart. But then -- he shakes his head sadly. She's dead. The crowd MOANS sadly. Michael covers Eleanor with a jacket.</context>
      <utterance>Is there a doctor in the house??!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now we'll place a blue crystal. Very high vibrations. It's wonderful for it's healing powers.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Let's try two of those... and one of the pink ones.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADMINISTRATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your friend is doing four crystal sessions a day, but it's just not helping.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know...  The cancer's terminal.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADMINISTRATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. That wasn't made particularly clear to us when he checked in...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man purses his lips.</context>
      <utterance>Look, personally, I think rubbing rocks on people is a load of horseshit. But if it makes Andy happy, that's all that matters.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADMINISTRATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zmuda is speechless.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry to sound crass -- but we don't want to be "that health resort in New Mexico where Andy Kaufman died."  I'm going to have to ask you to leave.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LITTLE WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this stuff?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly -- a SHARP VOICE.</context>
      <utterance>It's all macrobiotic. Millet, burdock root, kelp... Andy says it'll purify him.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY CLIFTON</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The women turn. It's Andy -- dressed as Tony Clifton. A spooked moment. Tony's wig, peach tux, and sunglasses are there... but Andy is barely strong enough to bark out the attitude.</context>
      <utterance>What is that crap? Looks like somethin' my dog would puke up!!</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY CLIFTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How 'bout me and you dolls go get some REAL food: French fries and a Porterhouse steak!</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Little Wendy's eyes pop: Oh no she broke the rule! Tony gets very indignant.</context>
      <utterance>...Andy...?</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY CLIFTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tony picks up a CHAIR and starts lifting it: Up, down, up, down. Worried, the women rush to stop him. They take the chair.</context>
      <utterance>I ain't Andy! I'm Tony! Andy's sick -- pick, chick, kick, lick! The doctor says he's a goner.  But Tony's built like a mule! Andy asked me to be his pallbearer! I'll do it for him! I'm getting stronger and stronger! Here, watch this!</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop it! C'mon, put that down.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY CLIFTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tony jauntily turns to exit. He gestures to the ladies. TONY CLIFTON (cont'd) Let's go! (he starts SINGING "New York, New York") "These vagabond blues, Are washin' away. I'll make a brand new start of it..." Tony reaches the doorway -- and collapses. He clutches himself in pain.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you're right. We better get movin'. We don't wanna miss Happy Hour at Kelbos -- all the Mai Tai's you can drink for $4.99.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNNE AND LITTLE WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tony lies huddled on the ground. He mutters sadly, defeatedly.</context>
      <utterance>Andy!! Shocked, they run over.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY CLIFTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dammit...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't move my arm.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy softly sighs.</context>
      <utterance>You've got good days and bad days.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My hair is coming out.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George silently pats Andy. Andy's energy is sapped, but he forces himself to be upbeat.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George is choked up. He goes along with it.</context>
      <utterance>I've got an idea for a new TV show for me to star in. It's called "Uncle Andy's Fun House" -- it'll be a Saturday morning thing where I can goof off with the kids. You know, puppets, magic tricks...</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George struggles not to shatter Andy's enthusiasm. Andy smiles gratefully.</context>
      <utterance>I think we can sell that. Silence.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George clenches Andy's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Hey... thanks for always backin' me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did your -- doctor say it's okay for you to go back to work?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ehhh, you know those guys. If he had his way, I'd be stuck in the hospital, running tests all day.  And anyway, I've found a new guy who's gonna be able to instantly remove the cancer.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy beams. George stares sadly.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah! He's a psychic surgeon in the Philippines, and he's amazing! He rubs you and sucks the disease right out!</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Philippines? I dunno... Andy... he sounds like one of your characters.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIGHT - ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His voice gets hushed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... this guy's special.  He performs miracles. George doesn't know how to respond. Andy looks up pleadingly. ANDY  He's my last chance.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GUTS.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jun turns to wash his hands. An attendant gives him a towel to dry with. Then a SICKLY MAN crawls up... Andy rolls closer. He stares at all this with fear. Nervousness. Hope. Jun impassively presses his hand against the man's head. He concentrates, searching... then pulls out some BLOODY GUTS. He flings them into a bucket. The man shakes. He is helped away. Andy is wide-eyed. He gets closer... closer... More patients. More bloody guts. More sobbing. Andy's excitement builds. Then -- he reaches the front. A moment. Lynne and Zmuda stare into Andy's eyes, drawn in by his total belief. They are overcome. It feels like they're saying goodbye. Lynne gives Andy a tender kiss. Zmuda starts to shake his hand -- and instead hugs him tightly. Andy smiles, then the attendants lift him from the wheelchair. They help him up to the bench. Andy lies down. Fluorescent lights buzz overhead. He looks over, and Jun Roxas is washing his hands from the previous patient. Andy shivers, anticipating the miracle. Jun turns. An attendant gives him a towel to dry off. Andy relaxes, readying for it all... He glances at Jun's hands. Jun hands back the towel -- and under it the attendant quickly slips Jun a sack of animal intestines. Jun discreetly palms it. He's a fake.</context>
      <utterance>He flings them into a bucket. The woman cries out. Andy gasps. The woman is helped away.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSEUP - ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is shocked. Outraged. Disappointed. Flabbergasted. The faith is meaningless. The joke is cosmic. The con man has been conned. Andy's overpowering emotions coalesce... and he starts to</context>
      <utterance>A moment of stunned disbelief.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>ON FILM</mode>
      <context>Some gathered people tentatively join in the SINGING. ANDY (ON FILM) (cont'd) So everybody! Put your arm around the person next to you, even if you don't like that person. Come on! (he resumes SINGING) "The world is such a wonderful place, To wander through, When you've got someone to love, To wander along with you. With the sky so full of stars, And the river so full of songs, Every heart should be so thankful, Thankful for this friendly, friendly world..." The curtain behind the coffin OPENS and the casket with Andy's body slowly slides into the DARKNESS. The curtain closes. The FILM ENDS. And all goes silent. Some people cry. Some begin to leave. Most of them are just staying, numbed. George and Zmuda whisper.</context>
      <utterance>Well... My show is over. I did my best, and I just want to say, until we meet again... please remember:  "In this friendly, friendly world... With each day so full of joy. Why should any heart be lonely."</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a perfect Kaufman audience.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZMUDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Taxi cast are flustered.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. They don't know whether to be sad, or angry.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROL KANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are people leaving? The curtain's gonna open. Andy's gonna come out... I know it!</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY DANZA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The closed curtain wafts... then settles motionless.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, the body was just made of wax...!  Wasn't it......? Silence. They look to the front.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DUDE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AT THE COMEDY STORE - The marquee says "TONY CLIFTON: LIVE!"</context>
      <utterance>Oh my GOD.  That's the freakiest thing I've ever seen!! Look! He points. His friend turns -- and gasps.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUDE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, we were right! He's not dead!</utterance>
   <speaker>DUDE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's just been lyin' low for a year!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TONY CLIFTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tony struts downstage. He waves to the crowd. TONY CLIFTON (cont'd) How you doin' back there?! (to the front rows) How you doin' up here?! Still no response. Until -- a lone reckless VOICE.</context>
      <utterance>How ya doin'? Dead silence.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tony grimaces.</context>
      <utterance>Andy! Whoa. The crowd rustles nervously.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY CLIFTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The BAND kicks in with disco anthem "I WILL SURVIVE." Tony starts SINGING the schmaltzy opening: TONY CLIFTON (cont'd) "First I was afraid I was petrified. Kept thinkin' I could never live Without you at my side." (he wipes away a pretend tear) "Were you the one that tried to Hurt me with goodbye? Did you think I'd crumble? Did you think I'd lay down and Die...?" We PAN the room full of enthralled spectators. At a front table are George and Lynne. Tony attacks the chorus. TONY CLIFTON (cont'd) "Oh no not I!</context>
      <utterance>Don't know nothin' about no Andy. Just some dead guy tryin' to ride my coattails.  Let's HIT IT, boys! One, two, anda one two three four!</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
