<movie id="373" title="Man in the Iron Mask">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The advisors, disregarding the Queen's privacy, scurry around the screen to see the doctor lift the beautiful baby, wet with birth. The mother -- the Queen -- is still in agony, yet she struggles to lift her head.</context>
      <utterance>The head is born! One arm... the other arm... it is a boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>ADVISOR 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I shall tell the king!</utterance>
   <speaker>ADVISOR 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hurry for the door. But their race to be first to bring this great news to the King is interrupted as the Queen emits another cry; it surprises the doctor.</context>
      <utterance>I shall tell him!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kneels again to examine the Queen.</context>
      <utterance>M'lady...?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The joy vanishes from the faces of the advisors. They look gravely at each other, as they hear a second BABY'S CRY.</context>
      <utterance>Another...? It is another!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You dead yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN THE IRON MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Keeper.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops dead in his tracks. From the POV OF PORTHOS AND THE WOMEN, we see ARAMIS. Always the most theological of the Musketeers, and ruthlessly brilliant, he is still lean and powerful. And still handsome, or at least he would be; but now he kneels before a single candle at a private altar, wearing sackcloth and ashes in penitent prayer.</context>
      <utterance>Aaaaaaaramis!! Porthos is --</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, my dears. You would have enjoyed it too. He's hung like a donkey.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENCH 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So are you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He whacks their bottoms, herding them out, then swaggers to Aramis, heaving himself to a seat beside his praying friend.</context>
      <utterance>Really? I haven't been able to see it for fifteen years. Go on now, leave His Holiness alone. I'll bring you back tomorrow when he's in a better mood.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please revel with me, Aramis, I need my spirits lifted. I'm old, I'm weak, my strength is gone --</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be quiet, you fat fool. Can't you see I'm praying?</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just said you're praying! Are you deaf too? I know you're blind, because if you had seen the tits that just walked out of here, you'd have tears in your eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are more important things than tits.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis is still trying to pray, but rises to the bait.</context>
      <utterance>Really? If you can name me one thing, one single thing, that is more sublime than the feel of a plump pink nipple between my lips, I will buy you a new cathedral.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forgiveness.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As if in reply, Porthos lets rip an enormous rolling fart.</context>
      <utterance>Forgiveness?</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis' fingers clamp down on the rosary beads, as he tries to keep praying.</context>
      <utterance>Forgive me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis abruptly backhands his huge friend. Porthos reels backwards, landing in a chair.</context>
      <utterance>Am I forgiven?</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I observe your forgiveness isn't sweeter than a plump nipple.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Porthos raises a foot and kicks the bishop in the balls. Aramis staggers back and grabs a chair to throw it; Porthos picks up the whole table -- just as d'Artagnan enters.</context>
      <utterance>Can't you see I'm praying, goddammit?!</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS AND ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Porthos tosses the table aside and bear hugs d'Artagnan.</context>
      <utterance>D'Artagnan.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis sets the chair down in embarrassment.</context>
      <utterance>How are you, you skinny little pup!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A simple theological discussion.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aramis -- the King wishes to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis lifts d'Artagnan's cloak as evidence: near its hem, sure enough, is the remnant of a broken egg.</context>
      <utterance>Still you serve him loyally -- though people hurl rotten eggs at his royal emblem.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see your mind is sharp as ever. The King said, "Right away." Cut deep and hard, my friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Artagnan clasps Porthos' hand, then that of Aramis, and leaves, as Porthos shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Deep and hard, D'Artagnan.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands a purse to Aramis. Surprised, even touched, Aramis reaches for it. Just as he takes the money, Porthos throws a haymaker; but Aramis sees the sucker punch coming and ducks. Suddenly the two old warriors are circling again.</context>
      <utterance>We were all Musketeers once, eh? Oh, I forgot. For the poor, the ones you were praying for.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wonder how Athos is doing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>RAOUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I look all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>None of the ladies will be able to take their eyes off you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAOUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I get so confused...</context>
      <utterance>I care only about Michelle. Should I ask her when we first arrive? Or... or when we're leaving? I could ask her in the carriage -- but it is more romantic at the palace.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands Raoul the simple gold ring he took from the box.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps this will help.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAOUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mother's ring. I can't take this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They embrace. Athos' eyes mist, but he smiles.</context>
      <utterance>She died giving you to me. And I want to die knowing it is one the finger of the women my son loves.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now go, and bring back your fiance.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>PIERRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your Majesty, I know it is a... a festive time, but before --</utterance>
   <speaker>KING LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The blue sash. No, the burgundy!</utterance>
   <speaker>PIERRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... before the party begins --</utterance>
   <speaker>KING LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The party has already begun -- so why are you delaying me?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIERRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We do not wish to delay you, Majesty, but... as your advisors, we feel it is our -- our --</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... our duty.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIERRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes! It is our duty to let you know... there are riots in Paris.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Riots? My people live in the world's most beautiful city, their king has the grandest palaces on earth. Why should they feel anything but pride and contentment?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIERRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well yes, of course, Majesty, and I'm sure they are content... except that... well, they are starving.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he says this, a replica of the Matterhorn made of fruits and meringues is carried past the window by a team of chefs.</context>
      <utterance>Sometimes the poor do grow hungry. But why would they riot about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIERRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Majesty... We have more than enough food set aside for your birthday celebration next week. If we distributed some of that, we would have time to gather more before --</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The tailors and advisors withdraw as Aramis -- still in his simple priest's robe -- strides forward and bows to the kind.</context>
      <utterance>Aramis! I have been expecting you!  We are satisfied, that will do.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your birthday celebration, your Majesty?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Next week. This is a mere garden party -- and I wish to join it, so I will be brief. I am experiencing resistance from the Jesuits.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... perhaps you should speak with them, your Majesty.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have demanded it -- and common priests present themselves! Can you imagine the arrogance? Common Jesuit priests try to act as my equals, and they refuse to reveal the names of anyone else in their order! No one can keep secrets like the Jesuits can, and the identity of their leader is the darkest secret they hold. Even the Pope himself does not know who leads the Jesuit Order in France! He suspects the Governor General of Jesuits, whoever he is, is angling to become Pope himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can I serve you in this?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps you can find out who this secret leader of the Jesuits is. You are now a priest, but you were once a Musketeer, serving the throne of France, a throne ordained of God. Can you accept this mission, and keep it private?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I find out the identity of this Jesuit rebel. I will kill both him and the man who told me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis bows and Louis turns back to his mirror. There are mirrors everywhere in his palace, and he loves his reflection, adorned as he is all in golden cloth, like fabric from the sun. Aramis leaves and the advisors return.</context>
      <utterance>Once a Musketeer, always a Musketeer, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah yes, the riots. We have food stocks on the wharves right now, no?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIERRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That food has spoiled. That is why it was not shipped to the army.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly why it should be given away.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIERRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What... an excellent idea, your Majesty!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't it glorious!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAOUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But just as he starts to speak, trumpets blast and the King steps through the doors and out into the lavish gardens; the party goers give him a rousing ovation. Raoul returns the ring to his jacket, to wait for another moment. Everyone watches the King, who begins guzzling wine and telling jokes to his sycophants, who howl at the King's witticisms. Then Louis catches sight of Raoul and Michelle, and lowers his voice, to his FRIENDS...</context>
      <utterance>Michelle...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIEND 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Raoul, son of Athos.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not the soldier, you idiot!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIEND 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The king is transfixed.</context>
      <utterance>Her name is Michelle.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your Majesty...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sycophants laugh loudly.</context>
      <utterance>What is it, d'Artagnan? Assassins falling from the sky now?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The plans for use of the maze were not disclosed to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I decided it this morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you must allow me to stay close to you so that --</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am King, d'Artagnan. I will change my mind as I wish, and I will enjoy my banquet as I wish!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I deployed the Royal Guards according to your previous --</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Artagnan bows sharply as the young sycophants chuckle. D'Artagnan retreats, then looks back to Louis and follows his gaze to the tender young beauty who caught his eye. D'Artagnan recognizes Raoul, son of his friend Athos.</context>
      <utterance>Let us play a game, d'Artagnan, let us pretend I am King and you are Captain of my Musketeers. Let us behave as if my wish is law. And my wish is to enjoy this party!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAOUL AND MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As the guests mix and mingle, Raoul tries again.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAOUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A gaunt SERVANT interrupts, presenting a tray of delicacies.</context>
      <utterance>Michelle, I... Ever since I returned I've been wanting to speak with you about... about --</utterance>
   <speaker>SERVANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monsieur, Mademoiselle...?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAOUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are interrupted by the SQUEAL of a piglet, squirming in the hands of the king's dwarf, who holds the fat little animal above his head and runs among the startled guests.</context>
      <utterance>No! Thank you -- Michelle, I --</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes the pig from his dwarf; the pig is clean and perfumed, a colorful fake horn tied onto its head.</context>
      <utterance>It pleases us to announce an entertainment for our guests! A contest of agility and cunning!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With this announcement the King produces a diamond the size of a pecan, suspended from a ribbon; the guests gasp at its richness. The King ties the diamond around the pig's neck.</context>
      <utterance>Behold our unicorn! Whichever of our guests captures the unicorn shall win its treasure!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAOUL AND MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Michelle is amazed at this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It almost makes Raoul ashamed of the modest ring hidden in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>I have never seen a diamond so large!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dwarf releases the pig, poking him through a tiny break in the hedge; the critter skitters as only a pig can, eluding the first laughing lunges of the guests. THE PIG CHASE is a merry melee, as the maze becomes a tangle of confusion. LOUIS climbs to a platform above the top of the ten foot hedge that forms the maze. From his perch he looks down on all the action, and calls encouragement.</context>
      <utterance>Into the maze! All of you! Disperse, I command you!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MICHELLE squeals as the pig scurries by and Raoul dives for it. He almost has the pig... then it kicks free.</context>
      <utterance>Are you men or mice?!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAOUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MICHELLE tries to follow, this way, that way, through the maze. Then she stops, face to face with the King, entering through a gate hidden in one of the maze's dead corners.</context>
      <utterance>The pendant will be yours! With that he races after the pig.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Speechless, she nods.</context>
      <utterance>Michelle, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would have said it was impossible, but I believe the excitement of the chase has made you even more beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sire, I --</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes go still; she understands what is happening. FROM BEHIND THE GATE, we see d'Artagnan, watching as Louis tries to seduce the young woman. Even as d'Artagnan watches, the pig comes rooting through the hedge; with a deft movement d'Artagnan catches the animal's leg and lifts it with the sureness of the farm boy he once was. The pig is quiet and comfortable in d'Artagnan's hands. D'Artagnan watches as the King approaches Michelle, and she allows him to touch her cheek. The king leans to kiss her... Michelle does not move... WHHEEEKKKK! The pig sails over the gate and hits the ground running, right at Louis' feet; it sets him dancing. The spell of the king's royal attention is shattered; as the pig scrambles away, Michelle backs away.</context>
      <utterance>You blush! You do not wish to be beautiful to your King?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Too late, he sees the shadow of the man looming above him, leaping down onto him from the observation platform. It is the servant who offered the tray to Raoul and Michelle; he has armed himself with a knife from the carving table, and is diving now to plunge the blade into the king's throat. The king is helpless, frozen. The assassin leaps, falling toward the king... and is impaled on the sword of d'Artagnan, springing through the gate to save his king. Michelle screams, the king gasps, and the assassin drops, mortally wounded. They stare down at him now; the would-be assassin gurgles words through his agony...</context>
      <utterance>Wait! Michelle, I --</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSASSIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Party guests, having heard Michelle scream, are running in to find them. Michelle rushes off, to find Raoul; several people are coming up.</context>
      <utterance>Feed... your... people.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSASSIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The king snatches out his own dagger and imperiously cuts the throat of the dying man, to stop these offensive words. The king looks at his stunned subjects.</context>
      <utterance>Your people starve...! Feed --</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The King prances away. It takes the guests a moment, but they know that only gaiety will please their King, and off they go again, laughing as if nothing happened. D'Artagnan stands still as the young Musketeers under his command come rushing up with swords drawn.</context>
      <utterance>A pitiful madman, nothing more. Come, let us continue our chase! Where is our unicorn?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MUSKETEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seeing the dead assassin, their eyes fill with admiration.</context>
      <utterance>Captain!</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MUSKETEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Artagnan can't even listen; with a last glance at the King he turns quickly and walks away.</context>
      <utterance>You are the best --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>KEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Food, moron.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN THE IRON MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not watching what he's doing, the bulbous keeper trips on something and stumbles, dropping the food. The prisoner jumps to his feet, concerned.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Keeper.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up the tray and slings it at the prisoner.</context>
      <utterance>Look what you've done!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN THE IRON MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The keeper looks for what he tripped on -- a worn Bible. He snatches it up and grabs a hunk of pages from its middle.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Keeper...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN THE IRON MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hearing the pleading in the prisoner's voice, the keeper looks squarely at him -- and rips out the pages.</context>
      <utterance>No, Keeper, it's my only book!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN THE IRON MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What number did you tear out?</utterance>
   <speaker>KEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN THE IRON MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What number, on the first page?</utterance>
   <speaker>KEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Two-thirty-seven.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN THE IRON MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the prisoner rattles off the names of Biblical genealogy, the jailer gawks at the pages in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Two-thirty-seven: "... And the descendants of Japeth are these: Obediah, Zebulon, Hezekiah..."</utterance>
   <speaker>KEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've... memorized...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN THE IRON MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the keeper is speechless, the prisoner looks for himself.</context>
      <utterance>What was the end page?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN THE IRON MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Keeper staggers in shock; the prisoner bubbles with joy.</context>
      <utterance>Six-two-one: "... Though I speak with the tongues of men and angels, and have not love, I am but a clanging cymbal or --"</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN THE IRON MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the prisoner takes the keeper's fat hands in his own and begins to dance and sing.</context>
      <utterance>We're playing, Keeper! A game! Take another page, any page! Keeper and I are playing a game!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN THE IRON MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The keeper's left arm goes rigid, and he clutches his chest with his right hand; he drops upon the stone floor.</context>
      <utterance>A game, a game, we're playing a --</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN THE IRON MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The prisoner approaches the jailer; the man is stoned dead.</context>
      <utterance>Keeper...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN THE IRON MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The prisoner tries to wipe his eyes, but he can't get at them, inside the mask. He edges to the open door.</context>
      <utterance>No... No! Keeper, please, you cannot die! You're my only friend!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN THE IRON MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slumps down beside the open door, and weeps.</context>
      <utterance>Help! Someone! Keeper is dead!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She wishes a word with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>M'lady...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand you saved my son's life today.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God smiled upon us.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you were not hurt?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, M'lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without a change of expression on her still beautiful but sad face, she enters her room.</context>
      <utterance>That is good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Duty lists of the day, Captain!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hand him the list and salute again, to leave.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Andre.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The young Musketeers try not to smirk.</context>
      <utterance>Wait. There is an entry here -- "Messenger sent by King to residence of Mademoiselle Michelle Beaufort." Why was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Captain...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="42">
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>D'Artagnan!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They embrace with deep affection -- friends who have shared each other's darkest times.</context>
      <utterance>Athos, my friend!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's been too long.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Artagnan takes one of the wooden chairs, by the meager fire. The whole place is modest at best.</context>
      <utterance>Life is too long. Except when we have our friends. Look at you! You're still a boy! Sit, sit! I'll open a bottle of wine.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, but not for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't drink with a friend you haven't seen in months?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have ordered a drill of the Royal Guard for midnight, and must be clear-headed for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Midnight! Mon dieu! Driving the youngsters hard, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They must stay sharp. There was an attempt on the King's life today.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Three? Four?</context>
      <utterance>Another? How many times have you saved his life in this year alone?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard your playing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A cloud passes d'Artagnan's face; he has something to tell Athos.</context>
      <utterance>I was feeling sorry for myself. Raoul is getting married, he proposed today! I love that boy beyond all measure, I've spent everything I own to give him education and opportunity. Now he has complete happiness, and I mope.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But whatever it is that d'Artagnan wants to say is interrupted by the sound of someone climbing the stairs. As Athos' face brightened with the arrival of d'Artagnan, now it glows as he jumps up to welcome his son.</context>
      <utterance>Athos...</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What's wrong? You look awful!</context>
      <utterance>That must be Raoul! Raoul! Look, d'Artagnan's come to visit...!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAOUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Athos is stunned; d'Artagnan witnesses this with agony.</context>
      <utterance>Michelle, she -- The king has invited her to come live in the palace.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But -- are you sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAOUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were at her door. I was just taking the ring from my pocket, for the third time today, when a young Musketeer brought the invitation for her to become a lady-in-waiting for the Queen Mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Michelle cannot possibly accept!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAOUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She cannot possibly refuse. Her family is poor, they have even less money than we do. And along with the invitation, the King sent the diamond pendant, from the piglet.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Piglet -- ? What are you -- ?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAOUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never mind, Papa, it doesn't matter now. She loved me once. I want to die remembering that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Die? What...?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAOUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have rejoined the army, and asked to resume my commission at the head of the troops of General Fromberge.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fromberge...?! At the front?! No.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAOUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is already done. I have just stopped at Mother's grave, to say goodbye, before coming to tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Raoul, no... You cannot do this. No matter how your heart is broken -- But Raoul stops him, with an embrace.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAOUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, father. I am sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raoul breaks away, and runs from the room. Athos, so joyful moments before, holds his head as if his brain might erupt.</context>
      <utterance>Raoul --</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This cannot be. Everyone knows the Queen Mother is a recluse, and the ladies-in-waiting are but mistresses for the king!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If the young woman truly loves Raoul --</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Artagnan is silent, and even ashamed. Athos realizes --</context>
      <utterance>She's a woman, d'Artagnan! From a poor family. You may still be young enough to believe love conquers everything, but I am old and hard and I've seen too much. Even when kings are hunchbacks they have any woman they desire, because power seduces even more than love!</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You knew this was happening. You knew and that's why you came.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I fear I know our King. I came to try to bring you hope.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What hope is there? A wartime commission cannot be vacated except by the king, and what chance is there of that? Fromberge is on the battle line, and Raoul --</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have dispatches a message to Fromberge requesting that Raoul be kept far from the fighting.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Raoul is everything to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Athos grips d'Artagnan in gratitude and desperate hope.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will also speak with the King, for he is surely unaware of the problems his invitation to Mademoiselle Beaufort has caused.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You trust his character more than anyone else does.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Raoul is hurrying to the front, so I must hurry too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They embrace once more, and d'Artagnan leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Save my son, d'Artagnan.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slowly at first the paupers stand and shuffle forward. As the soldiers begin handing out foodstuffs -- bread, cabbages, tomatoes, eggs -- those nearest the wagon begin to jostle each other, and a large crowd gathers quickly.</context>
      <utterance>Here is food, the gift of your loving King, on his birthday! He gives to himself by giving to you, in that he loves you so much!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's looking like a holiday celebration... until a RUFFIAN breaks open a loaf of bread, and wrinkles his nose.</context>
      <utterance>No need to fight, there is plenty for all!</utterance>
   <speaker>RUFFIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hurls the moldy bread back at the soldiers. Other paupers sniff the food, and its stink set off an explosion of anger: they throw food at the soldiers... Then a paving stone crashes through a shop window, and suddenly it's a riot, with the mob overwhelming the soldiers and dragging them down the streets in the direction of the palace. D'ARTAGNAN, riding toward the palace himself, turns a corner and sees the mob coming. And they see him: the elegant, dashing Musketeer on the prancing stallion. And at that moment, two more soldiers race out of a side street, fleeing a similar mob, coming from another direction. D'Artagnan understands everything at a glance; the second pair of fleeing soldiers reach him in panic.</context>
      <utterance>This stuff stinks. It is rotting! The King gives us rotten food!</utterance>
   <speaker>PANICKED SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Back, toward the palace! We cannot hold them off! We will fire a volley into them!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two new soldiers race away; d'Artagnan waits calmly on his horse, as the mobs from both directions converge on him. THE MOB, seeing the dashing Musketeer wait so confidently for them, slow up; but the ruffian urges them on.</context>
      <utterance>No! Run to the palace and close the gates. But do not fire!</utterance>
   <speaker>RUFFIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Artagnan sits calmly in their way. He doesn't even draw his sword, though members of the mob grab the reins of his horse. Some of the mob recognize him, and murmur...</context>
      <utterance>Come on! To the palace!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The mob hesitates -- for the name d'Artagnan means heroism and patriotism to all of them.</context>
      <utterance>It's d'Artagnan! Le Generale de Musketeers!</utterance>
   <speaker>RUFFIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One Musketeer can't stop us!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop you? You are Frenchmen, are you not? I am one of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUFFIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The King is a Frenchman, but he is not one of us!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Citizens of Paris! Give ear to me!</utterance>
   <speaker>RUFFIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that he draws a dagger from his filthy shirt and puts it to the ear of the young Lieutenant who is already bloody from being dragged through the street.</context>
      <utterance>We'll give you their ears!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait -- and listen! I beg you!</utterance>
   <speaker>RIOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that one of the rioters hurls a moldy beet at d'Artagnan, who draws his sword in a slick liquid movement, he cuts the vegetable from the air. The display of expertise is startling. Someone else throws a head of lettuce; d'Artagnan slices it in half, and as the pieces fly he skewers one with the point of his sword.</context>
      <utterance>They give us garbage, not fit for rats! They think we are garbage!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The mob laughs at this panache, and the amazing display of swordsmanship that lies behind it. Someone tosses more lettuce, and d'Artagnan divides and skewers this one as well. This time the crowd applauds.</context>
      <utterance>I'm on my way to a salad! Doesn't anybody have any endive?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Can he do it? Someone fires a tomato right at his head, and sure enough d'Artagnan spears it. Then, with a victorious flourish, he takes a bite of it. His face contorts with the taste, and he spits the pieces out; the crowd is hushed.</context>
      <utterance>A tomato?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The mob is completely won over by d'Artagnan; the ruffian, angry that his riot is fizzling, raises his knife again over the soldiers, but now the point of d'Artagnan's sword flicks to the ruffian's neck.</context>
      <utterance>You are right. It is rotten. I will speak to the King myself. You have my word.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you will release those men -- for they serve France... and you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIOTERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The soldiers who moments before were about to be ripped apart now stand and look at d'Artagnan in gratitude and awe. The mob has forgotten them; they see only d'Artagnan as he rakes his blade clean, returns it to its scabbard, reins his horse around, and slowly rides away, escorting the soldiers back toward the palace.</context>
      <utterance>Three cheers for d'Artagnan! Hurrah...!! Hurrah...!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We already know about the riots!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does he know?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIERRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We will tell him, when it is...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blocked by the advisors, d'Artagnan leaves them, turning down one hallway, and then another; he reaches the Hall of Mirrors and touches the golden frame of one mirror at its corner; the mirror becomes a door, revealing a secret passage within the walls. D'Artagnan steps through and the portal closes again, leaving no trace of its existence.</context>
      <utterance>Convenient.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis climaxes with a grunt. She tries to sound pleased.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yes! So good! Ooo, wonderful, Marvelous! Fan-tas --</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Louis, that was incredible. It was better than ever before. It --</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hops up, throwing on a silk robe embroidered in gold.</context>
      <utterance>I'm hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will have food brought.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves to what appears to be a wardrobe, standing against the far wall, and opens its door, revealing a secret staircase hidden within the thick walls of the palace.</context>
      <utterance>I like to eat alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leaving the girl without another word, he moves down the concealed stairs.</context>
      <utterance>By the way, you'll be moving tomorrow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aaa! D'Artagnan! These passages were constructed for the King's security, not so you could step from my father's portrait and startle me to death!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is for your security that I have come, your Majesty -- for the security of your honor.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I already know about the riots, d'Artagnan, I heard them out there whispering. Some fool gave the order to distribute rotten food. I will deal with it tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then there is one more thing, of an even more personal nature.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A personal nature?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The King begins to eat from the food laid out on the table.</context>
      <utterance>Mademoiselle Michelle Beaufort. She is betrothed to Raoul, the son of Athos the Musketeer, who has served France through many tribulations.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Betrothed? I think not.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The King pokes at his food.</context>
      <utterance>In his mind, anyway, and soon enough in hers. She had written him many letters of love.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miss Beaufort has accepted our invitation. By this we can only suppose that she wishes to come -- as we wish her to be here.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your Majesty has had many women --</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is my desire, and my desire is what should concern you, not the sentiments of some commoner!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is not Raoul's heart alone that concerns me. It is yours. I know you find women compliant -- especially the poorer ones like Michelle. But do they love you? Do you love them? What about a queen to love? A son of your own?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What quaint notions, d'Artagnan! But they contradict my father, who picked his queen when he was old, and only then to bear me.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is more to love than he knew, or that you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You dare criticize my father?! Or lecture me?!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not criticize -- plead. Love. Love your people, and you will not bear to see them hungry. Love women, and they will love you. Love yourself, and --</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is enough! You are a good servant, d'Artagnan, but you forget your place!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least help Raoul.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Silence! I order you!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Order Fromberge to keep him in safety! It is the least you can do, to protect your own honor!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will consider it. Now leave me.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Artagnan bows, steps to the lifesize portrait of Louis XIII, touches a hidden button on its frame and moves into the secret passage the painting reveals as it swings open.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, your Majesty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shoots a glance at his advisors, and they are pale from the display they've just witnessed.</context>
      <utterance>Do not rejoice -- but know that your King does not tolerate blunders that hurt his beloved people. More food is on its way, and my advisors tell me the new harvests are sure to be bountiful!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The advisors all applaud furiously, but from the crowd there is almost no reaction at all; the triple ranks of soldiers surrounding the square discourage any protest, and as the King leaves the platform the crowd begins to melt away.</context>
      <utterance>And I have new joys to announce to you! Today we decree a fresh glory for Paris, and for all of France! The laying of the foundations to expand Versailles, and make it truly a palace of the sun!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis turns to see the King, who moves up alone.</context>
      <utterance>Aramis.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your Majesty...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How goes that favor I asked of you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I grow closer to my target, your Majesty.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The King moves away, followed by his fawning advisors.</context>
      <utterance>You bring me the heart of the Jesuit General, and you will have a palace of your own.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HANDMAIDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tosses the dress onto the bed and is gone. Left alone, Michelle lifts the letter, and recognizes the writing.</context>
      <utterance>After your bath put on this, it is the King's favorite color. That letter on the desk came here for you this morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens the letter and reads quickly.</context>
      <utterance>Raoul!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She interrupts herself as her eyes fall on the gorgeous dress. She looks around at the sumptuous palace apartment, and gazes again at the murals painted above the bed. They depict naked gods and goddesses, in Olympian orgies.</context>
      <utterance>The army! Oh Raoul, don't despair! I will always be faithful...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HANDMAIDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the handmaiden leaves, exiting frame, we PUSH IN on one of the murals on the wall. The eye of one of the figures there is no longer the painted eye it was before, but is a real human eye, disguised by the mural...</context>
      <utterance>If you need me further, just ring.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KING, IN THE SECRET PASSAGEWAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>is spying on Michelle.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sire! I -- How did you --</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What is that?</context>
      <utterance>How did I get in? You're new here, and will soon learn many secrets.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes the letter; she has no resistance against him. The King reads, his eyes hardening suddenly; but then he smiles.</context>
      <utterance>A letter. May I see?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From Raoul. He urges you to guard your honor -- as if it could be in any danger... from your king.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Raoul... is in love...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tossing the letter aside, he offers her his arm. She takes it and allows him to escort her from the room.</context>
      <utterance>Enough of this, our dinner waits.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The food doesn't please you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's lovely. It's just...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is more than you are used to. Your mother is a seamstress, your father is dead. You have three younger sisters, two of whom suffer from consumption. Don't look so surprised, Kings know such things.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... we are humble people...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, no! Do not be ashamed. The straits of your family need not be permanent. It is a simple matter to have them brought to one of my country estates, where they may have fine meals, and physicians to look after them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You would do that, your Majesty?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rushes to him and throws herself at his knees, weeping in gratitude. Louis smiles, as if embarrassed.</context>
      <utterance>My dear, I've already done it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A servant quickly approaches with wine; the goblet at Michelle's place is quite large, and he pours it full.</context>
      <utterance>Please, darling, that isn't necessary. We are friends now. Mademoiselle needs wine!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are beautiful. You know you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sire, I --</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He touches his lips to her throat. She gasps, but then pulls away. She glances at the letter on the writing table.</context>
      <utterance>If you don't want to be so appealing, why did you touch the rose to your skin? Where was it? Here?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sees her hesitation and uncertainty. He's smooth, gentle.</context>
      <utterance>What is it? Raoul? If he really loved you, he would have proposed marriage. He didn't, did he?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her; for a moment she seems frozen... and then she yields. Never having doubted that she would. Louis pulls the gown from her shoulders. She doesn't resist.</context>
      <utterance>You have never known love until you have known the love of a king.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NEW KEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Man in the Iron Mask rises and takes a step forward; the new keeper recoils and raises his club threateningly.</context>
      <utterance>Ugh! He looks 'orrible.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEW KEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay back!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN THE IRON MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I frighten you. It's okay. Keeper was scared of me too, at first.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEW KEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The New Keeper steps forward and clubs the Man in the Iron Mask in the shoulder, then kicks him as he falls.</context>
      <utterance>Scared?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEW KEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The New Keeper strides out. The Man in the Iron Mask pulls himself to his knees; his eyes, visible through the slits of the mask, look sadly at the old Jailer.</context>
      <utterance>Scared of you? Not me. I'll kill him if he gets near me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN THE IRON MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I miss Keeper. I miss him so much.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAILER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The jailer leaves the cell, locking the door behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Moron.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STAFF OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without another word he goes back the way he came. Raoul grips his musket and looks around him; he finds himself among several dozen stark eyed men manning the forward curve of the trench. He has little time to wonder what will happen next. A horn trumpets close by, and with a shout, the French soldiers clamber out of their breastworks. For an instant, Raoul hesitates in pure terror, then joins the charge with a shout of his own --</context>
      <utterance>Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAOUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the stone wall looming above the French soldiers, orange blossoms of fire -- the muzzle flash of primitive cannons -- penetrate the smoke, and the ground at Raoul's feet explodes, hurling him backwards. He covered barely a few feet, and falls almost exactly where he started. Dead.</context>
      <utterance>Mi-cheeelllll!! --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Artagnan looks at the paper the Lieutenant hands him.</context>
      <utterance>Sir... a casualty report came...</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sags for a moment, then grabs his cloak and sword.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, no...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The grooms jump to work; several young Musketeers nearby stop their training, noticing their Captain's agitation.</context>
      <utterance>Saddle my horse!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But then d'Artagnan sees Athos coming, riding furiously through the Musketeers' gate. D'Artagnan steps out to meet him as Athos reins in his horse and jumps from the saddle.</context>
      <utterance>Hurry --</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Athos marches to the palace door; d'Artagnan cuts him off.</context>
      <utterance>Athos, my friend --</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Athos, please...!</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get out of my way.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Athos punches d'Artagnan with furious strength, knocking him aside. The young Musketeers reach for their weapons, but d'Artagnan is up quickly, throwing himself in front of Athos again, blocking the doorway into the palace.</context>
      <utterance>Athos, I beg you --</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At this, the swords of the young Musketeers sing from their scabbards. Athos wears a sword, but he has not drawn it.</context>
      <utterance>To kill the king.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Athos! I know life means nothing to you at this moment, but I will not let you kill yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The King killed my son!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A YOUNG MUSKETEER steps up.</context>
      <utterance>The cannons killed Raoul! The cannons, and love. But not the King.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MUSKETEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Athos spins, striking like a rattlesnake, his sword whipping from its scabbard and slicing off the arrogant young Musketeer's ear. He flicks another's sword from his grasp, then brings the the point of his own blade up beneath the chin of a third, shoving him back.</context>
      <utterance>I'll kill the old man for you, Captain, if you don't wish to --</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Artagnan tackles Athos from behind and pins him face down to the hay. For a moment Athos bellows in rage --</context>
      <utterance>Come on! All of you!</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Emotion spills up into Athos' throat, and he begins to sob.</context>
      <utterance>Coward! Fight me! Fight me...!</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Artagnan, dying inside, still grips Athos. Athos grows quiet, and the young Musketeers drift closer.</context>
      <utterance>He killed my son, d'Artagnan! He killed my son...!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Artagnan stands, and Athos rises, still holding his sword. He looks at d'Artagnan a long beat, then sheathes his sword and turns to his horse. The young soldiers move to him.</context>
      <utterance>Get back, all of you!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Athos mounts his horse, and with a last glance back at d'Artagnan, he gallops away.</context>
      <utterance>Let him go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis groans, and pulls on a robe. Michelle whispers --</context>
      <utterance>Your Majesty... it is Andre.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shall I leave?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michelle rises and slips behind a painted dressing screen as Louis goes to the door and admits the young Lieutenant. BEHIND THE SCREEN, Michelle lifts a jeweled hand mirror and appraises her face; she begins brushing her long hair. She can hear the conversation...</context>
      <utterance>No, you may wait behind the screen.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would not have disturbed you, Majesty, but you ordered me to keep you informed --</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, yes, go on.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind the screen, Michelle pauses at the mention of Athos.</context>
      <utterance>Athos, the former Musketeer, has just fought with several of your guard, at the Musketeers' Gate.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did they kill him?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CRASH! From behind the screen comes the sound of the mirror, shattering as it drops to the floor. It startles the Lieutenant, but the King goes on...</context>
      <utterance>No. He cut an ear from one of the men, no one else was hurt. Captain d'Artagnan allowed him to leave. Athos was upset about the death of his son, at the front.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Did he try to enter the palace?</context>
      <utterance>Who was Athos seeking? Tell me!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... He did -- but Captain d'Artagnan blocked his way.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Lieutenant moves back to the door.</context>
      <utterance>You may go, Lieutenant.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want Athos arrested, your Majesty?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Lieutenant leaves, and Louis moves behind the screen to see Michelle stagger and grip the dressing table; her bare feet step onto the broken glass of the mirror, yet she is oblivious to the cuts. Louis sees this and grabs her.</context>
      <utterance>Not by you. I will order d'Artagnan to do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls her to the couch and draws a blanket about her, cuddling her as she begins to shake.</context>
      <utterance>My dear! The glass -- !</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you know... about Raoul?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He cuddles her as she weeps.</context>
      <utterance>I did not want to upset you. It was tragic. I did everything I could for him. I ordered him positioned in a spot of complete safety, far from the fighting. But he disregarded my wishes and charged into danger.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will order a Mass for his soul. It will guarantee his place in Heaven.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She clings to him in her grief.</context>
      <utterance>Oh Louis, Louis...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aramis... is this the way to hell?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They reach an iron door and move through it, into</context>
      <utterance>Hell may be our destination, dear Porthos, but not this trip.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="36">
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are we?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Porthos notices niches in the walls; he looks closely and sees the face of a corpse, enclosed behind glass.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus of Nazareth found the holy among the profane. If we are to have a place of private prayer, where better than here, beside the channels where the shit and the garbage run to the river?</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mother of God!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is also a place of burial.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A tomb? We're in a tomb?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Porthos looks as if the bodies could resurrect at any moment -- then jumps out of his skin as the door opens.</context>
      <utterance>Catacombs. Very holy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A hooded figure, looking like the Grim Reaper, enters.</context>
      <utterance>Yaaaahhh!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And sure enough the hooded figure, whom we now see has been led in by a little monk, is d'Artagnan. Aramis nods to the monk, who leaves quickly. Before d'Artagnan can ask anything, Porthos jumps again; the back door has opened, and monks usher in Athos, who freezes as he sees d'Artagnan.</context>
      <utterance>Relax, you big fool, it's d'Artagnan.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The escort monks disappear, closing the chapel door so that the four Musketeers are left to sit at a small table the monks have set up, Athos and D'Artagnan opposite each other.</context>
      <utterance>It's all right. D'Artagnan was the one who warned us that he'd been given an order for your arrest. Here you have sanctuary -- does he not, d'Artagnan?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at us. We are old men now. But once we were young. And when we saw injustice, we fought it.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have grown wiser with age. Now we know that some problems cannot be settled with a sword.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And some problems cannot be settled without one.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well here is the problem at hand: the King has ordered me to discover the identity of the Governor General of Jesuits, and kill him. As our English rivals have left the Catholic Church, Louis has struck on a plan to dominate the whole of Europe by uniting Church and State and making himself head of both. He has already picked the Pope. Only the Jesuits, who put God above throne or papacy, stand in his way.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But -- doesn't God ordain both Pope and King?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So they tell us. But what are we to believe when the king is a tyrant, and the Church, meant to stand for all those oppressed, has become the tool of oppression? When no conscience is tolerated? No dissent, no objection?</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is a weighty problem, Aramis -- but perhaps you should leave it to this secret General of the Jesuits, whoever he might be.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A stunned silence.</context>
      <utterance>Easy to say, but hard to do. For what I am trying to tell you is that I am the Governor General of Jesuits in France.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you propose to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Replace the king.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I cannot hear this!</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It can't be done.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It can. I know the way.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am with you!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! Stop --</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One for all.</context>
      <utterance>I will need you all. All for one.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You -- You cannot ask me to betray my king! I have sworn to him!</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is honor you serve, and when the king is dishonorable you are removed from your oath of honor!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An oath is an oath precisely because it cannot be removed!</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you follow him, d'Artagnan?! I know you have put service above your own life, but why does this King deserve such loyalty? He is a monster! He executes ministers for his own blunders, with their families hostage so they take the blame! He has no honor!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Athos leaps up from the table, and glares at d'Artagnan.</context>
      <utterance>No man is all bad... or all good. I believe -- I must believe -- that Louis can learn. And perhaps I can help him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever the plan... I am in it! The next time we meet, one of us will die. He storms out of the rear door of the chapel.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Porthos follows Athos; Aramis and d'Artagnan are left alone.</context>
      <utterance>Porthos, see to Athos, won't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have heard many confessions, d'Artagnan. But even if I were not a priest, I could tell your heart has a secret weight, and it is hurting you to carry it alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Artagnan moves to the door.</context>
      <utterance>The secret I carry I cannot share. Not even with God.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I cannot betray Louis. I will defend him with my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Artagnan leaves Aramis alone in the secret chapel.</context>
      <utterance>I know. God go with you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They move into a moonlit courtyard of the monastery. A hooded Jesuit standing guard steps from the shadows, then recognizes Aramis and admits the trio to the monastery's forge, where more hooded Jesuits are working in secret, heating iron red hot in the bellows furnace.</context>
      <utterance>This way.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are they doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Making the key to the throne.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of the blacksmiths uses tongs to remove something red from the fire; he hammers it in a shower of sparks and plunges it into water. Aramis pulls the result from the water and shows it to Athos and Porthos. It is an iron mask.</context>
      <utterance>They are very large keys.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Porthos sleeps, and you plot. Don't you think it's time you told me what it is you are plotting?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kicking Porthos' feet to wake him, Aramis opens the carriage door, and they step out...</context>
      <utterance>Soon enough. Here we are.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Prison of Belle Sur.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As hooded Jesuits appear from the shadows to guide them, Athos and Porthos glance at each other; Porthos shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Come, we have a boat waiting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A body.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis ignores the question, and the guides dress him in priest's garb. With the robes spreading over the big bundle added artfully to Aramis' waist, it appears he is a very fat priest; the wig and false beard the assistants give him adds to the illusion of Aramis as a wild, reclusive monk. The sun is beginning to come up over the mountains.</context>
      <utterance>I see that is a body! But where did you get it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He gets one day of confession each year. Today is the day.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who does?</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis steps onto the boat. The little priest who first joined them gets in too, along with a couple of rowers.</context>
      <utterance>Best not to ask. Shouldn't even talk about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do we do now?</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The rowers pull the boat toward the fortress prison.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know about you, but I plan to wait here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HEAD GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The little priest remains in the boat, slumped over. One GUARD speaks to the little priest in Italian, and the little priest seems barely able to left his head; Aramis answers for him, in Italian, and the guard translates --</context>
      <utterance>Who is this, then?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis rattles off more Italian.</context>
      <utterance>He says he's the replacement.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He says it is only one day a month when the prisoner gets confession, and the little one is too sick to move. The big one doesn't speak French either.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The head guard gestures to let them pass.</context>
      <utterance>Then let's get it done.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MAN IN THE IRON MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis says something in Latin -- the first words of the ceremony of absolution -- as the guards lock the door behind him and move off down the corridor.</context>
      <utterance>My confession day! But where is the other one?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN THE IRON MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis goes on mumbling Latin mechanically, for the sake of the retreating guards. The Man in the Iron Mask is desperate for someone to talk to.</context>
      <utterance>I know you don't speak my language -- but is the other one all right? Please tell me he is not dead too, or I will have lost everyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN THE IRON MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis has stopped talking, and stares transfixed at this sight of the prisoner, in the iron mask.</context>
      <utterance>I... tore my Bible. Or someone else did. But it was all right. "Let the words of my mouth and the meditations of my heart be acceptable in Thy sight, Oh Lord our God and My Redeemer."</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN THE IRON MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis puts his finger to his lips.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. You're never seen me before. I must frighten you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN THE IRON MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis clamps his hand over the mouth hole, and whispers --</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing? Why do you --</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis hurriedly removes his robes, revealing the bundle.</context>
      <utterance>I am a friend, here to help you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN THE IRON MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What -- ?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is an escape. To freedom.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN THE IRON MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He says it as if the concept is beyond him. Aramis undoes the bundle, revealing the limp body.</context>
      <utterance>Freedom...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN THE IRON MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wh-- ? He is dead! Who is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis uncovers the head of the body. It is covered in a mask, identical to the prisoner's.</context>
      <utterance>He is you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What now?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He says he just fell stone dead as he was reading him the Mass.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis rattles off more Italian, and suddenly the guard who understands it stops examining the body and backs off.</context>
      <utterance>I never thought the bugger would last this long. But how could he just keel over and --</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He says the prisoner has the fever, just like the little priest does.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis rattles off a protest in Italian.</context>
      <utterance>Plague? They brought plague in here? Get him out of here. Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no last rites! Get away!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Athos, Porthos, and the others gawk at the sight of the Man in the Iron Mask, as Aramis loosens the ropes. As they back away from him, he sees the sky. Endless blue -- and bright. He shields his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>My God...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis helps him up, and turn him slowly around, to face... The fortress/prison, in the distance. THE PRISONER'S POV FROM WITHIN THE MASK: A vast vista -- the sky, the sea, and the prison on the island in the middle of it all. The prisoner falls to his knees, and weeps.</context>
      <utterance>It's all right. Take your time.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Athos moves over hesitantly, and puts his hand on the shoulder of the Man in the Iron Mask, who holds his hands against the mask as if to further hide his shame.</context>
      <utterance>Athos... He needs a gentle hand.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GUARD 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever wonder who he was?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They wrap the body, still in its mask, in a weighted sack.</context>
      <utterance>No... Yes. But I never asked -- and you better not either.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MAN IN THE IRON MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! Please!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the prisoner is shaking, and Athos understands why.</context>
      <utterance>What is wrong? We only mean to free you from the mask!</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Prison was horrible but it was his home. He's been torn from it by strangers. He's frightened, exhausted -- and the mask is familiar. Let him rest in it tonight, and remove it tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excellent, Athos. You have a keen sense of this man.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Athos, angry with Aramis' arrogance and insensitivity, leads the Man in the Iron Mask toward the house; then Aramis spots Porthos, looking downcast.</context>
      <utterance>His plight is obvious, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And why are you so glum?</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In deep depression, Porthos climbs out and shuffles off. Aramis sighs, shakes his head, and walks to the house.</context>
      <utterance>I expected action. There was no killing, no fighting, I was useless.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you hungry?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN THE IRON MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Athos pours a cupful from the water pitcher on the bed table; but when he tries to help the prisoner drink the liquid spills as the cup bumps the mouth hole.</context>
      <utterance>Just... water.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN THE IRON MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The prisoner manipulates the cup in the way he must to get a drink, then falls back to the pillow.</context>
      <utterance>This way.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN THE IRON MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This place... I once lived in a country house. I had guardians -- an old man and woman. And tutors. But no friends. Then when I was twelve, they came and took me to the prison.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who came?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN THE IRON MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A man in black. I never saw his face. He took me to the cell. A blacksmith came and they put me into the mask. For days I shouted, "What have I done? Why do you do this to me?" But no one heard, so I just stopped shouting.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you never knew why?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRISONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought... there is something about my face that men do not want to see. Something that makes them cruel. But then I realized they were cruel even when I was wearing the mask. I knew there must be some other reason, but I could not think what it was.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN THE IRON MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phillippe.</context>
      <utterance>The old man and woman called me...</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Athos moves to the door.</context>
      <utterance>Phillippe. Rest now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN THE IRON MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Athos nods, pauses a moment... and leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you... for your kindness.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>M'lady... are you...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, just... go away.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See? There is plenty of food in the country. But the King keeps it going to the army instead of -- Athos marches in, all business.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He breaks off as a voluptuous serving girl leans over to spoon food onto Porthos' plate; her breasts jiggle below his nose, and she gives him a smile.</context>
      <utterance>He is sleeping. Now see here, Aramis, it's time you told us --</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girl moves to whisper with two other serving girls, who seem fascinated with the roguish Porthos; their giggles and winks make Porthos even more morose; he tells his friends...</context>
      <utterance>I have no appetite for food, I am wasting away. Say goodbye to Porthos, for he is gone. Even women don't interest me now.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Porthos heaves himself to his feet and shuffles off; Aramis sighs, having heard all this before. Athos sits down.</context>
      <utterance>I tell you a secret. I sleep with three women at once, not because my appetite is so great, but because now it take three to excite me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is he, Aramis?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tonight! Right now! We steal a man from a royal prison, we hide in a country chateau among an assortment of saints and sluts such as only you could provide, and still you wish to tell me nothing?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You seek facts, when it would be better to seek truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are not my priest, Aramis! You would not be, even if I had one.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are bitter, Athos. You are torn by grief, not only for Raoul, but for d'Artagnan, whom you love, and now treat as an enemy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He who is not with us is against us.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those are the words of a broken spirit. My spirit is whole. I have trusted d'Artagnan with my deepest secrets, and I will never believe he is my enemy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you are a fool -- a fool who has never lost a son. What gives you the right to judge me, to play God with the lives of others? Is it because you are so much holier than everyone else?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are interrupted by Porthos' bloodcurdling SCREAM.</context>
      <utterance>There is that, of course -- but mainly it is because I am so much smarter than everyone else.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He draws his sword and runs for the outside.</context>
      <utterance>Porthos?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God I -- Forgive me...</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She whirls to see him; the sight of her face, bursting with emotions she has kept buried, draws him nearer.</context>
      <utterance>M'lady...?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What -- ?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He freezes in his tracks; she holds her hands out toward him as if warding off a blow. He's desperate to move to her; she sees it on his face.</context>
      <utterance>No, stay back! Stay back!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her emotions break all her resolve to keep him away; she rushes into his arms. They clutch each other, in an embrace they have denied for many years. They kiss hungrily.</context>
      <utterance>D'Artagnan!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>M'lady... if anyone sees, it is death...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I don't kiss you, I die anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't bear to see you cry. What is wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She draws back; he tries to hold her. But the thoughts of answering that question makes her stiffen.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing... Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And just like that, their moment is gone.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing. This... didn't happen. I must go back now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anne...! I know... I know that to love you is treason against France. But not to love you... is treason against my heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With those whispered words hanging in the air, she enters her room. And d'Artagnan moves alone, back to his.</context>
      <utterance>Then we will both die traitors, d'Artagnan.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is wrong? She says nothing. He tries kissing her again.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She begins weeping uncontrollably, and turns from him.</context>
      <utterance>What is wrong?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Raoul... Oh, Raoul...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, my darling... Raoul was a... a good friend. And now he is dead and that is very sad but --</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The King stands; he's had enough of this.</context>
      <utterance>We'll burn in hell. Both of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He snatches the gold coverlet from her bed to cover his naked body and stalks to his stairway; the embroidered coverlet trails behind him like a regal train in a royal procession. Leaving her weeping, he moves down into...</context>
      <utterance>No, my love. You will burn in hell, for your sins. But I will not -- for I am King. My position is ordained by God.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out there! Look! Out there! He -- The garden is empty.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just left the garden, it was empty. What did you see?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Artagnan guides his guards out, but glances back to see the King, ashamed and worried. D'Artagnan tells his men --</context>
      <utterance>It... was nothing. A nightmare, nothing more. Go away, I --</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Check the garden.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aramis! Athos! He looks exactly like... exactly like...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But first soap, water, and a razor.</context>
      <utterance>I will answer all your questions.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis' eyes are aflame as he looks across at Phillippe.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Identical.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The greatest secret of life is who we truly are. Now I must give you that secret, which has been kept from you your whole life. It began on the night when Louis was born.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I remember that night. D'Artagnan was drunk, the only time I've seen him that way. The three of us were reveling, remember, Athos?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I was on duty...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ARAMIS' VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the flashback we see the young Musketeer Aramis, his face shielded in shadow, handing a living bundle over to someone at one of the back doors of a large country house.</context>
      <utterance>They brought a baby from the back of the palace, into the black carriage I had waiting. They had given the driver instructions about where it was, and I was ordered to make the whole journey with the blinds of the carriage drawn.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS' VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I carried that baby into the countryside, to a chateau, like this one. And there I left him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have never forgotten that night, or what I carried.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand. What does this have to do with...? You carried a baby somewhere, it's unusual, but --</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not just a baby, Porthos. I carried the child of the king.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The child of the king is... the king. Louis!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not Louis!</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Athos, do you understand this? He confuses me --</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I carried the king's child! The queen had twins that night, and one of them was sent away, in secret!</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But why?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phillippe is pale... We DISSOLVE TO a flashback of Phillippe's early education in the country house.</context>
      <utterance>Because the old king had a twin as well, and through his whole reign his brother fought him for the throne. Then he had two heirs, not just sons but twins. So he decided that one be put away, as if he never existed. You, Phillippe.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS' VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The FLASHBACK moves to the palace, matching the narration --</context>
      <utterance>The old king ordered you be educated and well treated, but your identity kept from you and all those around you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS' VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see in FLASHBACK Louis wearing his new crown, plotting.</context>
      <utterance>On his death bed, he revealed your existence to Louis and your mother. Your mother had been told by her own priest that you had died at birth. Somehow she blamed herself for ever believing it, and she wished to restore your birthright. But now Louis was king.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS' VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We are in present time again. All eyes are on Phillippe.</context>
      <utterance>A priest, even a Pope, he could kill without hesitation, but he was afraid to kill you, for his whole claim to power rests on the sanctity of royal blood. So he had you hidden in a way that only a monster could devise. I know, for it was I who took you to prison, and the Iron Mask. Someday I will ask your forgiveness. But not until we have restored to you what is yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Restored...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We will replace Louis with Phillippe. No one but the King himself -- and now we -- knows Phillippe even exists. All we have to do is switch them.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Switch?! That is your plan? It is ludicrous!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have it all worked out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Physical resemblance is but one small thing! Louis has an arrogance, a manner --</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those can be adopted --</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And people close to him, who --</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think I have not considered that? I have a plan -- and you may rest assured that it is brilliant!</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is not just our lives you risk with this conceit of yours! It is Phillippe's as well!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis stops thundering at Athos, and turns to Phillippe.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, and he has a choice!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phillippe stands shakily, and faces them.</context>
      <utterance>What about it, Phillippe?! All that time in prison, all that time you suffered, was it for nothing?! You memorized the entire Bible, or so your priest told me! An act of survival, of defiance, of courage! Your years within the mask have given you reserves of strength that others could not imagine. Your home was a dungeon and now you may be a king, if you have the heart to make it so! Do you have the heart?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phillippe walks -- nearly wanders -- from the room.</context>
      <utterance>I will try.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Athos, with a glare at Aramis, follows Phillippe.</context>
      <utterance>You see? A king.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Recent hours have been a shock.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps not as much as you might imagine. When tutors answered every question except those about who I was. When I was imprisoned in a way no other man had ever been, I knew there was something different about me. But a king...</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Phillippe... there is something I hope you understand. Terrible cruelty has been used against you. And... you must understand that you did nothing to deserve it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is... wrath... in me. I have learned to hide it. Those years in the cell, I dreamed that freedom would someday just happen, the way the mask happened. Now I am free. And with each free breath I feel the growing desire to make someone suffer for all I lost. Look at this, all this that for ten years I could not see! What if I become a king -- a king no different from my brother?</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The desire for vengeance... can be a poison.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is its antidote?</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phillippe reaches to a flower, plucks it, and smells it. He looks around at the beauty of the garden, taking it all in. Athos looks around too; then Athos realizes Phillippe is no longer looking at the garden, but at him.</context>
      <utterance>I suppose... it is to remember there are many people who have never been in a prison, who pass such beauty every day, and never see it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look so sad. Is it something I have done?</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is something I have done -- or did not do.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Phillippe can pursue this, Athos turns businesslike.</context>
      <utterance>I did not share beauty with someone... who is no longer here for me to share beauty with.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have much to do, we'd best get started. Now suppose you were to walk into a garden, as a king...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Athos enters and sags into a chair, his energy spent.</context>
      <utterance>More wine!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis --</context>
      <utterance>Resting, he's had a long day.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More wine!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phillippe is like a child, he --</context>
      <utterance>You must reconsider this plan.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In a year, maybe two, I could teach him enough to --</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three days.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three days??!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The King is having a ball, a masquerade ball. It is the perfect opportunity and perhaps our only one. At any time Phillippe could be discovered, and what then? Remember France. Remember the poor. Remember Raoul. More wine!! Where are those serving girls...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's no use. My sword is bent.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERVING WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll be all right. You're just taking a while to get started.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Porthos heaves himself out of bed.</context>
      <utterance>No, it's dead. I am useless.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Phillippe -- he's very bright, he's perceptive, but he is in such turmoil --</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You grow fond of him. That's good.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Athos interrupts himself as he glimpses the naked Porthos moving across the courtyard toward the barn.</context>
      <utterance>Don't play God with me, Aramis I --</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go on.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But -- what is Porthos doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We INTERCUT Porthos in the barn with Aramis and Athos in the house...</context>
      <utterance>Going into the barn naked -- or so it appears.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now. You were saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But -- what is he doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About to hang himself, I should think.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hang himself?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's threatened to do it, it's been building up in him for months.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We must stop him!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come now, Athos, if Porthos is determined to end his life, then he will certainly manage to find the opportunity.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Athos jumps up and makes for the door -- but Aramis' hooded helpers, at a signal from Aramis, bar his way.</context>
      <utterance>But -- but --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His great weight drops. The rope snaps taught. The beam it is tied to snaps like a twig -- right in the place where it has been sawn nearly in half already. Porthos falls unencumbered and slams butt first into the floorboards of the barn, cracking them.</context>
      <utterance>A'dieu, cruel life! Farewell to useless Porthos! He steps off the stool.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS AND ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>can hear the crack from where they're sitting.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I sawed the main beam in half.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Porthos' eyes are bulging; he's terrifying in his fury. And he holds one of the broken barn's timbers like a giant club, ready to bash in Aramis' brains. Aramis is totally casual.</context>
      <utterance>Aramis!! You did this, didn't you! You knew I would try hanging myself, and you sawed the beam! Admit it! Admit it, by God!! ADMIT IT!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Porthos stands there, blinking.</context>
      <utterance>Well of course I knew it, Porthos.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've been moping for months. Now that you've gotten the idea of killing yourself out of the way, you can stop boring me and start being useful to me. Now get some rest.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Porthos starts back toward the house. Then one of the serving girls, heading back inside, sees in one of the upper windows -- the face in the Iron Mask. She SCREAMS --</context>
      <utterance>Well... Well... Okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Poor Phillippe!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The mask is terrifying... especially when unexpected. Do you notice?</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Athos hurries in; Aramis looks at Porthos.</context>
      <utterance>All I noticed was that Phillippe feels even more like an animal.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, Porthos -- secrets are hard to keep. We don't have much time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've worn this mask so long, I couldn't sleep without it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Athos settles into a chair, as Phillippe lays the mask aside on the table and closes his eyes. Athos looks toward the flames of the fireplace, and in their dancing shadows he sees the face of Raoul. Phillippe's voice interrupts --</context>
      <utterance>I will sit with you. I can't sleep either.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Athos had not thought of it that way. Phillippe closes his eyes again, and falls asleep.</context>
      <utterance>Athos...? Thank you for being my guide... back into the world.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We'll be back soon. Be ready.</context>
      <utterance>Paris. There is still much to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But Aramis -- ! Phillippe can learn in time, but --</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He can learn to be Phillippe in time. But first he must learn to be Louis, and for that he has two more days.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you're asking is impossible!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I offer you the perfect revolution. A revolution without bloodshed, without any loss of life, even without treason, for he too is the son of the King.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But --</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis motions to the driver, who snaps the reins and drives the horses away. Athos, wide-eyed and alone, watches the carriage roll away. He turns back toward the house, and see's Phillippe looking out the window -- without the mask.</context>
      <utterance>You said you'd do anything, Athos, anything to replace this King. So do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shows him, pinching the goblet between thumb and forefinger, as the other three fingers extend daintily.</context>
      <utterance>No, wait, do not hold your goblet that way. With a king it is... so.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phillippe tries it and the goblet slips from his fingers, crashing onto his plate and spilling onto everything.</context>
      <utterance>It is not to be dainty. Servants have touched the King's goblet, so he will touch it as little as possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am so sorry! Forgive me, I --</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! Do not be sorry! Never be sorry! The King cares for nothing and for no one! There are no mistakes when you are King! What you do is right for every person! A King has contempt for everyone!</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that the king of king you wish me to be? Or do you say this because of your son?</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you know -- ?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For a moment Athos can say nothing; then he shoves back from the table and storms from the room.</context>
      <utterance>Porthos told me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Athos' voice breaks, his body sags.</context>
      <utterance>I am not... I am not angry with you. You understand? Good. Now, as to acting like a king, we wish you to be a good king. But at first... at first you must pass as Louis, and Louis is cold and cruel. So you must stop looking at people with such softness. It is... not Kingly. The eyes of a King say that all he cares about is himself, and your eyes -- how do I tell him this -- ? You eyes... ask so much. You shouldn't care about me, about my -- about...</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Athos weeps.</context>
      <utterance>Oh Raoul, my son... my son...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coming?</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What use am I?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We go someplace dangerous.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Porthos steps out with him, and Aramis leads the way down a dark, spooky alley.</context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you say so?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis grunts non-committally, lost in thought.</context>
      <utterance>It is good to be out on a mission again... We are out on a mission, aren't we?</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just as he says this a sinister form steps from the shadows and blocks their way. He holds a knife. Another ROBBER with a sword rises from a doorway beside them.</context>
      <utterance>You're right. Tell Porthos nothing. He needs to know nothing, for he is useless.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis looks bored; Porthos stands blinking in surprise. Then a third robber steps up behind them, cocking a pistol.</context>
      <utterance>Your money or your life.</utterance>
   <speaker>THIRD ROBBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make it quick, old man!</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>rob us because you think we're old? The man with a sword steps forward to hack Porthos down, but Porthos spins, slapping the pistol, making it BOOM but miss; he kicks the swordsman in the groin, then smashes his head against the alley wall; he backhands the gunman. The robber with the knife tries to run; Porthos snatches a barrel from the street and hurls it into the fleeing robber's back; he falls in a heap. Porthos' fury has just begun. He picks the fallen gunman up by the throat, slams him stomach down across a broken alley cart, and with one sweep of his mighty hand Porthos snatches down the man's pants.</context>
      <utterance>Old? Old?! You're all trying to</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Porthos snatches the pistol from the cobblestones. We see the shock and terror on the robber's face as he feels something shocking happen behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Old?! I'll show you old!!</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's see you rob somebody with your pistol there!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis, acting as if nothing happened, leads Porthos away.</context>
      <utterance>Come on...</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis has found what he's looking for: a filthy brothel.</context>
      <utterance>I have to tell you something. I love Paris!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis leads Porthos inside.</context>
      <utterance>Here we are.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aramis... These are... these are whores!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So was Mary Magdalene, and our Lord loved her.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A greasy, disgusting PIMP shuffles over.</context>
      <utterance>Did she have tits like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both?</context>
      <utterance>What do you want? White? Black?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pimp reacts with fury, drawing a pistol.</context>
      <utterance>No. We want you, Father Belles.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis slowly falls to his knees, before the pimp.</context>
      <utterance>Get out! Now! I will kill you where you stand!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pimp -- the former Father Belles, the same man we saw as the priest who prayed with the Queen at the royal birth in the opening -- shoves his pistol at Aramis' face.</context>
      <utterance>Bless me, Father, for I have sinned.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't! Get out!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis' eyes are hypnotic, staring deep into the fallen priest's soul. Porthos is bug-eyed, certain Aramis' head is about to be blown apart.</context>
      <utterance>I have sinned. And no other priest's assurance of forgiveness can mean as much as yours. Tell me that I can be forgiven, no matter what I have done.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's going to kill you, Aramis.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares at the pimp. The pimp's finger trembles on the trigger.</context>
      <utterance>Then let him kill me, if all my faith is wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pimp shakes convulsively; he drops to his knees, bows his head, and weeps.</context>
      <utterance>I have come to help you make it right. I have come to take you home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PRIESTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crossing themselves, they embrace the prodigal priest; one MONK kneels before Aramis.</context>
      <utterance>Father Belles!</utterance>
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have made a miracle!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Aramis strides toward the dining room, a Jesuit hurries up to him.</context>
      <utterance>God makes miracles. You make dinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Aramis hears this in surprise --</context>
      <utterance>The ball has been rescheduled -- for tomorrow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These rooms are yours. Up these stairs -- or through this hidden passage -- is the room of your mistress... Michelle.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whose rooms are those?</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are interrupted as the carriage bearing Aramis and Porthos clatters in. Aramis is out immediately.</context>
      <utterance>Your mother's.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Change the horses! Clear out everything! NOW!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aramis, this will never --</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Louis is planning a visit to the Vatican, then who knows where after that. If we miss him now we may not get another chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But --</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It presses us but it is good for us too! Louis' whims make him more vulnerable. We are less ready, but so are his guards!</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>D'Artagnan, unready?</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At a ball, everyone watches the King!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what if something extraordinary happened? Something so unusual that all the attention went to someone else? Someone whose confirmation of Phillippe the King would never be questioned.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Aramis leans forward to tell them his plan...</context>
      <utterance>The Queen Mother. Anne.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bless me Father, for I have sinned.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER BELLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slides open the partition window between them.</context>
      <utterance>So have I.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He taps a silencing finger to his lips.</context>
      <utterance>Father Belles -- ?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They told me you were dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER BELLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anne stares at the eyes of the priest, back from hell.</context>
      <utterance>I was. I see you are still a woman of faith. I have come back to ask you if you believe that one lie can poison your whole life... and one truth can put it back together again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Artagnan enters, looking concerned.</context>
      <utterance>It shall be interesting tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your Majesty. This ball, with an open invitation to the nobility of Paris -- we have no way of checking --</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Through the window Louis sees more beautiful young women.</context>
      <utterance>You will protect me as you always have, d'Artagnan.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up to see that Michelle has entered through the open door behind him.</context>
      <utterance>By the way, Claude -- inform Mademoiselle Beaufort that she will be moving from her rooms --</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Michelle's appearance brings him up short. It is not the cruel brush-off; she is already harshly different: her eyes are red from crying, her lips are tight in anger.</context>
      <utterance>Never mind, it seems we have already told her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds a letter, crushed in her hand.</context>
      <utterance>Murderer! Murderer!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hurls the crumpled letter into his face. Everyone is frozen, silent. She staggers toward Louis as if to attack him, then falls to her knees, weeping. No one helps her... Except d'Artagnan. He kneels, hugs her shoulders, helps her to her feet, and guides her toward her room. But d'Artagnan looks back once, toward Louis.</context>
      <utterance>I wrote Fromberge! Under your seal! I wrote as you, demanding to know why he disregarded my order to keep Raoul from danger! He writes back: "But your Majesty! Your last letter ordered me to put him in front of the cannon!"</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hysterical woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sire, misuse of the royal seal -- !</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As d'Artagnan and Michelle move out, they pass Anne, coming in. Anne and d'Artagnan exchange a look; he remembers to give her a respectful nod, but she moves past, into the King's dressing room. Louis is surprised.</context>
      <utterance>She'll be gone tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mother -- ?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I speak with you? Alone?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am preparing for a ball!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We haven't visited in three years. And we should have privacy. Exasperated, Louis waves his attendants away.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it, mother?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish to discuss your brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is dead! By God's choice! There is nothing to discuss.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First they told me he had died at birth. Then your father admitted he was alive, but well cared for, in secret. But the message that told of his death said he had been a prisoner.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am King, Mother! And I do not wish to discuss this with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was my blood -- and I demand to know what happened to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would you ask now? You never asked before!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I have dreamed of him. Not as the baby they took away, but as a man.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Avoiding her stare, Louis lifts a plaster bust of his father, its eyes like the sightless pupils of Greek gods.</context>
      <utterance>You have prayed too much. Your mind is weak.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see her from a low angle, from a POV behind Louis -- and we see the plaster bust burst upon the marble floor.</context>
      <utterance>I believe in dreams, Louis. They are our souls speaking to us, from that world beyond our eyes. And that son I never saw in daylight was standing in the moonlight of my dreams. And he wore an iron mask.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It -- it doesn't matter, Mother! He is dead now! Dead!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the night of Louis' "dream." Anne begins to walk out.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Dead. Two nights ago. The night of my dream.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis smiles; he thinks he has her.</context>
      <utterance>If... if he was wearing an iron mask in your dream, then how could you know he was your son?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All the blood is gone from Louis' face. Anne walks from the room, past Louis' waiting tailors. He snaps at them.</context>
      <utterance>Then you did do it, Louis. You did put your brother in an iron mask.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They rush in. As they scurry about, dressing him in gold, Louis' composure returns; he stares at himself in the golden mirror, likes what he sees... and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I have a ball to attend!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whose carriage is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The new carriage lurches away.</context>
      <utterance>It was mine. But since you are about to be the king, it is yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSIDE THE NEW CARRIAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>are bundles of elaborate clothes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They begin to dress Phillippe in a masquerade costume.</context>
      <utterance>Phillippe first.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember, Phillippe... nobility is born in the heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold your goblet with two fingers.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis tucks a note into Phillippe's pocket.</context>
      <utterance>And make love as if you don't care. The way Kings do. And fart whenever you wish.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phillippe nods; everyone's nervous. Aramis grabs more clothes and hands them out.</context>
      <utterance>Remember, all you have to do is get through tonight. Smile and nod a lot, and if you get stuck just wave and announce, "Continue." In the morning you hand this note to d'Artagnan, pardoning Athos and instructing that he, Aramis and Porthos be brought to the palace as your advisors. And all is well.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now the rest of us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>D'Artagnan watches everything. We have to be lucky.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis peers across the ballroom, to where Athos and Phillippe mix among the revelers, using thin sticks to hold broad masks to their faces. Behind the masks we see their eyes -- Athos' intense, Phillippe's nervous and darting.</context>
      <utterance>We will make our own luck tonight... if Phillippe holds up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then Phillippe's eyes go strangely still; he sees, for the first time in his life, his twin brother, the King.</context>
      <utterance>Stay calm, you're doing fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis dances the minuet, prancing as if he is the center of the universe; but this bliss is broken when one of the dancers who swirls by him -- it is Aramis -- lifts the baroque outer mask he's wearing and reveals an iron mask beneath. The King staggers, stopping. The sight stuns him, confuses him; he looks around but the wearer of the mask has disappeared among the weaving patterns of dancers. Louis' hands dart to his eyes: are they playing tricks on him? Seeing his reaction, Phillippe whispers --</context>
      <utterance>My brother...</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The YOUNG BEAUTY dancing with Louis notices him falter.</context>
      <utterance>He knew. He knew what they did to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG BEAUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is wrong, your majesty?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis rejoins the dancing... and then sees, on the balcony above him, a different person -- a huge "woman," Porthos -- who lifts off an outer mask to reveal an iron mask below.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing, I -- continue.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There! Do you see it?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG BEAUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Porthos has slipped away from the railing when the King looks back up; the young beauty sees nothing, and turns back to the King with a look that questions his sanity. D'Artagnan notices the King's reaction -- though he did not see the glimpse of the iron mask -- and is just as baffled as everyone else when the King turns and staggers away.</context>
      <utterance>See what, Majesty?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your Majesty...?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The music splatters to an awkward stop; Louis hurries out, leaving his partner abandoned in the center of the ballroom, with everyone staring as if she just ruined the party.</context>
      <utterance>... tired. Must... lie down.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The music begins again, and the party goers, not knowing what else to do, politely continue. Athos draws Phillippe away from the ballroom, into a side corridor.</context>
      <utterance>Carry on, everyone...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hurry in the same direction Athos and Phillippe went.</context>
      <utterance>Quick, to the passages.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The room of the King's favorite mistress?</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She will be at the ball.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MUSKETEERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LOUIS, still on his bed, now wears Phillippe's clothes.</context>
      <utterance>Your Majesty.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wh-- Wha--</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Come, you're going back to prison.</context>
      <utterance>Don't look so shocked, Phillippe.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now Louis understands everything. He tries to struggle, but instantly Porthos shoves a rag into his mouth. Aramis opens the main door a crack, and sees d'Artagnan has entered his room down the corridor, through whose open door he can guard the approaches to the King's rooms. Aramis shuts the door again and turns to the others.</context>
      <utterance>Phillippe?! Why do you call me --</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Athos puts his hands on Phillippe's shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>D'Artagnan guards the hallway! You must go back the way we came!</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis and Porthos bow again to Phillippe -- now dressed and looking exactly like the King. Phillippe's mouth is dry; he swallows hard, and follows Athos up the hidden stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Now, your Majesty. It is time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phillippe nods, tremendously nervous.</context>
      <utterance>You know the way.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phillippe pats his pocket, like a boy being sent off to his first day at school. He surprises Athos, hugging him. Then Phillippe opens the door and walks slowly down the hallway. Athos stands at the door and watches him go, all alone. Athos whispers, though Phillippe can't hear...</context>
      <utterance>You have your note?</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reluctantly, he shuts the door behind Phillippe.</context>
      <utterance>You have the heart of a king.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As if by magic the music plays, the dancing resumes. Phillippe moves to the throne and takes his place upon it. He seems to have made it; people glance -- dancing ladies, young Musketeers, old advisors -- but no one gives him a second look. For a moment, Phillippe feels safe. And then he sees Michelle, her eyes glassy and riveted upon him. She wears her most beautiful gown -- the first one Louis gave her -- but one shoulder strap dangles sloppily. Her lips and cheeks are awkwardly rouged, her hair is mussed; she is drunk. She weaves her way to him and curtsies elaborately.</context>
      <utterance>Continue.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phillippe's heart is pounding; he looks around for help. He can only guess who this woman is. The advisors have now noticed her; Claude quickly dispatches orders to keep the party going along, and waves guards over.</context>
      <utterance>My gracious noble lord...</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She doesn't react, so he must have guessed right; but Phillippe knows nothing of what happened just before the ball, and he's ambushed by her anger.</context>
      <utterance>How are you... Michelle?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts tearing off her dress. Claude and the guards reach her; the young Musketeers grabbing her.</context>
      <utterance>How should I be? I came to give this back to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Michelle fights, slapping, clawing -- and when one of the young Musketeers grabs her from behind, his arm to her throat, Phillippe jumps up.</context>
      <utterance>Fret not with this, your Majesty --</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phillippe's face shows something Louis' never did: compassion. He looks into Michelle's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Stop! You're hurting her!</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phillippe could not have said anything more unlike Louis; everyone who heard the remark -- Claude, the guards, and especially Michelle -- stare at him in frozen amazement. Phillippe realizes his blunder; they've caught him. The MUSIC STOPS. But the attention is not directed at the throne; all eyes shift to the main doorway, where Anne has appeared. She is indescribably beautiful; she wears a bright gown, her hair is brushed and bejeweled, she radiates the light of a woman who felt old at thirty and who has discovered, at forty, that she is more stunning than ever. Her arrival draws even more attention than the reappearance of the King; everyone watches transfixed as she approaches. Phillippe sees her -- his mother. He stands on legs that seem to have no bones. His mother. She moves to him, her eyes filling with tears. When she is almost to the throne, Phillippe falls to his knees before her and kisses her hand. No one can believe it, not from this King. Yet the moment strikes them as beautiful, and they applaud happily. Phillippe and the Queen Mother rise, and guide each other -- depending on each other for support, to a seat, he on the throne, she on a seat the servants place beside him. Phillippe gives a wave.</context>
      <utterance>However I have wronged you I will make amends. Whatever the cost.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ball continues, the music exuberant. Michelle wanders away, like a blind lamb. Phillippe and his mother sit side by side, holding hands, their reunion passing in private between their clasped hands, and glistening in their eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Continue.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Porthos drapes Louis over his shoulder, and they move into the passages. Just as they close the portal behind them, the door opens and Michelle wanders in like a zombie. Suddenly, d'Artagnan is at her shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, your Majesty. We have a prison for you, where you can rest peacefully.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then he sees the room is empty; he thought Louis was here.</context>
      <utterance>Michelle --</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In... the ballroom. But he isn't the same man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CLAUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guests applaud and reach for wine glasses; servants present Phillippe and Anne with champagne, and they sip --</context>
      <utterance>To King Louis! And to Anne, the Queen Mother!</utterance>
   <speaker>GUESTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone drinks; Phillippe suddenly remembers to hold his glass in his fingertips -- and it slips through his nervous fingers, hitting the floor with a crash. Dead silence; everyone is looking. Then Anne drops her glass too -- and everybody does it, as if to break the glass is part of the celebration. As the music begins again, Anne leans to Phillippe --</context>
      <utterance>To King Louis, and the Queen Mother!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I retire now. Wait two waltzes, then retire to your room; and spend the night in safety. We have much to talk about, and have the rest of our lives to do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good night, Mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses him on the cheek; it brings tears to both of them. She moves to the door, everyone bowing as she leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Good night... my son.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anne! You look -- Remembering himself, he bows deeply.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My Queen...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes his hand, not caring who is watching.</context>
      <utterance>D'Artagnan.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have never seen a sight more beautiful than you, tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves off, toward her room. D'Artagnan enters the ballroom.</context>
      <utterance>We have much to discuss. Tomorrow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long has the King been back?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some while, Captain.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He didn't pass my doorway, I was in my room.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Artagnan stands and thinks; his mind begins to spin.</context>
      <utterance>He must've, Captain, there is no other way here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Continue.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sire, we have an emergency -- of security. I must ask you to accompany me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... The ball... Continue.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phillippe stands, and follows d'Artagnan from the ball.</context>
      <utterance>I must insist, Sire.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The only one they can see it d'Artagnan. They all look at each other, in the small circle of light from the lantern.</context>
      <utterance>My friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phillippe steps out of the darkness; his eyes are full of shame and failure as he looks at Athos, but still he holds on, trying to maintain the charade that he is Louis.</context>
      <utterance>Only we four, the most trusted Musketeers, knew about the passages, meant to keep the King safe... Your Majesty...</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes...? Why do you bring me here, d'Artagnan?</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He means Phillippe.</context>
      <utterance>The King! Look! It's the King!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Porthos turns and looks at Louis -- then reacts as if he's totally surprised at the presence of this man tied up and gagged beside him.</context>
      <utterance>Then who is that lying beside you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Athos grabs d'Artagnan's arm.</context>
      <utterance>Wh-- ? Where did he come from?</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you ever loved me -- if you ever loved honor, or anything else -- then stand now, and let it happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Artagnan takes his dagger and cuts the ropes that bind Louis' hands, and the gag that has kept him from talking. Aramis suddenly backhands Louis, knocking him flat on his back in the boat, and pointing to him -- Louis.</context>
      <utterance>I cannot, Athos. Dearly as I love you, I cannot.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis struggles upright.</context>
      <utterance>This man is an impostor. We caught him trying to impersonate the King, and were just getting rid of him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>D'Artagnan, arrest them all!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis slaps Louis again, and pleads with his eyes that d'Artagnan accept their ruse. D'Artagnan is dying inside.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up, knave!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seeing they are about to be arrested, the old Musketeers in the boat spring into action against their younger counterparts. Athos swats one swordsman with an oar; Porthos seizes the guard who has grabbed a hold of the boat and flings the man back into two of his comrades; Aramis grabs Louis by the hair and puts his dagger to his throat.</context>
      <utterance>Before I came here, I insisted the King come with me. The real Louis would never have let me insist.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pull them back, d'Artagnan.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pull them back!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone back.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phillippe obeys.</context>
      <utterance>Phillippe, get into the boat. Into the boat! Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Artagnan nods to his men, and they open the iron gate leading out to the river. The boat makes for the opening. Just as it is about to reach it, Louis forces Aramis' hand.</context>
      <utterance>Open the gate.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kicks at the boat and struggles to stand, making the boat tip wildly and throwing everyone in it all around. Aramis draws the dagger away from Louis' throat to keep from killing him, and d'Artagnan makes a grab at Louis and drags him onto the stone floor of the channel. The boat is almost through the opening -- and Louis snatches at his brother, Phillippe. The current outside the gate is rushing by, and the boat is already caught in the current; it's pulling away and the Musketeers can't stop it. Athos seizes Phillippe's legs and tries to hold him, but the pressure of the current is great, and now not only Louis but some of the young Musketeers are helping hold Phillippe. Phillippe's legs slip out of Athos' grasp, and the boat flashes downriver... Aramis, Porthos and Athos have escaped... but Phillippe is captured, looking into the hate-filled eyes of his twin brother Louis.</context>
      <utterance>You will not shed royal blood!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seal them all, every one!</context>
      <utterance>I want all these passages sealed! Another stupid idea of my father's!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It shall be done, your Majesty.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even the bedchamber passages! Let none remain!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They reach a doorway, and the King bangs through it, into his own bedchamber, still spouting anger.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, your Majesty.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was told this impostor was dead!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... You knew you had a double?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Artagnan is frozen in surprise. Phillippe and his guards move into the room; seeing him in full light, wearing Louis' own clothes, fans Louis' anger; he jumps forward and begins ripping the royal garments off Phillippe. D'Artagnan forces himself between Louis and Phillippe.</context>
      <utterance>He is my brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I -- I thought he was but... an impostor who resembled --</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Until now.</context>
      <utterance>My twin. Which has kept him alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They whirl to see the Queen Mother, who has entered through the main door. She hurries to the space between her sons, hugging Phillippe, then trying to hug Louis.</context>
      <utterance>No!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Louis, please -- !</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He motions to the young Musketeers to restrain her; reluctantly they grip the arms of the Queen Mother.</context>
      <utterance>My guards are useless! Take her from me!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What had you to do with this, Mother?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is your brother!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis draws a sword from the scabbard of one of the young Musketeers -- but d'Artagnan steps between him and Phillippe.</context>
      <utterance>He is nothing now.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your Majesty... This man before you... He is royal blood, the same as you. To spill it is the one thing even you cannot do. It is against the laws of God, and of France.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get out of my way.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not once have I ever asked anything for myself. I ask now. Forgive this man, this prisoner... your brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forgive?!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Forgive them.</context>
      <utterance>Aramis, Porthos and Athos too. I know what they have done was a threat against you -- and yet that threat has been removed, with no harm coming to your Majesty. If their passions were in error, their spirits have ever been noble.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Artagnan sinks to his knees before the king.</context>
      <utterance>They have plotted against me! Me! The embodiment of God's will!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The words cut into everyone: Anne, Phillippe, the young Musketeers. But Louis' eyes are cold, as he responds --</context>
      <utterance>Your Majesty... Every day of your life, I have watched over you. No angel could have stood a more faithful vigil. I have bled for you, and have prayed, every day, to see you become greater than your office, better than the law. Show me now what my faith and blood have purchased. Show mercy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You take the side of traitors?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phillippe's plea makes Louis pause... then smile.</context>
      <utterance>Please, may I speak? M'lord... I beg that you kill me. I release you, before Almighty God, from any claim of sin in taking my life. In fact I will pray that God reward you for your mercy to do it. But do not -- I beg you -- return me to the prison, where I have lived so long.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>D'Artagnan, you will hunt down Aramis, Porthos and Athos, and bring me their heads, or I will have yours. And as for you, Phillippe... Back to the prison you shall go, and into the mask you hate.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Louis! No!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anne screams, and Louis waves to the guards, who draw her from the room, as d'Artagnan sags, on his knees before the King he has served so faithfully. Slowly, Phillippe lowers his head.</context>
      <utterance>Wear it until you love it. And die in it!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is Michelle?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to the window. Louis shoves open the drapes and leaps back in horror. Michelle has hanged herself outside Louis' window, the golden bunting of her bed tied as a noose around her neck.</context>
      <utterance>There.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There were two. Not one. But two.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I couldn't tell you. You had enough to carry.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her. She drinks in his love. Then he stands and moves to the door. He looks back, then stares out.</context>
      <utterance>Anne... The night we had together... I always wanted more. But that one, it was enough. Enough to make me love you forever. I want you to remember that... and go on. As strong as you are now. No matter what happens.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks back once more; he seems to want to tell her something; but whatever it is, he can't find the words, and with a last loving look at her, he walks away.</context>
      <utterance>D'Artagnan -- ?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BLACKSMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Soldiers, swords drawn, appear in the doorway behind them.</context>
      <utterance>Pay me quick, I want out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What --</utterance>
   <speaker>BASTILLE JAILER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Understanding, the blacksmith raises his hammer toward the soldiers; but he is stabbed in the back by the jailer, and the soldiers skewer the two guards who helped him. A soldier lifts the jeweled key from the hand of a dead guard.</context>
      <utterance>You saw the prisoner's face.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now. Where is d'Artagnan?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out directing the search for the traitors.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Lieutenant bows. Louis smiles, and fingers the key.</context>
      <utterance>When he returns, watch him. When he leaves again, you tell me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bloody hell...</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't... stay here. That traitor d'Artagnan... knows about this place.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we eat... before we go? This excitement's given me an appetite.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Porthos hauls himself to his feet and turns up the wick of the lantern. The rising light reveals a note, stuck to the cupboard with the blade of a dagger.</context>
      <utterance>Bread and wine... in that cupboard.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He removes the note, and reads...</context>
      <utterance>A note. Pinned with a dagger, like the old days.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Phillippe has been removed to the Bastille, to the lower dungeon. At midnight tonight I will order the guard changed, and will delay the replacements for ten minutes. That should give you ample time. Never have I needed more to say: One for all, and all for one. D'Artagnan."</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He lures us to capture.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He seeks redemption.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a fool!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps. But of d'Artagnan I am certain. What he did tonight was what he told us all along he would do -- be faithful to his King.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what has changed?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps he serves a different king.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What choice is there? If Phillippe is in the Bastille, then to the Bastille we will go.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are right. But it is a trap.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what? I'd rather die covered in blood, than an old man, lying in my own piss.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then to the Bastille.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To the Bastille. And death.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It worked!</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis shushes them, and leads them into another quiet corridor. They hear the distant bells of a church, then suddenly they must scramble, as a platoon of guards carrying torches troop up stairs into the corridor; the Musketeers dart like rats into dark nooks; as the guards pass, the Musketeers huddle, and the bells end their tolling.</context>
      <utterance>It's a prison, you idiot! They don't expect anyone to try getting in! The problem will come when we want out!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They press on, deeper into the Bastille.</context>
      <utterance>Midnight! We have ten minutes!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Phillippe...?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They open the door and release him -- from the cell, but not from the mask. He tries to hug Athos. They head back the way they came.</context>
      <utterance>How did you --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They take cover on either side of the corridor, and lift their swords. It's a man coming down the stairs, with a hooded lantern... they raise their swords to strike --</context>
      <utterance>Someone's coming!</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>D'Artagnan!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The way is blocked above. The Captain of the Bastille has turned back from the mission I sent him on, and is in the courtyard with a party of men.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He lies. He is here to trap us.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Porthos climbs the stairs to check; D'Artagnan looks at Phillippe, in the mask.</context>
      <utterance>I came to see you safely out. Check for yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Athos spits on the floor, in derision. But Porthos comes barreling back down the stairway.</context>
      <utterance>All you have suffered, I would gladly have borne myself, to keep it from you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>D'Artagnan is right, the courtyard is filling with soldiers!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leads them quickly down a side corridor; the others have no choice but to follow.</context>
      <utterance>This way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Once you are through, don't stop until you reach the river.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They will know you helped us, if we go this way.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They open the door... and as they do they see Louis and his platoon of young Musketeers arriving outside.</context>
      <utterance>That doesn't matter now.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There! Stop them!</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The young Musketeers serving the King jump from their horses and grab for the door; but d'Artagnan leaps forward, his sword flashing. After a second of surprise, Athos, Aramis and Porthos jump forward too, and there is a brief, bloody skirmish at the door. But the young Musketeers have overwhelming numbers, and firearms too; protecting Phillippe, the old Musketeers draw back inside and succeed at pulling the door shut and latching it quickly.</context>
      <utterance>Betrayed!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They race back up the corridor -- the four Musketeers, and Phillippe, in the iron mask -- and turn the corner. They reach another inner door, pass through it -- and see the soldiers of the Bastille coming at them.</context>
      <utterance>Back the way we came!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They retreat, and Porthos slams the second door. Like all the inner doors of the Bastille, it's heavy wood, a foot thick, and Porthos seals it with a huger iron bar. But there's nowhere else to run.</context>
      <utterance>Back!</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the far end of the corridor, the King's young Musketeers have the same keys to the outer door that d'Artagnan did, and they are breaking through. Louis and two dozen of his personal bodyguard pour through the door.</context>
      <utterance>Trapped.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The young Musketeers obediently charge down the corridor. Stepping up shoulder to shoulder -- Aramis, d'Artagnan, Athos, Porthos -- the four veteran Musketeers meet the charge, first with pistols, then with swords, a wall between Louis' men and Phillippe. The battle in the cramped confines of the corridor is bloody and fierce; the young attackers can only get a few men into the fight at any one time, and those who step before the famous veterans are cut down. Louis' young Musketeers retreat, to regroup.</context>
      <utterance>Charge them!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cowards! Twenty run from four?!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis is disgusted by this loyalty -- and he has a solution.</context>
      <utterance>The corridor nullifies our number... And no one has stomach to fight the Captain.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>D'Artagnan!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LOUIS' VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The words bounce down the long corridor; then silence. D'Artagnan stands holding his sword, staring away from his friends, toward the King and his gang of young Musketeers.</context>
      <utterance>I am not angry with you. I knew you would lead me to them, and so you have! Lay down your sword, and I will not punish you! I will let you retire in peace -- to live out your days in the countryside! And I will give your friends a swift execution, if you surrender now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>D'Artagnan. Perhaps you should accept his offer, for we are dead anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Athos says nothing; but when d'Artagnan looks at him, he lowers his eyes in shame for ever having doubted d'Artagnan's loyalty and friendship. Phillippe speaks up, from behind the Iron Mask.</context>
      <utterance>He is right, d'Artagnan.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait. Bargain me to Louis, for all your lives. You have done your best. Let me go, and let all of you find peace.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This hits them like a bombshell -- and suddenly it all makes sense; d'Artagnan's loyalty to Louis, his dogged hope that he could somehow influence him toward goodness. We see their stunned faces, each in turn: Athos, Aramis, Porthos, and Phillippe.</context>
      <utterance>No. Even if I could give up my friends, I could never give up my son.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Artagnan and Phillippe embrace, lost father to lost son. From the heavily barred door to their rear comes a powerful pounding; the Bastille's soldiers are trying to break it down. Time is running out. Aramis looks back down the corridor toward the door to the outside, barred now by Louis and his young guards, their long muskets bristling like spikes; and yet that way is the only possible hope for escape to the outside.</context>
      <utterance>I never had any idea you existed... until they found you. And in all that time, I never had a moment's pride as a father -- until now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Why don't we charge them?</context>
      <utterance>D'Artagnan... Those are young Musketeers down there. They have been weaned on our legends. They revere us -- it is an advantage.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He draws his sword and points it into the air. Aramis lifts the tip of his sword to join that of d'Artagnan. Porthos does too... and then Athos joins them.</context>
      <utterance>I trained those men myself. They will stand and fight. But if we are to die, let it be this way.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One for all. All for one.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Artagnan gives Phillippe a dagger. They look at each other. Then d'Artagnan begins to scream. The others take up the shout. Then they step around the corner, and charge.</context>
      <utterance>If I could have a blade, then I would be please to run with you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Magnificent valor...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis grabs a musket from one of the reluctant soldiers and fires: SSSBOOM! With the first explosion of gunfire the others pull their triggers; the powder in their weapons flashes and crashes... The musket balls fly down the hallway, sparking off the stone walls and floor, ricocheting, punching holes through the capes and flesh... but still the Musketeers charge like the young men they once were -- still are, in spirit. In the confines of the Bastille's stone corridor the noise is deafening, and the space in front of the guards is filled with the dense gray smoke of the gunpowder. None of them can see anything beyond it... and all is quiet.</context>
      <utterance>Shoot them! Shoot them!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The King's Guards draw their swords, and wait; are all the old Musketeers dead? Slowly the figures emerge from the smoke -- in SLOW MOTION, walking now, no need to run. All are wounded, but all are still alive. The Four Musketeers, along with Phillippe, move slowly and steadily toward the blades of the young Guards; a fight to the death? So be it. But the young Lieutenant will have none of it; as one of his men lifts a sword to plunge it into the chest of d'Artagnan, the young Lieutenant bats the sword down, with his own.</context>
      <utterance>Draw blades!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps forward toward d'Artagnan; but instead of thrusting his sword he salutes with it. His men follow suit, saluting and bowing to the courage of these men they have grown up wanting to follow. King Louis, for the moment, is frozen. D'Artagnan looks back at Phillippe; he has bullet holes in two different places at the edges of his clothes, but he is unwounded. Then d'Artagnan sees Louis, with his long dagger, leaping at Phillippe.</context>
      <utterance>Stop!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Phillippe!</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louis bounces off the wall and thrusts back again, driving the blade into d'Artagnan's back. D'Artagnan's face jolts; he staggers, his legs buckle. D'Artagnan falls into the arms of his friends. Louis stands holding his bloody dagger, everyone staring at him: d'Artagnan, the old Musketeers, the young ones.</context>
      <utterance>I am unhurt --</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaps into Louis, overwhelming him in fury, wrenching the dagger from his brother's hand and gripping his throat.</context>
      <utterance>You! Vicious... evil...!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phillippe releases Louis, who falls, choking, gasping. Lieutenant Andre is surprised by what he just heard.</context>
      <utterance>Phillippe...! No... Don't... He is your brother!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phillippe darts to d'Artagnan, being cradled by Athos; Athos lifts a hand from d'Artagnan's back; it is drenched in blood. D'Artagnan is dying. Athos, Aramis, Porthos... none of them can speak. They grip d'Artagnan, as if through their will alone they could keep his life from leaking away. The young Musketeers stand transfixed, watching their legendary Captain die. Phillippe sags; his voice from behind the iron mask is torn by grief.</context>
      <utterance>Brother...?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All this time... I was a lost secret. But you were hiding all your loyalty, all your love. You were the Man in the Iron Mask.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>D'Artagnan...</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ARTAGNAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phillippe rises with a slow, terrible resolve, and moves to Louis. When Louis tries to rise to his feet he finds the blade of the young Lieutenant Andre pointed at his chest.</context>
      <utterance>Shhh. All my life, this is the death I have wanted. To die among you. One for all... and all for... He is gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to d'Artagnan. Phillippe rips away the key that dangles around Louis' neck.</context>
      <utterance>All my life, all I ever wanted to be... was him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have recaptured the prisoner.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN THE IRON MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A blow in his chest from the Lieutenant stuns the prisoner and drops him to his knees. The King orders the BASTILLE</context>
      <utterance>No, no! I am your --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will put this madman where no one can hear his insanity. Let him be fed by a deaf mute. But feed him well, and let him have a long life within the Iron Mask.</utterance>
   <speaker>BASTILLE GOVERNOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He means Aramis, Porthos, and Athos.</context>
      <utterance>And them?</utterance>
   <speaker>KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They are my loyal servants.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN THE IRON MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the guards are dragging him to the deepest, darkest dungeon of the Bastille.</context>
      <utterance>No! No...!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ARAMIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Athos moves up between Aramis and Porthos, and links them with his arms.</context>
      <utterance>Amen.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATHOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aramis and Porthos move off together, to walk the lane of elms; Athos remains by the grave, unable to leave. Phillippe pats Anne's arm.</context>
      <utterance>He was the best of us all.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She too moves down the lane of trees, touching the tip of the rose pedals to her lips as the tears run down her face. Phillippe moves up to Athos.</context>
      <utterance>I will be with you in a moment, Mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILLIPPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Athos can't speak; he can only nod yes. Phillippe moves to join his mother, leaving Athos to take one final look down at the grave. Then as Athos moves off to join Aramis and Porthos, we PAN from the name "D'ARTAGNAN" on the stone, to the pattern chiseled beneath the name. It is a mask, of iron.</context>
      <utterance>After all you have done, I must ask you one more service to your king. I have lost my father. And you have lost your son. Let me love you like a son to a father. And I pray you live for this, to love me like your son.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
