<movie id="370" title="Man Trouble">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LEWIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spruance, would you like to show me where it's marked smearing here...  ... because I swear, I don't see it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. I didn't know I was.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEWIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Also, I'd be mildly content if I could have a little less delirious self-appreciation and some small regard for remaining somewhere in the vicinity of the goddamned note.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wasn't smearing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sssh, come on now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>incredibly pricklike...</context>
      <utterance>No, I'm telling you, this is personally motivated. Since I moved out he's been doing this, making remarks and being...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEWIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, if our lovely soprano would like to stop grumbling for a moment, I'd like to take it once again.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See what I mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEWIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pardon me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said fine, let's do it again.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEWIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He signals a down beat and they resume somewhere near the top of the duet.</context>
      <utterance>From the beginning please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>THERAPIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns her gaze to EUGENE EARL AXLINE, alias HARRY BLISS. He sits in an adjacent chair, an abject hostage. Discomforted by her flinty stare, he glances away, to the window where the faint sounds of the CHORAL REHEARSAL can be heard.</context>
      <utterance>Now I want you to look at Harry and tell him how you feel.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry shakes his head, shifting about uncomfortably.</context>
      <utterance>I feel like he's not plugged into my needs, and I'm not getting enough positive feedback...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, look at him shaking his head.</utterance>
   <speaker>THERAPIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, let's see what he wants to say here. Harry, how do you feel when she brings out this material?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do I feel? I feel she just overheats on every little side issue, and when I go to try and communicate with the woman, for some unknown reason she doesn't believe a damn thing I say.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh that's a lie.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See what I mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you know what this whole thing hinges from? He came to rent a building from me which is now his place of business...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what, he's not interested in that, that's not what he's asking.  See what she does? She wants to dig up and haul out miscellaneous things that's got nothing to do with this. I mean, I agreed to come here, okay, but I have to tell you, Iwo Jima's got a lot of faulty notions in her head about me that....</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, there. Right now. That's another thing I want to interject...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pardon me, I was making a statement here.</utterance>
   <speaker>THERAPIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, let's try and hear each other out if we can. Go on, Harry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I forgot the upshot of what I was saying, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, this syndrome where I've asked him to address me by my given name and he just goes on ignoring my wishes.</utterance>
   <speaker>THERAPIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright. Look at him and really tell him how you feel about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want you to ever call me Iwo Jima again!</utterance>
   <speaker>THERAPIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry begrudges a slight nod.</context>
      <utterance>That's a legitimate request, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you can't call me Adele, don't call me anything at all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THERAPIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So? Can you look at Iwo Jima, Harry, and tell her... She darts a confused frown at the Therapist.</utterance>
   <speaker>THERAPIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reluctantly, he reaches over and takes her hand, mumbling something which though indistinct, causes Adele's features to pucker with emotion and brings her to the edge of tears.</context>
      <utterance>Better yet, can you take her by the hand and say, 'I hear what you're saying'?</utterance>
   <speaker>THERAPIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. That's good... because there's a lot of love here, isn't there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Next time I want to bring out some of our sexual hot spots.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hell you are, honey.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hell I'm not.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... at fifty bucks a shot, out a my pocket...  I'm going to listen to some pencil-necked butthead tell me I don't know how to relate to you...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Daddy, do you want this marriage to work or not.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hear you, honey. But let's have just a little more trust on your end of this thing, okay? That's all I ask.  Get in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MELVENOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure nothing of value has been removed from the dwelling?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, nothing. That's what's so disturbing. I mean, why would someone do something like this...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MELVENOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you have quite a nice little mess here.  It kinda looks like somebody doesn't like you, doesn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Fingerprinter interrupts:</context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, somebody doesn't like me?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINGERPRINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not much on the window. A few partials and a bunch of smears.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVENOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he moves to the hallway leading to the bedroom:</context>
      <utterance>Check out the bedroom.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think this is someone I know?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVENOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's explore that. Have you had any recent trouble with anyone?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helen hobbles INTO VIEW, seating herself in a nearby chair.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MELVENOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now thoroughly paranoid, she frowns down at the carpet, scanning her memory for the commission of some past offense.</context>
      <utterance>Anyone whose displeasure you might've incurred in some way?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVENOS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For instance, just the other day we had a homicide concerning a dispute over a parking space.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who could it be?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVENOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her mind is still off searching for enemies and she fails to respond:</context>
      <utterance>You're not married, I take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's in the process of a divorce.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVENOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about him?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about him? He's our conductor, he's an artist and not someone who'd ever...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean Lewie? He'd never do anything like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVENOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a light knock at the partially opened front door.</context>
      <utterance>You never know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello? Anybody home?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Joanie...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh great.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just got in from Hawaii and thought I'd drop by for a minute.  What the heck happened in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, it's my sister...</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVENOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Joan gets up and moves over to Andy, he glances at his watch and exits to the bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>Uhm hmm.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andy, this is not the most opportune time. I happen to have had a burglary in here last night...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh really? That's awful.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So could I just call you later?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, can't you give me one minute? I'd like to know if you got the manuscript I sent you.  Who's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Helen Dextra, you've met her before.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I have?  Anyway, did you read it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Read what? I don't know what you're talking about.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm talking about the book I've written about Red and me, that I sent you a copy of, is that so hard to follow?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no. You've written a book about Red Layls.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not just about him, Joanie, he's only one of many episodes in my life, you know that. Have you got a Perrier?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I don't. Let me just call you at home later.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Melvenos and the Fingerprinter re-enter:</context>
      <utterance>I'm not going to be home. I'm checking into a hospital to have a bone spur removed from my foot. Then I'm going to New York, to meet with a top publisher...  ... which, incidentally, I would not care for Mr. Redmon, fecal- face Layls to know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MELVENOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I might put some bars on the windows.  My name's Melveny, if you want to get in touch.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really though, I don't see how this could be somebody I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVENOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start down the hallway and Joan addresses their backs:</context>
      <utterance>Maybe not.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I actually go miles out of my way to avoid conflictual situations.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And to top it off, my lawyer said, 'Don't worry, they're just pissing into the wind...'</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some help I'm going to get from him, because he's scared to death of Red.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andy, are you telling me the truth?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, he's afraid, they're all afraid, they're all off skiing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Speaking of lawyers...  One fell on me while I was sunbathing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, are you really going to New York?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I'm going to New York, where I intend to remain in semi-private seclusion, at an undisclosed...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well maybe I could stay at your house while you're gone. So could you tell your housekeeper to...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, I just want you to hear what this colosal shit said about me, through his great white shark of a lawyer.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pardon me, but I don't care what he said. My apartment, as you can see, is a complete shambles, I have a terrible headache, I've been informed that somebody doesn't like me, and I really don't want to stay here by myself!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joan sinks down into a chair, exhausted:</context>
      <utterance>Fine, why don't you take my house then?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gee whiz, why make such a big deal out of everything?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now don't start lazing around, June. Let's get with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sits down at his desk and begins going through his drawers, looking for something. She lowers the paper and looks over at him:</context>
      <utterance>You get with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you like my hair this way, or do you like it straight?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes back to reading.</context>
      <utterance>It's very nice, Sluggo. Go hose out the kennel.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The PHONE on his desk begins to RING:</context>
      <utterance>Where the hell are my nail clippers?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told everybody to stay out of these drawers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JUNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I'll go down to the Amazon, and get involved with the trees.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets up and moves over to the desk:</context>
      <utterance>Get this first, will you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They need people, because that hole is getting...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She picks up the receiver and speaks into it:</context>
      <utterance>Remember, don't say I'm here 'til you find out who it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hangs up.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah?... I doubt that he's here at this present time... Yeah, maybe later today sometime... Who are you addressing? Uh, the executive kennel maid... uh-huh. Yeah. Okay, I'll tell him... So long.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Who was it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ferde at something Motors. He wants two payments by tomorrow or he's gonna come an' repop the van.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes back to reading. June returns to the bench, lies down again and starts grumbling:</context>
      <utterance>Bastard.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, you said you were going to get me a little Honda Elite to tool around in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't give me a bad time, lard. I've got enough trouble with Iwo Jima and her complaints, alright? Now the woman doesn't even believe you're my niece.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm not.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly irritated, he begins fumbling through a pile of bills on top of the desk:</context>
      <utterance>That's not the point I'm making.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what's gonna happen if I can't pay these damn breeders and get some adult dogs on the premises? Pretty damn quick, some asses are going to hit the pavement, believe me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So? I'm sick of dog turds anyway. He scowls at her, then looks out the window:</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He catches sight of something outside:</context>
      <utterance>Jesus, here I am, sitting in the center of a lot of wealth, the escalation in crime couldn't be better, and I'm not turning a damn nickel on it...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh shit. There's Lee.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Low-Rider comes to a stop. Joan approaches the pas- senger window and leans down to Socorro:</context>
      <utterance>Socorro!! Wait a minute! I want to talk to you!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, Socorro, but do you mind if I ask what's happening, why are you leaving?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOCORRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No se, lo siento.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm asking, where-are-you-going?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOCORRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Esto me yerno, Balthazar. You speak please Balto para mi.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, what's going on, are you bringing her back later or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BALTO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Monday I bring her back.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monday? But this is Thursday, I can't stay here alone 'til Monday.</utterance>
   <speaker>BALTO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joan straightens up, sighing angrily and looking up at the house:</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but she got her time off, too, man, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The low-rider moves down the driveway and as it disap- pears onto the street, Joan moves to an electric box atop a metal column at the edge of the driveway. She presses the button and looks at the gates. They remain open. She steps over to the gates and tries to close them manually. The locking device fails to engage and a portion of it falls off into the bushes.</context>
      <utterance>Well, this is just glorious.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the vicinity of the bedroom window, a man in work clothes can be seen pounding on the glass as he continues yelling:</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Andy!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She calls loudly out to him:</context>
      <utterance>It's Butch! Get your ass in gear and say hello to your old drinking buddy!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves to the glass facade and peers inside, looking for the source of the voice:</context>
      <utterance>Andy's not here!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, who are you, honey?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's out of town, and there happens to be several other people in here trying to sleep, so...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whyn't you come out and say hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you please go away!?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, stick your head out the door an' let's see what you look like.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, but if you don't leave, I'm going to call the Foothill Patrol.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He cups a hand over his crotch and, sticking his tongue out, flicks it in an obscene manner across his lips.</context>
      <utterance>Well, fuck you, honey.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tch, where does she find these people.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans down, picks up a dirt clod from the flower bed and throws it toward the window:</context>
      <utterance>I was just trying to be nice.  Go ahead an' call 'em, bitch, I don't give a shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll just come back and kick your ass in for you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes hold of the dog's muzzle, lifting the lips to reveal the large scimitar-like canines:</context>
      <utterance>Now, in regard to any aggressor seeking to give you a bad time, I want to show you what you can expect from a dog of this caliber.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here we have the dog's arsenal, so to speak. The animal is trained to apply pressure to specific points of the body until the bone is more or less crushed.  If the attacker is bearing a weapon of any kind, be it a gun, a club, a knife or what-have-you, the dog will, excuse me for saying...  ... automatically go for the testicles.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh god, what if I don't want him to do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want him to do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I just want him to scare someone.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Believe me, this will scare them, as well as incapacitate their mind and any ability to maneuver against you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I have an extremely sensitive reaction to dog dander, so maybe I shouldn't...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me ask you something. I like to get a general picture of the individual situation I'm working with.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you married, single, living alone or with some other party?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm in the process of a divorce and I moved up here because my apartment was burglarized and...  But I'm not entirely alone, there's a housekeeper here, and several friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, the hills are hit heaven as far as burglaries go. And right up on Mulholland is where they found the fifth victim of the Westside Slasher...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, please, don't tell me about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Believe me, I know what you're up against, being an attractive, and I take it, unattached woman, such as you are...  But we're going to remedy that situation right now, and get you to feeling as safe as a little baby, alright?  What've we got there so far?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ober, platz, geh am platz, bringen, komm, sitz, fuss', fahrt and blieb.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He scans the grounds for signs of something we as yet know nothing of:</context>
      <utterance>Well, that's enough for a start on the basic control commands...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now let's do a little work with the assailant.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright now, Joan, give him the command, 'Duke, wachen sie.'</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Duke, wachen sie.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they walk, Harry glances about, impressed with the appearance of wealth inherent in the house and grounds:</context>
      <utterance>Good. The dog is now on alert.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is really a nice piece of real estate you've got here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not mine, it's my sister's.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, it's your sister's.  And where's she?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I doing this right? Shouldn't I be prepared for something?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never look at your dog.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They move forward a few feet, when Harry, now slightly behind Joan, makes a covert hand signal in the direction of some trees several yards ahead of them. June, in a padded attack suit, suddenly jumps out from behind the trees, assuming an aggressive stance and emitting a repertory of menacing sounds.</context>
      <utterance>Never look at your dog? Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seeing the dog still in pursuit, June ignores the command and as Duke continues to tow Joan behind him:</context>
      <utterance>Dammit, June, don't exhibit fear until I tell you!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get him under control now, Joan.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am...  Good boy, be nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give him the off command!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hurries up behind her, grabbing her around the waist to anchor her and addressing the dog:</context>
      <utterance>I forgot it! You tell him! Duke, stop!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dog instantly assumes a sitting position. Joan, out of breath and exhilarated with fear and excitement, turns to Harry:</context>
      <utterance>Duke, aus!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My golly, that was incredible. I love this dog. Did you see that? I can't believe how strong he is. I felt like a rag doll...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did I tell you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lays the pen aside, studying him with evident interest as he looks at a photograph of Andy and a man on a hunting safari in Africa.</context>
      <utterance>Ordinarily I wouldn't do this, even on a temporary rental basis, because he's the absolute top security and attack dog in the country.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this your sister?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, that's her, with her third husband, Eric Ellerman.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uhm hmm.  Wait a minute, who's this guy, isn't this Red Layls?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No kidding. Your sister's involved with Red Layls? This guy's gotta be one of the five or ten richest men in the country, with business connections all over the place.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans in close to a photograph of Andy in a bikini.</context>
      <utterance>And she's your sister. That's amazing. I mean, this is an individual I'd really like to meet sometime.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, look at that figure. I have to say, your sister is really an attractive looking woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'll have to pass it on.</context>
      <utterance>Well, that's quite a compliment.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll skip back up in a day or two, okay, just to see how you're doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Joan, I want you to know, it's been a great pleasure doing business with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh well...  ... thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anytime of the night or day, 24 hours.</context>
      <utterance>Feel free to call on me for anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she gestures toward June, Harry takes hold of her hand, looking earnestly at her:</context>
      <utterance>And would you also thank your...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I sincerely mean that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You big flirt.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps past her and goes to the van:</context>
      <utterance>Come on, dumpty, don't start that.  This is quality clientele. It calls for a certain kind of approach.  Just soak some of this in, will you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he opens the back panel:</context>
      <utterance>Soak this.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Start to pattern yourself. Breed up.  Observe the woman, for Christ sakes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He closes the back panel and as he moves past her:</context>
      <utterance>Oh screw her.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't screw this type of individual.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On his way to the driver's door:</context>
      <utterance>You would.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the kind of atmosphere we want to gravitate toward.  Did she even ask me the cost?  Dammit, I really respect that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I don't, he isn't even your dog.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HER POV OF LEWIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As he addresses the sopranos over their voices.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEWIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is supposed to sound virginal, ladies, so let's try to fake it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to see Joan approaching with a paper cup filled with water.</context>
      <utterance>Don't do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't do what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not supposed to look him straight in the eye.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have a dog you can't look in the eye, Joan?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not just a dog. He's a Schutzhund trained attack dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps back from the dog as Joan leans down to give Duke some water from the cup.</context>
      <utterance>Oh...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was told to avoid a direct gaze and always look at the base of the right or the left ear.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to go to all this trouble, I've offered to stay up at your sister's with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't tell you how mad I am at Lewie, that I have to leave him out here, tied to a tree...</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, you're stubborn, Joan.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pats Duke on the head and stands up:</context>
      <utterance>I'm not stubborn, I'm so accommodating, it's sickening.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you won't tell me what's really bothering you. Why don't you confide in me anymore?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No you don't. Come on, talk to me. Let's go have a drink after rehearsal.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A WOMAN chorus member sticks her head out the stage door:</context>
      <utterance>Tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eddy, you better come, he's rehearsing the tenors!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm coming...!  How about tomorrow night then?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Let's say maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves quickly toward the rehearsal room. Immediately afraid of his displeasure, she calls after him:</context>
      <utterance>Well don't go out of your way, Joan.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before disappearing into the studio, he makes a gesture acknowledging her capitulation.</context>
      <utterance>Eddy? Tomorrow's fine. Okay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'd have to say this place is a snap to break into.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew it. I shouldn't have moved here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves down into the living room, crossing toward one of the couches, with Harry following:</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. The dog'll take care of anyone trying to get inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what to do. Maybe I should move into a motel.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you don't have to do that. This is just some ding-dong that's trying to scare you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sits down.</context>
      <utterance>Well he's succeeded.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you don't want to give off that impression, by acting too timid or afraid, because that's what invites an aggressive attitude from certain types of men.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't invite this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For instance, don't go mincing along, taking mousey little steps, and waving your hanky, because you're drawing a target on yourself if you do...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I do that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, let's see. Just walk back and forth the way you normally do.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She attempts a few steps then stops abruptly:</context>
      <utterance>Well I don't normally walk back and forth, but... okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, I can't do it with you watching me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, but keep in mind that you want to exhibit a very confident attitude. Look like you know what you're doing and where you're going.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uhm-hmm.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just remember to stop short of appearing a little dykey, because that's not attractive.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I thought that's your point, no to attract...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, you always want to remain a little bit attractive. Otherwise that can set somone off too.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves back to the couch and sits down.</context>
      <utterance>This is just impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just can't win.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure you can, it's just a matter of degree.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dropping her head into her hands.</context>
      <utterance>Well darn it, I give up...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-oh.  Now what's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sits down next to her:</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry but this is really getting to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell you what. Let me take you out of here, buy you a drink, and see if we can't get your mind off these kind of things.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'd like to do that.</context>
      <utterance>That's very sweet of you, Harry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long have you been divorced?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'd say seven or eight years, around there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lifts her glass, takes a sip, then sets it back down:</context>
      <utterance>And so you like, well, assuming you live a single existence, I mean most men don't seem to enjoy that, I've read.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to tell you the truth...  I've been observing your hands, and I have to use the word exquisite.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? Well...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're probably quite a singer too.  I'd like to come down and catch you sometime.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, anytime. Do you like Classical music?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thinking he is revealing a peculiar brand of wit, she laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Very much. Even to the degree that when it's playing on the radio, I sometimes have to turn the damn thing off.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just mean it starts to get to me too much. I can't swallow my saliva.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I shouldn't have laughed.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, symphonies, operettas, poems, things like that. All those type of things really get to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A JAPANESE HOSTESS appears at the table, bowing reveren- tially and gesturing that their table is ready.</context>
      <utterance>Uhm hmm.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're full of surprises, Harry, you know that? That you've actually read Dante's Divine Comedy I mean...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it was a while back there that I did, yeah...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods, while Joan, hoping to disguise the extent of her emotions, looks down and begins moving her wine in circles:</context>
      <utterance>You know that part? 'Yet as a wheel moves smoothly, free from jars, My will and my desire were turned by love, The love that moves the sun and other stars.'</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For some reason, the sublimity of that always touches me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>MAN TROUBLE - Rev. 4/22/91 37.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, it's very sad. I look at my sister and all her marriages and affairs, not to mention the mess my own life is in, and I think it's very sad and very bleak that men and women can't manage to be friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They arrive at the fence and as she speaks she rests one of her hands on the railings:</context>
      <utterance>It depends on the man and woman you're talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a tragedy that sex is often such a barrier to friendship between men and women.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He places his hand over hers. She remains silent a moment, restraining her response to the gesture. Then:</context>
      <utterance>There I disagree with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know Dante and Beatrice never slept together.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that right?  Oh yeah, I forgot that part.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, anyway... I shouldn't have had so much wine... because I prefer to go a little slow here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>why not?</context>
      <utterance>We can go as slow as you want...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So...  You think men and women can be friends?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah, absolutely.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The excitement has unleashed Duke's libido and as she tries to resume her mission, he makes a few attempts to rise against her flanks. Just before she approaches the mailbox, he manages to grip his paws around one of her thighs and unmistakably begins to hump her:</context>
      <utterance>Alright now, don't play too rough.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sits, panting, with a furtive expression on his face, watching as she steps over to the mailbox and opens it. She takes out a number of letters and sorts through them as she starts back to the house with Duke following. They are in the main addressed to Andy, but in amongst them she finds a bank statement addressed to her, as well as a letter with her name written in pencil on the envelope. She opens it, takes the contents out and stops suddenly:</context>
      <utterance>No, no, Duke, don't do that, that's not nice. Now sitz. And behave yourself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Lewie. Mad at me.' The CAMERA PERUSES Lewie.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Helen leans her head in close to Joan's:</context>
      <utterance>Doesn't want a divorce. Maybe he's trying to scare me, or punish me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's definitely not Lewie.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not exactly a disinterested party. You're always promoting his cause...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Number one, I've known the man for fifteen years, number two, he... loves you. She glances at Eddy, then consults the list:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What my cup size was.  Steve Jewel! Who's Steve Jewel?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My piano tuner.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he weird or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helen returns to the list, tapping her finger on one of the names:</context>
      <utterance>Well everyone appears weird to me right now. So I put every possible name down, except for one, who happens to be post- burglary.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it's him, the tree surgeon. He sounds very suspicious...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just don't tell Lewie about the phone message or the thing I got in the mail, because he'll just use it to...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I already did.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Helen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LEWIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She regards him suspiciously. He modulates his voice to a more persuasive and intimate tone:</context>
      <utterance>I'm extremely concerned about this situation. I don't want you living alone up there.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEWIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now come on, wouldn't you feel much safer if you moved back into our house?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I wouldn't feel comfortable about doing that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEWIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes hold of her arm and moves her out into the hall:</context>
      <utterance>Come here...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Darn it, Lewie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>LEWIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Are you afraid of your responses to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tch...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEWIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you resisting?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are very upsetting, really shitty circumstances I'm dealing with and I...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEWIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know how hard all this has been on me? Do you think it's that easy for me to admit I want you back?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Couldn't you spare yourself then?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEWIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rolls her eyes, sighing impatiently.</context>
      <utterance>Are you seeing anybody? Just tell me that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEWIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, you're not the abstinent type.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, don't judge me by your scrotal excesses, Lewie.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEWIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you're seeing somebody.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you spying on me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEWIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on. Be open about it.  Who is it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls back, narrowing his eyes at her:</context>
      <utterance>Alright, I am seeing someone, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEWIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe you. Who is it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I hate to mention this but we're having a slight problem with Duke.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well...  He keeps getting up and trying to ride on one's extremities.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh don't worry about that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Especially Socorro, who can't speak English, let alone German, and sometimes she has to go pulling him from room to room like a vacuum cleaner.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He places his arm on the couch behind her:</context>
      <utterance>No, that's just normal in most of your adult males. Some percentage of the time they're gonna attempt to make these vulgar motions on your person.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>In the sky beyond the hills a helicopter beams its light.</context>
      <utterance>You just have to be very firm and stay on top of him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not affecting you too much, is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's very nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Chopin, a nocturne.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what's affecting me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Night-piece, it means.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches over and runs his hand slowly down her back.</context>
      <utterance>You are.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I should say something.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the problem though, I want to be honest with you...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans over and kisses her. After a moment she breaks off:</context>
      <utterance>There's no problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I recently realized something about myself. That I've slept with a number of men in my life just because I didn't want them not to like me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uhm hmm.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But the thing is, I didn't like most of them that much, so why did I care whether they liked me or not?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I'm not one of these guys who's going to look upon you as an object.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I know, that's not what I'm saying...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I look upon a woman as a whole.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I'm saying is I don't know if right now I might not go to bed with you because I don't want to be alone, so I thought maybe we... could try to explore other modes, or...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Other modes?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, there are other ways of being intimate, that people don't even realize.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uhm hmm.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which doesn't mean I'm not attracted to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you don't want me to bring you around.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pardon me?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her once more. Her response, is far less tentative. As it begins to border on the ardent, she breaks off again:</context>
      <utterance>Other modes is fine. You don't have to be shy with me.  I've been asked to do do every kind of thing in the book.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, it's so hard to pioneer in this area... when you keep doing that...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no phone in my room, or cable TV. I've had to sneak into this cell next to me, with some poor lithium zombie lying here like a comatose cabbage...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tries to move closer to the phone, hindered by Harry's weight.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe I better take this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And this is the lengths this assassin is willing to go to suppress me, because he does not want me to have my book.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves off of her and she leans across his torso, pinning him to the bed as she addresses the speaker:</context>
      <utterance>Harry, excuse me, it's my sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INTERCUT BETWEEN Joan and:</context>
      <utterance>Andy... It's Joan.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh you're there. Thank God.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you? Are you in New York?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, that's what I'm telling you. I went into the hospital first, for one day, just to have a simple bone spur...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, you told me that, but where are you now?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... and the next thing I know I'm transported some place the hell else, against my knowledge, while I was completely medicated...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andy, wait a minute...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joan sits up, and in her alarm is unaware that one of her hands grabs hold of a swatch of hair on Harry's chest, causing him to wince:</context>
      <utterance>Do you understand the implications of this, I have no underpants on, and absolutely no recourse to my rights!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God, this is because of Red, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evidencing interest in their exchange, Harry manages to reach to his cigarettes on the night stand.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, it's because of Red, isn't that obvious!?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joan turns to Harry, a stricken look on her face:</context>
      <utterance>And if he and that fuckface lawyer in his paid employ, think they can ... Wait.  I think I hear someone.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What am I supposed to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Find out where she is.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello? Andy? You have to tell me where you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>MAN TROUBLE - Rev. 4/23/91 49.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at the heavily-meshed wires covering the window:</context>
      <utterance>I told you, I don't know where I am, these bastards are very clever.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm in some private cracker box in the boonies, with godammed wires on the windows...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ask her the name of the first hospital.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andy, tell me the name of the hospital you checked yourself into.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mount Haven, it's in the South Bay, and don't ask me these inane questions, just do something...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell her we'll find it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll find it, okay, so don't worry...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hear someone coming, I have to get off.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is cut short by the abrupt sound of the PHONE HANGING UP on the other end. Again, she turns to Harry:</context>
      <utterance>... because I'm sure there's some simple explanation...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What should I do? Should I call the police?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches to an ashtray on the night stand and quickly douses his cigarette:</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's just take a run out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean right now?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told her she shouldn't do this, I mean, to be so maniacally obsessed with this soul of mud that she'd even want to write a book about him, is beyond me...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well the guy must be doing something right to have amassed that amount of wealth.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But she does this, you know, she just periodically drops the entire weight of her life on me like a ton of bricks.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Joan, can I make a suggestion?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, please, anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You better try an keep up a little with the flow or we're gonna get cited.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>A.C.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ellerman, Antonia. She was admitted on the third of the month and was signed out at 3:45 P.M. on the fourth, by her personal physician...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know he was her physician?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell, I could come in here and say I was a doctor an' sign somebody out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And even if he was a doctor, it doesn't mean he was my sister's doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>A.C.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>According to this he was her doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then who was the doctor who operated on her foot?</utterance>
   <speaker>A.C.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's nothing on here about her foot. It says 'observation for clinical depression.'</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a lie. She was in here for an operation, then she was drugged and taken out of here against her will.</utterance>
   <speaker>A.C.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That couldn't possibly happen, we have very strict regulations about...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, let's stop wasting time here, where is this guy, what's his name?</utterance>
   <speaker>A.C.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His name is Dr. Monroe Park.  It doesn't say where he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe this, you mean there's no phone number or address?</utterance>
   <speaker>A.C.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, but I didn't type this file...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of business are you running here, buddy?</utterance>
   <speaker>A.C.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns away from them and back to the computer.</context>
      <utterance>All I can do is give you the data I have on here. If you want to call the Physician's Registry...  There's some public phones over there. He's probably listed with them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How am I supposed to find this man? Maybe he used a false name, or maybe he isn't even a doctor...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got a couple of ideas here. First, we want to try an' connect with Red Layls.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I don't want anything to do with Red, I'm terrified of him.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's nothing to be afraid of, believe me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, you hear all kinds of things, about government kickbacks, and Panamanian drug couriers and...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know these type of guys. You take away their money and their power, and what are they.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops walking and takes a hold of her hand:</context>
      <utterance>No, really, I have to do something. I have to go to the police...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just hold off a bit on that, honey, will you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, that's nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You called me honey.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well that's what you are.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to get a hold of this top private investigator, who's a close, personal friend of mine, okay, and get him to find out who this doctor is.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harry, this isn't your problem and I don't want to draw you into it...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, we're going to find your sister.  Everything's going to turn out fine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, go ahead, I've gotta hear this. Who is it this time?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's not what you think. This is a very unique individual I'm talking about. Plus there's a mind there, as well as a body and a face.</utterance>
   <speaker>VITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't I hear this before, about the hostess at Denny's, that was a college graduate and had a mole like Elizabeth Taylor?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Under the following, June can be seen crossing the street from the House of Bliss and approaching the coffee shop:</context>
      <utterance>I'm telling you, this is something completely different. You gotta meet her. She sings opera and has the hands of a hula dancer...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyway, you remember that private detective that use to come in here all the time? On the portly side, bald, had kind of crossed eyes...</utterance>
   <speaker>VITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Fred, you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that's him. How do you think I could get a hold of him?</utterance>
   <speaker>VITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh gee, I think he's moved out of the area and went into gourmet snacks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're talking to the wrong godammed party, you know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONCRIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it's in your best interest to hear me out.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes note of the driver (STURGE) coming around the front of the car. He stops a few feet off and unbuttons his jacket, revealing the cross-strap of a shoulder holster. Harry steps over to the window, leans down and communicates in more politic tones:</context>
      <utterance>No, you hear me out, friend...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I happen to have a very high regard for this party. And maybe I even have some feelings of a personal nature here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONCRIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I don't want to appear to be taking unfair advantage of you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Moncrief reaches into a briefcase, takes out a folder and makes reference to its contents as he speaks:</context>
      <utterance>Goddamned right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONCRIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But in developing certain information on you, it's come to our attention that your name isn't Harry Bliss. That in fact, your name is Eugene Earl Axline...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONCRIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry stands up, leaving the vulnerable area of his stomach framed in the passenger window. When he leans back down, a deeply conflicted expression is apparent on his face:</context>
      <utterance>And that both the I.R.S., and an impressive number of creditors in several Eastern cities...  ... seem to be somewhat interested in your whereabouts.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, that's not necessarily entirely accurate, I mean, I don't know where you come up with these so-called facts, but...  I can't go sneaking around, stealing this lady's property.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONCRIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a voucher from the folder and sets the file aside:</context>
      <utterance>I'd like to pose that the name and reputation of this very decent man, is not the property of Mrs. Ellerman, or her sister.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MONCRIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And it's my hope that we can avoid any unpleasant eventualities, either for you, or for someone you have such admirable feelings toward...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, 'unpleasant'?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONCRIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds the voucher out to Harry who avoids looking at it:</context>
      <utterance>I mean that Mr. Layls is prepared to do whatever it takes to confiscate this document. And if you'd like to be of some assistance to us, by finding it and turning it over to me, he'd like to offer you this very generous gift.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry stands in the parking lot, watching as the Con- tinental drives off. He starts to move toward The House of Bliss, then stops and opens the voucher, braving a look at it.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ, I hardly know the woman. I'm just renting a dog to her, that's all.  What kind of a person do you take me for?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>As Socorro comes to the landing, Joan indicates one of the open desk drawers:</context>
      <utterance>Could you come in here, por favor?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Socorro steps closer and glancing into the the now disorderly contents of the drawer, shakes her head defensively:</context>
      <utterance>I-am-looking-for-my-sister's-book.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOCORRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. No es mi.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Socorro smiles apologetically:</context>
      <utterance>La manuscripto  ... de mi hermana, Andy, si?  I go... toda la casa...  Everywhere... Looking y looking...  And no es anywhere. Sabe usted?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOCORRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Continuing to mumble some disclaimer, she moves out into the hallway and disappears.</context>
      <utterance>No se, no entiendo...  Lo siento...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told this detective I wanted to press charges against Red Layls, for abducting Andy, for burglarizing my apartment, for breaking into her house...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh come on, you're way off.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that he's been trying to scare and intimidate me in case I might have read something in her manuscript that he doesn't want anybody to know. And you know what he said? That I haven't given him probable cause to even go and question Red Layls, or his lawyer...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, he's right, I could've told you that. This is a man who goes fishing with the President, honey.  He's a little high up to go around burglarizing people and sending them nasty notes. So why don't you just ease back on this thing for awhile...  Life's too godammed short.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't do that, Harry. This is my sister. I can at least make out a missing persons report on her, and then I want to talk to the private detective friend of yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He begins pushing the paraphernalia around on his desk:</context>
      <utterance>I'm trying to chase the guy down, okay? But don't go and make yourself sick...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, Jesus, why don't you just get this damn thing and hand it over to me and I'll give it to these guys.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean to Red?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, to Red, or whoever...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well if I ever find, it, that's the last thing I'd do with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dammit, you're making my work more difficult for me, you know that!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this, have I come at the wrong time or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joan looks down at the floor, attempting a drollery:</context>
      <utterance>I tell you what the hell to do and you don't listen to me!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, someone abates your maidenhood and suddenly feels they can start ordering you around.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not ordering you around. I'm just giving you my opinion. And maybe I get tired of hearing about this stuff all the time, this book business, this manu-whatever, and Red Layls, and your sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she crosss to the door, Harry stands up:</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Well...  I'm sorry if I've overtaxed you with my problems, Harry, but I never asked you to consider them a part of your work.  So why don't we speak when you're in a better frame of mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah honey, now...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SOCORRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Duke returns to the kitchen and Joan moves into an enter- tainment alcove off the living room. Helen is seated on a couch, eating a slice of pizza from a delivery box on the coffee table, her attention on the TV, where a talk show is in progress:</context>
      <utterance>Ah, si. Duke, venga aqui.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOST</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... And now I'd like you to meet the director and the star of the smash hit movie, Blood And Kisses. So let's give them a nice warm welcome...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HOST</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Do you want to set it up for us?</context>
      <utterance>Before we begin, why don't we show the audience a clip from the movie.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>After clip:</context>
      <utterance>Well, it's a bit... this scene involves... just go ahead and run it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HOST</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I hear you're a little sensitive about the criticism you've had about the amount of sexual violence and nudity you have in the picture...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Any scars, marks or tattoos.'</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well it's absurd. In the first place, I didn't invent this genre. And it happens to be a tradition in this kind of film that women make more interesting and exciting victims than men do...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOST</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>She looks up from the document to the screen. Then both women look at each other with their mouths open:</context>
      <utterance>Well, I understand...</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And secondly the violence directed at Mimi's character is an essential component of the story, and is not in any sense of the word, gratuitous.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOST</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, Mimi, now what about you. That scene where you run nude through Times Square with those multiple knife wounds all over your body. That must've been horrendous for you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ACTRESS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Harry steps INTO VIEW, only half-listening and grumbling:</context>
      <utterance>... and that scene came directly after the gang rape in the elevator.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's her problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACTRESS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Also, I love Dick's taste so I knew he was handling it very artistically...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds out his hand to June, requesting the remote control:</context>
      <utterance>Now what's she complaining about?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A COMMERCIAL comes on. June hands him the remote and he sits down on the couch, channeling to a BASEBALL GAME:</context>
      <utterance>... I come over here to look at the ball game and you give me these clowns.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, what's wrong with these women.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want a know something?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't want to hear the truth, that's what disturbs me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JUNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's some people that don't treat me like you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You tell them the truth and they come at you with a cleaver.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know one guy that says very complimentary things to me, like that I have nice features and a sense of humor.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her, then reaches over and places a hand affectionately on the nape of her neck:</context>
      <utterance>Some guy I met, that likes me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going to leave me, lard, just after I've broken you in, and taught you the fine art of dog training?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe.  As if you cared.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Women.  What's the score?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helen leans down and looks in at her:</context>
      <utterance>Helen, quick, get in the car!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looking in the direction of Joan's gaze she sees the dark figure of a man wearing a hood over his head, stepping out from behind the sheet of plywood, holding the ax in his hand and as he moves toward the front of the car, she screams. He lifts the ax over his head and swings it down vio- lently, cleaving the blade into the hood of the Mercedes. (From inside the house, DUKE can be heard BARKING furiously.) Joan leaps from the car and in stark terror, runs out of the garage toward the house. Stopped by the sounds of HELEN'S HYSTERIA, she turns around to see her, hampered by her crutches and unable to move. ON the hooded man's eyes, shifting their homicidal intent from Helen to Joan. Joan runs back into the garage and frantically tries to pull Helen away from her death grip on the door handle. The man begins stalking around the front of the car toward her. She grabs one of Helen's crutches and raises it up as if to hit him. As he steps back to the ax and tries to extract it from the hood, she suddenly rushes at him and begins belaboring him with the crutch. He lifts an arm to fend off the blows while his other hand con- tinues to tug at the ax handle.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Helen! Help me!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raising both arms to protect himself, the man is forced to give ground, moving further back into the garage, with Joan continuing to batter at him. Then in a sudden burst of rage he grabs hold of the crutch, yanks it from her grasp and lunges at her.</context>
      <utterance>I can't! I can't move!!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>)O( MAN TROUBLE - Rev. 5/30/91 69.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you have the damn dog with you, that's what he's for!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you, he was in the house.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell good is that! You have to have him with you at all times!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No you didn't, I said he was dangerous, and you said he wasn't...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but that's before he tried to part your hair with an axe!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts to move toward the bedroom and he stops her:</context>
      <utterance>I don't know if it was him. Maybe it was this tree surgeon...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helen, now with a drink in her hand, steps INTO VIEW behind Harry:</context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute. How tall was he? About six one? Kind of ugly?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was about your height.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, he wasn't, he was much taller.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well let's not quibble, for god sakes. The man is a complete maniac...  And excuse me for saying, but this isn't a job for an amateur...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But wait, he couldn't be the same man who burglarized my apartment, because that's before I came up here...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget about him. I know what I'm talking about...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes the drink out of Helen's hand and drains it while Harry continues:</context>
      <utterance>Joan, if you don't call the police, I'm not staying here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guy like Red Layls have hit men working for them, that drive them around and do their dirty work for them.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gee whiz, first it isn't Red, now it is Red. I can't keep up with these sudden reversals.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON Helen, as she clumps away in the direction of the guest bedroom:</context>
      <utterance>Alright... I'm calling a cab.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what I think? It's more than one person.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm telling you who the hell it is!</context>
      <utterance>It's not more than one person.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I don't think Red would have someone sing into my answering machine...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>)P( MAN TROUBLE - Rev. 6/4/91 71A.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't seem like something he'd do.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She steps out of the closet and comes toward the bedroom, dressed in one of Andy's negligees.</context>
      <utterance>Dammit, Joan!!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, what is this?! I can't say anything to you anymore, you're so darn touchy!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a moment:</context>
      <utterance>You can mention anything you want, honey. I'm just trying to keep you from turning up face down, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She moves toward the bed, aware of Harry staring at her.</context>
      <utterance>I mean, I can't leave you up here alone now...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Andy's --</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sits down on the edge of the bed, looking over at him.</context>
      <utterance>It's very becoming on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Maybe I don't quite fill it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a brief moment:</context>
      <utterance>Yes you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He remains seated, looking at her. She reaches to the answering machine on the night stand, disconnects it, then once again looks over at him.</context>
      <utterance>Well?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you going to do now? Are you going to leave?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'm going to skip down the hill, take care of a few things, pick up some clothes...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could you be back for dinner, around 7:00?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She waves to him and pulls the rest of the way out of the garage, revealing the ax handle still embedded in the front of the car, its handle sharply angled up from the hood like a soup ladle.</context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOCORRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ella no esta aqui.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just want to look for my...  ... watch, I think I left it...  ... in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOCORRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She steps out of the way to let him in.</context>
      <utterance>Ah si, es okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Soco.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just got a phone call, honey, from a prominent entertainer up in Vegas, a very well-known singer...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is it, Paul Anka?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a rock star, you probably wouldn't know the name. Anyway, I gotta run a couple a dogs up to him...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, it's T-minus zero and counting, Harry, on this whole shitty deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now Iwo, don't blow this way out of proportion. You think I want to do this. I need the extra cash right now, believe me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you leave, I'm getting Top Lock to come over and change the front and back doors!</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean it! You get in that van, and I'm taking my building back and putting in a Fingernail Salon!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts an arm around her, giving her a perfunctory hug:</context>
      <utterance>Come on now, honey, don't say things like that...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's really very nice looking, honey.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you like it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She finishes securing the watch.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I do. Very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're welcome.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans over and kisses her on the cheek, then picks up his fork and begins poking with disinterest at his food. Joan's eyes remain on him, trying to divine his mood:</context>
      <utterance>Yeah it's great and it's something I really needed, so...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is anything wrong?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She resumes eating. Then, desirous of drawing his atten- tion, she fixes her gaze on the table top and smiles pensively, making the assumption that he is looking at her. When no response is forthcoming, she attempts a verbal solicitation:</context>
      <utterance>No. Nothing's wrong. Everything's fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks over at her:</context>
      <utterance>You're probably wondering why I'm smiling.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just thinking that I find this moody side of you very attractive.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In fact, if you want to know, and I can see you're dying to...  I completely adore you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, same here, honey.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lays his fork down and tries to make an awkward and difficult excursion into the truth:</context>
      <utterance>Why are you all wet?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, there is something I feel I gotta say here, Joan, that's been preying on my mind. Something I maybe should've handled a bit differently with you from the start, about this particular situation I'm in...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What situation?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SOCORRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mira, alli estoy.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Regarding an earlier press release announcing Mrs. Ellerman's intention to publish her book, which purportedly contains several explosive details concerning Redmon Layls' controversial business dealings. Harry coughs loudly as Moncrief appears, standing outside a government office building, encircled by a picket of microphones attached to a number of floating hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Layls' lawyer, Laurence Moncrief, had this to say when asked if he was concerned about what might be revealed in the Ellerman book:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MONCRIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have no knowledge whatsoever of Mrs. Ellerman's so-called book, or her alleged disappearance, which appears to have all the ear marks of a publicity stunt.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns contemptuously back to the screen. The Reporter now stands in the f.g. of a three-story build- ing. SLIGHTLY OUT OF FOCUS, but discernible over its entrance, are the words: Monroe Park Center.</context>
      <utterance>Can you believe this?!</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>As the Reporter continues, Joan moves closer to the TV.</context>
      <utterance>Recent reports of Layls' failing health were denied by his personal physician, Dr. Park. When questioned in a phone interview, he responded that the elusive billionaire...</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>She points to the sign over the building's entrance:</context>
      <utterance>... was recovering from quote, 'nothing more than the treatment of an ordinary virus.' Meanwhile...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you see that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without waiting for his answer, she strides across the room:</context>
      <utterance>What did she say? San Dimas?  Where's San Dimas?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's call the T.V. station and find out.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she moves OUT OF VIEW into the living room, he turns to Socorro:</context>
      <utterance>This is not the way you want to go about this, honey.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First you tell me I go around acting too timid...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but this is a whole different situation here...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And now when I suddenly feel like I could save the Pope in an earthquake, you start trying to...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is not the Pope we're talking about here, believe me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They disappear out the front door.</context>
      <utterance>That's just a figure of speech.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She begins moving a little less purposively than before:</context>
      <utterance>Dammit, Joan, these people are holding all the cards. They'll probably throw you into that bughouse with your sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stop in front of the garage where Joan's car is parked:</context>
      <utterance>You want to go there and call 'em a bunch of names, throw a lot of accusations at them? They don't care. People with that kind of money behind them, with their kind of connections, they never go to jail, you never see them behind bars.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She nods.</context>
      <utterance>Am I getting through to you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Though evidently very troubled, she nevertheless goes into the garage, opens the driver's door and gets into the car.</context>
      <utterance>Alright.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is just nuts, what you're doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you stop trying to undermine me every inch of the way.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at this goddamned traffic.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyway, I didn't ask you to drag along with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the one that's dragging along.  Go around the goddamned truck.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't tell me what to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, just let me drive the goddamned car, that's all I ask.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why should I let you drive?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? I'll tell you why, because you're a terrible driver, that's why.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, now all the ugly little truths are coming out.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You operate this vehicle like it was a cane with a red tip painted on the end of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He angrily folds his arms across his chest, assuming a sullen silence for a moment. The traffic has come to a grid-lock stop, raising their anxiety levels:</context>
      <utterance>Don't talk to me, Harry. I mean it, just don't say another word to me!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was doing just fine until you started in on me...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Driving around with a goddamned ax stuck in your car...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He suddenly opens the door, gets out and moves to the ax handle. Joan watches as he makes several unsuccessful attempts to pull the ax out of the hood of the car.</context>
      <utterance>And now look at me. I've got purpose tremors...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>MAN TROUBLE - Rev. 4/22/91 85.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I at least offer some advice?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops walking and as he moves up beside her, looks defiantly at him:</context>
      <utterance>Good. Just barge into the place, honey, and play the big hero.  When he tells you your sister's not there, what're you going to do, cry?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. What?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They approach a nurses' station and Harry steps forward to address one of TWO NURSES behind the counter:</context>
      <utterance>This isn't going to work. You look like a busboy.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, Nurse...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope you know what you're doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They approach room 206. (In the hallway outside the adjacent room, an old man in a hospital gown is seated in a wheelchair. He wears a stingy-brim hat on his head and reads a pamphlet entitled "Colostomy and You.")</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. Just do what I told you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NURSE ONE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doctor! Just a minute please!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY'S POV - NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Approaching up the hallway.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the problem, dear?</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE ONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're trying to contact Doctor Park, just to be sure he's authorized you to examine Mrs. Ellerman, because you know, we have to follow certain...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand. You're doing your job.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE ONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did your assistant...?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She had to step inside for a moment, to relieve herself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joan thrusts her skirt at Andy:</context>
      <utterance>And if this little kinglet of corporate shit thinks he can get away with this, he's greatly mistaken. Just wait 'til he hears what I'm going to come out with now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put this on.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember when he passed me off as staff and I was put on official government payroll all through Maui and the Yucatan Mission?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And as Andy steps into the skirt, Joan takes over the uncompleted buttoning chores:</context>
      <utterance>No, I don't. And hurry up, will you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to look critically at her face in the mirror:</context>
      <utterance>Yes you do, remember, when I almost died of the vomito negro? Well that's when he was doing all that illegal oil drilling off the Mexican Gulf...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you got any lipstick?</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE ONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I assume you're a fairly recent associate of the doctor's?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's very correct.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NURSE ONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uhm hmmm... What do you specialize in?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd say female troubles, mainly.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE ONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, so Dr. Park feels there's a gynecological involvement here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes he does, yes.  By the way, did anyone ever tell you what attractive eyebrows you have?</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE ONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry watches as she moves away, and while the two Nurses engage in an exchange some distance down the hall, he steps back to the door, opens it and sticks his head inside:</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me a minute, Doctor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about her hair?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's he?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NURSE ONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was my superior. She tells me Dr. Park is in surgery and she suggests that you wait in the Administrative Lounge until we can get a hold of him. Would that be alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves to the door, opens it, blocking the Nurse's view into it with his body.</context>
      <utterance>Certainly.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIS POV OF JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looking frightened at her imminent abandonment.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Andy, wearing dark glasses and with her hair hidden up under the stingy-brim hat, steps out into the hallway.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry Mrs. Ellerman, we'll be right back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which way?</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE ONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That way, Doctor, and thank you very much for your patience.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Nurse watches briefly as they move away, then extracting a key from her pocket, she steps over to the door and locks it.</context>
      <utterance>Don't mention it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands him the skirt out through the window:</context>
      <utterance>And this man, who wouldn't know the truth if it came up and spit him in the eye, is accusing me of lying...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry lays the skirt on the hood of the car and begins getting out of the doctor's jacket.</context>
      <utterance>You know what that prick had his lawyer say to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands him out the blouse and he turns politely away from her semi-nudity as he hands her the doctor's jacket.</context>
      <utterance>That I was a pretty, grudge- bearing little malcontent, grasping at some splinter of celebrity for myself at his expense. Can you believe that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here, put this on.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, the arrogance...  What did she say your name was?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He immediately moves off, rolling Joan's clothes into a bundle and heading back to the hospital grounds.</context>
      <utterance>Stay in the car. Don't talk to anybody, and I'll be right back.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>MAN TROUBLE - Rev. 4/22/91 92.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A soft WHISTLE comes from the vicinity of the windows behind her, followed by Harry's voice, whispering:</context>
      <utterance>Christ.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She crosses quickly to the windows, looking out through the thick wire mesh at Harry:</context>
      <utterance>Joan? Are you there?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm having a little trouble getting back in.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh great, Harry. What have you got me into?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, honey...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to get me out of here!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he moves out of sight, her attention is drawn to the sound of MUFFLED VOICES in the hallway. In a panic, she starts toward the bathroom, changes her mind, moves to the bed and gets into it. As the door begins to open, she grabs one of the pillows and quickly covers her head with it.</context>
      <utterance>Everything's under control, just hang on a few more minutes and I'll be right back, okay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MONCRIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andy? It's Larry Moncrief.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIS POV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>of the unresponsive figure under the covers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the hell do you think it is?!</utterance>
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls the dark glasses off...</context>
      <utterance>Sweetheart? Is that you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... and throws them onto the dashboard.</context>
      <utterance>No thanks to you, it's me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MONCRIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He removes several typed pages, stapled together and looks down at the pillow covering Joan's face:</context>
      <utterance>Before he arrives, I'd like you to take a look at a list of certain deletions and expurgations, which if agreed to...</utterance>
   <speaker>MONCRIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No response. Moncrief glances over at Sturge, standing near the door, then back at the figure on the bed.</context>
      <utterance>... Red is, very generously, I think, prepared to offer his sanction to a sanitized version of your book.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONCRIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches down and removes the pillow. Joan looks fear- fully up at him:</context>
      <utterance>I think you should know, that if you push this too far, you run the risk of having him withdraw his consent to your well-being.  I don't think we want that, do we, Andy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andy's not here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONCRIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can see that, Miss Spruance. Would you care to tell me where she is?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her bluff is immediately belied by:</context>
      <utterance>As a matter of fact, she happens to be on her way to the police right now, accompanied by a close friend of mine...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Moncrief and Joan look toward the window:</context>
      <utterance>Honey? It's me again.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Joan jumps from the bed and moves to address Harry:</context>
      <utterance>I have to tell you something.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Moncrief looks at the chauffeur, gesturing toward the door.</context>
      <utterance>Don't say a word, Harry! I'm not alone!</utterance>
   <speaker>MONCRIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sturge exits to the hallway, leaving the door open.</context>
      <utterance>Sturge.</utterance>
   <speaker>POV OF HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>standing below the window, whispering:</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's there?</utterance>
   <speaker>BACK TO SCENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Moncrief steps in beside Joan:</utterance>
   <speaker>MONCRIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you better come in here, Mr. Bliss.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the distant b.g., the previously seen old man is being wheeled along the main walkway by a hospital orderly.</context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just go get Andy and leave, will you!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I'm trying to tell you...</utterance>
   <speaker>MONCRIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a little disappointed to find you defaulting on our agreement.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What agreement?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Harry, how could you...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tears the envelope in half and as he throws it on the ground, a hand the size of a large dictionary reaches INTO FRAME and grabs him roughly by the back of his shirt collar.</context>
      <utterance>Honey, don't go by anything this guy says, because I'm the only one who knows what the hell I'm doing.  It just slipped my mind, I was going to tell you.  See? I never cashed the fucking thing!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... And in response to Andy's stoical nod:</context>
      <utterance>Are you alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No you're not.  What did that bastard do to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves toward the nightstand with Joan following:</context>
      <utterance>I need a Kleenex.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what they're trying to do, don't you? To force you into signing some kind of agreement that...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She extracts a tissue from a dispenser on the nightstand:</context>
      <utterance>Wait, I want to tell you what he said to me...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said I was the only woman he's ever really cared for...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joan's jaw goes slack in disbelief.</context>
      <utterance>And when he said it...  ... he had a tear in his eye...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MONCRIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well this moves to the top of the list, Red, as one of your more stunning achievements.</utterance>
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get me something cold to drink, will you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONCRIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Certainly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, after all I do love him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You 'love' him?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, he's been a very important man in my life, you know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, now he's not a fecal-faced, great white shark! Andy looks over at RED, now seated in one of the two chairs in the room. Moncrief can be seen re-entering and joining him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know where she got that.  Will you please keep your voice down. He's very sensitive to what people say.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Sensitive'? Have you lost all your beads?! This man had you kidnapped and kept in a drugged stupor for the last three weeks, and now he's...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, what the hell's going on in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONCRIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the dog trainer.</utterance>
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought he was working for us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MONCRIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well there seems to be a little grey area there, Red.</utterance>
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come over here, I want to talk to you. Harry releases Sturge and moves over to Layls, offering his hand and trying to maintain his gruff manner:</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joan looks with dismay at Harry's apostasy as he shakes "the great man's" hand, then quickly returns her atten- tion to Andy:</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Layls...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you listen to me! This man is not only a bastard, he's a scummy, soul-less little thug and a criminal!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>defective judgement in men, Joanie? Red and Harry, as before. In the b.g., a hospital employee wheels a cart holding several glasses of iced tea. Moncrief moves over to the cart and the employee exits.</context>
      <utterance>Are you implying that I have</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just want a say, that though you're someone in a category I admire, you've gone to some lengths on this thing here, that I don't entirely agree with...</utterance>
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sit down. I have a neck condition and it aggravates me to have to look up at you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he seats himself in the other chair, Red reaches up and takes a glass of tea offered by Moncrief:</context>
      <utterance>Okay. No problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I want to go on and finish my thought on this, because...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry takes a second glass from Moncrief:</context>
      <utterance>You know, I'm not in the best of health right now, and I've been advised to avoid excitement...</utterance>
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So if you intend to do that...  I might just have to have my shock troops blow your brains out.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, uh huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More sugar.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And furthermore, this 'sensitive' man's lawyer more than implied they were willing to put your feet, as well as probably mine, into a block of cement!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh that's just all talk...  Would somebody please get me my clothes!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uhm-hmm.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harry, I can't believe you're sitting there nodding your head and having a tea party with these crooks!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not nodding my head, honey, I'm just listening to the man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is this guy, anyway? Isn't he a little sleazy, Joanie, a bit infra dig? I mean Lewie's a bit of a stiff, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going to talk to me about sleaze, when you consorted with some maniac tree surgeon, who was flicking his tongue out at me like some rutting iguana, and groping at his naturalia at three in the morning?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks to the chauffeur, re-entering with her clothes.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, 'him.'</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh 'him'?! He came at me with an ax!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Joan can respond, she crosses to take her belongings from Sturge, and as she moves toward the bathroom:</context>
      <utterance>Well, he's very immature.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MONCRIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miss Spruance, would you care for a...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves past him, striding over to Harry and Red:</context>
      <utterance>No, thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what kind of spell you've cast on my sister, but it doesn't extend to me...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In fact, I've been to the police and I intend to press charges against you...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey, he's not supposed to get excited.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Not only for having my apartment burglarized but for breaking into Andy's house, as well as hiring someone to frighten, harass and intimidate me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, maybe you better not...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Dammit!</utterance>
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never much cared for you, young lady. And I find your display of anger both unattractive and unfeminine.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now wait a minute...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Under the following, Red's BEEPER begins SIGNALING:</context>
      <utterance>I'm not here to beg your good opinion...</utterance>
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doctor Park is trying to reach you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell him to hold on.  First, you assume far more interest in you on my part than exists. I had nothing whatsoever to do with your supposed misfortunes...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe you!</utterance>
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And as regards Andy's house, I'd have no need to break into Andy's house, because I own Andy's house.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care whose house you own, you're nothing but a slimy, mean- minded little hood!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Red lifts the beeper to his mouth again:</context>
      <utterance>Will you please stop interfering in my personal life, Joanie.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she moves over to Andy, Red gets up, paces around with the beeper and his and Parks' VOICES are MUFFLED in b.g.</context>
      <utterance>Andy, you know something?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The kind of woman you are is a danger to the kind of woman I am, so the next time you and your boyfriend have a domestic spat, don't call me!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And as she goes back into the bathroom, Joan turns to Harry:</context>
      <utterance>Well if you're going to take this kind of grumpy attitude, I certainly won't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harry, where are my clothes?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands up and Red steps INTO FRAME beside him, a distressed look on his face as he listens to Park (V.O.):</context>
      <utterance>Uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>please, I'd like to leave. Wait a minute, don't rush me on this, Monroe. Harry moves around Red and steps up to Joan:</context>
      <utterance>Will you go get them RED</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joan and Harry are forced to listen to the following exchange:</context>
      <utterance>Will you people be quiet, I can't hear this.  Go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's as sound a muscular bag as I've ever seen and the pericordium is a gorgeous color.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well whose heart is it? Give me a profile.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have any specific data, but the host was around 35 and she was obviously very healthy.</utterance>
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He begins pacing anxiously again, the CAMERA FOLLOWING him:</context>
      <utterance>Godammit, Monroe!</utterance>
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you I don't want a woman's heart!</utterance>
   <speaker>PARK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, it's not going to change you in any way.</utterance>
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know?! You don't know that!</utterance>
   <speaker>PARK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>As Red paces toward the open bathroom door, Harry and Joan resume their discord:</context>
      <utterance>Look, let's just get it done.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Moncrief steps in beside Joan:</context>
      <utterance>Would you please get me my clothes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONCRIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanted to tell you a moment ago, that I was privileged to see you at the Bowl on the Fourth of July...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what. I'm talking to this lady...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>MAN TROUBLE - Rev. 4/23/91 109.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ROOM - NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>ON Moncrief, Joan and Harry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONCRIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry suddenly grabs Moncrief roughly by the arm:</context>
      <utterance>And I was especially moved by your rendition of 'The Battle Hymn of The...'</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shakes him, causing him to spill his iced tea onto the front of his jacket:</context>
      <utterance>Never mind that shit. Tell her...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Harry releases him and under the following, Moncrief takes out a handkerchief and dabs at his jacket:</context>
      <utterance>Did I spend your money! Did I give you any services for it. Tell this woman the truth, you son of a bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>MONCRIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, shall we start with the fact that you're a married man...  ... and then go on from there?</utterance>
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ! What are you trying to do to me!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she disappears inside, Red re-enters, and covering the speaker vents on the beeper, strides over to Moncrief:</context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute, honey...</utterance>
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joan comes out of the bathroom with the doctor's jacket and moves immediately to the hallway door and exits.</context>
      <utterance>You know whose heart this body- snatcher is trying to give me?! A victim of somebody called the Westside Slasher! And this is the doctor you recommended to me!  You're killing me, Monroe! You know that?! You're pushing me to the goddamned wall!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey, there's a simple explanation to all of this, if you want me to go into it... I was trying to tell you at dinner... She disappears into an intersecting hallway.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He disappears into the same hallway.</context>
      <utterance>Will you just stop for one minute and let me talk to you... It's very complicated...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="143" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She reaches down and proprietarily brushes the scarf from his shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>Well Red, better a woman than dead, don't you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So let's just go there, sweetheart, and have him sew the darn thing in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="144" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, you know, you live a life, honey, you make some mistakes. You get married for maybe mutual benefits, or business considerations weighing on you at the time, and because you don't think the right person is ever going to come along.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would never have knowingly become involved with a married man.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know that, that's why I was trying to come out and tell you...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, I don't want to discuss it anymore.  I bet you never read Dante, either.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now there you're 75 percent wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, I can't believe it, that you'd lie to me about this...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, I lied. Didn't you ever tell a lie? If not let me kiss your high heel.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going in the house.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="145" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Or how things are going?</context>
      <utterance>Wait. Can I call you tomorrow, just to see how you're feeling?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches to the door handle, then very emotionally:</context>
      <utterance>I have a dress rehearsal tomorrow and a concert on Friday. That's all I care about right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I don't want to see you anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't say that, please. I'm asking you to just give me the chance to clear up all these things in my life, because...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I didn't extricate myself from the infidelities of one man, just to fall into the arms of the prince of prevaricators...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She finally looks over at him, her eyes brimming with tears:</context>
      <utterance>Well, I may be all kinds of a son of a bitch, and the prince of whatever, but that doesn't mean I wouldn't, when it comes down to it, stand up and take the bullet for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens the door and gets out.</context>
      <utterance>That's not what I observed, Harry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="146" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Lee, how are you.  I just this minute got back from Vegas. I was dealing a couple of dogs to Paul Anka.  I was about to give you a call.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't embarrass us both, man. Just give me the dog back, and let's preserve the friendship.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lee, I'm in the neighborhood of getting my hands on the money. I'm about to close a business deal with Vark Zulethian of Zulethian Carpets, you've probably heard of him...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stop beside the van. Harry glances at the printing on the side panel: Lee MacGreevy - Trainer of "Duke," - The World's Smartest Dog.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, I know these dodges backwards and forwards. I need the dog. He's up for a TV series.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't even want the ten thousand now, compared to what he might appreciate to.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, our agreement was I could buy the dog back. He's the only thing I got to prove to people what I can do, and all I'm asking you, Lee, is...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="147" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He ignores the command and looks at Harry:</context>
      <utterance>Get in.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Duke jumps into the back of the van. Inside is a large wire travel kennel with another German shepherd inside. Lee removes the leash from Duke and gestures at the other dog:</context>
      <utterance>Duke, geh im wagen.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens the cage and clips the leash to the dog's collar.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you take this dog, Harry. He's green, but maybe you could do something with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The shepherd jumps out to the ground, wagging his tail:</context>
      <utterance>No, I don't want the dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Lee starts to walk past him, Harry detains him, indi- cating the words on the side panel of the van:</context>
      <utterance>Go ahead, man. Take him. If you don't want him, pick up some change.  Sell him for a pet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="148" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do me one favor, will you? Say 'owner' if you want to, but don't say 'trainer.' I trained that dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry, watching Lee's van pull away. In the rear window Duke's face can be seen, looking back at him.</context>
      <utterance>Let me think about that, okay? He moves past him and OUT OF FRAME.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="149" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without responding, he looks across to the House of Bliss.</context>
      <utterance>What do you want, Harry?</utterance>
   <speaker>VITA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He looks up at her, unable to answer.</context>
      <utterance>You want the Meatloaf Special?</utterance>
   <speaker>VITA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>No response.</context>
      <utterance>Chicken pot pie?... Tuna melt?</utterance>
   <speaker>VITA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He finally answers, but from some place deeply felt and unrelated to the day's specials:</context>
      <utterance>Do you want anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="150" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A few of us are going to grab a bite. You want to join us?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, go ahead. I'm not hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, who's going to drive you home?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eddy steps INTO FRAME:</context>
      <utterance>I'll call a cab.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can take her home.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves away and Joan returns her attention to the mirror, then:</context>
      <utterance>Good, because I don't want you to be alone. Alright?  See you tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Eddy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="151" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLOSE ON HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Following the last grouping, Joan, carrying a garment bag, and Eddy Revere, exit and move in the direction of the other Chorale members, crossing the Plaza to the stairway leading down to the surface parking lots.</context>
      <utterance>Searching for Joan.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>MAN TROUBLE - Rev. 4/23/91 118.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="152" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate living here now.  I'd like to move to a small town, where it's friendly, and everybody knows each other, and there are no bars on the windows...</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the milkman's a child molester.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs, then:</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Eddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's true. It doesn't matter where you live. Shit happens.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you in a bad mood or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a moment, he begins softly singing the words to a popular song.</context>
      <utterance>No. I'm not in a bad mood. Not as bad as yours.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="153" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>EDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks over at him.</context>
      <utterance>Remember when we were on tour in Japan, in '86?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The night after we did a concert in Osaka?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could you be more specific?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="154" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>EDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She appears uncertain that she shares the same memory.</context>
      <utterance>We had a few drinks in your room. And a certain intimacy took place.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And when I asked to see you the next night, you know what you said? You were too tired and sleepy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was witty of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you weren't. Because an hour later, you went into Lewie's room and you didn't come out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if you remember, I was in love with Lewis around that time, which I confided to you, so you did know...</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not the reason.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No response.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, Eddy, you just passed the turn off to my street.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sighs impatiently, then:</context>
      <utterance>I just want to drive a little, so we can talk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="155" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches up to adjust the rearview mirror, inadver- tently drawing her atttention to his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Anyway, if I remember correctly, we only kissed. But if that led you to believe something that hurt you in any way, I apologize.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>MAN TROUBLE - Rev. 4/23/91 121.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="156" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It looks like somebody bit you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He returns his hand to the steering wheel. She looks at him, with a slight smile, waiting for him to elaborate, then:</context>
      <utterance>Somebody did.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She breaks off, suddenly aware that the teeth marks are her own:</context>
      <utterance>Well, am I supposed to guess, or are you going to...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Eddy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="157" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did you do these things?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because you deserved it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't deserve it. I've always thought of you and treated you as one of my closest and dearest friends...</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I use to think very highly of you, too, but now I don't like what I see. In fact, it's been very disturbing to me, Joan.  Very disillusioning. To see that before you've even gotten rid of Lewie, you've started up with some other man.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eddy, I want you to take me home now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="158" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, there's so many things about me you have no idea of. You never ask me about my life or what I'm thinking, because you have no interest...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She breaks off as she catches sight of a knife held in his left hand.</context>
      <utterance>Yes I do. You can tell me whatever you want to, but let's go back down to...</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She suddenly reaches frantically to the door handle and tries to get out. He grabs hold of her arm and pulls her back into the seat:</context>
      <utterance>Creative things, and dreams, and feelings I have, that Lewie or anyone else in your life, are not capable of...</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See? You're not genuinely interested. You're not at all sincere, Joan.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eddy...</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes her arm and places it around his neck.</context>
      <utterance>You present yourself like you are, but you're not...  Don't you think I know that, better than anybody?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="159" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He brings his mouth close to hers.</context>
      <utterance>I want you to listen to me, and I want you to kiss me. And this time, like you mean it...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="160" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, what is this! What the hell are you doing with this guy! He reaches in and pulls Eddy away from Joan.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The warning is simultaneous with an attempt by Eddy to stab him with the knife.</context>
      <utterance>Harry, look out!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs Eddy's arm and in hauling him out of the car, rips loose the sleeve of Eddy's shirt.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="161" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The search beam of the COPTER spotlights Joan. She is bent over, picking up sticks and stones and as if routing a deadly enemy, she begins hurling them, as well as a series of invectives, at the lights of the city below, her words barely audible over the sound of the ROTORS. The beam sweeps from her, to pick up Harry and Eddy and an AMPLIFIED, God-like voice comes from above:</context>
      <utterance>You bastards!!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you people doing down there? Joan turns back to Harry. He holds the now unconscious Eddy by his shirt front and resuming his accusations, starts to move toward Joan:</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She raises her arm, ready to hurl the last stone:</context>
      <utterance>Are you crazy?! What are you doing, running around with a guy like this!!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You maniacs!! You liars!! You shits!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="162" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Let's get a car up here quick.</context>
      <utterance>It looks like a domestic quarrel.</utterance>
   <speaker>BACK TO HARRY AND JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She is yelling at him:</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm finished wagging my tail and leaving little puddles on the floor...!!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute, honey...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And smiling on command, because I don't give a damn whether any of you like me or not!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you alright, ma'am?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, she's alright!! I've got him!!  The Westside Slasher, I got him!!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not the Westside Slasher!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="163" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A friend of yours! This guy's a friend of yours?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>None of you are friends of mine, you fucker!!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, you assholes! The guy was holding a knife at her throat!!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then to Joan again, taking a step toward her:</context>
      <utterance>Okay, put the knife down, fellow.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What were you doing, kissing this guy!?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wasn't kissing him!!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stand where you are, and put down the knife.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put the knife down, Harry!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="164" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you go harass someone else!!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've got a bead on you, so just put it down. Terrified that they are going to shoot him, she moves over to Harry:</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay where you are, don't go near him.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just saved her life, you son of bitches!!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grabs the knife out of his hand, throws it away, then places her arms around him, desperately pantomiming to the helicopter:</context>
      <utterance>Give me that thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See? He's not hurting me! He's my friend!!  This is just for their benefit.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't touch her, buddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But that's what I am, honey, your friend, that's what I wanted to tell you, and then I saw you with this guy...</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, lady, we've got a car on the way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="165" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you please shut up and go away!! This is private! Can't you see that!?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just wanted to tell you, because you don't know, how important you are to me...</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She waves the voice off, trying to listen to Harry.</context>
      <utterance>Step away from him, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I needed you to know this one other thing about me, because I don't want to withhold anything from you anymore...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God, I don't want to know, Harry. What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My real name's not Harry. It's Eugene.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eugene puts his arms around her. The "ET RESSUREXIT" from Bach's B-Minor Mass BEGINS OVER the sound of the</context>
      <utterance>Oh.  'Eugene.' I love that name.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
