<movie id="381" title="Marty">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>MRS. FUSARI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your kid brother got married last Sunday, eh, Marty?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right, Missus Fusari. It was a very nice affair.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. FUSARI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the big tall one, the fellow with the moustache.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, that's my other brother, Freddie. My other brother Freddie, he's been married four years already. He lives down on Webb Avenue. The one who got married Sunday, that was my little brother, Nickie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. FUSARI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marty sets the five chops on the scale, watches its weight register.</context>
      <utterance>I thought he was a big tall fat fellow. Didn't I meet him here one time? Big tall, fat fellow, he tried to sell me life insurance?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, that's my sister Margaret's husband, Frank. My sister Margaret, she's married to the insurance salesman, and my sister Rose, she married a contractor. They moved to Detroit last year. And my other sister Frances, she got married about two and a half years ago in Saint John's Church on Kingsbridge Avenue. Oh, that was a big affair. Well, let's see now, that'll be about a dollar- seventy-nine. How's that with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. FUSARI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Fusari produces an old leather change purse from her pocketbook and painfully extracts one single dollar bill and seventy-nine cents to the penny and lays the money piece by piece on the counter. From the rear of the shop a woman's VOICE rings out.</context>
      <utterance>Well...</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Marty, I'm inna hurry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're next right now, Missus Canduso.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. FUSARI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When you gonna get married, Marty? You should be ashamed of yourself. All your brothers and sisters, they all younger than you, they married and they got children. I just saw your mother inna fruit shop, and she says to me, "Hey, you know a nice girl for my boy Marty?" Watsa matter with you? That's no way. Now you get married.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. FUSARI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My son Frank, he was married when he was nineteen years old. Watsa matter with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's swell, Missus Fusari.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. FUSARI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes her package of meat. Marty gathers up the money on the counter, turns to the cash register behind him to ring up the sale. Mrs. Canduso sidles up to the counter.</context>
      <utterance>You should be ashamed of yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CANDUSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marty, I want a nice, big fat pullet, about four pounds. I hear your kid brother got married last Sunday.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it was a very nice affair.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CANDUSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marty, you oughta be ashamed. All your kid brothers and sisters married and have children. When you gonna get married?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Yanks took two.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Young Men exit without answering. Marty moves further into the bar, which is crowded with locals, smoky, noisy. ACROSS GROUP at bar with Marty in the background approaching, we see a group consisting of RALPH, who wears a suit and tie, the only man in the room who isn't in shirtsleeves or a Basque shirt; JOE, thirty-two, hunched over a girlie magazine; a KID, twenty-two, studying the magazine over Joe's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Any homers?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kid indicates a booth where a small wasp of a man, mid- thirties, is sitting, bent over the sports pages of the Daily News.</context>
      <utterance>Angie come in yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So these two girls come over to the bar...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Ang'...</utterance>
   <speaker>RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and they sit down right next to me...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want a beer, Ang'?</utterance>
   <speaker>RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I look over at this one nexta me, not bad, about thirty-five -- Hiya, Marty...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hiya, Ralph...</utterance>
   <speaker>RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I been talking about two nurses Leo and me picked up in a bar on Seventy-First Street.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Lou, gimme two bottles-a beer...</utterance>
   <speaker>RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, Marty, lemme tell you about these nurses, Marty...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Waddaya read there, Joe?</utterance>
   <speaker>AD LIB VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Lou, turn the television off!</utterance>
   <speaker>RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turns out these two girls are nurses in some hospital on a Hundred and Fourth Street...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They shouldn't sell magazines like this on a public newsstand...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you imagine the effect this has on adolescents?</utterance>
   <speaker>RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, Marty, let me tell you about these nurses...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What nurses?</utterance>
   <speaker>RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The nurses Leo and me picked up last night. We got a date with them tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe turns another page in the girlie magazine.</context>
      <utterance>You still owe me ten bucks from last week, if that's what you're working up to.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now that's something, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I used to go out with a girl like that...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should live so long.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So waddaya feel like doing tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, Ang'. Wadda you feel like doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we oughta do something. It's Saturday night. I don't wanna go bowling like last Saturday. How about calling up that big girl we picked up inna movies about a month ago in the RKO Chester?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which one was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That big girl that was sitting in front of us with the skinny friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We took them home alla way out in Brooklyn. Her name was Mary Feeney. What do you say? You think I oughta give her a ring? I'll take the skinny one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She probably got a date by now, Angie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, let's call her up. What can we lose?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't like her, Angie. I don't feel like calling her up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what do you feel like doing tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. What do you feel like doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we're back to that, huh? I say to you, "What do you feel like doing tonight?" And you say to me, "I don't know, what do you feel like doing?" And then we wind up sitting around your house with a coupla cansa beer, watching Sid Caesar on television. Well, I tell you what I feel like doing. I feel like calling up this Mary Feeney. She likes you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What makes you say that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could see she likes you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll call her up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angie sits down again. They both return to their papers for a moment. Then Angie looks up again.</context>
      <utterance>You call her up for yourself, Angie. I don't feel like calling her up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marty makes a wry face at the suggestion.</context>
      <utterance>How about going downa Seventy-Second Street, see what we can find? Ralph says you have to beat them off with clubs.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, you're getting to be a real drag, you know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Angie, I'm thirty-four years old. I been looking for a girl every Saturday night of my life. I'm tired of looking. Everybody's always telling me to get married. Get married. Get married. Don't you think I wanna get married? I wanna get married. They drive me crazy. Now, I don't wanna wreck your Saturday night for you, Angie. You wanna go somewhere, you go ahead. I don't wanna go.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My old lady, every word outta her mouth, when you gonna get married?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angie leans back in his seat, scowls at the paper napkin container on the booth table. Marty returns to the sports page. For a moment, a silence hangs between them.</context>
      <utterance>My mother, boy, she drives me crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what do you feel like doing tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. What do you feel like doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marty, your mother wants you onna phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on over about half past seven, we'll think of something.  Hello, Ma, what's the matter?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm coming home right now, Ma. I'll be home in about two minutes. Tell Thomas stick around, I wanna see him about something.</utterance>
   <speaker>PILLETTI HOME, LIVING ROOM.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Pilletti is on the phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hangs up, braces herself, turns and starts back to Thomas and Virginia in the dining room.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, you come on home, okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He coming home right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what happened, Aunt Theresa, about the milk bottle was my mother-in- law, she comes inna kitchen, Aunt Theresa, and she begins poking her head over my shoulder here and poking her head over my shoulder there, so then she begins telling me how I waste money and how I can't cook, and how I'm raising my baby all wrong, so she got me so nervous, I spilled some milk I was making for the baby...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was here, you know, Wednesday, and I said, "Catherine, my sister..."</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So she say, "You're spilling the milk." So she kept talking about these coupla drops of milk I spilled, so she got me so mad, so I said, "Mama, you wanna see me really spill some milk?" So I took the bottle, and I threw it against the door. I didn't throw it at her. That's just something she made up. She goes around telling everybody I threw the bottla milk at her. I didn't throw it anywheres near her. Well, I was sorry right away, you know, but she ran outta the house.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas and Virginia suddenly frown and look down at their hands as if of one mind.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't know what you want me to do, Virginia. If you want me, I'll go talk to her tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'll tell you, Aunt Theresa...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lemme tell it, Tommy.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We want you to do a very big favor for us, Aunt Theresa.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aunt Theresa, you got this big house here. I mean, you got this big house just for you and Marty. And I thought maybe Tommy's mother could come here and live with you and Marty.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I called up Tommy's brother Joe, and I said, "Joe, she's driving me crazy. Why don't you take her for a couple of years?" And he said, "Oh no!" I know I sound like a terrible woman...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Virginia, I know how you feel.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just can't stand it any more! Every minute of the day! Do this! Do that! I don't have ten minutes privacy with my husband! We can't even have a fight! We don't have no privacy! Everybody's miserable in our house!</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, Ginnie, don't get so excited.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Virginia promptly bursts into tears.</context>
      <utterance>She's right. She's right. Young husband and wife, they should have their own home. And my sister Catherine, she's my sister, but I gotta admit, she's an old goat. And plenty-a times in my life, I feel like throwing the milk bottle at her myself. And I tell you now, as far as I'm concerned, if Catherine wantsa come live here with me and Marty, it's all right with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's very nice-a you, Aunt Theresa.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We gotta ask Marty, of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(exits into the kitchen)</context>
      <utterance>You just sit here, I gotta turn the fire on under the cooking.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's very nice-a you, Aunt Theresa.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's Marty been lately, Aunt Theresa?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, he'll get married, don't worry, Aunt Theresa.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't know. He sits arounna house alla time. You know a place he can go where he can find a bride?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, there's the Stardust Ballroom. That's a kind of a big dance hall. Every Saturday night, it's just loaded with girls. It's a nice place to go. You pay seventy-seven cents. It used to be seventy-seven cents. It must be about a buck and half now. And you go in and you ask some girl to dance. That's how I met Virginia. Nice, respectable place to meet girls. You tell Marty, Aunt Theresa, you tell him, "Go to the Stardust Ballroom. It's loaded with tomatoes."</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Stardust Ballroom. It's loaded with tomatoes.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SOUND of the DOOR BEING UNLATCHED in the kitchen can be heard. Mrs. Pilletti promptly rises.</context>
      <utterance>This is very nice-a you, Aunt Theresa, what you're doing for us, and don't think we don't appreciate...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hurries into...</context>
      <utterance>He's here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Ma.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marty, Thomas and Virginia are here. They had another fight with your Aunt Catherine. So they ask me, would it be all right if Catherine come to live with us. So I said, all right with me, but we have to ask you. Marty, she's a lonely old lady. Nobody wants her. Everybody's throwing her outta their house...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, Ma, it's okay with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns and leads the way back into the dining room. Marty follows.</context>
      <utterance>You gotta good heart.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He says okay, it's all right Catherine comes here.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Marty, thanks a lot. That really takes a load offa my mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, we got plenny-a room here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure! Sure! It's gonna be nice! It's gonna be nice! I'll come over tonight to your house, and I talk with Catherine, and you see, everything is gonna work out all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just wanna thank you people again, because the situation was just becoming impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She exits into the kitchen. Virginia follows her to the kitchen door, where the two women ad-lib the following lines over the ensuing scene between Marty and Thomas.</context>
      <utterance>Siddown, Thomas, siddown.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry we gotta rush like this...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all right, that's all right...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On accounta...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Over this, Thomas talks to Marty.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna see you tonight...</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marty, I don't know how to tell you how much I appreciate what you and your mother are doing, because the kinda thing was happening in our house was Virginia was in the kitchen making some milk for the baby. So my mother comes in...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tommy, I promised the babysitter six o'clock.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tommy, before you go, I wonder if you gimme a little advice.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the accountant inna family, and I figure you might know about these things. My boss wantsa sell his shop to me. His kids are all married, you know, and he and his wife live alone, and they wanna move out to California where his daughter lives, so he wantsa sell his shop. He wants five thousand dollars down, although I think I can knock him downa four...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tommy!</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll see you at mass tomorrow. We'll sit down and we'll discuss the whole thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, I'll see you, Thomas, because he wants an answer by Monday.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. Thanks a lot about my mother. We'll work out some arrangement, because naturally I want to pay...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, listen, that's my mother, I'm gonna pay for her...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodby, Marty!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas has moved off to join his wife in the kitchen where we can hear them exchanging final protestations and goodbys with Mrs. Pilletti. Marty sits at the table, hands folded in front of him, stolid, pensive.</context>
      <utterance>Goodby, Virginia! See you soon!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He waits again. With his free hand he wipes the gathering sweat on his brow.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, is this Mary Feeney?... Could I speak to Miss Mary Feeney?... Just tell her an old friend...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girl apparently doesn't remember him. A sort of panic begins to seize Marty. His voice rises a little.</context>
      <utterance>...Oh, hello there, is this Mary Feeney? Hello there, this is Marty Pilletti. I wonder if you recall me... Well, I'm kind of a stocky guy. The last time we met was in a movie, the RKO Chester. You was with another girl, and I was with a friend of mine named Angie. This was about a month ago...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up, sits for a moment, then rises, opens the sliding doors, enters...</context>
      <utterance>The RKO Chester in Westchester Square. You was sitting in front of us, and we was annoying you, and you got mad, and... I'm the fellow who works in a butcher shop... Come on, you know who I am!... That's right, we went to Howard Johnson's and we had hamburgers. You hadda milkshake... Yeah, that's right. I'm the stocky one, the heavy-set feller... Well, I'm glad you recall me, because I hadda swell time that night, and I was just wondering how everything was with you. How's everything?... That's swell... Yeah, well, I'll tell you why I called...I was figuring on taking in a movie tonight, and I was wondering if you and your friend would care to see a movie tonight with me and my friend...  Yeah, tonight. I know it's pretty late to call for a date, but I didn't know myself, till... Yeah, I know, well how about... Yeah, I know, well maybe next Saturday night. You free next Saturday night?... Well, how about the Saturday after that?... Yeah, I know... Yeah... Yeah... Oh, I understand, I mean...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what are you gonna do tonight, Marty?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Pilletti nods a couple of times. A moment of silence.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, Ma. I'm all knocked out. I may just hang arounna house.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This gives Marty pause. He looks up.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you go to the Stardust Ballroom?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marty regards his mother for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>I say, why don't you go to the Stardust Ballroom? It's loaded with tomatoes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's loaded with what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tomatoes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ha! Who told you about the Stardust Ballroom?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thomas. He told me it was a very nice place.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Thomas. Ma, it's just a big dance hall, and that's all it is. I been there a hundred times. Loaded with tomatoes. Boy, you're funny, Ma.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marty, I don't want you hang arounna house tonight. I want you to go take a shave and go out and dance.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ma, when are you gonna give up? You gotta bachelor on your hands. I ain't never gonna get married.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gonna get married.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sooner or later, there comes a point in a man's life when he gotta face some facts, and one fact I gotta face is that whatever it is that women like, I ain't got it. I chased enough girls in my life. I went to enough dances. I got hurt enough. I don't wanna get hurt no more. I just called a girl just now, and I got a real brush-off, boy. I figured I was past the point of being hurt, but that hurt. Some stupid woman who I didn't even wanna call up. She gave me the brush. I don't wanna go to the Stardust Ballroom because all that ever happened to me there was girls made me feel like I was a bug. I got feelings, you know. I had enough pain. No, thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marty...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ma, I'm gonna stay home and watch Jackie Gleason.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gonna die without a son.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I'll die without a son.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put on your blue suit...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blue suit, gray suit, I'm still a fat man. A fat ugly man.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You not ugly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm ugly... I'm ugly! I'm UGLY!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marty...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands abruptly, his face pained and drawn. He makes half- formed gestures to his mother, but he can't find words at the moment. He turns and marches a few paces away, turns to his mother again.</context>
      <utterance>Ma! Leave me alone!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sullenly, he marches back to his seat, sits down, picks up his fork, plunges it into the spaghetti, stuffs a mouthful into his mouth, and chews vigorously for a moment. It is impossible for him to remain angry long. After a while, he is shaking his head.</context>
      <utterance>Ma, waddaya want from me?! Waddaya want from me?! I'm miserable enough as it is! Leave me alone! I'll go to the Stardust Ballroom! I'll put onna blue suit and I'll go! And you know what I'm gonna get for my trouble? Heartache! A big night of heartache!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He plunges his fork in again, starts to eat. Mrs. Pilletti watches Marty anxiously as we...</context>
      <utterance>Loaded with tomatoes...boy, that's rich.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you she wasn't especially attractive, but that she had a good deal of charm, and she's really a real nice girl...</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. KEEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's all right, Andy. It's just that I get one Saturday night off every three weeks, and I was expecting something better, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you she wasn't attractive...</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. KEEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You told me that she was a little tall, but that she wasn't bad looking at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Millie's been after me to fix her up with a date, so I...</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. KEEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They join the two girls waiting for them and start up the broad stairway to the second floor. They are halfway up, when two GIRLS come in at the top of the stairs and start down. Dr. Keegan, who is holding Clara's arm, looks up, nods.</context>
      <utterance>All right, I'm having a fair time. It's just that I get one Saturday night off in three weeks, and I wanted to wind up with something tonight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DR. KEEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girl turns. Recognition floods her face.</context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Herbie! Wadda you doing here?!</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. KEEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I came up to dance, wadda you think? You here with somebody?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just here with another girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. KEEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you going now?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just gonna get my cigarettes. I left them in my coat.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. KEEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll see you around.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns and continues on to the cloak room. Dr. Keegan turns to Clara.</context>
      <utterance>I'll see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. KEEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a girl used to know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, it's packed in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some of these kids are awful young. Aren't you afraid you'll bump into one of your students?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't think so. I teach out in Brooklyn.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You been up here before, Clara?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, twice.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shall we try to get a table and get something to drink or shall we just go in and start dancing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Keegan doesn't seem to hear.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Herbie...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Herbie...</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. KEEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna have a drink before we start dancing?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. KEEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and moves quickly through the crowded lounge, back to the swinging doors leading into the anteroom. CAMERA STAYS with Clara, Millie and Andy staring after him.</context>
      <utterance>Listen. You people go grab a table. I'll be back inna minute. I'll be right back.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what do you say, Clara? Wanna see if we can get a table?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They turn and move toward the booths.</context>
      <utterance>All right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not a bad crowd tonight, you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was one nice-looking one there inna black dress and beads, but she's dancing now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a nice-looking little short one for you right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>REVERSE ANGLE PAST Marty and Angie across the dance floor toward the wall opposite, where three GIRLS are standing. Two are leaning against the wall. The third is facing them with her back to the dance floor. This last girl is the one Angie has in mind. She is a cute little kid about twenty and wears a bright smile.</context>
      <utterance>Down there. That little one there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, she looks all right from here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, waddaya say, you wanna ask them? I'll take the one inna green dress.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tries a few tentative steps, testing for tempo.</context>
      <utterance>I think this number is a little fast. Wait a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two cavaliers turn their heads and look off-screen in the direction of the three girls. Apparently, the girls are still there. Marty and Angie relinquish their lounging positions against the wall and slouch along past the line of stags with a show of determined unconcern. They edge through the crush of people on the non-dancing margin of the dance floor and slowly push their way toward the...</context>
      <utterance>It's all right, I think. They still there?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Short Girl gives Marty a quick glance of appraisal, then looks quickly at her remaining friend.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, would you care for this dance?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHORT GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't feel like dancing just yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and heads sluggishly in the direction of the stag line.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You say something?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. KEEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I was just asking you if you was here stag or with a girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm stag.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. KEEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'll tell you. I got stuck on a blind date with a dog, and I just met an old girl I used to know, and I was wondering how I'm gonna get rid of the girl I'm with. Somebody to take her home, you know what I mean? I'd be glad to pay you five bucks if you take her home for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. KEEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take you over, and I'll introduce you as an old army buddy of mine, and then I'll cut out. Because I got this other girl waiting for me out by the hatcheck, and I'll pay you five bucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. KEEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm not kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Keegan shrugs, moves down the line of stag guys. Marty turns to watch him, still a little shocked at the proposition. The Doctor approaches THREE STAGS and obviously broaches the subject with one of them. This STAG seems more receptive to the idea. Dr. Keegan takes out a wallet and gives the Stag a five dollar bill. The Stag detaches himself from the wall and, a little ill-at-ease, follows the Doctor. Marty stands against the wall, watching the Doctor and the Stag, who come in and move past him. Concerned and curious, Marty stares after them, then moves out of his leaning position, following in their general direction. Marty moves through the crush of young men and women in the area around the dance floor.</context>
      <utterance>You can't just walk off onna girl like that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DR. KEEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...in that case, as long as she's going home alone, give me the five bucks back...</utterance>
   <speaker>STAG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They move past and away and Marty stares after them before he turns his attention toward Clara off-screen. Clara is sitting as she was, gripping and ungripping the glass of Coca Cola in front of her. Her eyes are closed. Then, with a little nervous shake of her head she gets out of the booth and stands momentarily at a loss for what next to do. As she glances around, CAMERA ANGLES to include a sign over an exit that reads "Fire Escape." Clara starts moving toward that door. Marty is staring off-screen toward Clara. He slowly works his way down the length of the lounge in the general direction of the fire escape.</context>
      <utterance>Look, Mac, you paid me the five bucks. I was willing. It's my five bucks...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Virginia helps her with her coat.</context>
      <utterance>Is Catherine here?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We didn't tell her anything yet. We thought that we'd leave it to you. We thought you'd put it like how you were lonely, and why don't she come to live with you. Because that way it looks like she's doing you a favor, insteada we're throwing her out, and it won't be so cruel on her. Do you want Tommy and me to stay here with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas appears at the living room end of the foyer with an anxious smile on his face.</context>
      <utterance>I think it be a better idea if you and Thomas go out, because otherwise she's gonna start a fight with you, and everybody's gonna be yelling.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Aunt Theresa.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Thomas.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He comes down to Mrs. Pilletti and Virginia, lowers his voice to a conspiratorial whisper.</context>
      <utterance>I just this minute got the baby to sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aunt Theresa, we figure the best way to ask her is you say that you're very lonely, see? And wouldn't she come and keep you company, because that way, you see...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A shrill, imperious woman's voice breaks into the whispered conference in the hallway.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. I'm gonna take care-a the whole thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Pilletti heads up the foyer to the living room, followed by Virginia and Thomas.</context>
      <utterance>Who's there?! Who's there?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two sisters quickly embrace and release each other.</context>
      <utterance>I came to see you. How you feel?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta pain in my left side, and my leg throbs like a drum.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I been getting a pain in my shoulder.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta pains in my shoulder too. I have a pain in my hip, and my right arm aches so much I can't sleep. It's a curse to be old. How you feel?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now that the standard greetings are over, Aunt Catherine abruptly turns and goes back into the living room. Mrs. Pilletti follows. Virginia and Thomas remain in the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>That's nice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="47">
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aunt Catherine grimaces to describe how everything is with her.</context>
      <utterance>Well, how's everything with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas comes in from the hallway, stands in the back of the room, somewhat apprehensively.</context>
      <utterance>My son Marty's fine. Everybody's fine...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We gotta postcard from my son Nickie and his bride. They're inna big hotel in Florida on their honeymoon. Everything is very nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's nice. I gotta letter from my husband's cousin in Abruzzi. His mother died.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you remember Emilio DiGiorgio, owned the tavern in Abruzzi?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think I remember him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, he died. You know who else died?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know the old man upstairs in this house. Old Irishman, always drunk. He got pleurisy. He was inna hospital two weeks. He died yesterday.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Virginia comes into the living room with Thomas. They remain in the background.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I always like to visit you, Catherine, because you always got such cheerful news.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ma, you want something to eat, some tuna fish?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas looks indecisively at his wife.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, why don't you go to the movie? Your mother and me, we're gonna be baby-sitter.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, let's go downa Kaplans' apartment. They told us to come down.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas ponders a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They exit. The two old sisters sit rigidly until they hear the SOUND of the door closing. Catherine cocks an eyebrow and promptly launches into her statement.</context>
      <utterance>All right, Ma, we're going downstairs to the Kaplans, if you want us for anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wake up this morning, I hear the baby crying. So I wake up. I come in their room. That girl is shaking her hand atta baby. I said, "You brute! Don't you strike that baby! That's my son's baby!"</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's her baby too, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's my son Thomas's baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it ain't your baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did I tell you she threw the bottle- a milk at me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You told me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's a witch, that one. I tell you what happen yesterday?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happen?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She demonstrates this by pulling the lower lid of one eye down and staring grotesquely at the ceiling.</context>
      <utterance>She gave me the evil eye.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ufa!</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I keep one eye open when I sleep, because she's gonna come in, stab me in my bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her sister turns, genuinely surprised at this request.</context>
      <utterance>Catherine, I want you come live in my house with Marty and me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You son Thomas and Virginia, they come to my house this afternoon...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your son Thomas and his wife Virginia...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When was this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This afternoon, about four, five o'clock.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What they say?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine surveys her sister coldly.</context>
      <utterance>You know what they say. They say things are no good in this house. Catherine, your son is married. Leave him in peace. He wantsa be alone with his wife. They don't want no old lady sitting inna balcony. Now I tell you what I think. I want you come live with me in my house with Marty and me. In my house, you have your own room. You don't have to sleep onna couch inna living room like here. We will cook inna kitchen and talk like when we were girls. You are dear to me, and you are dear to Marty. We are pleased for you to come.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My son Thomas came to see you this afternoon, and he said to you he wants to cast his mother from his house?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine stands abruptly. She is deeply hurt.</context>
      <utterance>Catherine, don't make an opera outta this. The three-a you anna baby live in three skinny rooms. You are an old goat, and she has an Italian temper. She is a good girl, but you drive her crazy. Catherine, you are no fool. You know this is no good, an old woman living with a husband and wife. Two women inna same kitchen, anna house burns down.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I am an old garbage bag, put inna street.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Catherine, please! Don't make a tragedy. You come to my house where you know you be happier yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It pains that they should do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine turns and meanders a few steps. The stiff edge of mordant humor that has been her one defense against life has deserted her, and she is just a hurt old lady now.</context>
      <utterance>I know it pains.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She seats herself on an Eames chair. On her right, a Modern- Age lamp towers slimly. On her left is a Modern-Age endtable with a Modern-Age ashtray on it. The hardened muscles in her face suddenly slacken.</context>
      <utterance>These are the worst years, I tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Catherine, you are very dear to me. We have cried many times together. When my husband died, I would have gone insane if it were not for you. I ask you to come to my house, because I can make you happy. Please come to my house.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are the worst years. I tell you. It's gonna happen to you. I'm afraida look inna mirror. I'm afraid I'm gonna see an old lady with white hair, like the old ladies inna park, little bundles inna black shawl, waiting for the coffin. I'm fifty- six years old. What am I to do with myself? I have strength in my hands. I wanna cook. I wanna clean. I wanna make dinner for my children. Am I an old dog to lie in fronta the fire til my eyes close? These are the terrible years, Theresa! Terrible years!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Catherine, my sister... Catherine stares distraught at Mrs. Pilletti.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares at Mrs. Pilletti, her deep eyes haggard and pained. Mrs. Pilletti stares back for a moment, then her own eyes close. Catherine has hit home. Catherine sinks back onto her chair, sitting stiffly, her arms on the thick armrests. Mrs. Pilletti sits hunched a little forward, her hands folded nervously in her lap.</context>
      <utterance>It's gonna happen to you! It's gonna happen to you! What will you do if Marty gets married?! What will you cook? What happen to alla children playing in alla rooms? Where is the noise?! It is a curse to be a widow! A curse. What will you do if Marty gets married?! What will you do?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You come up here often?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was up here twice before. Once with a friend of mine and once I came up alone. The last time... do you see that girl in the gray dress sitting over there?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, the last time I was up here, that's where I sat. I sat there for an hour and a half, without moving a muscle. Now and then, some fellow would sort of walk up to me and then change his mind. I'll never forget just sitting there for an hour and a half with my hands in my lap. Then I began to cry, and I had to get up and go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I cry a lot too. I'm a big cryer.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is something recent with me, this bursting into tears at the least thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I cry all the time, any little thing. My brothers, my brother-in- laws, they're always telling me what a goodhearted guy I am. Well, you don't get goodhearted by accident. You get kicked around long enough, you get to be a real professor of pain. I know exactly how you feel. And I also want you to know I'm having a very good time with you now and really enjoying myself. So you see, you're not such a dog as you think you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm having a very good time, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So there you are. So I guess I'm not such a dog as I think I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a very nice guy, and I don't know why some girl hasn't grabbed you off long ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clara smiles briefly at this.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know either. I think I'm a very nice guy. I also think I'm a pretty smart guy in my own way.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They dance silently for a moment, cheeks pressed against each other.</context>
      <utterance>Now I figure, two people get married, and they gonna live together forty, fifty years. So it's just gotta be more than whether they're good looking or not. You tell me you think you're not very good-looking. My father was a really ugly man, but my mother adored him. She told me that she used to get so miserable sometimes, like everybody, you know? And she says my father always tried to understand. I used to see them sometimes when I was a kid, sitting in the living room, talking and talking, and I used to adore my old man, because he was so kind. That's one of the most beautiful things I have in my life, the way my father and mother were. And my father was a real ugly man. So it doesn't matter if you look like a gorilla. So you see, dogs like us, we ain't such dogs as we think we are.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm twenty-nine years old. How old are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm thirty-four.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...you teach chemistry? That's funny. Where? What school?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Benjamin Franklin High School.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has reached the street landing and waits for Clara to catch up with him. They stand in front of the glass doors leading to the street.</context>
      <utterance>Benjamin Franklin, where's that? Brooklyn? I went to Theodore Roosevelt right up here on Fordham Road. It's right arounna corner from my house. I have a cousin who's a teacher. He teaches Latin. He lives in Chicago. He was studying to be a Jesuit, but he gave it up after his first vows.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes her arm, and they start walking.</context>
      <utterance>You know what I was good at in high school? I was good in Math. You know how long ago I graduated high school? June, nineteen-thirty-seven. Holy cow! June, nineteen-thirty-seven! What is that? Fifteen, seventeen years ago! Holy cow! Seventeen years ago! Is that right? Seventeen, that's right. Where did it all go? I'm getting old. I'm gonna be thirty- five November eighth. Thirty-five. Wow. Time goes on, boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nineteen-thirty-seven... that's right. My old man died December, nineteen- thirty-seven.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA HOLDS as Marty, caught in his story, stops and continues intently.</context>
      <utterance>Two o'clock in the morning he died. The doorbell rings, and I knew something was wrong right away. Because my room is onna ground floor inna front, you see, and I got outta bed, and I answered the door...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly he looks at Clara, rather startled.</context>
      <utterance>There was Mr. Stern. He had a house down about a block from us. He moved out though. My old man, he used to play cards with him and some other old guys. He's a Jewish feller. So he said, "Is your mother home?" So I knew right away there was something wrong. I was only eighteen, exactly eighteen years old, just the month before. So I said, "Is something wrong, Mr. Stern?" I was in my pajamas, you know? So he said, "Marty, your father died." My father died right inna middle of playing cards, right at the table. He had a heart attack. He had low blood pressure, my old man. He used to faint a lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes her arm again, and they continue strolling toward the corner intersection in silence.</context>
      <utterance>Boy, am I talking, I never talked so much in my life. Usually, everybody comes to me and tells me all their troubles. Well, I'm gonna shut up now, and I'm gonna let you get a word in...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They reach the corner intersection. CAMERA HOLDS on Marty as he pauses again. He stares at Clara, confused at his strange loquacity.</context>
      <utterance>Seventeen years ago. What I been doing with myself all that time?... Well, I'm talking again. I must be driving you crazy. Mosta the time I'm with a girl, I can't find a word to say. Well, I'm gonna shut up now. Because I'm not like this usually. Usually, I... well, here I go again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marty stares at Clara, absolutely aghast at his inability to stop talking.</context>
      <utterance>I can't shut my mouth... I'm on a jag, for Pete's sake. You'd think I was loaded...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands there in the middle of the sidewalk with PEOPLE moving past, back and forth. Marty continues to stare at Clara, his broad face widened by a foolish, confused smile. Clara regards him affectionately.</context>
      <utterance>I can't stop talking! Isn't this stupid?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta real nice face, you know? It's really a nice face.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stroll along farther up the noisy, jangled, trafficked Saturday night avenue.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has to interrupt the narrative to control a seizure of giggles. Clara wipes her eyes and catches her breath.</context>
      <utterance>...so I'm inna kneeling position, and if you ever try shooting a BAR inna kneeling position, you know what I mean. I can't holda steady position. I'm wavering back and forth...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He can't go on. He has to stop and cover his face with one hand.</context>
      <utterance>...so the guy next to me, he's shooting from the prone position, and he's cross-eyed like I told you...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...so just then I hear five shots go off from the guy next to me... It's too much for him. He lets out a sudden guffaw and instantly smothers it under shaking shoulders. Clara hides her face in her hands and giggles desperately. Some of the other people turn to look at them.</context>
      <utterance>So just then...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares at the girl, spent from laughter.</context>
      <utterance>So my target goes down, and a minute later, the flag comes up. I got five bulls-eyes. This cross-eyed guy next to me, he shot five bulls-eyes into my target...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He closes his eyes, shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>...so I said to the sergeant who was checking my score, "Pretty good, eh, Sarge? Five bulls-eyes? So this sergeant, he don't know what happened, he says, "Say, that's all right, Pilletti"...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For a moment they seem to have controlled their laughter. They sit, shaking their heads, studying their fingers on the table in front of them. Then slowly, Marty begins to giggle again. It communicates itself to Clara. In a moment they are hiding their faces in their hands, their shoulders shivering with laughter.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, man. So that's what happened. That's how I got the reputation-a being the best shot inna whole battalion... oh, man...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BUCKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything good in there, Mac?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He crosses to the Men's Room.</context>
      <utterance>A buncha dogs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...When I got outta the army, Clara, I was lost. I didn't know what I wanted to do. I was twenny-five years old, what was I gonna do, go back to my old job, forty cents an hour. I thought maybe I go to college under the G.I. Biller Rights, you know? But I wouldn't graduate till I was twenny-eight, twenny-nine years old, even if I made it in three years. And my brother Freddie wanted to get married, and I had three unmarried sisters -- in an Italian home, that's a terrible thing. And my kid brother Nickie, he's a one got married last week. So I just went to pieces. I used to walk inna streets till three, four o'clock inna mornings. My mother used to be so worried about me. My uncle Mario come over one time. He offered me a job driving his hack onna night shift. He got his own cab, you know. And God forgive me for what I'm gonna say now, but I used to thinka doing away with myself. I used to stand sometimes in the subway, and God forgive me what I'm going to say, I used to feel the tracks sucking me down under the wheels.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a Catholic, you know, and even to think about suicide is a terrible sin.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So then Mr. Gazzara -- he was a frienda my father -- he offered me this job in his butcher shop, and everybody pleaded with me to take it. So that's what happened. I didn't wanna be a butcher.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's nothing wrong with being a butcher.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I wouldn't call it an elegant profession. It's in a lower social scale. People look down on butchers.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marty looks quickly up at her, then back down.</context>
      <utterance>I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, the point is Mr. Gazzara wantsa sell his shop now, because he and his wife are lonely, and they wanna move out to California in Los Angeles and live near their married daughter. Because she's always writing them to come out there. So it's a nice little shop. I handle his books for him, so I know he has a thirty-five percent markup which is not unreasonable, and he takes home net maybe a hundred, hundred and fifty bucks a week. The point is, of course, you gotta worry about the supermarkets. There's two inna neighborhood now, and there's an A&amp;P coming in, at least that's the rumor. Of course, mosta his trade is strictly Italian, but the younger Italian girls, they get married, and they don't stick to the old Italian dishes so much. I mean, you gotta take that into account too.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's my feeling that you really want to buy this shop, Marty.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clara looks down at her fingers, her face alive and sensitive. She carefully assembles her words in her mind. Then she looks at the squat butcher across the table from her.</context>
      <utterance>That's true. I do. But I'm gonna have to take outta loan inna bank eight thousand dollars. That's a big note to carry, because I have to give Mr. Gazzara a mortgage, and what I have to weigh is: will it pay off in the end more than I can make onna salary?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marty shuts his eyes, then opens them quickly, bows his head.</context>
      <utterance>Marty, I know you for three hours, but I know you're a good butcher. You're an intelligent, sensitive, decent man. I have a feeling about you like sometimes a kid comes in to see me for one reason or another. And some of these kids, Marty, in my classes, they have so much warmth in them, so much capacity. And that's the feeling I get about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you were one of my students, I would say, "Go ahead and buy the butcher shop. You're a good butcher." Clara pauses.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up at her now.</context>
      <utterance>Well, there's a lotta things I could do with this shop. I could organize my own supermarket. Get a buncha neighborhood merchants together. That's what a lotta them are doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wadda you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tears begin to flood his eyes again. He quickly looks away. He licks his lips.</context>
      <utterance>I think anything you want to do, you'll do well.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clara looks down at her hands.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Catholic. Are you Catholic?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marty looks up at her.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I only got about three bucks on me now, but I just live about eight blocks from here on the other side of Webster Avenue. Why don't we walk back to my house? I'll run in, pick up some dough, and let's step out somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She twists in her seat and looks toward the back of the luncheonette.</context>
      <utterance>I really should get home...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's only a quarter of twelve. The clock's right over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marty considers this problem for a second, then leans out of the booth and calls out.</context>
      <utterance>I really should get home, I told my father... Well, I suppose a little while longer. I wonder if there's any place around here I could put some makeup on...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA ANGLES to include the PROPRIETOR of the luncheonette. He is sitting in one of the booths ahead reading the Sunday Mirror. He looks up toward Marty.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Mac!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta Ladies' Room around here?</utterance>
   <speaker>PROPRIETOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Inna back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clara smiles at this innocent gaucherie, then edges out of the booth, taking her purse with her.</context>
      <utterance>Inna back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>FIRST IRISH WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angie shuffles in, pausing near the bar and standing behind the two Irish women.</context>
      <utterance>...so she told me that the doctor told her that if she had any more babies, she would do so at the risk of her life...</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND IRISH WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was always a bit thin in the hips...</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST IRISH WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, at the time she told me this, she already had six. Every time I saw the woman, she was either...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Lou!</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST IRISH WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...going to the hospital or coming from it. She was hatching them out like eggs.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND IRISH WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that husband of hers is a skinny bit of a fellow, isn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST IRISH WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I bumped into her on the street, and she was as big as a barrel.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA ANGLES to include Lou, the Bartender.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Lou!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST IRISH WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...so I said to her, "Mary...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marty been in here the last coupla hours or so?</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST IRISH WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"...Mary, for heaven's sakes, didn't you tell me that another one'll kill you?"</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't seen Marty all night...</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND IRISH WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And her husband is a little bit of a man, isn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is everybody? I been walking around, I can't find anybody...</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST IRISH WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, last week Tuesday, she gave birth to the baby in Saint Elizabeth's hospital... a big healthy boy of nine pounds...</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND IRISH WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, that's nice. So the doctor was wrong, wasn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST IRISH WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, no! She died right in the hospital...</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND IRISH WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, that's a sad story. And her husband is that little fellow, works in Peter Reeves.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST IRISH WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the one.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND IRISH WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angie has nothing better to do than give his attention to the last lines of the story. Perturbed, he turns and leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, that's a sad story.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...It's really a fine opportunity for me. But I'm not sure I want to be a department head. It's mostly executive and administrative work. Well, anyway, I told you about my father, and he depends on me a great deal, and...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you just move out to Portchester?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pauses as he straightens. He looks at her a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Well, that's what I was saying. My father is getting old. And we're very close. He's a wonderful man, really...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you're kidding yourself, Clara. I used to think about moving out, you know? And that's what I used to say. "My mother needs me." But when you really get down to it, that ain't it at all. Actually, you need your father. You know what I mean? You're living at home, and you got your father and mother there, and you can go on like that -- being a little girl all your life.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid of being lonely.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you won't be so lonely. You'll make friends right away.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, I don't make friends easily.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They have only gone a few paces farther when Marty's shoelace comes loose again. He fidgets self-consciously, bends down and begins to retie it. The VOICE of Ralph, the well-dressed man, established previously, is heard.</context>
      <utterance>What're you talking about? You're a real likeable person. You'll make friends out there in Portchester one, two, three. You'll have people visiting you alla time. I'll come visit you. I'll borrow my brother Freddie's car, or you can call me up when you feel blue, or I'll call you up. And it's gonna be nice. Don't be so afraid.</utterance>
   <speaker>RALPH'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marty and Clara both look off...</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Marty!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marty and Clara look around to find the source of the voice.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Marty!</utterance>
   <speaker>RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marty and Clara again look around trying to find Ralph. Marty spots him leaning out of the window of a '47 Chevy parked in the background.</context>
      <utterance>Marty! Over here!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Ralph.</utterance>
   <speaker>RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marty and Clara start walking toward the Chevy.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Marty, come over here a minute.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll like this guy. This guy's a nice guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's this? Marty?</utterance>
   <speaker>RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, this guy's a nice guy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Ralph, what's new?  Hiya, Leo.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hiya, Marty.</utterance>
   <speaker>RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marty leans with his elbow on the open front window of the car, his head bowed, waiting for Ralph to speak his piece. He studiously avoids looking at the girls in the car.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Marty, come here a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marty allows his eyes to flicker quickly over the girl in the seat next to Ralph.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Marty, we got an odd squirrel here, you interested?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Waddaya mean, Ralph?</utterance>
   <speaker>RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Louise, I want you to meet Marty Pilletti. Marty, that's Louise Kelly, inna back seat there.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Louise, not an unattractive girl by any means, is a little surly at the moment. She merely nods at the introduction.</context>
      <utterance>Hiya.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are we going to do, just sit around here all night?</utterance>
   <speaker>RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Marty, these three squirrels are nurses. We're all going over Leo's house later because there's nobody there. These are the squirrels I told you about. Money inna bank, man. Wanna get inna car? She's a pretty nice-looking doll.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm with a girl, Ralph.</utterance>
   <speaker>RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get ridda her. This is money inna bank.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't do that, Ralph, because somebody already brushed her off once tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marty straightens, looks surreptitiously back to the corner where Clara is standing. Clara stands alone on the corner. She is an angular, awkward, plain girl. Marty brings his attention back around to Ralph who is leaning out of the car window.</context>
      <utterance>This is a good deal here, Marty.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't do it, Ralph. Thanks anyway.  Very nice to have met you all.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, let's get outta here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ralph bends forward and starts the car.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Ralph, we might as well get going.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll see you, Leo.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marty takes a step or two back from the car, and Ralph begins the business of wheeling the car from out of its parking place. The car backs and fills once or twice and eventually clears and whisks into the street. Marty stands looking after the departing car, then slowly turns and goes back up the sidewalk. He joins Clara and we...</context>
      <utterance>I'll see you, Marty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He finds the lights. The kitchen is suddenly brightly lit. The two of them stand squinting to adjust to the sudden glare.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute. Lemme find the light.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clara advances into the kitchen, a little ill at ease, and looks around. Marty closes the porch door.</context>
      <utterance>I guess my mother ain't home yet. I figure my cousin Thomas and Virginia musta gone to the movies, so they won't get back till one o'clock at least.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the kitchen.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns the light on as he enters. Clara follows him into the...</context>
      <utterance>Come on inna dining room.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Siddown, take off your coat. You want something to eat? We gotta whole half-chicken in the icebox.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, thank you. I don't think I should stay very long.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He helps her off with her coat. He remains behind her, looking down at her. Conscious of his scrutiny, she sits uncomfortably, breathing unevenly. Marty takes her coat into the dark living room. Clara is patient but nervous. Marty comes back, sits on another chair, and there is an awkward silence.</context>
      <utterance>Sure. Just take off your coat a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I was telling you, my kid brother Nickie got married last Sunday. That was a very nice affair. And they had this statue of some woman, and they had whiskey spouting outta her mouth. I never saw anything so grand in my life.  And watta meal. I'm a butcher, so I know a good hunka steak when I see one. That was choice filet, right off the toppa the chuck. A buck eighty a pound. Of course, if you wanna cheaper cut, get rib steak. That gotta lotta waste on it, but it comes to about a buck and a quarter a pound, if it's trimmed. Listen, Clara, make yourself comfortable. You're all tense.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want me to take you home, I'll take you home.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stands. He stands. He's a little angry. He turns and sullenly goes back to the living room for her coat. Wordlessly, he begins to help her into the coat. Standing behind her, he puts his hands on her shoulders, then suddenly seizes her, and begins kissing her on the neck. As Marty holds Clara, kissing the back of her neck, the dialogue drops to quick, hushed whispers.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe that would be a good idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Marty, please...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like you. I like you. I been telling you all night, I like you...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marty...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He attempts to turn her face toward him. She resists.</context>
      <utterance>I just wanna kiss, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He releases her and turns away violently.</context>
      <utterance>Marty...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He marches a few paces away, deeply disturbed. He turns back to her.</context>
      <utterance>All right! I'll take you home! All right!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and goes into the living room to hide the flush of hot tears threatening to fill his eyes. Clara is also on the verge of tears.</context>
      <utterance>All I wanted was a lousy kiss! What do you think, I was gonna try something serious with my mother coming home any minute!? What am I, a leper or something?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="45">
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to rise but instead sinks back onto the couch, looking straight ahead. Clara looks at him, her face peculiarly soft and compassionate.</context>
      <utterance>I'm old enough to know better. Comes New Year's Eve, everybody starts arranging parties, I'm the guy they gotta dig up a date for. Let me getta packa cigarettes, and I'll take you home.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marty stares down at his hands.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like to see you again. Very much. The reason I didn't let you kiss me was because I just didn't know how to handle the situation. You're the kindest man I ever met. The reason I tell you this is because I want to see you again very much. I know that when you take me home, I'm going to just lie on my bed and think about you. I want very much to see you again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Waddaya doing tomorrow night?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll call you up tomorrow morning. Maybe, we'll go see a movie.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like that very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The reason I can't be definite about it now is my Aunt Catherine is probably coming over tomorrow, and I may have to help out.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll wait for your call.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We better get started to your house, because the buses only run about one an hour now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stands.</context>
      <utterance>All right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rises and goes into his bedroom. CAMERA ANGLES to include door to bedroom. Marty opens his bureau drawer and extracts a pack of cigarettes. He comes back out and looks at Clara for the first time. They start to walk to the dining room. In the archway, Marty pauses and turns to her.</context>
      <utterance>I'll just get a packa cigarettes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Waddaya doing New Year's Eve?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They quietly slip into each other's arms and kiss. Slowly their faces part, and Marty's head sinks down upon her shoulder. He is crying, detectable from the slight shake of his shoulders. The girl presses her cheek against the back of his head. They stand. The SOUND of the kitchen door opening splits them out of their embrace. A moment later Mrs. Pilletti's voice is heard.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She comes into the dining room, stops at the sight of Marty and Clara.</context>
      <utterance>Hallo! Hallo! Marty?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Marty, when you come home?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This seems to impress Mrs. Pilletti.</context>
      <utterance>We just got here about fifteen minutes ago. Ma, I want you to meet Miss Clara Snyder. She's graduate of New York University. She teaches chemistry in Benjamin Franklin High School.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Siddown, siddown. You want some chicken? We got some chicken in the ice box.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Mrs. Pilletti. We were just going home. Thank you very much anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Pilletti pulls her coat off.</context>
      <utterance>Well, siddown a minute. I just come inna house. I'll take off my coat. Siddown a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd you come home, Ma? Thomas give you a ride?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, it's a sad business.  My sister, Catherine, she don't get along with her daughter-in-law, so she's gonna come live with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, she's coming, eh, Ma?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, sure.  Siddown, siddown. Marty, tell her siddown.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clara smiles and sits. Mrs. Pilletti likewise seats herself, holding her coat in her lap.</context>
      <utterance>Might as well siddown a minute, Clara.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you offer the young lady some fruit?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I offered her, Ma, she don't want nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, thank you, really, Mrs. Pilletti.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a very sad business, I tell you. A woman, fifty-six years old, all her life, she had her own home. Now she's just an old lady, sleeping on her daughter-in-law's couch. It's a curse to be a mother, I tell you. Your children grow up and then what is left for you to do? What is a mother's life but her children? It is a very cruel thing when your son has no place for you in his home.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Couldn't she find some sort of hobby to fill out her time?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hobby! What can she do? She cooks and she cleans. You gotta have a house to clean. You gotta have children to cook for. These are the terrible years for a woman, the terrible years.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Pilletti darts a quick, sharp look at Clara. Then she looks back to her own hands, which are beginning to twist nervously.</context>
      <utterance>You mustn't feel too harshly against her daughter-in-law. She also wants to have a house to clean and a family to cook for.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't think my sister Catherine should live in her daughter-in-law's house?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't know the people, of course, but as a rule, I don't think a mother-in-law should live with a young couple.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do you think a mother-in-law should go?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think a mother should depend so much upon her children for her rewards in life.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, maybe that's what they teach you in New York University. In real life, it don't work out that way. You wait till you are a mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's silly of me to argue about it. I don't know the people involved.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ma, I'm gonna take her home now. It's getting late, and the buses only run about one an hour.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was very nice meeting you, Mrs. Pilletti. I hope I'll see you again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marty and Clara move toward the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, Ma. I'll be back in about an hour, an hour anna half.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodnight, Mrs. Pilletti.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marty and Clara go out through the kitchen. CAMERA STAYS on Mrs. Pilletti, who stands expressionlessly by her chair, staring after them. She remains there rigid even after the kitchen door has OPENED and SHUT.</context>
      <utterance>Goodnight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angie starts into the street without waiting for the lights to change. Impatiently, he has to wait until traffic stops for the light.</context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marty and Clara still stand, seeming not to hear Angie.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Marty! Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marty and Clara turn and stare off-screen. Angie pushes his way through the CROWD on the sidewalk and manages to join Marty and Clara.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Marty! Marty!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you been, for Pete sakes?! I been looking all over for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I looked for you, Angie, before I cut out, but I couldn't find you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angie is absolutely unaware of, or simply refuses to acknowledge the presence of the girl. He has pushed himself in between Marty and Clara, and addresses himself entirely to Marty.</context>
      <utterance>I been looking all over for you!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened, Angie, was that we thought we were just gonna go for a short walk, and then we thought we were gonna come right back, but we got to talking. Listen, Angie, I want you to meet Clara...  Clara, this is my best friend, Angie. I told you about him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angie acknowledges the introduction with a surly nod.</context>
      <utterance>How do you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Waddaya gonna do now?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna take Clara home. It's close to one.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want me to ride down with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What for?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's early.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It must be one o'clock.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Saturday night! There's still plenty-a action around!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angie stares with thick, sullen jealousy at his best friend. He turns sharply and starts away from Marty and Clara.</context>
      <utterance>Angie, by the time I get Clara home, it's gonna be one, one-thirty. By the time I get home, it's gonna be two o'clock. I gotta get up for ten o'clock mass tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, I'll see you!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angie, feeling rejected and jealous, moves swiftly out into the other PEDESTRIANS on Fordham Road.</context>
      <utterance>Where you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares for a moment at the departing form of his friend, then turns to Clara with a shrug and a smile, as if to say, "I don't know what's the matter with him." The long-awaited downtown bus ROARS up to the corner, blocking our view of Marty and Clara.</context>
      <utterance>I'll see you tomorrow after mass!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got an elevator in this house?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We just live one flight up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I'll call you tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clara leans against the iron banister of the stairway.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The doors of the ELEVATOR slide open, and a middle-aged COUPLE comes out. They have obviously been having a heated exchange; but at the sight of Marty and the girl at the stairway, they become silent. They march across the lobby and out to the street in repressed silence. The door CLANGS behind them. Marty and Clara have waited stiffly through this interruption, and now they look at each other and smile.</context>
      <utterance>Call me about two-thirty, because I won't be home from my aunt's till about then.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, so I'll see you tomorrow night then.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marty turns and moves across the lobby toward the street door.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE-UP of Marty standing in the street, crying...</context>
      <utterance>Taxi! Taxi! Hey, taxi! Taxi! Taxi!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Taxi!... Taxi!...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you think I feel lousy about this too?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, Ginnie. I don't wanna talk anymore about it.  I don't think I got one hour's sleep the whole night.  Last night was the first time in my life I ever heard my mother cry, you know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tommy...</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know what you're gonna say. A man's gotta stop being his mother's baby sooner or later. How many times you gonna say it? She's my mother, you know. I oughta have some feelings about her, don't you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you always put me inna position of being the louse?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas has risen, a slim, dark, unsettled young man in undershirt and trousers, holding his shoes in one hand. He starts toward the...</context>
      <utterance>Tommy, I love you, and I know you feel lousy right now, but we're never gonna be happy unless we have a chance to work out our own lives. We can't keep talking in whispers like this the resta our lives. We gotta have some privacy. We...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns from her, sits down on the bed miserably angry with the world, his wife, his mother, himself. The baby begins to whimper again. Virginia turns wearily to her husband.</context>
      <utterance>All right, get dressed, because we're gonna drive my mother over. Why couldn't you get along with her?! Why couldn't you make just a little effort?! She's a little hard to get along with! All right! All I asked you was try a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tommy...</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't wanna hear anymore about it, you hear me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Aunt Theresa.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Thomas, how do you feel?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, my mother, she drives me crazy. I hadda beg her to let me drive her over here. The martyr. She always gotta be the big martyr.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A burst of spirited song soars from upstairs. Mrs. Pilletti, Aunt Catherine and even Thomas pause to look up in the direction of the voice.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, will you go to mass, please. This one, he woke up this morning with salt in his nose. Do this! Do that! Will you leave me in peace, ah?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Aunt Catherine! How are you? Hello, Thomas. You going to mass with us?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was at mass two hours ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, make yourself at home. The refrigerator is loaded with food. Go upstairs, take any room you want. Thomas, you going to mass with us?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He abruptly goes out into the living room and onto the front porch.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, yeah, sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marty has followed Thomas out into the living room.</context>
      <utterance>You wanna cuppa coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, beautiful day, hey, Thomas?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas goes out the door onto the porch. Marty stands in the open doorway. He looks out into the warm sunshine in the front yard.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, great if you ain't married.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes out into the yard to Virginia. He is as gay as a bird. He takes the baby from Virginia's arms, holds it high up above him.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Virginia.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, little boy, you sure getting fat. You weigh more than a side-a beef now.  Hey, Thomas, so I was telling you yesterday you was over my house -- Mr. Gazzara, my boss, so he wantsa sell his shop, go out to California because his kids are all married, and he... Thomas hasn't been listening to Marty and crosses quickly to Virginia.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wadda you so sore about?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marty comes up to them, holding the baby.</context>
      <utterance>Oh shaddup, will you do me a favor?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas has been trying to listen to Marty, but his thoughts are all with his own problem. He whirls on Virginia.</context>
      <utterance>So Thomas, he does about twelve, thirteen hundred gross. Rent's a hundred and two. The problem, of course, is the supermarkets. That's what I wanna ask you. If I get together with a coupla other merchants, make our own supermarket...</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the time she wanted to make an old-fashioned Italian dinner for my brother, but you wouldn't let her!?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Waddaya talking about?!!</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Once a month you couldn't let her use the kitchen!</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told her she could use the kitchen any time she wanted...</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...You hadda be the boss inna kitchen alla time!</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She don't wanna use my pots and pans!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So Tommy...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The baby in Marty's arms has started to cry a little.</context>
      <utterance>Waddaya want me to do, go out and buy a whole new setta pots and pans?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tommy, gimme a coupla minutes, because I promised Mr. Gazzara I'd let him know tomorrow. See, what I wanna know, Tom, if a buncha individual retail merchants get together, how does it operate? On individual mark- ups? You know what I mean? Say I'm the butcher and Aldo Capelli, he's the dairyman and grocer, so suppose I mark up thirty-five percent, but he works on forty, so...</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Waddaya talking about, do you know what you're talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The baby starts to cry again. Thomas turns to his wife.</context>
      <utterance>No, I don't know. That's why I'm asking you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Virginia hurries over and takes the crying baby from Marty's arms, walks around comforting the child. Thomas turns back to Marty.</context>
      <utterance>Take the baby, will you?!</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wadda you wanna buy a shop for, will you tell me? You gotta good job, you got no wife, you got no responsibilities. Boy, I wish I was you, boy. Waddaya wanna tie yourself down with a shop? What's he want? Five thousand down? You're gonna have to carry a mortgage sixty, seventy bucks a month. A mortgage anna note from the bank. For Pete's sake, you're a single man with no responsibilities. Stay that way, boy. Take my advice.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you see, Thomas I figure the big problem is the supermarkets. But Patsy's shop, that's a specialized trade. The supermarkets don't carry Italian meat.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who buys Italian meat anymore? You think my wife buys Italian meat?  She goes to the A&amp;P, picks up some lamb chops wrapped in cellophane, opens up a canna peas, and that's dinner, boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marty is a little taken aback by Thomas's frontal assault.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, all you wanna eat is that greasy stuff your mother makes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I understand the problem about the supermarkets, but I was talking to this girl last night, and she made the point that a likeable personality is a valuable business asset.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marty, see that my mother is nice and comfortable, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. This girl said...</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What girl, what does she know?  Why don't you let her hold the baby once in a while?! Your mother, boy, she wantsa take the kid for a day, that's fine!</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marty stands, watching the young couple yakking at each other. The little baby starts to cry again.</context>
      <utterance>Your mother handles the kid like he was a yoyo!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I come home from your house last night, Marty was here with a girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marty.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your son Marty?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what Marty you think is gonna be here in this house with a girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were the lights on?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh sure.  This girl is a college graduate.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're the worst. College girls are one step from the streets. They smoke like men inna saloon. My son Joseph, his wife, you know, she types onna typewriter. One step from the streets, I tell you. Mrs. Pilletti ponders this philosophy for a moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine nods bleakly.</context>
      <utterance>That's the first time Marty ever brought a girl to this house. She seems like a nice girl. I think he has a feeling for this girl. You heard him sing. He been singing like that all morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's all. You will see. Today, tomorrow, inna week, he's gonna say to you, "Hey, Ma, it's no good being a single man. I'm tired-a running around." Then he's gonna say, "Hey, Ma, wadda we need this old house? Why don't we sell this old house, move into a nicer parta town? A nice little apartment?"</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't sell this house, I tell you that. This is my husband's house. I had six children in this house.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will see. A coupla months, you gonna be an old lady, sleeping onna couch in her daughter-in-law's house.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marty comes in from the living room, a little down after his session with Thomas and Virginia.</context>
      <utterance>Catherine, you are a blanket of gloom. Wherever you are, the rain follows. Someday, you gonna smile, and we gonna declare a holiday.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Ma, waddaya say, it's getting a little late.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marty goes to the sink to get himself a glass of water. He examines a piece of plaster that has fallen from the ceiling.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Pilletti exchanges a brief frightened glance with her sister.</context>
      <utterance>Boy, this place is really coming to pieces.  You know, Ma, I think we oughta sell this place. The whole joint's going to pieces. The plumbing is rusty. Everything. I'm gonna have to replaster the whole ceiling now. You know what we oughta do? We oughta get one of those new apartments they're building down on Southern Boulevard. A nicer parta town, you know?...You all set, Ma?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sends another frightened look at her sister and follows Marty out into the living room.</context>
      <utterance>I'm all set.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was a nice girl last night, Marty.  She wasn't a very good-looking girl, but she looks like a nice girl.  I said, she wasn't a very good-looking girl... not very pretty...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard you, Ma.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She looks a little old for you. About thirty-five, forty years old?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A nearby kneeling penitent looks disapprovingly at Mrs. Pilletti and shushes her. The mother nods briefly.</context>
      <utterance>She's twenty-nine, Ma.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's more than twenty-nine years old, Marty. That's what she tells you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, Ma?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marty frowns but remains silent.</context>
      <utterance>She looks thirty-five, forty. She didn't look Italian to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said, is she Italian girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's Mrs. Pilletti's turn to frown. A silence. She turns back to Marty.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marty turns, on the verge of anger with his mother.</context>
      <utterance>She don't look Italian to me. What kinda family she come from? There was something about her I didn't like. It seems funny, the first time you meet her, she comes to your empty house alone. These college girls, they all one step fromma streets.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about? She's a nice girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A silence hangs between them.</context>
      <utterance>She didn't look Italian to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't like her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't like her. You only met her for two minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't bring her to the house no more.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What didn't you like about her?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know! She don't look like Italian to me. Plenny a nice Italian girls around.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kneeling woman shushes them again. By now the nine o'clock worshipers have filed out, and Marty joins the flow of ten o'clock people moving in. His mother turns back to him again.</context>
      <utterance>Well, let's not get inna fight about it, Ma.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They continue down the aisle of the church.</context>
      <utterance>What are you getting so worked up about? I just met the girl last night. I'm probably not gonna see her again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Lou, Angie come in yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was here last night till about two o'clock. I hear you really got stuck with a dog last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who told you that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Angie. He says she was a real scrawny- looking thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns away from the bar annoyed, notes Ralph, sitting alone in one of the booths, reading the Sunday comics. Marty ambles over to him.</context>
      <utterance>She wasn't so bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Ralph. How'd you make out with those nurses last night, Ralph?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He feels very ill at ease and a little guilty for defending himself.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I hadda nice time...I didn't try nothing. She's a nice girl. I just met her last night, you know. I just talked with her. I didn't even try nothing...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves back down the bar and goes out into the street.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, you see Angie, tell him I went home, I'll meet him after lunch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="37">
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...so the whole book winds up, Mike Hammer, he's inna room there with this doll. So he says, "You rat, you are the murderer." So she begins to con him, you know? She tells him how she loves him. And then Bam! He shoots her in the stomach. So she's laying there, gasping for breath, and she says, "How could you do that?" And he says, "It was easy."</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angie reaches over to Marty's plate and filches a piece of rissole, evidently annoying Marty.</context>
      <utterance>Boy, that Mickey Spillane, boy he can write.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We gotta whole pot inna kitchen. We give you a plate-a your own.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This doesn't prevent him from filching a second piece of rissole.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I couldn't eat nothing. My mother just stuffed me right up to the jaws.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I like about Mickey Spillane is he knows how to handle women. In one book, he picks up a tomato who gets hit with a car, and she throws a pass at him. And then he meets two beautiful twins, and they throw passes at him. And then he meets some beautiful society leader, and she throws a pass at him, and...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, that Mickey Spillane, he sure can write.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marty looks down at his watch, then stands and starts for the phone, sitting on a chest of drawers at the other end of the room.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, somebody turn onna ballgame. It must be after one o'clock by now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who you gonna call?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was gonna call that girl from last night. Take her to a movie tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Angie, I wanna tell you, you were very impolite last night. I introduced you to the girl, you just turned and walked off. Now, why did you do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe, having finished his dissertation on Mickey Spillane, is now studying another girlie magazine. He proffers an opened page to Marty, who stands over by the phone.</context>
      <utterance>You got me mad, that's why. Hey, Joe, show Marty that picture.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put that away, for Pete's sake. My mother's right out onna porch.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wonder where they find those girls that pose for them pictures.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those are Hollywood starlets.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe closes the magazine.</context>
      <utterance>Put it away, Joe. My mother'll come walking in.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marty, let's go downna Seventy-Second Street area tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't feel like going, Angie. I thought I'd take this girl to a movie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, you really musta made out good last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We just talked.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, she musta been some talker. She musta been about fifty years old.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I always figure a guy oughta marry a girl who's twenny years younger than he is so that when he's forty, his wife is a real nice-looking doll.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That means he'd have to marry the girl when she was one year old.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never thoughta that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't think she was so bad-looking.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She musta kept you inna shadows all night.</utterance>
   <speaker>RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marty, you don't wanna hang around with dogs. It gives you a bad reputation.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go downa Seventy-Second Street.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told this dog I was gonna call her today about two-thirty.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brush her. Listen, you wanna come with me tonight, or you wanna go with this dog?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Waddaya getting so sore about?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns away sulking. Marty doesn't pick up the phone but returns to his seat, upset.</context>
      <utterance>I looked all over for you last night, you know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Another book that I read by Mickey Spillane, I can't remember the name of it, but it was about this red- headed tramp he finds inna street, and he gives her some dough, because he's sorry for her... Wait a minute, I think that's the same book I was telling you about before...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't like her at all?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marty lowers his head. Over this, Joe's VOICE DRONES on.</context>
      <utterance>A nothing. A real nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA ANGLE HOLDS on Marty looking down, as Joe's VOICE continues.</context>
      <utterance>You know something...?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I can't tell one-a those Mickey Spillane books from the other, but he's a real good writer, though...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MRS. PILLETTI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what are you gonna do tonight, Marty?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly he pauses, sharply aware of the repetition in his life. Mrs. Pilletti is also aware of it.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, Ma. I'm all knocked out. I think I'll just hang arounna house and watch...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They eat silently a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe, I'll go out and see what Angie and the boys are doing...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>LEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What time is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About eight o'clock.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't feel like going downna Seventy-Second Street?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll take an hour anna hour back, and the whole evening's gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's playing on Fordham Road? I think there's a good picture in the Loew's Paradise.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys feel like working up a game- a cards?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE-UP of Marty, his head down, his eyes closed. The group continues their dialogue back and forth. Their VOICES can be heard as Marty's head slowly comes up.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, let's go down Seventy-Second Street, walk around. We're sure to wind up with something.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll never forgive LaGuardia for cutting out burlesque outta New York City...</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a burlesque in Union City. Let's go over to Union City...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you're the one who don't even wanna take a ride onna subway for half an hour. Now, you wanna go alla way over to Union City...</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel like playing cards. I saw Richie Rizzo, that's what he said he felt like doing...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't feel like playing cards. Waddaya feel like doing tonight, Angie?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Wadda you feel like doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A fury rises in Marty's face. He cries out at them.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, Angie. Wadda you feel like doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA ANGLES over to the others who, at this outburst, stare at Marty astounded.</context>
      <utterance>"What are you doing tonight?"... "I don't know, what are you doing?!"...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marty pauses, one foot in the booth.</context>
      <utterance>Watsa matter with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marty has been fishing in his pocket for his address book. He opens it to its proper page and steps decisively into the phone booth. Nearby, Angie prowls around outside the booth. The booth door is open. Marty starts to dial. A hush fills the room except for the CLICKING of the telephone dial.</context>
      <utterance>You don't like her. My mother don't like her. She's a dog, and I'm a fat, ugly little man. All I know is I hadda good time last night. I'm gonna have a good time tonight. If we have enough good times together, I'm gonna go down on my knees and beg that girl to marry me. If we make a party again this New Year's, I gotta date for the party. You don't like her, that's too bad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Still smiling at his very private joke, Marty returns to the phone, and after a fraction of a second...</context>
      <utterance>When you gonna get married, Angie? Aren't you ashamed of yourself? You're thirty-three years old. All your kid brothers are married. You oughta be ashamed of yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Angie looks miserable, and Marty slowly reaches out and pushes the phone booth door shut, and continues to talk into the phone, we very slowly...</context>
      <utterance>Hello... Clara?...</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
