<movie id="387" title="Midnight Cowboy">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MODERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tonight we'll discuss a subject most of us seem to consider either bad taste or frivolous or funny. But if our experts are right, we face what might be called a masculinity crisis. Every fourth American man uptight, threatened by the increasing sexual demands of American women...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRATE WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They always put it that way, but well, all it means, you know, is every fourth American woman's never satisfied. That's it. I never am -- have been, you know...</utterance>
   <speaker>COOL WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This, this image of the, the man eating woman. It isn't our increasing demands. I think it's the shrinking American male...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I never had, well, whatever it is you call it. But the hours he works, I can't blame him...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SAD WOMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Camera pulls back to show the picture among other pinups of women -- rich, beautiful or naked, but all blonde -- steam wilted on the wall over a dishwashing machine. JOE BUCK grins at the wall as he scrapes garbage.</context>
      <utterance>... but it's a problem. A big problem. With so many women I know...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just keep your pants on, ladies...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LADY COMMENTATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Lady Commentator is replaced by Joe, stacking dishes, surrounded by frustrated ladies. He laughs tolerantly.</context>
      <utterance>Before World War One -- American men outnumbered women by over six percent. Today American women not only outnumber men, but live five years longer -- leaving them in control of vast corporate wealth and seventy-five percent of America's purchasing power...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'all,line up and take your turn...</utterance>
   <speaker>MODERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My question is this -- will American know-how come up with a marketable male to replace all the men who are worrying themselves into an early grave over women's increasing sexual demands?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Look at those dishes, look!</context>
      <utterance>You're due here at four o'clock.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe picks up his suitcase, a portable transistor radio, walks away from the mirror, then pauses to run a comb through his hair, hook a cigarette at the corner of his mouth and strike a match on his thumbnail before he turns back for one admiring glance at himself in the mirror -- proud, exultant, ready -- freezing the image as CREDITS END.</context>
      <utterance>Know what you can do with those dishes? And if you ain't man enough to do it yourself, I'd be happy to oblige...</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angle widens to include Joe, holding his suitcase and radio. Ralph stares at him curiously, stacking dishes.</context>
      <utterance>Four to midnight, understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, look, uh, I gotta have a word with you, if you got a second.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Manager hurries away, carrying a basket of dishes.</context>
      <utterance>Later. Later maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ain't coming to work?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe tilts his Stetson as the Waitress appears at the door...</context>
      <utterance>Don't guess. Just come for my day's pay owing and to tell you I'm heading East.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... but she disappears without noticing Joe. Ralph offers his hand. Joe takes it, holds it.</context>
      <utterance>Cups!</utterance>
   <speaker>RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you gonna do back there, East?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lotta rich women back there...</utterance>
   <speaker>RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Men, they mostly faggots.</utterance>
   <speaker>RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Must be some mess back there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, ain't no use hanging around here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't gonna collect your pay?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got me two hundred twenty-four bucks of flat folding money...  He know what he can do with that chicken-shit day's pay. And if he ain't man enough to do it for himself, I be happy to oblige!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Benson and Hedges One Hundreds makes special awards from time to time for anything that's longer than anything...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the same moment, a recognizable variant of the "Big Country" theme blares loud.</context>
      <utterance>Care to get out your yardstick, gentlemen?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ignored by the driver, Joe rises and walks back to his empty double seat, glancing around to see what impression he's made on his immediate fellow travelers -- an OLD LADY in front of him -- a hostile young sailor with acne behind him -- two teeny-boppers flirting with Joe hysterically -- a PALE BLONDE directly across the aisle, smiling at Joe weakly.</context>
      <utterance>This is a powerful mothah, ain't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PALE BLONDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe leans across, snapping his gum as he offers her a stick. He watches her nibble it daintily on her front teeth.</context>
      <utterance>Do you have a stick of gum?</utterance>
   <speaker>PALE BLONDE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Plenty more where that came from.</utterance>
   <speaker>PALE BLONDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, no, it's just till the Dramamine works. I get carsick.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe realizes that her eyes are closed. Mildly depressed, he stretches himself across both seats and turns on his radio, finds only static and snaps it off. Further depressed, he examines his reflection in the bus window, squeezes a black head and runs the comb through his hair, picks a piece of tobacco off his tooth and lights a cigarette, watching the flame die in reflection, forgetting to discard the burnt-out match as he stares out at a vast lonely prairie, a solitary cowboy in the distance, a row of sharecropper shacks apparently deserted, a barefoot little girl motionless at the roadside, watching the bus pass. Through this, leading into the next scene, Sally Buck sings softly "... if that mocking bird don't sing, Grammaw gonna buy you a golden ring..."</context>
      <utterance>I only get carsick on boats.  But seems to me that's more the fish smell than the bouncing...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SALLY BUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, a little lower, sugar, yeah, yeah, that's good. Grammaw's beat.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALESMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta sell yourself, that's the whole trick...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SALESMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It ain't the product and it ain't the price, no sir, and it ain't what you sell, it's personality, pure and simple. I ain't shined my own shoes or shaved my own face in forty years, how's that? Not bad for a kid that didn't pass the eighth grade, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, hell, yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALESMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that's my golden rule. Make 'em love you. Put yourself over and you can sell them anything. If they like you, they'll buy horsemeat for prime beef...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SALLY BUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sally Buck turns, pretending to be stern as Toe laughs.</context>
      <utterance>You get him to the church, honey. He ain't gonna find out you ain't a real blonde till after you're married, then's too late.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY BUCK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You getting too big for your britches, sugar.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SALLY BUCK'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe leans forward to help the old Lady, irritably struggling with the release button on her seat. She scowls as Joe leans over to release her seat, then pulls her blanket around her and turns away from him. Joe switches off her reading light.</context>
      <utterance>Don't forget to say your prayers, honey...</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe switches it on again, fakes a good-natured grin, settles back with his radio, aware of an OLD COWHAND seated opposite him, replacing the Pale Blonde. The Old Cowhand is appraising Joe's wardrobe curiously. He looks away when he sees Joe watching him. Joe settles back, unable to think of a way to open a conversation.</context>
      <utterance>I want it on.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVANGELIST'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Old Cowhand has rolled-himself a cigarette. Joe quickly lights a match on his thumb and holds it across the aisle.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, my friends, I say unto you, invest with Jesus, put your dollars to work where they'll pay off at compound interest. The Good Book says money answereth all things...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Old Cowhand's "thanks" is lost in a fit of coughing as he inhales his first drag. He settles back, wiping his watery eyes on a faded bandana.</context>
      <utterance>Light?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVANGELIST'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... everyone who sends a dollar to the Evangelical Congregation of the Air will get free gratis a genuine leatherette hymn book so you can sing along with Sister Rosella and the Evangelical Choir...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe glances across the aisle. The Old Cowhand manages a faint, humorless smile.</context>
      <utterance>You throw in Sister Rosella and you got a deal, right, old timer?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Going far?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD COWHAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Up the line. Not far.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Old Cowhand reappraises Joe's wardrobe even more curiously.</context>
      <utterance>I'm bound for New York City.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Old Cowhand considers, shakes his head. Joe leans back, laughing to himself.</context>
      <utterance>Ever happen to come across a cowman name of Woodsy Niles? Friend of my grammaw Sally Buck...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SALLY BUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like it, honey? Does it fit?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Woodsy grabs Sally Buck, lifting her off her feet, carrying her to the bed. Struggling, they fall across the covers together, Little Joe laughing with them.</context>
      <utterance>You do me good, Sal, you do me real good. You know what I gonna give you for that Stetson?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY BUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Woodsy Niles! The boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He don't know what makes little apples by now, it's time he found out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe stuffs a stick of gum in his mouth, turns to wave at the Old Cowhand through the window as the bus pulls away.</context>
      <utterance>Nice talking to you, old timer.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODSY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She-dogs squat, boy. He-dogs stand up and lift their leg...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>VETERAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ever stationed at Kennedy? Those Florida chicks...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Instant V-goddam-D.</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This Pensacola teeny-bopper -- jail bait -- but built? Ten bucks she wanted. Three of us made a deal for, twenty-five, see, big goddam bargain?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big peni-goddam-cillin bargain, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus goddam Christ, I ain't laughed so hard since I was out at Fort Benning, Georgia.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you make the Viet?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Oh, hell no. Motor pool mostly...  Kee-rist...</utterance>
   <speaker>PROSTITUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You gonna cost me money, soldier!</context>
      <utterance>Hey, hey, what you try to do to me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JOE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After all them dishes are washed, what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE'S REFLECTION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then they bring some more dishes and I wash them and then I, uh, sleep some and then wash some more dishes and then I...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say it, lover boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE'S REFLECTION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Die.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe rises abruptly, rips up the postcard and tosses it out the window.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you better just shake your tail, lover boy, and root, hog or die.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddam if I came to this town to write postcards.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The delicate profile gives no signs of hearing. Joe follows her to the parkway in the middle of the avenue. There she stops and turns, neither friendly nor hostile.</context>
      <utterance>Beg pardon, ma'am, I'm new here in town, just in from Houston, Texas, and looking for the Statue of Liberty.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICH LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were you looking? About the Statue of Liberty?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Joking? No, ma'am. Oh no! I mean business!</utterance>
   <speaker>RICH LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I thought you were -- never mind -- I've never actually been there, but let me see, you take the Seventh Avenue subway, I think, to the end of the line...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Rich Lady tries to frown, taken aback, blushing.</context>
      <utterance>You sure are a pretty lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICH LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not looking for the Statue of Liberty at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, ma'am, I'm not.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICH LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A twinkle of amusement and sympathy reveals the age lines at the corner of her eyes. Then she continues on quickly, just as the light turns. Joe's view is blocked for a moment by traffic, then he sees... ... the Rich Lady, newly aware of her flanks as she climbs the steps of a brownstone and searches for her key. Still from Joe's viewpoint, he sees himself move into frame and follow the Rich Lady up the steps. The love theme swells O.S. as the Rich Lady leads him into the house and closes the door... ... leaving Joe standing alone on the parkway island, surrounded by towering wealth. The love theme continues over...</context>
      <utterance>Why, that's perfectly dreadful. Aren't you ashamed of yourself?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CASS'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe grins, holding his hat over his heart as he approaches CASS TREHUNE, a blonde lady in a tight black dress, with the look of a movie star who wrecked her career with food.</context>
      <utterance>Hurry up, Baby. Do um goody-goods for Mama.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beg pardon, ma'am. I'm brand spanking new to this town, come from Houston, Texas, and hoping to get a look at the Statue of Liberty...</utterance>
   <speaker>CASS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're hoping to get a look at what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Statue of Liberty.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But as she turns, Cass winks, dimpling the corners of her mouth, signaling Joe to follow her.</context>
      <utterance>It's up in Central Park, taking a leak. If you hurry, you'll make the supper show. Now get lost.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CASS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... as Joe steps from the elevator, which opens directly onto Cass's penthouse. Cass beckons him toward her, hooks a finger into his neckerchief and pulls his mouth toward hers while she talks on the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cass gurgles happily as her free hand unbuckles Joe's garrison belt.</context>
      <utterance>Morey? Hi-ee, honey...</utterance>
   <speaker>CASS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>As her fingers reach for Joe's zipper, cut to... ... Joe's hand unzipping her dress.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just out of breath, honey, running to catch the phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The poodle tugs at Joe's slacks until they fall. Cass steers her ear to Joe's mouth, shuddering deliciously.</context>
      <utterance>I was walking Baby. Him got to do him goody-goods, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cass holds the phone toward the yapping poodle, twisting herself against Joe as she wriggles out of her dress, passing the phone from one hand to the other.</context>
      <utterance>Oh God, oh stop. I can't stand that. I just die...  It's Baby, Morey. Him trying to say hello. Say hello to Morey, Baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cass hangs up. The poodle yaps hysterically, disentangling himself from her tumbling dress -- hops onto the couch glances off and flees again as an overturned lamp crashes</context>
      <utterance>Okay, old goosie? Now lookie, when do you want me to meet you? Whatever you say. I'll take a nap, watch TV, you know, kill time. Okay, but just one, a big wet one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CASS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... the images and sound of the television set flicking joyfully from channel to channel... ... Joe laughing, engulfed by Cass's abundance... ... Cass wild-eyed, overflowing the frame... ... a gleaming slot machine -- three Sahara cowgirls clicking into line for jackpot -- silver dollars overflowing the frame...</context>
      <utterance>Ye gods...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy shee-it, this is a goddam penthouse you got here, Cass, a real goddam penthouse.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>CASS'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe turns to look as Cass comes from the bathroom, holding a towel around her as she runs behind the closet door.</context>
      <utterance>Don't look, baby...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, Cass, I, uh, sure have enjoyed being here. Believe it's as fine a time as I've had in my life!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASS'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me, too, lover.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A tower of black bugle beads emerges from the closet door.</context>
      <utterance>That's good, it is, cause, well I guess I didn't tell you why I came to New York, did I?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe zips her dress, follows her to the dressing table, where she sprays her hair with lacquer.</context>
      <utterance>Zip this thing, will you, Tex?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Truth is, Cass, I'm, well, I'm in business.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cass stretches her upper lip across her teeth and she smears it with, orange lipstick.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, poor you. Morey's got terrible ulcers.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't know what line Morey's in, but myself now, fact is -- I'm a hustler.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hers'n zodda meg a livig.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beg pardon, ma'am?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Said, a person's gotta make a living.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure you heard what I said?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe grins, relieved as she takes out a gold lame purse and opens it. He frowns as she folds; it upside down, empty.</context>
      <utterance>Scuse me, hon, fraid I'm only half here. Maybe you oughta run on along. But why don't you take this phone number?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Joe stands mute as she cups his chin in her hand, seductively.</context>
      <utterance>Darn! I didn't get to the bank -- Tex -- could you let me have a little coin for the taxi-waxi?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're such a doll. I hate money, don't you? God, it's been fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe tries to laugh but it sticks in his throat as Cass speaks -- an impassioned whisper -- still holding Joe's chin.</context>
      <utterance>Funny thing, you mentioning money. I was just about to ask your for some...</utterance>
   <speaker>CASS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sobbing suddenly, she throws herself on the bed. Joe stands bewildered by the vastness of her grief.</context>
      <utterance>You bastard! You son of a bitch! You think you're dealing with some old slut? Look at me! You think just cause you're a longhorn bull you can get away with this crap? Well, you're out of your mind. I am a gorgeous chick, thirty-one, that's right, you said it!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe waves his wallet at her, but she only cries louder. He hands her a kleenex. She clutches it to her face, wailing. Joe leans over the bed, whispering in her ear:</context>
      <utterance>Hey. Hey, Cass. Did you think I meant that? Christ, would I be asking you for money with a wad like that riding on my hip?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Joe tucks a twenty-dollar bill into her bosom, tilts his Stetson and starts out. Cass blows her nose, looking after him. O.S. chorus sings, "From this valley they say you are going -- we will miss your bright eyes and sweet smile..."</context>
      <utterance>Hey. You are a gorgeous-looking piece, Cass. Guy gets horny, just looking at you. It's a fact. How much you need for that taxi? Ten? Twenty? There you go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>RATSO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RATSO studies Joe across the corner of the bar -- a sickly, child-size old man of twenty-one -- hopefully nursing an empty beer glass, contemplating the money on the bar in front of Joe.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, I'm just admiring that colossal shirt...</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is one hell of a shirt. I bet you paid a pretty price for it, am I right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ratso spits as JACKIE leans on the bar next to Joe -- a feminine young person, heavily made-up, hair teased, wearing earrings and a lace-trimmed blouse over shocking pink levis.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, it ain't cheap. I mean, yeah, I'd say this was an all right shirt. Don't like to, uh, you know, have a lot of cheap stuff on my back.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got a cigarette, cowboy?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reaching for a cigarette, Joe glances at Jackie, startled as Jackie twitches his pink levis angrily and turns away.</context>
      <utterance>More goddam faggots in this town.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shee-it...  Kee-rist, you really know the ropes. Wish to hell I bumped into you before. I'm Joe Buck from Texas and I'm gonna buy you a drink, what do you say to that?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enrico Rizzo from the Bronx. Don't mind if I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>TV HOST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In a booth now -- the TV screen in the background, continuing the game -- Joe is refilling Ratso's beer glass as he speaks, loud over the laughter of the TV audience.</context>
      <utterance>... and for the losers, who don't get the girl, we'll give as consolation prices -- a six month supply of underarm deodorant...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... you see what I'm getting at here? She got a penthouse up there with color TV and more goddam diamonds than an archbishop and she busts out bawling when I ask for money!</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For money.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For money for what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a hustler, hell, didn't you know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How would I know? You gotta tell a person these things  A hustler? Picking up trade on the street like that -- baby, believe me -- you need management.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you just put your finger on it, I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My friend O'Daniel. That's who you need. Operates the biggest stable in town. In the whole goddam metropolitan area. A stud like you - paying! -- not that I blame you -- a dame starts crying, I cut my heart for her...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ratso grabs the neck of a bottle, sliding back in the booth. Joe scowls as Jackie appears with the tall farm boy.</context>
      <utterance>I'd call that a very minor operation...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... in fact, you just sit comfy and I'll cut it out with my fingernail file. You won't even need Blue Cross, Ratso.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The name is Rizzo.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I said, Ratso.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the TV screen -- the Date Girl announces:</context>
      <utterance>Hey now, you heard him.</utterance>
   <speaker>TV DATE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I pick Number Two! He's cool!</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's okay, Joe. I'm used to these types that like to pick on cripples. Sewers're full of 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I ask one thing, cowboy? If you sit there and he sits way over there, how's he gonna get his hand into your pocket? But I'm sure he has that all figured out...  Good night, sweets.</utterance>
   <speaker>TV HOST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The TV host pulls aside the screen which has concealed the lower half of the three young men. Number Two, her chosen mate, is a dwarf sitting on a high stool. The girl's spontaneous dismay starts everyone laughing hysterically, including the dwarf.</context>
      <utterance>May present your chosen mate!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe hesitates as Ratso darts into traffic against a red light, yelling unheard obscenities at a cab driver who blasts his horn. Joe runs recklessly forward as Ratso slams the taxi fender with his fist, pretending to be hit, falling into Joe's arms. The taxi stops, halting traffic. Ratso, recovers, strolls casually in front of the cab, biting his thumb at the driver.</context>
      <utterance>Look, with these chicks that want to buy it, most of 'em are older, dignified, right? Social register types. They can't be trotting down to Times Square to pick out the merchandise. They need a middleman, right? That's O'Daniel.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>More if you wanta moonlight...</context>
      <utterance>It is a crime, a stud like you passing out double sawbucks to a chick like that. With proper management you should be taking home fifty, a hundred bucks a day.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, listen, how about you take me to mee this Mister O'Diddle bird right now?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ratso stops opposite the Plaza hotel, pointing across at an aristocratic blonde stepping out of a Rolls Royce.</context>
      <utterance>Well, Joe, you're a nice guy, and I'd be doing you both a favor, but why? What'm I dragging my bum leg all over town for? It's no picnic and what for, for me myself, what?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow when some piece like that's scratching your back in a Fifth Avenue townhouse, where'll your pal Rizzo be? Nedicks.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe peels a ten from his wallet and offers it to Ratso.</context>
      <utterance>Hold it, just hold it. You think I'm that kinda sombitch? Just name your cut, whatever you want, you got it right now. Five? Ten, how's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Joe, please. You know what I'd ask anyone else? Oh hell, tell you what I'll do, I'll take the ten...  ... but when I hand you over to Mr. O'Daniel, I'll have to have another ten, Joe; just to like cover expenses...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... but the operator slams the door and starts on up. Ratso leans heavily on the down button, glancing at Joe.</context>
      <utterance>Hold it a second...</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ratso glances up the elevator shaft nervously, rings again and turns back to Joe.</context>
      <utterance>Nine-oh-one, got it?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's see how you look. Fine. You look fine. Now I'm gonna have to have that other ten...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten, ten -- I got a twenty -- take that...</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh hell, forget it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now take it. Go on.  Listen, where can I reach you? Cause I'm gonna make this right with you soon's I get me set up...</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ratso leans on the DOWN as the cage grinds slowly down into view and stops.</context>
      <utterance>I mean, dammit, where you live?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ratso steps into the elevator as the door opens then closes, leaving Joe alone, repeating "Cherry Neverlin" as he starts along the corridor looking for 901.</context>
      <utterance>Sherry-Netherlands Hotel. Now get your ass in there. He's waiting!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>O'DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Daniel, fat in a worn-out bathrobe, examines Joe like a prodigal son as he leads him into the room -- as anonymous as Joe's own room.</context>
      <utterance>You must be Joe Buck. Come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I tickled to find you, boy! Come on in and let's get a look at you. Turn around. Good strong back. You'll need it. So you want help -- take a seat, relax, tell me about yourself. Cowboy, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No sir, I'm no cowboy really, but I'm a first class stud.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take it,easy, boy...  Seems to me you're different than a lotta boys that come to me. Most of 'em seem troubled, confused, but I'd say you knew exactly what you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You bet I do, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I'll bet you got one thing in common with them other boys. I'll bet you're lonesome.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Daniel rises suddenly in a fury of self-righteousness, pacing, his voice simpering, whining sarcastically.</context>
      <utterance>Well, not too, I mean, a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm lonesome. I'm lonesome so I'm a drunk. I'm lonesome so I'm a dope fiend. I'm lonesome so I'm a thief, a fornicator, a whore-monger. Poop, I say, poop! I've heard it all and I'm sick of it, sick to death.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yessir, I can see that.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lonesomeness is something you take. You bear? Dammit, you take it and go about your business, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, uh, I'm raring to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I believe you are. Cowboy, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, yessir.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ready for hard work, son?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ready for anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got a hunch, Joe Buck, it's gonna be easier for you than most.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gonna be like money from home.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe laughs, driving an obscene uppercut into the air. O'Daniel laughs with him.</context>
      <utterance>Money from home, see, there's your strength, you put things in earthy terms any man can understand, son. I warn you I'm gonna use you, I'm gonna run you ragged!</utterance>
   <speaker>O'DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a wonderful boy. You'n me gonna have fun, dammit, it don't have to be joyless. Say, why don't we get right down on our knees now?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get down -- where?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Daniel drops on all fours, crawling to find the plug of an electric cord. He shoves it into a wall socket, switches off the overhead light and suddenly a hollow, tinted plastic Jesus glows on the dresser. O.S. a revivalist congregation sings. And now we notice, with Joe, placards and flags, horns and tracts, all the paraphernalia of a street corner evangelist.</context>
      <utterance>Right here, why not? I prayed in saloons, I prayed in the street, I prayed an the toilet. He don't care where, what He wants is that prayer.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shee-it...</utterance>
   <speaker>O'DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the ticket, just open your heart and let it flow. It ain't the words, it's the love beyond 'em!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>O'DANIEL'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't fight it, boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>O'DANIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pray and you shall be heard!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, you know that runty little bastard I was with?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe tenses as he sees the . tabloid picture of himself on the back of the bartender's paper. Joe's hand closes around an empty beer bottle, a terrible violence surging very near the surface. O.S. women scream.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know nothing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JOE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Action continues as the DESK CLERK hands Joe a folded paper instead of a key. Joe opens it, deeply perplexed.</context>
      <utterance>Key to 1014...</utterance>
   <speaker>DESK CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like you been locked out of your room, buddy. Till you pick up your tab.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, what about my things'n all?</utterance>
   <speaker>DESK CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We keep them nice and safe till you get this straightened out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That suitcase means a lot to me.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, tell you what, you can keep all the rest of the goddam junk if you let me have just the suitcase.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERCUT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The postcard photograph marked X -- THIS IS ME.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESK CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We keep everything. House rules.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woman stares at Joe blankly. The boy runs a toy mouse across the table, up his mother's arm and around her face. With a polite nod, Joe opens the crackers and squirts one with ketchup. Joe upsets his chair as a great gob of ketchup spills onto his pants...</context>
      <utterance>Y'ain't gonna eat them?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... glancing around with an embarrassed laugh, but the only one looking is a cop, scratching his calf with a night stick. Joe keeps his back to the customers as he moves to the water dispenser, wets a paper napkin and tries to wipe away the stain. But the water has only spread the stain across his pants and down his leg. He blushes as a blonde young streetwalker giggles.</context>
      <utterance>Shee-it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY BUCK'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wet your britches, lover boy?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MIDDLE-AGE LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do I get to Grand Central?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Automatically,checking the trough of a gum vending machine, Joe unexpectedly faces himself in the mirror, the eyes staring at him tired and hopeless. His hand reaches unconsciously for a cigarette, The package is empty. He crumples it in his fist but holds it.</context>
      <utterance>Shuttle. Follow the green light.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, cowboy. Enough of this shee-it. You know what you got to do?  Then go do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANASTASIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... the remembered passion continuing, mounting -- intercut with flash impressions, like flipping pages of a nudie magazine -- naked, half-draped blondes gazing into camera with sultry eyes, including one comic strip sexpot and the calendar girl in Joe's Texas hotel room...</context>
      <utterance>You're the only one, Joe, the only, only one ever!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANASTASIA'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... Joe's face in extreme close-up, sounds of both movie houses merging, confused, dominated by the voices of adolescent boys...</context>
      <utterance>You're the best, the very best, yes, yes, kiss me, oh God please kiss me, Joe, now, now, now!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOYS' VOICES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... an adolescent ratpack waiting in line behind the screen, laughing in coarse whispers, watching Joe and Anastasia. O.S. theremin voices call "Earthling, where are you?"</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Joe, give someone else a chance! What's he doing for chrisake? He kissing Anastasia? You better swallow a whole goddam drugstore, man!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm awful damn sorry you're sick, kid, but you gonna have to gimme that money like you said.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What're you going to do to me?</context>
      <utterance>I was lying. I don't have it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much's that worth?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Joe has already kicked open the door. Theremin voices drown out the Fat Boy, calling "Earthling, where are you?"</context>
      <utterance>I can't go home without my watch! My mother'd die! She'd die! Take my books! Not my watch! She'd die!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BONNER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe appears in full figure as the bus passes. He stands looking at the suitcases in a luggage shop window.</context>
      <utterance>Why call me, baby? If you want to do it; just do it, don't talk about it. Are we drunky? Feeling a little sorry for ourselves maybe?</utterance>
   <speaker>DESPERATE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Bill, what I got thinking, I didn't want the neighbors to have to find me, this young couple with the boy I want to have my cat, see, Bill?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe's hand falls on Ratso's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Don't hit me, I'm a cripple.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cigarette in Ratso's mouth burns into his lip. He jerks spasmodically, choking on smoke as he rips skin away with the butt and drops it in his coffee cup.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I ain't gonna hit you, I'm gonna strangle you to death...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Coughing, eyes tearing, Ratso empties his pockets on the counter, finally producing: sixty-four cents, a few sticks of gum, an almost empty cigarette package, a book of matches and two pawn tickets. He raises his eyes, somehow ashamed. Joe kicks the toe of Ratso's loafer.</context>
      <utterance>... only first I'm gonna turn you upside down and shake you out right here and now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's in your socks?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ratso removes his loafers and shakes them, glancing at the counter man. His socks don't even conceal his toes. Disgusted, Joe shoves Ratso's small pile back at him.</context>
      <utterance>Not a cent, I swear to God, I swear on my mother's eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You keep the sixty-four cents. I want you to have it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe should leave -- Ratso obviously has nothing tangible to offer -- but Joe hesitates, lighting a cigarette as Ratso pulls on his loafers.</context>
      <utterance>It's sticky. What you do, slobber on 'em? I wouldn't touch 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ratso touches his chest, forcing a cough which continues itself beyond his intention.</context>
      <utterance>How do you like that O'Daniel, flipping out like that? I wanted to get in touch with you when I heard, but I been laid up with this cold...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want some free medical advice, shut your goddam mouth about that night.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, right, right, okay. Another subject. Where you living? Still at the hotel?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shee-it. I got better things to do than talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... Ratso hop-skipping to overtake Joe at the traffic light.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, wait up, for crissake!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, keep away from me, hear? You come near me again, I snatch you bald-headed!</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm inviting you. I mean if you're not located, I got a place. I'm inviting you, goddamit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You inviting shee-it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ratso fills a saucepan from the tub-sink, sets it on a Sterno stove. Joe sits himself on the mattress-bed, pretending to test it, weeks of exhaustion and tension overwhelming him suddenly, his only immediate problem being the effort to restrain a large, comfortable yawn.</context>
      <utterance>I got no heat, but by that time, you know, cold weather, hey, I'll be in Florida. Stretch out. Make yourself comfortable. You hungry? I'll put up some water for coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe stretches himself, yawning, his eyelids drooping heavily. The sounds of the city recede. Joe's love theme plays softly on a distant radio. Joe's eyes close momentarily in spite of him elf.</context>
      <utterance>Comfortable, kee-rist, I slept on subways softer than this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smart thing for me to do is haul ass outta here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe shivers, pulls a blanket around him, resisting sleep, but the noises of demolition fade, the love theme lures Joe back.</context>
      <utterance>Whatsa matter now?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't seem like no fag...</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe's eyes close, his voice continuing out of half-sleep.</context>
      <utterance>What's that supposed to mean?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANASTASIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say you love me. Just say it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anastasia purrs as her lips find Joe's breast, trying to nurse. A flashlight flares suddenly through the car window.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NIGHTMARE - MULTIPLE SPLIT SCREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Full frame -- Anastasia catatonic in hospital gown -- a woman's voice "What'd he do to you, Annie?"... ... gang-bang ratpack surrounding car with flashlights... ... Jackie shrieking "He loves her he loves her"... ... hands closing on Joe's buttocks... ... hand closing on Joe's naked left foot... ... hand on naked right foot... ... dentist leaning over Joe's mouth... ... hands pulling Joe's legs apart... Zoom close-up -- Anastasia screaming soundlessly... ... thermometer under Little Joe's tongue... ... Sally Buck shoves chocolate in her mouth... ... bewigged poodle licks her fingers... ... Sally Buck hangs enema can on bedpost... ... Ratso leads ratpack chasing naked Anastasia... ... corona of flashlights... Anastasia screaming soundlessly -- flashlight shoved into her mouth -- electronic rock blasting... ... blank-eyed go-go girl in dance hall window... ... Joe held naked by ratpack... ... Ratso breaking beer bottle on Everett's bar... ... dwarf laughing on television... ... Ratso aims broken bottle at Joe's crotch... ... shooting gallery cowboys riddle Joe's pelvis... Anastasia catatonic in courtroom -- between gaunt parents - whining singsong "Raped her raped her Joe Buck raped her"... ... Fat Boy's mouth finds Joe's breast, tries to nurse... ... Sally Buck kisses him open-mouthed... ... slug crawls up Joe's stomach, trailing mucus... ... Cass's poodle laps at his toes... ... butterflies settle on his eyes... Anastasia catatonic in courtroom between parents -- who are now O'Daniel and Sally Buck... ... drawling voice "evidence of repeated violations"... ... Bill Bonner in flag-cloth judge's robe... ... police advancing, swinging night sticks... ... Joe running into Times Square, suddenly naked... ... Anastasia sitting in all-night cafeteria... ... freaky child running toy mouse over her naked body... Siren screaming -- Anastasia staring catatonic from rear window of ambulance... ... ambulance racing away... ... Joe chasing naked after ambulance... ... running into the arms of the police... ... Ratso laughing as police beat Joe...</context>
      <utterance>Low angle Ratso bending over Joe, into camera... ... Sally Buck shocked, hand still on switch... ... Joe blinded by halation... ... Anastasia's mouth screaming soundlessly... ... flashlights multiplying on car window...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Still wild-eyed, Joe suddenly points at his stocking feet.</context>
      <utterance>For crissake!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's my boots -- ?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>JOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd they get off me?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I took 'em off.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What for?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe inspects the boots, seats himself on a battered Army cot - which has been added while he slept -- swinging a boot by its strap, considering whether to stay or go.</context>
      <utterance>So you could sleep! I mean Christ!</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I drug in a cot, if you want to stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ratso offers a cigarette from his crushed package, Joe strikes a match on his thumbnail and lights up, staring at Ratso.</context>
      <utterance>Well now, Ratso, I'm gonna tell you something for your own good, only first gimme a cigarette.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want me to stay here tonight, is that the idea?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't forcing you, like, I mean, who's forcing you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe makes a slow move to pull on one boot.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Guess I got the wrong impression.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to stay, okay? I goddam invited you, didn't I?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I hope you know what you're in for. I'm a very dangerous person. Someone does me bad like you. If I caught up with you that night, there'd be one dead Ratso long about now. Hear?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm impressed. You're a killer.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe yawns, picks up a few blankets and spreads them on the cot. He puzzles out the faded printing on one blanket.</context>
      <utterance>So if you want me to hang around for a few days, I thought you should know.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ratso blows out the candle and wraps himself in blankets.</context>
      <utterance>Property of the YMCA. You make me wanna puke sometimes, Ratso.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Joe -- do me one favor -- this is my place, am I wrong? You know, in my own place my name ain't Ratso. I mean it so happens my name is Enrico Salvatore Rizzo.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shee-it, man, I can't say all that.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rico then, at least call me Rico in my own goddam place.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rico! Rico! Rico! Is that enough?  And keep your meat hooks off my radio.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GREENGROCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other shoppers deliberately turn their backs, avoiding involvement. As the Greengrocer grabs Ratso, Joe ambles into the scene, wearing his dangerous little smile.</context>
      <utterance>You! Out! Out! I told you, I calla cops!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe intervenes just long enough for Ratso to escape, then ambles on, leaving the Greengrocer in frustrated fury. Camera holds on a tray of coconuts.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, looka here, that ain't nice, picking on a cripple...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The two basic items necessary to sustain life are sunshine and coconut milk. That's a known fact. If I can find the goddam hole the milk squirts out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is an okay setup you got here, but I'd say you ain't just exactly, uh, flush, is that right or not?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe takes his time rising to hold the coconut while Ratso tries to poke a hole with a bent ice-pick.</context>
      <utterance>I been sick. Hold this, will ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Tough, hey?</context>
      <utterance>In Florida, they come smooth, ready to eat. Down there, your only problem is, diet-wise, you gotta lift an arm to wipe warm milk off your chin.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe jerks his hand away just in time to avoid the ice-pick. The coconut bounces on the floor. Ratso picks it up, holds it, while Joe tries to crack it, swinging his boot like a hammer.</context>
      <utterance>I think finding you's the smartest thing I ever did, for both of us. You just the crooked kinda sneaky little sidewinder I need to get me hustling in this town. Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miami Beach is the only place for a real hustler. Florida has more rich chicks per square yard than any resort spot in the world. They lie out in their pagodas and pergolas waiting to grab the first jockstrap that passes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe swings violently. Ratso yelps, hopping on his one good leg, sucking his thumb.</context>
      <utterance>What's all this sweet talk about Florida? Your friend O'Daniel got a stable down there now?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ratso holds his thumb under the tub-sink faucet.</context>
      <utterance>Cowboy killers! Break my finger, Christ! I got news for you, baby, no chick with any class buys that big dumb cowboy crap...</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Joe holds the coconut like Yorick's skull, thinking hard.</context>
      <utterance>... the cowboy bit's out, except among fags of a certain type, which take a certain, type hustler to exploit. Like I could handle it -- being a stealing operation basically -- but take your average fag, very few of them want a cripple.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe sets the coconut on the floor, holding it with both hands while he tries to smash it with the heel of his boot.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I am dumb, that's for sure. I don't talk right. I can't think too good. Just only one thing I ever been good for's loving. Women go crazy for me. Fact. Crazy Annie. Had to send her away. So I don't cash in on that, what am I? I'm shee-it. May's well flush me down that hole with the dishwater.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why you gonna stop crapping about Florida and get your skinny butt moving to earn twenty bucks worth of management you owe me...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at yourself, Joe, no offense, but frankly, you're beginning to smell. For a stud in this town that's a handicap.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ratso sets the coconut on the window sill, balancing it as he raises the X window.</context>
      <utterance>You talk like a man with a tin twat.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ain't got a chance in hell. You need threads and glitter, baby. A front, hey?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe slams, the window down. The coconut flies down to crash O.S. on the sidewalk below.</context>
      <utterance>Well, uh, my manager's gonna manage all that crap, or else he gonna get a coconut up his flue.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... adroitly slipping Joe's cleaning in with her load as she turns to seat herself beside Joe.</context>
      <utterance>A woman in your condition shouldn't do that. Let me help...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It ain't right, stealing from a pregnant lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The owner brings Joe's clean and blocked Stetson from the rear of the shop. Joe sets it on his head and examines himself in a mirror as the owner hands Ratso, the bill.</context>
      <utterance>What did it cost her? The laundromat syndicate lost a couple coins. I'm crying.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The owner glances at the slip, puzzled, returns to the rear of the shop to search for the nonexistent homburg. Ratso quickly drags Joe away from the mirror and out of the shop.</context>
      <utterance>Where's mine? The black homburg? I brought it in the same time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, you're good! I bet you could pick up a living at this if you tried.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ratso demonstrates a chimpanzee walk. Joe laughs. Ratso turns back in panic as another man takes a chair next to Joe. Ratso is about to retuse when a cop takes the third chair, swinging his handcuffs around to the front, tapping his shoe with his night stick. Ratso quickly drops a rag over the broken padlock, cursing under his breath as he starts working on all three customers at the same time.</context>
      <utterance>And end up a hunchback like my old man? You think I'm crippled? You shoulda caught him the end of a day.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think it's funny?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As if by conditioned reflex, Ratso chokes on the cigarette in his mouth, coughing painfully. He crushes it out, opens the window to spit, shivering, then slam it and turns back to remove the towel from Joe's neck.</context>
      <utterance>Stupid bastard coughed his lungs out breathing that resin all day. They buried him with gloves on. Even the fag undertaker couldn't get his nails clean.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kee-rist, you pretty damn clever for a skimpy little gimp.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like it? Take a look.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe performs his ritual as he speaks, but more relaxed, faintly laughing at himself with Ratso. The wall mirror has been added since we last saw the flat, along with a legless overstuffed chair with burnt-out cushions, a tasselled table cover, pinups, calendar girls and several new Florida tourist posters, Ratso moves to Joe's side, arranging the neckerchief, nodding.</context>
      <utterance>Don't rush me. How I do it, see, I get myself primed, like I was turning on the charm for some pretty little blonde lady, then kinda mosey away slow and easy and - swing around! -- and there you are, you handsome devil.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not bad -- for a cowboy -- you're okay, you're okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe slaps his hat on Ratso's head, tilts it, hooks Ratso's thumbs in his jeans and shoves a cigarette into the corner of Ratso's mouth. Ratso laughs till he chokes -- for one instant, self-consciously, mimicking Joe -- then removes the hat and reaches for his threadbare black raincoat.</context>
      <utterance>What I'm gonna do, I'm gonna make a cowboy outta you, kid. How about that? Build you up a little, teach you couple little tricks'n turn y'out to stud, Rat-stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, you got yourself one handsome, sweet-smelling cowboy, strut your stuff...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. McNeill, I'm calling for Miss Beecham at the Barbizon Hotel for Women. She won't need you tonight...</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe and Ratso watch from across the street.</context>
      <utterance>Would you believe a whole goddam hotel with nothing but lonely chicks?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe cracks his gum, tilts his hat, starts across the street.</context>
      <utterance>Score once in that setup, the way chicks talk, Christ...</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>In Ratso's eyes -- as Joe enters the hotel -- its facade suddenly wipes away to reveal rich ladies in negligee waiting in every room.</context>
      <utterance>Get the money! Remember Cass Trehune? Cash! These rich bitches write a check at night, call the bank and stop payment in the morning. Get the cash!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the movies?</context>
      <utterance>Shee-it. Cough yourself inside out, then light a fag, a goddam fag. You make me puke. Where'd you steal it?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The coat? A guy I did a favor once gave it to me. Christ.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe slams ten dollars on the table. Ratso glances at Joe with curious concern.</context>
      <utterance>Who'd you ever do a favor for? You just let some poor bastard freeze to death, wouldn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd that come from?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forty-second Street. Where'n hell you think it come from?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ratso pulls off the coat and throws it at Joe.</context>
      <utterance>You wanna know the truth? You dumb bastard, I got it for you. Look at it. Goddam thing's ten sizes too big for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe throws it back at Ratso.</context>
      <utterance>Wear it yourself. I wouldn't put it on my back.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ratso hurls it in a corner. Joe shoves the ten at Ratso.</context>
      <utterance>Goddamned if I'll wear it!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go get your medicine. Before you die on my goddam, hands...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shee-it. I hate boneyards.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So split. He ain't your goddam, father.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kee-rist, you sure are one twisty little bastard, Ratso.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The name's Rico, at my own father's grave, a man deserves some respect.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Respect shee-it! You even steal flowers for his grave.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe reads from the ribbon on the floral display.</context>
      <utterance>Can he smell the difference, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, uh, he dam well know he ain't 'be-loved Aunt Winifred'.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe is frowning, standing at the,headstone, momentarily depressed with an undefined sorrow.</context>
      <utterance>He can't read. Even dumber than you. Couldn't write his own name. X -- that's what it ought to say there on that goddam headstone. One big lousy X like our flat. Condemned. By order of City Hall.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My Grammaw Sally Buck, she died without letting me know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the background, as Ratso speaks, HANSEL and GRETEL MACALBERTSON enter the lunch counter, inspecting the customers one by one. Both wear black turtlenecks and jeans, dressed as twins, both blond and pretty.</context>
      <utterance>Just ain't right, cheating someone dead and can't cheat back.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Conditioned reflex, Ratso starts to cough. Joe sees the MacAlbertsons in the mirror, standing behind him, studying him. Gretel nods, Hansel hands Joe a large black card, smiling vaguely, then moves on.</context>
      <utterance>You and my old man. Same kinda mind. Putting me down till the day he died...  ... why can't you be like your brothers? Sons a father could be proud of. Yeah, sure. My brothers. Too goddam busy making something of themselves to show up when the old man's dying!</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Joe studies the black card, frowning at first, suddenly smiling, turning as if to call after the MacAlbertsons, but they are disappearing around the corner. Joe hands the card to Ratso.</context>
      <utterance>What was that all about?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shocking pink letters on the black card read YOU ARE INVITED</context>
      <utterance>You wanna read something, read this. I been invited somewhere.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They picked me. The only one in the whole goddam place. You see how they looked me over, up and down before they give me that?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe sees a young man washing cups behind the counter. Joe shakes his head, wonderingly, turning to study himself in the mirror.</context>
      <utterance>So?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, this thought just struck me. It wasn't too long ago I was washing dishes way the hell somewhere in Texas.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, so?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now I'm here. I'm in New York City. Getting picked for things. Don't you see what I'm driving at?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you're driving at, you want me to get lost so you can go to your fancy-ass party.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did I say that? Did I?  It don't say nothing about you...</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't say nothing about you either.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But they picked me, right? So what I'll do, I'll just say, now look, you want me? Well, I don't go nowhere without my buddy here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what the hell, I got nothing better to do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe pulls out his shirttail, grabs Ratso by the neck and rubs his head dry.</context>
      <utterance>Better dry your hair some. You sweating all over the goddam place.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a comb?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't need a comb.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe hands Ratso his own comb. Ratso swipes at his tangled hair angrily until two teeth break in the comb. He hands the comb back, tugs at his hair with his fingers, pats it in place, then looks back into Joe's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Few dozen cooties won't kill me, don't guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In a moment of silence, distant sounds can be heard -- a siren, the grinding teeth of a garbage truck, the twang of an electric guitar upstairs at the party -- then Ratso makes a quick gesture of impatience and starts up the stairs, pulling himself on the bannister.</context>
      <utterance>Okay? I look okay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ratso points to his ear -- he can't hear -- following Joe across the room. The huge loft is crowded with a random selection, gathered to serve as dress extras in an underground film. The party is the scene. The MacAlbertsons merely supply the ingredients and allow it to happen, with cameras strategically placed to record the happening... ... Hansel with tape recorder, Gretel with hand-held camera drifting through the crowd -- catching words and images in a detached, whimsical fashion. Gretel turns her camera on Joe and Ratso as they approach.</context>
      <utterance>Better get a hold of someone and tell them I'm here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I made it. This here is Ratso Rizzo and I...</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gretel smiles without recognition. Hansel gestures vaguely.</context>
      <utterance>Rico. Rico Rizzo.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANSEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The twins move away together, pausing to confer with the operator of a tripod camera -- focused on an emaciated flower girl with long hair and dirty feet, stretched in a sarcophagus, clutching a dead daffodil, her eyes glazed. Scrawled in huge letters on the wall over her head -- LOVE!</context>
      <utterance>Do you need anything? I mean there's beer and so forth. Whatever your thing is...</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ratso heads for the refreshment table. Joe starts after him but pauses, intrigued by an alcove under the balcony where a light show is in progress -- surreal images of naked bodies projected against abstract currents of color and strobe light... ... a bored fat lady in a muu-muu, squatted like a Buddha at a low table, rolling joints for the guests. She lights a joint and offers it to Joe as he wanders in to watch the show. Joe laughs delightedly when he realizes what it is...</context>
      <utterance>If you want the word on that brother and sister act, I'll give you the word. That Hansel's a fag and Gretel's got the hots for herself. So who cares, right? Load up on the salami...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... glancing around at the others, imitating their techniques -- the quick inhaler, who follows with sharp gulps of air - the deep inhalers who draw air as they inhale -- the stylist who lets the smoke drift out and inhales through the nostrils -- Joe puffing himself slightly dizzy, starting to laugh at the silent flick effect of the strobe light -- the action around him slowing almost imperceptibly, overcranked -- a veil of smoke hanging over the fat woman's face, transforming her into a laughing witch -- a similar veil around Joe's head, relaxing the self-conscious tension of his face, spontaneously curious about the play of light on his hand, grinning at... ... a serious young technician handling the light show, scattering psychedelic stars across a sky of magenta flesh... ... Joe reaching for the stars as he rises and wanders back to the crowded loft, fascinated to see... ... a crew with cameras and lights, on the balcony at one end of the loft, photographing the scene below... ... a dark-haired lady by the name of SHIRLEY -- chic in the style of a gangster's moll -- drinking beer from the bottle, predatory eyes searching the crowd... ... Ratso surreptitiously stuffing his pockets from the buffet table, glancing nervously over his shoulder, unaware of Gretel and her hand-held camera, photographing Ratso as he steals, turning away casually, disinterested... ... Joe laughing as he dances for a moment with a tall black girl -- the lights swinging around them -- faces swimming... ... Shirley in fleeting close-up, gone in an instant, reappearing...</context>
      <utterance>Shee-it, this is one helluva party!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SHIRLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can tell, can't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, oh yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHIRLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe grins, watching Shirley's lips move, unable to keep her in sync, startled to hear Ratso's voice.</context>
      <utterance>What'll we do? Leave now or what? Your place or mine? Oh God, the second I looked at you I knew. Did you?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's hooked...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Joe is watching with terrible fascination as Hansel and Gretel lift the flower girl from her sarcophagus.</context>
      <utterance>... I'd say she was good for ten bucks, but I'll ask for twenty...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHIRLEY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe glances down to see himself flanked by Ratso and Shirley.</context>
      <utterance>Did you know? We were going to make it?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really want to do business?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHIRLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The flower girl, hypnotically dazed, accepts a broom dipped in black paint and smears a huge X across LOVE. Joe laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Who's he? Oh God! Don't tell me you two are a couple -- ?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANSEL'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hansel holds a microphone toward Joe, who shrugs, grinning at Ratso and Shirley. Gretel's camera moves down Joe's body.</context>
      <utterance>Why are you laughing, Joe?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANSEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you for real, Joe?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shirley glances at Ratso, who nods, whispering in her ear.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I ain't a f'real cowboy, but I'm one hell of a stud!</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The scene -- from Joe's viewpoint -- becomes increasingly confusing and fragmented, dialogue and image moving in and out of focus, cameras and lights surrounding him, keeping the center of attention in his own blown mind... ... Shirley's eyes unnaturally bright, inspecting his body, lingering on his thighs, moistening her lips...</context>
      <utterance>A very expensive stud. And I happen to be his manager.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHIRLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... the tall black girl dancing in stroble light, starting to remove her clothes -- Gretel following her with a camera...</context>
      <utterance>It's too much -- to come face to face with a walking talking sex fantasy -- to buy a man's -- God!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHIRLEY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... Shirley's talon-like fingernails caressing the gooseflesh on her tanned arm...</context>
      <utterance>I can't wait to tell my man Monday. I should be taking notes. Look at my arm!</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ratso stretched out on a Victorian love seat -- the flower girl walking unsteadily, passing out dead daffodils, placing one in Ratso's hand Gretel photographing his reaction...</context>
      <utterance>I gotta sit down. I feel crummy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHIRLEY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... Shirley bringing Joe a massive sandwich on a paper plate, watching him bite into it...</context>
      <utterance>Eat it -- a man in your line of work has to keep his strength up...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHIRLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... the tall black girl and a few others are trying to promote an orgy. A scrofulous old wino dances spastically, working his toothless gums, preparing to expose himself to two girls dancing together...</context>
      <utterance>It's fantastic, now I know, everything you do has sexual implications. If I you know, bought it -- could I take pictures of you naked? That's part of it, isn't it, kinky kinda things?</utterance>
   <speaker>HANSEL'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... five youths stand beside the sarcophagus -- two sailors, two cycle freaks, a weight-lifter -- waiting to be pallbearers. Joe joins them. All lights and cameras are turned on the slow funeral procession, carrying the flower girl out of the loft to the tune of "Moonlight and Roses". Strobe light adds to the unreality of the scene...</context>
      <utterance>We want you, Joe. You've been chosen.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHIRLEY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... Shirley talks to Gretel as she photographs the funeral.</context>
      <utterance>I had a thing for him. Before I knew. Why should knowing make it more of a thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHIRLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naturally I'll have to ask myself why a cowboy? And why a cowboy whore? But not tonight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SHIRLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe turns to Ratso, whose attention is fixed on the coats.</context>
      <utterance>Incidentally, how much is this going to cost me anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell her, Ratso.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty bucks...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHIRLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sold. Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... and taxi fare for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHIRLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get lost.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes a dollar from her purse and hands it to Ratso, takes Joe's arm and starts down the stairs. Ratso lingers, starting quickly through the coats, frisking them for loose change.</context>
      <utterance>I agree. And for that service I charge one dollar taxi fare.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SHIRLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They glance up as Ratso appears, swinging down too rapidly on the bannister. He misses a step and falls -- a clown's fall, unable to stop but apparently not hurting himself. Shirley and Joe are laughing when Ratso lands at the foot of the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Your name's Joe. Which is fabulous. Joe could be anyone. Kiss me, Joe, move over, Joe, go away, Joe. It's just perfect.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHIRLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He fell. Hey, fella, you fell. Is he all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he all right!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if you're awright, why you hanging on the bannister. Can you walk or not?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Walk? Naturally I can walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHIRLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got taxi fare.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure you're all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said yeah! Yeah, yeah, yeah!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>SHIRLEY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shirley leans on one elbow, looking at Joe sympathetically, fighting an almost irrepressible desire to laugh. Still avoiding Shirley's eyes, Joe finds a cigarette on the side table, searches for matches.</context>
      <utterance>That happens. Don't worry about it...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's something never happened to me before, you can bet your bottom dollar. Uh, where's the matches, ma'am?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHIRLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe finds the matches, lights up and lies back, staring at the mobile as he smokes, still not looking at Shirley.</context>
      <utterance>Top drawer. Maybe if you didn't call me ma'am, things would work out better.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The repressed laugh finally breaks through. Shirley stifles it quickly as Joe sits up, looking at her.</context>
      <utterance>First goddam, time it ever quit on me. Fact.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I'm lying!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHIRLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Close on Joe -- watching Shirley closely, reacting.</context>
      <utterance>No. Of course not. Just something struck me funny...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHIRLEY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shirley composes her face, reaching out to touch Joe. But that doesn't help either. He reacts sharply.</context>
      <utterance>I just put myself in your shoes. I had this image of a bugler without a horn, a policeman without a stick, etcetera, etcetera and I...  I think I'd better shut up, I'm making it worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHIRLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe we should take a little nap, see what happens?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't sleepy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHIRLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Extreme close-up of Joe -- frowning, puzzled...</context>
      <utterance>I know. Scribbage!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... camera pulling back to show Joe concentrating on a game, spread out on the sheet, consisting of nine dice lettered on all sides, the object being to build as many words as possible, Scrabble fashion, while a sand timer counts the seconds. Shirley watches Joe's efforts to think with sympathetic amusement. The only word Joe has composed so far is MAN.</context>
      <utterance>Shee-it...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHIRLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's pretty Freudian, Joe.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? It's a perfectly good word, ain't it. How much time I got?  Goddam sand thing drive you crazy. Kee-rist. Spelling never was a very strong point with me. Even in school.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHIRLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you didn't talk so much, maybe you could think more.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe spells out MONY, down from the M in MAN.</context>
      <utterance>Talking helps. Don't talk, you get muddled in your head. Hey! Now you just look at this here!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHIRLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's an E in MONEY. If that's your word.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>M-O-N-Y -- I'm right! That's just exactly how they spell it up there on that big building, bet you could see it from here. M-O-N-Y.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHIRLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Never argue with a man.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shirley slyly trails the tips of her fingernails across Joe's chest as she leans over to study the game, breathing softly into his ear as she speaks.</context>
      <utterance>Y -- what in hell starts with Y?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHIRLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One predatory hand rests on his knee -- as if by accident - disarranging the sheet, talon nails lightly brushing his thigh.</context>
      <utterance>It can end in Y day, pay, lay -- hey, pay lay!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cut it out. That's cheating, teasing me so I can't think. Just one bitsy Y word and I gonna beat you!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHIRLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gonna beat me, Joe?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beat your butt, you don't lemme think!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHIRLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gay ends in Y. Fey. You like that -- gay fey -- is that your problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the end of his sentence is swallowed by Shirley, taking his kiss in her open mouth, crushed by its impact, an animal noise snarling deep in her throat -- the agonized alley cat wail of pleasure -- Joe's problem is solved. Joe's love theme swells triumphant. At the same time, Shirley half-rises, trying to force Joe's head down, her own on top. The issue is joined. Shirley has named the game. Her objective is to force Joe onto his back. Joe's objective is to retain his initiative. Camera ignores the classic action on the central front, concentrating exclusively on peripheral tactical maneuvers... ... Joe's elbows pinning her shoulders... ... her eyes bright, accepting the challenge... ... his tight smile revealing clenched teeth... ... her fingers searching out then tickling his underarm... ... Joe laughing as he falls lopsidedly... ... Shirley laughing triumphantly... ... his hand closing on her wrist... ... her talon-nails clawing the air... ... her toes walking up his calf... ... her legs suddenly locking around his knees... ... her free hand grabbing his hair... ... her shoulder rising as she forces his head back... ... her lips pressing down on his... ... his hand swatting an unidentified mass of flesh... ... her eyes popping, teeth clamping his ear lobe... ... his hand catching her ankle... ... her teeth losing the ear lobe as she screams... ... her foot appearing upside down beside her face... ... her talon-nails furrowing flesh, drawing blood... ... his head rearing back, roaring... ... both rolling to the floor, out of view... ... her feet suddenly flying up into view... ... her hand tugging rhythmically at the blanket... ... her other hand wildly exploring Joe's back... ... her ankles locking spasmodically... ... her eyes and mouth wide, gaping... ... the blanket suddenly ripping free, flying into the air as her arm flings itself around Joe... ... the bedclothes spilling down around them, muffling her ascending shrieks.</context>
      <utterance>I show you what problem --</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoopee ti yi yo...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHIRLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'll leave a key with the super...</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you just come here? I'll be working every night this week.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shirley opens her purse, savoring the moment. As she places the money in Joe's hand...</context>
      <utterance>Well, ma'am -- Shirley -- I sure hate to trouble you, but...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ratso opens the paper bag, trying to control his shivering, pulling out the socks and a suit of long underwear. He sees Joe watching him for a reaction. The best Ratso can do is a slight shake of his head.</context>
      <utterance>See what you think of that crap. I'll pour your soup. Got some of that junk you like to swill, too. Mentholatum. Aspirin. All that shee it...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. But while you was buying the underwear, I could have lifted the socks.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe hands Ratso the soup. Ratso seems steadied by the warmth in his hands. He nods, sipping the soup.</context>
      <utterance>You couldn't lift fly specks from a sugar bowl. Can you hold this?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But thanks.  Hey, Joe, don't get sore about this or anything. You promise?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't think I can walk.  I mean, I been falling down a lot and, uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm scared.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What of?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'll happen. I mean what they do to, you know, do with you -- if you can't -- ah, Christ!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ratso is trembling so violently that the sou, starts to slop over. Joe takes it and sets it on the table.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Cops. Or the -- how should I know?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Here it is. You gonna go see the doctor. I got nine bucks and twenty more Thursday and I gonna be riding high before you know it. So you gonna get you the best goddam doctor in this town and get yourself straightened out, that's what.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No doctors. No, sir. Not me. Doctors are like goddam auto mechanics. Fix one-thing, unplug another. Operate for piles and while they're there, they unscrew your liver. My old man, for God's sake, wasn't any sicker'n I am when he went to the doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, just exactly what the hell you think you're gonna do? Die on me?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to Florida, that's my only chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>How you gonna get to Florida?</context>
      <utterance>You know what's wrong with you? You got fevers. You kinky as a bedbug.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll find the money. If you just get me on the bus, that's all I ask.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just when everything's going my way, you gotta pull a stunt like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe sets his Stetson on his head.</context>
      <utterance>I don't even want you to go. Whaddya think of that? I got other plans for my life than dragging around some dumb cowboy that thinks he's God's gift to women. One twenty-buck trick and he's already the biggest stud in New York City. It's laughable.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I put you on that bus down to Florida tonight, that'll be the happiest day of my life!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TOWNY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... TOWNY -- a stout, round-faced man -- clasps Joe's hand between both of his own, like an old friend.</context>
      <utterance>Bravo...</utterance>
   <speaker>TOWNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Towny grips Joe's elbow, almost forcibly leading him away.</context>
      <utterance>How are you?  Townsend P. Locke, from Chicago. Call me Towny. I'm here to attend a paper manufacturers' convention and, frankly, to have a little fun, dammit...</utterance>
   <speaker>TOWNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Towny's mouth continues speaking at an incredible rate, but his words are drowned out momentarily by the grinder of a sanitation truck, chewing up a discarded Christmas tree with tinsel clinging to it. Towny is still talking when they've passed the truck.</context>
      <utterance>This is my first night in town and I'll consider it a ghastly omen clouding my entire ten days, if you don't consent to have dinner with me. Anywhere you like...</utterance>
   <speaker>TOWNY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... never mind how you're dressed. They know me. I'll say you're with the rodeo. There's always a rodeo in New York, dammit. Besides, you look very elegant...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TOWNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, dammit all, I just remembered, we'll have to eat in my room because I have this phone call coming at nine-thirty...</utterance>
   <speaker>TOWNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I like about you, you're such a wonderful conversationalist. So won't that be nice to have dinner sent up?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOWNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fifty years ago this was the only hotel in Manhattan. My mother always calls me at her bedtime, so I've got to be there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TOWNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A drink? I've got some nice gin. If you'd prefer something else, they'll send it up...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gin's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOWNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's so exciting. New York. The mad forward thrust of everything. My sense of time here is completely altered.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TOWNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes it seems to me time stopped twenty years ago. There was this war, there was this handsome young man with quite black hair and he was supposed to die. But he didn't. Isn't that amusing?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Towny's dialogue moves out of sync. Towny's eyes seem to look into camera -- from Joe's viewpoint -- but slightly past it. The quality of the scene grows increasingly disjointed as Joe glances around the room, looking for something to steal, losing personal contact with Towny, viewing him as an object to be used for a specific purpose.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOWNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enough about me. I'm through talking for the evening. Now I want to hear about conditions in the West. The romance of the West holds a tremendous power over me. Mother was actually a pioneer woman, can you believe it? When she calls, I'll introduce you and she'll be so thrilled.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>TOWNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe moves into frame past camera, standing in front of him, so that we can see the scene from behind Joe's waist.</context>
      <utterance>I was so childish with her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What d'you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOWNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you got me up here for?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOWNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Please.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, difficult, it's so difficult. You're a nice person, Joe -- I should never have asked you up -- a lovely person. Oh, how I loathe life. I loathe it. Please go.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want me to leave?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOWNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, yes. No, I mean yes please go. Help me to be good. Come back tomorrow. Promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to Florida.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOWNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You'll let me please...</context>
      <utterance>This is terrible. I meet someone who -- then -- wait, I want to give you a present. For your trip.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, I gotta have money.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOWNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Towny hurries across the room to the bedside table. Beside the telephone is a picture of a prosperous pioneer woman wearing a hearing-aid. Towny tries to conceal his movements as he takes a wallet from the drawer, lifts out a bill and tucks the wallet back and turns -- terrified to see Joe close behind him -- almost knocking the lamp off the table in his fright. Pressed against the table, protecting but calling attention to his wallet, Towny holds out the bill.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Yes. Of course. I should have thought. You shouldn't have to ask. That was thoughtless of me. Yes. Wait here...</utterance>
   <speaker>TOWNY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here. Don't even thank me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta have more'n ten. I gotta have fifty-seven dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOWNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I simply don't have it, Joe.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get outta my way.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOWNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Towny clutches the table, staring at Joe, shaking his head like a bad little boy. Joe backhands him angrily. Trying to duck the blow, Towny stumbles and slips to the floor, but grabs the table in his arms, watching Joe out of the corner of his eyes, whimpering. Joe grabs his hair, turning his face up.</context>
      <utterance>You're wasting your time. There's nothing in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe slaps him, but Towny clings more fiercely to the table as Joe tries to jerk it free. Joe strikes him with his fist.</context>
      <utterance>Let go. Let go of the table.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOWNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he clutches the table wildly. His mother's picture falls unnoticed. Joe stands in panic, sickened, unable to fulfill the role Towny has assigned him.</context>
      <utterance>I deserved that, I know I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOWNY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Towny's eyes shine, teeth clenched in a crazy smile, blood trickling from his nose. Suddenly Joe jerks the lamp free of its socket.</context>
      <utterance>I brought this on myself. I'm bleeding, my nose is bleeding, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Towny simply stares at the lamp.</context>
      <utterance>You wanna gimme fifty-seven dollars or you wanna busted skull?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Joe threatens, swings the lamp down, but stops short of hitting Towny. Towny shrieks -- eyes rolling back as he falls limp -- loosing his grip on the table, leaning on the bed, laughing and crying hysterically. Joe has to step over him to reach the wallet in the drawer. He takes all the money -- probably twice what he needs -- desperate to get out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>Please let go of that table.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOWNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... provoking Joe to glance back. Towny is reaching for the telephone, his eyes on Joe with wild brightness, holding his hand on the receiver. Joe knocks the phone from his hand, hits Towny in the mouth, jerks the cord from the wall as Towny falls -- gagging -- finally dislodging his dentures on the carpet. Joe stands sick and confused, holding the useless phone in two hands...</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Joe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They ride a few moments in silence.</context>
      <utterance>Thirty-one hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Both nod for a moment in silence.</context>
      <utterance>The trip is. Nine-thirty in the morning we get there. Not this morning but the next one at nine thirty.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These guys're good drivers.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They gotta be.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You get your first palm tree in South Carolina.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'n hell a dumb Bronx kid like you know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I read it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shee-it. You believe all you read?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you have to shiver, why don't you pull the blanket up more?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I been thinking. I hope we're not gonna have a lotta trouble about my name down there. Because like what's the whole point of this trip anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep the goddam blanket on.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean New York's one thing, but can you see this guy, imagine it, running around the goddam beach all suntan and he's going in swimming, like, and then somebody yells 'Hey, Ratso' -- how does that sound to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds like they knew you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe nods. Ratso closes his eyes, momentarily at peace.</context>
      <utterance>Sounds like crap, admit it. And I'm not gonna have it. I'm Rico all the time, okay, do you blame me? That's agreed, okay? We're gonna tell all these new people my name's Rico?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey -- whatsa matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm wet.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're what?</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wet my pants! My seat's all wet.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell, don't cry about it!</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe laughs suddenly, uncontrollably.</context>
      <utterance>Here I am going to Florida and my leg hurts, my butt hurts, my chest hurts, my face hurts, and like that ain't enough, I gotta pee all over myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm falling apart, that's funny?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, what size pants you wear?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Waitress draws coffee, wraps crullers.</context>
      <utterance>Couple crullers'n coffee to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you from?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe pays. She smiles, gives him change. Joe smiles, starts on toward the bus, hardly aware that he has accomplished something rare and remarkable for Joe -- a simple human contact without fear or threat, a pleasant everyday happening.</context>
      <utterance>New York.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, what the hell you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both smile. It isn't funny enough to laugh at. Joe arranges the blanket, takes out a package of cigarettes, glances at Ratso and puts it away.</context>
      <utterance>I'm zipping your fly, what the hell you think I'm doing?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>RATSO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Joe.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Surreptitiously, Joe takes out a cigarette, turns his face away from Ratso and lights it, hiding it cupped in his hand as he smokes.</context>
      <utterance>Shee-it, you know, I got this thing all figured out, Ratso. I mean Rico. When we get to Miami, what I'll do, I'll go to work. I gotta do that, 'cause see, I ain't no kind of a hustler. I ain't even any goddam good as a bum. I'm a nothing, that's what I am. So reckon I'd better go to work and get me a goddam job. Okay? Joe glances at Ratso, but there is no response.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>They ride for a moment in semi-darkness, Joe smoking, looking at the other people on the bus, brighter without the shades down. Joe turns, checking the blanket around Ratso, noticing that Ratso is sitting in a peculiarly stiff, awkward position. Joe leans over to straighten Ratso's head, blocking our view for a moment. Then Joe leans back, frowning, thoughtful. We still do not see Ratso's face. Joe rises slowly, starting forward in the bus... ... passing an older couple, a schoolgirl, two ladies with straw hats, a young man trying to read, pausing when he reaches... ... the DRIVER, staring out at the Sunshine Parkway with the Driver, leaning over so he won't have to speak too loudly.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, guess that's what I'm gonna do.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE,</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My friend's dead in the back seat.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your friend's what in the back seat?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dead. Dead as a doornail.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances at Joe, then pulls off the road and stands up.</context>
      <utterance>Is this some kind of...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The passengers crane their necks as Joe follows the Driver to the rear of the bus. The passengers at the rear are staring ahead, trying not to see what is going on. The Driver touches Ratso, straightens, touches his hat, but doesn't remove it.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, folks, everything's fine. Nothing to worry about.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Joe nods no.</context>
      <utterance>Is he kin to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you want to close his eyes?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Close them?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joe closes Ratso's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Just reach over and close them. That's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Nothing else to do.</context>
      <utterance>I guess we'll just drive on, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Driver moves to the front and turns to the passengers.</context>
      <utterance>No, sir. Not till Miami. I'll see to burying then.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a little sickness, folks, nothing serious. We'll be in Miami...  ... in forty minutes.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
