<movie id="388" title="Midnight Express">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LOUDSPEAKER VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILL walking down a long CORRIDOR. He moves somewhat stuffly in the clothes we saw laid out on the bed; his face complicated by dark, rather ridiculous aviator sunglasses and an increasing edge of nervousness to his actions. With him is: SUSAN 23, healthy outdoor looks, dressed casually colorful like an American student abroad. APPROACHING P.O.V. - a group of TURKISH SECURITY GUARDS, in rumpled green uniforms, at a security CHECKPOINT inspect the carry-on bags of several PASSENGERS. BILLY tensely contemplating the guards as he walks. SUSAN digging in her bag for her passport as she walks. BILLY, looking from guards ahead to SUSAN. He suddenly breaks stride, still a fair distance from the checkpoint. SUSAN glances at him. He is holding his belly.</context>
      <utterance>Pan American Flight 1 to Frankfurt, London, and New York has arrived and will be ready for boarding at Gate 7 in 20 minutes. REPEAT IN ENGLISH over:</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I've been poisoned.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you ate two baclavas, right? I not to touch them, mine was awful.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY PASSPORT. The Guard's tobacco-stained FINGERS take it open it. Basic information on Billy: Birth Date April 17, 1949. Birth Place: Babylon, Long Island. No wife, no minors. Signature. GUARD gives it back to BILLY.</context>
      <utterance>Passport!</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY opens his shoulder bag, proffers it. The GUARD tosses it, pushing aside books, grabbing a white plastic dish.</context>
      <utterance>Bag!</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nebu?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a frisbee.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nebu?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Curious, one of the other GUARDS ambles over looking at the frisbee. BILLY tightens. Cursing the frisbee. Sweat now runs his sideburns again. HEARTBEAT up.</context>
      <utterance>A Frisbee.  You throw, catch it. Game!</utterance>
   <speaker>2ND GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>American game. Baseball.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE SECOND GUARD studies BILLY curious about the sweat. Suddenly reaches up, indicates the eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Ah!</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY understanding the gesture rather than the words, removes his glasses. His eyes. Straight, staring at the GUARD without trying to look away. A long moment. FIRST GUARD stuffs the frisbee back into the bag. Scowls. Takes a puff on his cigarette, coughs. Phlegm rattles around in his throat. Reads the International Herald Tribune, seated on a crowded olive-colored out on the tarmac She has saved him a seat and pulls her bag off as BILLY sits down.</context>
      <utterance>Take off the glasses.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He waves BILLY through. BILLY puts his glasses walks past the back the SECOND GUARD turns away. BILLY walks past the Checkpoint. His HEARTBEAT drops. SUSAN reads the International Herald Tribune, seated on an crowded olive-colored BUS out on the tarmac. She has save him a seat and pulls her bag off as BILLY sits down.</context>
      <utterance>Aaaah!</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her. Relief. A smile, awkward - he wishes he could tell her.</context>
      <utterance>Are you all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lays his head back on the wooden bench. Reaches out: TAKES HER HAND in his. She returns the grip. THE BUS DOOR slams shut. THE TURKISH BUS DRIVER rolls the bus out towards the PLANES visible in the far distance?. SUSAN, feeling Billy is better, shows him the Herald Tribune.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah... Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context>NEWSPAPER Picture of JANIS JOPLIN. That big, earthy, rugged smile. BILLY'S P.O.V. - Moves Up page One To The Headline: NIXON</context>
      <utterance>Overdose, in a Hollywood motel.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY, thinking other happier things, reaches over and playful!.:squeezes her tit twice, rapidly.</context>
      <utterance>Never Was anybody like Janis.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never was anybody like you...</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't take anything seriously.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bus stops suddenly. BILLY changes expression. THROUGH FRONT WINDSHIELD we see TURKISH SOLDIERS in several HALFTRACKS drawn up in a semicircle blocking the bus. The Pan American PLANE is directly behind. Also JEEPS and a POLICEMAN waving the bus down. BUS BOOR opens and the Turkish Police OFFICER hops aboard briskly:</context>
      <utterance>You're right.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PASSENGERS. A confused hum.</context>
      <utterance>Attention please, Ladies and Gentlemen. For your own safety we're conducting a security check before you board your airplane, Kindly file out the back. Women and children in one line. Men in another.</utterance>
   <speaker>VARIOUS PASSENGERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Turkish-speaking PASSENGERS are gathering together their items and beginning to exit as: POLICE OFFICER repeats, in ENGLISH</context>
      <utterance>What's he saying? I don't know... Marian. Hey Marian, what the hell...</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE BILLY. The POLICE OFFICER is only beginning the speech.in English but already Billy realizes, And it's panic. Silent panic. That horrendous cold feeling all over his back: Oh God what have I done, what can I do now? He freezes. MOVE TO SUSAN rising, fetching her things, irritated.</context>
      <utterance>Idem.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind her we see the other AMERICAN PASSENGERS beginning to disembark with the usual chorus of overlapped conversations, expletives, including:</context>
      <utterance>Jesus, they do everything ass backwards in Turkey.</utterance>
   <speaker>PASSENGERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laughter is returned from several of the American contingent, but we MOVE BACK to BILLY in foreground; all of a sudden he is on his knees trying to crawl under the seat.</context>
      <utterance>They're checking for hijackers. Any Palestinians aboard? Hey Harry, get rid of your grenades...</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Billy, what's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My passport!</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She bends down to look, coming FACE TO FACE with him. He grips her arm.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Susan - forget it. Go get us a seat on the plane. Now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it? . . . Billy?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TURK</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context>BILLY turns trying to seem casual; he confronts the SECOND OFFICER face to face and gestures towards the: FIRST OFFICER who happens to glance at them.</context>
      <utterance>Just a minute! BILLY his eyes flattening. SUSAN in LONG SHOT, reacting.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nebu? Did you search him?</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SECOND OFFICER tightens his grip on BILLY, angry, and pulls him back to the TABLE. MOVE with them. The officer has been lied to; in addition he is young, inexperienced, about eighteen.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AMERICAN PASSENGERS scream and the deck all around.</context>
      <utterance>Bomb! He's got a bomb!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMERICAN PASSENGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY stands there, arms straight up in the air, eyes clamped shut, trying not to breathe. CHORUS of rifle and revolver CLICKS OFF as: PULL BACK to OVERHEAD SHOT BILLY surrounded by thirty SOLDIERS with rifles pointed at him from all directions, crouched nervously. The PASSENGERS all huddled on the ground. BILLY, eyes closed. Edge of frame shows a shaky muzzle a REVOLVER poked into his belly, moving up. MOVE to THE FIRST OFFICER, older, more experienced but scared, poking with the revolver; reaches in with his hand cautiously, starts to pull up the turtleneck sweater. MOVE with the hand, revealing the HASHISH PLAQUES around the navel. A pause. His HAND draws the sweater higher. More</context>
      <utterance>Bomb! Bomb!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FIRST OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's hashish. just a smuggler.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is washed back along in the flow of passengers.</context>
      <utterance>...Billy...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FIRSTOFFICER</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Name?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context>MOVE BACK QUICKLY to the OFFICER with notebook at the desk. Part of the confusion is that each time we see another police officer we see he has another face.</context>
      <utterance>William Hayes.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vi... Vilyum... Vilyum...</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hayes.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(writes it down)</context>
      <utterance>Hi-yes...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FIRST OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Merican?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The OFFICER is puzzled.</context>
      <utterance>New York.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>New York... New York...</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(writes it down)</context>
      <utterance>Ahhhh...Nev Yok!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SECOND OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Name?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>William Hayes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vil... Vilyum...?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sharp SOUND OFF of FILM BEING RIPPED FROM CAMERA. He darts a look at POLICEMAN stretching the undeveloped film out. Another loud SOUND OFF, interrupting this-- THE DOOR flies open again and a THIRD OFFICER strides in, obviously the most important yet, because the SECOND OFFICER jumps up from the desk, and all the others immediately move down one seat in the hierarchy without a moment's hesitation. But the THIRD OFFICER strides right up to Billy, waves to the SECOND OFFICER. THE CAMERAMAN in background bubbles with enthusiasm, sliding into position. Billy is puzzled - what's going on? His arm is grabbed and he is swivelled around.</context>
      <utterance>Hayes...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CAMERAMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SECOND OFFICER slugs BILLY in the stomach with a quick back-handed fist. BILLY groans, sinks to his knees. The plaques fall on the floor.</context>
      <utterance>No.. He's smiling. Make him look miserable.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He growls, grabbing Billy's arm and hauling him up, gathering the hashish plaques and putting them back in his arms. The TWO OFFICERS put their arms back on Billy's shoulders. BILLY, in pain, makes the proper expression of misery. FLASH! The bulb goes.</context>
      <utterance>Gel? Gel??</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>THIRD OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>screaming at SECOND</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER)</speaker>
      <mode> OFFICER)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You idiot, you fool. You told me the American was searched... and he's pulling hashish out of his boots! You're all dogshit!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You worthless piece of garbage, where did you learn to search a prisoner? He's been in our custody for an hour, etc.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amid all the screaming TWO POLICEMEN rush over and yank BILLY upwards, and start to strip all his clothes.</context>
      <utterance>Who searched him? Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it! That's all I have!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context>A perfect Texas drawl. BILLY glances over his shoulder. Sees: TEX a tall, lanky blonde-haired American in a business suit with boots. Clean cut, very handsome, with a strong flavour of danger in his blue eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Howdy, Billy. Howya doing, Ok?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANOTHER ANGLE - BILLY, so grateful at last to see a fellow American, reaches quietly for the clothes, his eyes never leaving Tex. Release?</context>
      <utterance>I think these gentlemen have finished for the time being if you'd like to put your clothes on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY, standing to the side of the desk, clothed now, buckling his belt - afraid.</context>
      <utterance>Are you afraid, Vilyum?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm not afraid.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. There's nothing to be afraid of. If you co-operate with us, you will be on the plane for New York tomorrow... yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes...?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. Now, where did you get the hashish?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A cabdriver. He picked me up in the Pudding Shoppe in the bazaar.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you recognize him again?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. Would you go back to the Pudding Shoppe now and point him out to my men if you see him?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context>STREETS, ISTANBUL, AFTERNOON. TEX drives his American CAR; BILLY in the passenger seat; TWO TURKISH PLAINCLOTHESMEN in the rear seats . Various BACKGROUND SHOTS of the city.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You decided to fly at a bad time Billy Palestinian Guerrillas all over the place blowing up planes and all.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four planes in four days...but I guess you kids don't read the newspapers...and what with our people kicking up a shit storm 'bout the flow of heroin from Turkey you got...</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But didn't have heroin.</utterance>
   <speaker>TURK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I'm not up on all that. A drug's a drug seems to me Billy and...</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it was my first time. I'm not really a smuggler, was just two kilos.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you see Billy, it don't really matter right now if it's 2 kilos or 200 kilos. The Turks love to catch any foreigner smuggling - it shows the world they're fighting the drug trade.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But just...</utterance>
   <speaker>TEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It sounds bad. Tex looks at him without expression. Pause.Billy tries to sense a sympathy in this ambiguous man, a liking towards himself. But feels nothing yet, except someone who can speak English.</context>
      <utterance>I just needed some extra money. I was broke, the guy offered me the hash and...</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...are you with the Consulate?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANOTHER ANGLE - BILLY nervously takes the pack and matches.</context>
      <utterance>Something like that. Cigarette?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much you pay this joker... this cab driver?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two hundred dollars. It was my last two hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY fumbles to light up his cigarette. He is nervous, grateful to volunteer any information...anything.</context>
      <utterance>How much did you figure to make?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three, four thousand...I don't know. The guy offered me the hash--  ...it just seemed like easy money.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beats working.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TEX grins, sceptical of his naivete, changing the subject.</context>
      <utterance>I was just going to sell it to friends. I'm not a pusher, honest.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got a family back there?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Parents, brother, sister. Babylon, Long Island.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your father do?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He sells insurance for Metropolitan Life.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY nods, takes a deep drag on his cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>Be tough on 'em.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Girlfriend?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tex glances at him, questioningly.</context>
      <utterance>...She was on the plane.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She didn't know anything about...I wouldn't have wanted her to.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billy leans back in seat, blowing out the cigarette smoke.</context>
      <utterance>Lucky girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeez, she used to say I was the lucky one.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A narrow cobblestone STREET. TEX pulls the car to a halt.</context>
      <utterance>Let's hope so, Billy. Let's sure hope so.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ESTABLISH PRISON - OVERHEAD ANGLE. A large and Byzantine structure suggesting the 15th Century Sultan's Janissary Barracks. Irregular crescent various wings; a MOSQUE inside the prison. The possibly a shapes to the sense of an endless a decorative an equally in a city, labyrinth built by some mad Arab architect to suit purpose and now, in the 20th Century, transformed by mad Turkish bureaucracy into a prison. It should be preferably made to look like Istanbul. Faint background atonal Turkish CHANTING. Evening Muslim prayer."Allah wakbah, Allah wakbah..." on and on, suggesting to us fear rather than praise.</context>
      <utterance>You seem like a nice enough kid to me Billy, but try it and I'll blow your fucking brains out. BILLY - the sense of betrayal in his eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY - his scalp being shaved off by a prison BARBER in an un-specified ANTI-CHAMBER, His eyes are staring dead ahead.</context>
      <utterance>Dear Mom and Dad. This is the hardest letter I've ever had to write. know the confusion and the pain it will cause you. And the disappointment...</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY is now completely BALD, SOUND SHARP OVER:</context>
      <utterance>I really thought knew what I was doing with my life. I'd hoped somehow to get out of this quickly so that you'd never know about it. But that just isn't possible now. I don't know what's going to happen. But what can I say to you? Will 'I'm sorry' make a difference? Will it ease the pain, the shame you must be feeling? Forgive me...Please...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ZIAT VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context>The cell is dark, almost black, an overpowering stench; a small grey metal bunk is bolted to the floor with a lumpy mattress. BILLY turns, looking back at the man staring at him from the door. ZIAT is quickly summing up Billy's character. This is his craft.He is a prisoner and trustee. sinister man whose one motivation in life is the accumulation of money, in the pursuit of which he has acquired an ugly purplish SCAR running the width of his throat, various other facial SCARS; and one blind milky white EYE. He's stocky and strong -- about five ten, with bushy eyebrows, brown cigarette teeth, big dirty nails, repulsively in need of a bath. What's surprising is that he is no more than thirty years old looks and behaves like sixty. The personification of the denaturalization of a man. Time, body, mind - all of them warped. BILLY, not yet attuned to his nature, only repulsed, is still wearing his own clothes and makes a shivering gesture, enunciating very clearly, hoping he will understand.</context>
      <utterance>Git!</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ZIAT smiles, showing his stained teeth, and starts to slide shut the cell door on its ROLLER.</context>
      <utterance>Cold. Very cold. Can I get blanket? Blanket?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A cobra smile flashes, as the cell door bangs shut.</context>
      <utterance>Mo sell...Too late. Tomorrow...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY walks around the cell, hugging himself for warmth.</context>
      <utterance>You be here tomorrow. "Ayi Gedjaler" Goes.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context>BILLY stops, goes to the edge of the cell. A BONY BARE ARM motions from the bars of the cell next to his. We never see the face but hear a thick ITALIAN ACCENT, hoarse and cracked.</context>
      <utterance>Pssst!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context>BILLY takes it. Hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>Your cell, no key. Open...! Blanket. Three cell down. You get me one. Take... Extends a stick with a big nail pounded into the end, twisted over to form a hook.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context>BILLY cautiously slides the cell door open, amazed that it's been left open. Nothing makes any sense to him in this labyrinth ANOTHER ANGLE - BILLY steps out into a WALKWAY. A bare bulb overhead casts light. He glides past the three cells, seemingly empty. Finds the cell with blankets, sheets, towels and various supplies stacked inside. But it's locked. He slips the stick in between the bars and stretching, hooks the first blanket. BILLY asleep with the blankets pulled up to his chin. Suddenly DIRTY HANDS reach into frame and rip the blanket off. WIDEN TO:</context>
      <utterance>Ziat go for night. Go!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then SLAPS at BILLY. BILLY ducks away. Encouraged, ZIAT steps up closer to him, sticks his fingers in his chest screaming.</context>
      <utterance>Brack!...Brack!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And feints as if to hit BILLY again. BILLY reacts to defend himself, pushing ZIAT off and jumping out of the bunk. ZIAT, Enraged by the shove, comes back at BILLY, screaming, arms flailing like a bear to pummel him, but BILLY, not understanding the Turkish bluster in his mannerisms, meets him with a sharp right FIST into the front of his face. ZIAT staggers back, startled into silence; he has misjudged this kid. BILLY waits, ready for the fight in the defensive position. The guy is bigger than himself. ZIAT, however, now feels the blood from his mouth and nose and freaks out, running out of the cell SCREAMING at the top of his lungs as if he's dying.</context>
      <utterance>You, goddamn you, give me sheet. Give me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HAMIDOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Name?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vilyum Hi-yes</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMIDOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And slowly his hand moves up to caress the edge of his hairless upper lip. An erotic gesture in Turkey.</context>
      <utterance>Vilyum Hi-yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMIDOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>"Its in my memory locked." He slowly extends his right arm stiff out to his side. BILLY watches, fascinated. HAMIDOU lets the arm linger; then: SMASHES BILLY across the face with an open palm. BILLY shoots back: and smashes against the wall just from the force of one blow. Stunned. HAMIDOU advances, taking a wooden CLUB (FALUKA STICK) about feet three long and three inches wide from a GUARD. BILLY scared, emphasizing the words, trying to make himself understood.</context>
      <utterance>Vilyum Hi-yes</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was cold. Cold! I get blanket. Blanket! Cold!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey man, he's gotta walk, or his feet gonna swell up worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>2ND VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then: ERICH - a gentle long bird's face. Long whitish-blond- hair, Swedish, well above six feet, 25. Another FACE moves into view JIMMY BELL, American, 23 fiery eyes, black hair and moustache, intense, strong.</context>
      <utterance>We take him down to courtyard...</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANOTHER ANGLE - BELL puts a huge cone-shaped JOINT with aluminium foil filter into BILLY'S LIPS. He hardly knows what it is, Puffing weakly. Though dehydrated and his face white without color, he has no facial markings.</context>
      <utterance>Smoke this rocket, it'll cool the pain.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HIS FEET Bloated black and blue with inflamed red points in various spots. A vicious bruise on his anklebone. ERICH is running a cold rag from a basin of water over them, his fingers tender.</context>
      <utterance>You gotta walk around some man, or your feet gonna swell up something bad... BILLY looks down at</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context>BELL eases BILLY up from the bed, as ERICH puts a pair of clip-clops on his feet.</context>
      <utterance>You've been out for days man, talking all kinds of shit. Come on, we'll walk you down to the courtyard.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY nods. They rise together, bracing his shoulder. BILLY adjusting to the sensation of standing.</context>
      <utterance>Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's it feel?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About as good as it looks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Getchmis olsun</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Getchmis...?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Olsun - "May it pass quickly." I'm Bell, Jimmy Bell. This is Erich something Swedish.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just Erich.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A DORMITORY TYPE ROOM with 24 bunk beds set head to head in horizontal fashion, cramped and with minimal privacy. A narrow WALKWAY leading towards a TOILET AREA and STAIRCASE.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Billy Hayes... At least I used to be. Looks around.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like a cheap hotel.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE COURTYARD. The THREE of them emerge in a thin AFTERNOON sun, Billy now disengaging and hobbling on his own power.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah... Only the room service is lousy. Come on, let me show you the tennis courts. Helps him with ERICH to take the first steps.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Feeling all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. That guy who beat me?  I feel stoned.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Figgers.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...He had a bald skull and...</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY glances at him, understanding. Pause.</context>
      <utterance>Hamidou. Chief of the Guards. Don't fuck with him. He almost killed an Italian dude couple months ago. Bad news. He try anything with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Glances at ERICH.</context>
      <utterance>No... I don't remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With these fucking Turks, soon as the light goes out... I keep one hand on their feet and their feet better not grow. You'll meet Max. He got raped something bad down in Section 13. That's the pits.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The kids? Why are they...</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context>ZIAT leaves the stove in the hands of an ASSISTANT and moves down the window to a particularly gaudy AFGHANI a fierce hawk-faced old man with a chunk of his ear missing. He wears a colorful flowing robe, various scarves, turban, trinkets, rings, baggy pants, and pointed curved shoes, and makes emphatic violent gestures at ZIAT with his mutilated THREE FINGERS. ZIAT Seems to speak something of his language and bargains back.</context>
      <utterance>...They tell Ziat everything. He's the squeal round here. Goes all over the prison. Sells watered- down tea, blankets, hash, black money, nembutols --anything for a buck...</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context>BILLY turning his eyes away from ZIAT</context>
      <utterance>Whatcha' in for, smuggling? Rash?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>History, man, history. How much?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two kilos.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The airport. Trying to get on the plane for the States.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could be ten or fifteen. Maybe even twenty.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty months?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY stunned.</context>
      <utterance>Twenty fucking YEARS, man - YEARS! I figger ten at the least.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Years?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BELL snorts, amused, kicking the SOCCER BALL away hard as it dribbles towards them.</context>
      <utterance>Don't pay too much attention, anything is possible in Turkey. You might get bail.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...If you make bail, you're free. You can get a fake passport or sneak across the border to Greece. The Greeks hate the Turks so much they never send you back. The Turks know it. They just keep the bail. money.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, keep dreaming and see where that gets you... like Max, up in the head, you know...  You gonna eat a lot more fasoulia beans, Billy baby, 'fore you taste a hamburger 'gain cause you broke the law man, and you got caught...  And that... is history.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The law is sometimes wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>New people sometimes get on his nerves.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did he do?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>ERIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was caught steeling from a Mosque. That's heavy here. He got 30 years.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirty years?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BELL him across the courtyard huddling with a cigarette, bartering angrily. a raggedy GUARD giving him a cigarette, bartering angrily. BILLY and ERICH.</context>
      <utterance>Jimmy has more balls than brains. He didn't tell his parents he was in jail for a year and a half. He says he got himself in and now he's going to get himself out. He shakes his head, looking at:</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk.</context>
      <utterance>Hashish. Ninety percent of the foreigners are in for hashish.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What they give you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billy stops.</context>
      <utterance>Twelve years.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much did you have?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A hundred grams.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Even ERICH has to smile now.</context>
      <utterance>It's not fair!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is no fair in Turkey, Billy. It's all "sula-bula" like this, like that. An Italian hippie had a car accident and a Turk was killed. SO, they threw him in here for six months...</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That doesn't seem so bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But he was eating lunch a mile away when the Turk smashed into killed himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wasn't even in the car?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ASLAN - a young big fat heavily moustached Turk, wearing a black silk double-breasted business suit, grotesque cuff- links, heavily pomaded hair, is huddling in a section of the YARD with FIVE other grinning GANGSTER TYPES, all in suits.</context>
      <utterance>Aslan, there...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICH</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context>ERICH Glances back at BILLY</context>
      <utterance>Killed a guy. But his father's a big gangster on the docks. A "Kapidiye." He'll stay in... twelve months no more, and get parole. In Turkey, murder is manly - "erkek".</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just got to get yourself a good lawyer. And some money... Talk to Max. He's been in the longest.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seven years...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gastro. Stomach medicine. Has codeine in it... Best can do Pulls out the needle, loosens the tourniquet. His eyes take on a far away stare.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lawyers?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gives a spoon with a taste of the black residue to: HIS CAT who is full of spunk, and tries to catch Max's</context>
      <utterance>Yeah... there's no straight lawyers in Turkey... They're all bent bent as hairpins...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAND.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He looks at BILLY, not remembering him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His name?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MAX is beginning to go. He sits on his bunk.</context>
      <utterance>The lawyer?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What lawyer?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who got the Frenchman out?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANOTHER ANGLE - MAX'S head begins to bob back and forth.Focuses on BILLY.</context>
      <utterance>Oh Yesil... Yesil's his name but I...don't know anything... 'bout...Yesil...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Best way is get your ass out... any... way... you can...</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get the... midnight... express.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MAX smiles from faraway like a Cheshire cat and his head drops forward onto his knees, nodding off.</context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FATHER AND SON embrace; the father's left hand grabbing Billy's arm tightly as if never to let go.</context>
      <utterance>Billy!</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HAMIDOU looks on, intrigued by the Father and Son; leaves silently, closing the door. FATHER looks into his son's eyes, his own eyes moistening. He looks tired, pain all over his face. BILLY looks down.</context>
      <utterance>Dad!</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad...I'm...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Don't worry about it.  I can punch you in the nose later. Right now we've got to get you out of here. You all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. How's Mom?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bad. She couldn't make the trip. You know Her boy...  Susan told us before we got your letter. She's fine; she's trying to get the money to come back and see you, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, don't let her! I'll... How about Peg? Robbie?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Same. None of the neighbors know. We told them you were in a hospital in Europe. Oh... this is Stanley Davis. He's the American Consul here... And Necdit Yesil, the lawyer you wanted...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Billy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The professional smile from the Consul, but in the handshake and the eye contact, BILLY is cool. The unanswered question: Where were you before my father arrived?</context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to know we're going to do everything, in our power to get you out as soon as possible. Believe me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>YESIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vilyum, I am Necdit Yesil.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Yesil.</utterance>
   <speaker>YESIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause, BILLY looks at him wondering how to take him in.</context>
      <utterance>I know exactly what you feel but you must not worry, we are acting immediately, we get the right court, the right judge, I arrange everything - just right. And I think we get you bail. If very bad, maybe twenty month sentence... But I think we get you bail...</utterance>
   <speaker>YESIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(smiles)</context>
      <utterance>You know I have lectured at the University of Maryland in your country? Also University Michigan Very nice country. We both go back.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I get bail, Mister Yesil, they say it's easy to cross the border into Greece?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right! That's what we're shooting for. Mister Davis and have been in contact with the State Department, but right now relations with the Turks aren't too good, Nixon's upset the hell out of them. Our best bet's... right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad...  I'll pay you back for all this, I Promise.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause. YESIL Shifts, Throats are cleared. BILLY moves to sit down, limping faintly; he is wearing sneakers and the bruises don't show.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about it. Right now money doesn't count. Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd you get that limp?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sits down at the conference TABLE.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing. Just twisted my ankle.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you staying, Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Hilton.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you like it? Istanbul?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it's an interesting place...  Tell you the truth, I think the food is lousy. The crap they sell in these little restaurants. I went out to eat in one of them last night, and I had to run to the damn toilet... You shoulda' seen the toilet.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FATHER is happy to see his son laugh.</context>
      <utterance>You mean you got toilets?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY laughs again.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, with real toilet paper - and you don't have to use both sides.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY smiles. A pause. A worried look returns to the Father's face</context>
      <utterance>So now I'm eating at the Hilton every night.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why'd you do it, Billy?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(Looks away))</context>
      <utterance>For the money...</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you kids smoke that stuff, and we drink booze, but taking it across a border - it was stupid, Billy. Stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Glances at DAVIS, YESIL back to his father, his voice beginning to tremble, ashamed of himself for letting it show.</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANOTHER ANGLE. The FATHER understands the desperation in his voice, puts his hand on his son's. FATHER I promise you, Billy. Just sit tight and don't.. DON'T do anything stupid. Let me work with Mr. Yesil and Mr. Davis. We'll get you out... Okay? Billy, okay? All the assurance of the world is written in this kindly Irishman's face. BILLY feels it. BILLY being led by TWO GUARDS down a huge arched CORRIDOR in the COURTROOM BUILDING.</context>
      <utterance>Dad get me out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROSECUTOR VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...We must alter this image by punishing only our own drug smugglers-but by handing out foreigners who infest our culture with their depravity ungodly and behavior. We must start now - by sentencing this American, Vilyum Hi-yes, to the maximum sentence for smuggling, to be held up to the light of the world as an example of Turkish justice and its intention to halt the drug trade once and for all.. .I ask the Court therefore to sentence Vilyum Hi-yes to Life Imprisonment.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROSECUTOR VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE JUDGES rise.</context>
      <utterance>He sits, staring malignantly at BILLY.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANOTHER ANGLE, General commotion in the courtroom as people move about. The FATHER and DAVIS and the OTHER LAWYER consult among themselves, the FATHER vigorously nodding his head. YESIL approaches BILLY. BILLY leans forward anxiously in the dock.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Prosecutor. The Court will now recess to consider its verdict. The JUDGES exit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd the Prosecutor say?</utterance>
   <speaker>YESIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not important, just technical things. We make our case. You were very good, you spoke well. The Judge like you. It look good. Don't worry.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But YESIL is called over by the other LAWYER and hurries off. A SOLDIER comes over and sits BILLY down.</context>
      <utterance>Did you ask for bail?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JUDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PROSECUTOR, his expression souring, makes a gesture of defeat. We wanted a conviction for smuggling, not possession. BILLY, not understanding sees the Prosecutor's gesture, and a hint of hope crosses his expression. JUDGE puts the paper away, looks at BILLY directly.</context>
      <utterance>The Defendant has been found guilty by the Court of the illegal possession of Hashish...</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY looking at the JUDGE doesn't understand. Thinks he might be free. But suddenly TWO SOLDIERS move in, and start chaining his hands together. He is bewildered, looking at: YESIL hastily conferring with Billy's FATHER, more concerned about making a good impression with him than with Billy.</context>
      <utterance>...Therefore. this court sentences you, Vilyum Hi-yes to be imprisoned at Sagamilcar Prison for a term of four years and two months. This Case is now closed.</utterance>
   <speaker>YESILF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four years, two months. It's good.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four years!</utterance>
   <speaker>YESIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FATHER is too shocked to do anything but look at YESIL who continues on:</context>
      <utterance>We appeal it. BILLY watching this, a lost look.</utterance>
   <speaker>YESIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY is forcibly removed from the DOCK - in chains.</context>
      <utterance>You will see, he will have maybe one year taken off this sentence for good behaviour. Remember, it is only for possession; the prosecutor wanted life sentence for smuggling...  To be honest Mr. Hayes, it is a great victory!</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY looks down.</context>
      <utterance>...With good time Billy it works out to about 3 years... then there's the appeal. Yesil, Davis, they're all working for you We're going to try to make a deal to get you transferred to a Stateside prison. And Davis thinks there might be a political amnesty any month... Stops. Knows it sounds bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FATHER grips BILLY by the arm hard.</context>
      <utterance>Look - I know it sounds tough, Billy, but we're gonna get you out...</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY nods, acquiescent.</context>
      <utterance>...I promise you, but I don't want you to get stupid again. Pull anything. They can play with your sentence.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATTIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY nods. His FATHER points to a stack of ITEMS on the conference table, picks up a cigarette carton.</context>
      <utterance>I'm putting $500 in the bank for you. Anything you need you write...</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HUGS HIS SON BILLY is on the verge of tears.</context>
      <utterance>There's food, candy, writing paper, soap, books...  ...cigarettes, soap, tooth-brush, there's... Jesus!  I been writing insurance policies on people for thirty goddamn years...  And now I gotta see my own son...Jesus! Jesus! If I could be where you are Billy, I'd be there... Goddamn Jesus! These bastards.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HAMIDOU enters the room. A morbid curiosity in his expression about this show of grief. Watches a few moments, then indicating the visit is over, he taps his falaka stick lightly a few times on the hollow door. THWACK! THWACK! FATHER breaks the embrace with BILLY, tears streaking his cheeks. Silently indicates for him to "Go, go Fast." BILLY goes, past HAMIDOU FATHER shaking his finger at HAMIDOU</context>
      <utterance>Oh Jesus!</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HAMIDOU who closes the door. He has an angry glint in his eye.</context>
      <utterance>You take good care of my boy, you hear, or I'll have your fucking head, you Turkish bastard! It sputters out of his mouth, senseless to:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BILLY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CAMERA DRIFTS around the SECOND STORY KOGUS revealing the sleepers: ERICH, BELL, MAX...</context>
      <utterance>Dear Susan. 1970 has now passed into 1971. You can drift in here and never know you're gone. You can fade so far out and you don't know where you are anymore or where anything else is...</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I find loneliness is a physical pain which hurts all over; you can't isolate it in one part of your body. I so much need your softness, your strength. I have your letters. They charge me, give me courage.News about amnesty and getting out - tangled, complicated... The CAMERA LINGERS on ZIAT in a far corner of the Kogus, top bunk, against a wall. Never secure, he shuffles in his sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ZIAT is evidently awake he pulls his RADIO over into the bed, and peering around to make sure no one is watching, here moves the screws from the back of it, pulls off the cover and puts in a sheaf of large denomination GERMAN MARKS: inside we briefly glimpse a wad of different-colored CURRENCIES stacked with rubber bands.</context>
      <utterance>...I feel myself drifting more heavily into smoking hashish. The haze helps the time pass. Also I do soap carvings. Erich taught me. And I have been learning Turkish because it helps me to deal with the guards and the prisoners. I'm trying hard to maintain some sort of schedule to my life, but sometimes it seems like I'm just trying in order to try...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BILLY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BELL across the pointyard grins at him and points him out to BILLY, and ERICH.</context>
      <utterance>...To the Turks all foreigners are "ayip" - unclean, dirty. We don't shave our under-arms or around our crotch...</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even the yoga I sometimes do is "ayip" - too suggestive... THE TURK scowls back at BELL, huddles menacingly with another TURK.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BILLY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BELL, smirking at the Turk, turns and walks away.</context>
      <utterance>And you're never supposed to eat with your left hand. You know why? Because that's what they use to wipe their asses with instead of toilet paper. And yet they hate pigs. There are no pigs in Turkey. They're considered dirty...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMIDOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unfortunately my youngest son Arief is having problems with his teeth; he needs braces, but dentists are so expensive these days</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Poor kid... You know I have a friend, a very good friend; he's a dentist; maybe he could get you some braces at a... reasonable price.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Please! As a favour... I insist They go on, each protesting.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hamidou hints that he needs new braces for one of his sons. Aslan of course has a friend who's a dentist. They bullshit for half an hour and Hamidou finally accepts the "Baksheesh" in return... A BURLAP BAG comes flying over the WALL of the COURTYARD late at NIGHT. Then another comes over, lands in the yard. one is around.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dope and all kinds of shipments get delivered to Aslan, who re- sells it through his runners. People like Ziat. But one night, it backfired... A THIRD BAG comes over, gets caught on a hooknail and rips right open. HUNDREDS of yellow PILLS spill out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BILLY VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There were thousands of yellow nembutols. Aslan as usual had the privilege of going into the courtyard before anybody else to pick up his stuff but... ASLAN arguing vehemently with a GUARD, in his ragged uniform, who won't open the cell of the FIRST FLOOR KOGUS into the courtyard.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...it happened to be a new guard that day and he didn't understand the system.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. It's too early.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Open the fucking Gate, you asshole! Do you know who I am? You want to get in trouble!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PRISON DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aslan...be reasonable. Come down and talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You come up here and talk!</utterance>
   <speaker>PRISON DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aslan... if you give up the gun, you can keep the bullets</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I know all this must sound crazy to you, but this place is crazy...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HAMIDOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see Mamur, Mamet - what happens when you're not a good boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then there's Ziat. The more I know of him...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BILLY VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MAX and BILLY are next to him, MAX eagerly gouging with his knife into a small bar of SOAP: PULLS out a ball of HASHISH inside, neatly concealed. Brings it up to his NOSE, sniffing. ANOTHER ANGLE - BILLY is watching with glazed eyes - stoned. Approving of the $10, tucks it into his belly cloth looking over and scowling at: MAX'S YOUNG CAT on his bunk scratching playfully at one of his wool sweaters. ANOTHER ANGLE MAX holding the ball of hash:</context>
      <utterance>...the more hate him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten dollars for this shit? You greedy one-eyed git.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>NO! Is good!  Me good shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ZIAT thinking MAX is correcting his English, nods and repeats:</context>
      <utterance>No! You big shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY and MAX snigger and ZIAT realizes they are making fun of him. He hates that and suddenly reaches over and:</context>
      <utterance>Yeah! Efe big shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then hurries after it, calling its name...</context>
      <utterance>You asshole!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hikmet come here boy. Hikmet ZIAT shrugs. So what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it with you man, what the hell is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cat, ah! Ayip!</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're ayip!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, you don't fuck with me, I don't fuck with you, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you fuck with me. You fuck with me all the time. You make crummy tea. You rip us off on the hash.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I make special tea for you, Hiyes, okay? We've to live like brothers. We have to be in here together.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY watches, repulsed and fascinated.</context>
      <utterance>You 'Merican. You don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Know what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was..  ...seven years old. I was on street in Suk. Buy. Sell. No family to take care. I learn.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ZIAT shrugs. He thinks BILLY is an idiot.</context>
      <utterance>Learn what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dog eat dog, Hi-yes. You fuck other man before he fuck you.  And you must fuck last.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a great philosophy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MAX has followed his cat down to the end of the floor but it has run up into a rafter which he cannot reach. He calls up.</context>
      <utterance>You 'Merican. You don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Max gives up.</context>
      <utterance>Here Hikmet! Come down here boy! Hikmet... RAFTER Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shuffles off back to his bunk. THE CAT is back on ZIAT'S BUNK - NIGHT scratching with his paw around the radio. of the neck, hard. Suddenly he is GRABBED by the scruff of the neck, hard.</context>
      <utterance>Sodding cat!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SUSAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...But I cannot say I am for it. Nor are your parents. They consulted the priest, and he said to send you money for that reason would be like sealing your death.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The blueprints!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY, puzzled, turns the drawings upside-down, sideways. THE DRAWINGS are a lunatic mess of scrambled lines, dots, crosses.</context>
      <utterance>The prison, man. There was this German cat an architect in the hospital. He was helping the Turks build some shit round the place. I laid some bread on him and he let me copy them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too bad you didn't have a machine.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's two ways out I figger - over the roof, but that's only one person, maybe two. The other way is Under.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tunnel?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's already built! There's a basement substructure where they used to keep weapons and stuff, but beneath that there's these old catacombs that the Christians built 'bout a thousand fucking years ago to bury their dead. We're sitting right on top of it -- here. INSERT DRAWING, illustrating roughly the structure of the prison. His FINGER tracing, bubbling with nervous enthusiasm.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context>MAX is standing, tapping on the wall, listening, a funny look on is face.</context>
      <utterance>The Kraut said there's a whole bunch of hollow sealed shafts sort of like dumbwaiters running along this wall; one of them is right in there, right next to our shower. We get in there, he says, we can get down into the catacombs. With three of us working....</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gotta be here someplace. Thought I heard a couple of dead Christians singing down there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop shitting me, man!</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But how would you get into the shaft, Jimmy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose you knock three times and ask for St. Peter.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! I'm getting this together man and I don't need no fucking Gastro-head along on this trip!  We go through the wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We go through the wall?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BELL between BILLY and MAX walking in the COURTYARD continuing intently:</context>
      <utterance>We go through the wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BELL reaches the wall, turns around and continues Lowers his voice occasionally as other PRISONERS intersect them.</context>
      <utterance>...The Kraut was right! I checked it out - there's no reinforced steel in those bath walls. They're real soft from underground seepage--</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--the water like "'weeps" through the cement, see. Twenty, thirty years, you can almost push it over. All we do is use Gastrohead's screwdriver here and scrape the mortar out. Pull out 2, 3 stones, squeeze through, put 'em back, and get our ass down the shaft, It's a two night operation, maybe three.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what do you do when you in the catacombs?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Max is fed up with it now, no longer joking.</context>
      <utterance>The catacoombs? Whaddya want, a door? There's miles of em like a sewer system but they got to come up someplace in Istanbul.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta be fucking crazy! You got stabbed in the ass once too much, sweetheart, cause you're gonna end up in Section 13, that's what - not the 'catacombs.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Section 13?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, for the criminally insane.  I was there once for two weeks and it ain't an illusion. It's awful. Namidou runs it like a death camp, that's where he spends most of his time...</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes go back in time, haunted, vague breaks off.</context>
      <utterance>I don' t know. It's someplace down in there....  ..deep.. A big door...a wheel....</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, you know what's gonna get us out of here? It's not a map, Max. It's our balls. You know what I mean...  ...I gotta get laid man, I don't know 'bout you guys, but if I don't get it on soon, I'm... I'm not gonna make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Billy?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>P.O.V. - THE ROOF, its edges visible over the courtyard. BILLY shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>...The roof sounds better to me than digging through a wall. Ziat's round there all the time. But the roof....</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause. BILLY looks away from BELL'S stare.</context>
      <utterance>The bullet percentage is awful high.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BELL understands, deeply disappointed.</context>
      <utterance>If I get caught, Jimmy, I'm facing another months. I'd be back up to 3 years, maybe more... Looks down.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bell leaves:</context>
      <utterance>Well fuck it! Choose your own death, babe, I'm taking the roof out of here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BILLY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly he starts SHOUTING angrily in TURKISH. The DENTIST screams back at him. AD LIB. THE DENTIST still screaming, leans BILLY back in the chair and looks in his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>...I have problems with my stomach and my leg muscles feel very weak. My gums seem to be shrinking and they sometimes bleed when I massage them... They've pulled five of my teeth...</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...sometimes they null the wrong one...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BILLY VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ERICH uses a coarse washing sponge on BILLY's back.</context>
      <utterance>...even my dreams don't seem to work any more. Because the outside doesn't seem real any more. It's not even a fantasy...because there is no fantasy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even masturbation has become boring. It teaches you, like the rest of prison life, to seal up your emotions, and this is the greatest danger, this is what makes so many of the men change into something monstrous... EYES of the ARABS peer through the musky vapors at Billy and Erich; they loll about the door curious, lecherous for their bodies.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BILLY VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY rises gracefully onto his toes, stretching his arms out above his head. It is the beginning posture, his body greeting the day. BILLY and ERICH sit silently now in lotus position, facing each other, breathing slowly, relaxing minds still, looking into each other's eyes. Billy closes eyes.</context>
      <utterance>...and now strange as it seems, Susan, without having seen you in so long I feel myself more inside of you than ever before. I feel your female mind. I sense you, touch you; ...know you; and find myself falling more and more... in love with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SOUND OFF, interrupting the clomp of FOOTSTEPS on the</context>
      <utterance>A prison a monastery a cloister a cave, Prison monastery cloister cave, Prison monastery cloister cave, Prison monastery cloister cave, Prison monastery cloister...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rises from his position.</context>
      <utterance>Prison.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY erases out a scraped numeral (54) on the wall and with a chalky piece of rock, inscribes in bold strokes the numberal: 53</context>
      <utterance>Dear Susan. Erich has been transferred to a prison back in Sweden. He has profoundly affected my life and though I am lonely without him I am calmer than ever...</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Though I only have 53 days left, I feel I have never been so well adjusted to prison and to living as now....</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context>JIMMY BELL wakes, hearing the perpetual "Allah Wakbah"</context>
      <utterance>Allah fuck Off!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Asina Covaciml.  He is noticeably pale and weaker than before.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY cuts hair in the FIRST FLOOR there with a disturbed tight look on his face, work with a pocket mirror. BELL sits inspecting the</context>
      <utterance>...Poor Jimmy...</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>GUARD approaching with a slip in hand.</context>
      <utterance>...Though his health is bad he still won't give up...</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY sits, tense.</context>
      <utterance>Sit down a moment, Billy. I'm afraid I have some bad news for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DAVIS swallows hard, not to say it</context>
      <utterance>Something happen to Dad?... Mom?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... It looks like your going to have a new court.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Prosecutor objected to your sentence for possession; he wanted a smuggling conviction and the High Court in Ankara reviewed it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billy's face drains of all expression.</context>
      <utterance>We've been notified that they rejected the sentence...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY'S EYES. Numb, dazed, surreal.</context>
      <utterance>There were 35 judges on the High Court. Twenty eight of them voted for a life sentence.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVIS</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context>Suddenly he is GRABBED by his ivy-league striped tie and his face is yanked up to the bars, his glasses falling off. BILLY is berserk, his face right up against the bars, GRIPPING Davis tight.</context>
      <utterance>The Lower Court in Istanbul will have to go along with the decision. The Judge likes you and he'll do the only thing he can do under the law.... . He'll reduce the sentence to thirty years... We're notified... Billy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean LIFE FOR FOR WHAT!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I spent the last three and a half years of my life in your prison and I think I paid for my error and if it's your decision today to sentence me to more years, I...</utterance>
   <speaker>I...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know my lawyers told me 'be cool Billy don't get upset, don't get angry, if you're good I can maybe get a pardon, an amnesty, an appeal, this that and the other thing.' Well that's been going down now for 35 years... YESIL looks over, surprised he is talking like this. Looks at DAVIS.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PROSECUTOR looks over, through his dark green glasses.</context>
      <utterance>And I've been playing it cool and I've been good and now I'm damn tired of being good cause you people gave me the belief that I had 53 days left. You hung 53 days in front of my eyes and then you took those 53 days away, and Mister Prosecutor! I just wish you could...</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context>TRANSLATOR stops, looks puzzled.</context>
      <utterance>... stand right here where I'm standing and feel what that... ...feels like, cause then you'd know something you don't know you'd know what means, Mister Prosecutor and you'd know the concept of a society is based on the quality of its mercy means, of its sense of fair play, its sense of justice... but  I guess that's just like asking a bear to shit in a toilet...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sits down, disgusted; under his breath:</context>
      <utterance>For a nation of pigs, it's funny you don't eat them. Fuck it, give me the sentence. Jesus forgave the bastards, but I can't. I hate you. Nation. I hate your I hate your people. And I fuck your sons and daughters!</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SILENCE in the uncomfortably. courtroom. PEOPLE looking at each other DAVIS looks down. YESIL flips some pages abstractedly.</context>
      <utterance>...cause you're all pigs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TRANSLATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE OLD CHIEF JUDGE, the same one as before Shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Would Your honor like me to translate?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANOTHER ANGLE - THE JUDGE turns to BILLY in the foreground rises, and unexpectedly crosses his wrists out in front of him.</context>
      <utterance>That won't be necessary</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Makes the gesture of the hands forcefully, with anger.</context>
      <utterance>My hands are tied by Ankara!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRANSLATOR</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My hands are tied by Ankara!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JUDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... to be imprisoned at Sagamilcar for a term no less than thirty years...Getchmis olsun</utterance>
   <speaker>TRANSLATOR</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context>As he translates, the JUDGE unable to control his emotion exits rapidly, not looking at Billy, followed by the TWO</context>
      <utterance>"I must sentence you, Vilyum Hiyes, to be imprisoned at Sagamilcar for a term no less than years... "Getchmis Olsun"</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SONG OVER</speaker>
      <mode>MAX AND BELL</mode>
      <context>SEVERAL TURKS are partying it up down at the other end of the SECOND FLOOR KOGUS, playing a "sas" - Turkish type guitar, counterpointed by a little drum; the music is stridently Turkish, and one of the men does a belly-dance in underpants with two lemons masquerading as breasts under his shirt. The LOUD TWANGING of Bell's GUITAR can be heard OFF, interrupting them. They are annoyed. BELL leading MAX into the next stanza:</context>
      <utterance>"Busted at the border Two keys in my shoes Said I was busted at the border with two keys in my shoes An they gave me thirty years, babe To learn the old Istanbul blues..."</utterance>
   <speaker>SONG OVER</speaker>
      <mode>MAX AND BELL</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"I said Lord now save me Please save me from this pain" BILLY, touched - listening, thinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>SONG OVER</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"I said Lord come and save me, Come save me from this pain Come set me free sweet Jesus..."</utterance>
   <speaker>TURK</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context>TWO TURKS from the party walk up, waving at BELL's guitar, annoyed.</context>
      <utterance>Hey knock off that shit music...</utterance>
   <speaker>TURK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...We're playing the sas.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BELL gets even angrier, puts the guitar aside, ready to spring.</context>
      <utterance>Omina koyden your sas!  THE TWO TURKS tense, the mood changing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They don't understand but one of them is reaching into his pants for his shiv.</context>
      <utterance>...And besides that I fuck Allah and I fuck your Muslim mother too...</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got that, shit face? Asina...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BELL looks.</context>
      <utterance>Cut it! No more fights.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BELL astonished.</context>
      <utterance>We're getting out of here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY has his head pressed close to the loosened stone. Suddenly:</context>
      <utterance>We gotta take a chance and do that one next -  Then pull out this one -  Just jiggle it, scratch it out, loose nit up, it's soft real soft!</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's there!</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANOTHER ANGLE - all THREE press their ears to the stone. A silence. The faintest whisper of WIND and dripping 'WATER - indicating a shaft of some nature. BELL looks back at BILLY.</context>
      <utterance>Listen!</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY smiles. MAX reaches over and grabs Bell's face between his hands, kisses him violently.</context>
      <utterance>I told you, I told you you cock- suckers! You didn't believe me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck me! You beautiful mother, you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Ziat, hurry up with the tea will ay!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Work, work, work, that's all do</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY followed by ZIAT into the KITCHEN casts a look of relief at: BELL and MAX who wait at a table with empty tea cups.</context>
      <utterance>I don't hear you bitch about the money.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want me to take over?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to split your hernia again?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bell turns to go. Suddenly a LOUD CRUMBLING NOISE and: A FOURTH STONE starts to go - but brakes itself. BILLY, MAX, BELL all framed in a posture of fear -- not daring to move. SECOND STORY KOGUS remains silent. BELL looks up the STAIRS, tiptoes back, indicating they are clear. MAX AND BILLY. All THREE of them look: THE THREE A HALF STONE SPACE. Easily big enough for them to squeeze through. BILLY shines a candle in the shaft,</context>
      <utterance>Get off our tits!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY looks at his watch, hates to do it. Shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go!</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MAX groans to himself.</context>
      <utterance>No. No time. Put 'em back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANOTHER ANGLE - MAX, BELL, AND BILLY. A pause.</context>
      <utterance>We go early. Any fuck-ups we should be back here and have the stones in by dawn.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got your stuff?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Haps, railroad, bus timetables?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He extends his hands and the other two cross in a six-handed shake.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.  Let's do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah!</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jimmy?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's your hernia?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY in a sweat, slips. A tense moment - then he catches himself. OFF - the TRAIN WHISTLE can be heard, echoing into the shaft.Mixed suddenly with LOUD TALKING OFF. Arguing in Turkish. BILLY freezes, signals upwards with a sharp hiss of breath.</context>
      <utterance>Don't make me laugh.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE #1</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, you forgot, he'll have my ass!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE #2</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context>BILLY identifying the relative location of the voices, eases downwards, coming to a GRILL, looks in at: A BASEMENT ROOM with FURNACE. TWO TURKISH GUARDS throw the prison rubbish in the furnace, still arguing, AD LIB. BILLY signals upwards. REVERSE ANGLE, from inside the basement, of BILLY slipping past the grill, his face sharply illuminated by the flame of the furnace. Off the walls around the grill we can see the GIANT SILHOUETTES of the two guards still arguing. BILLY comes to the base of the shaft. A puddle of scummy water. Unstraps the candle. A current of WIND He peers around.</context>
      <utterance>Well I can't do two things at once, you were supposed to be here at nine o'clock!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY looking up.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus!</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anybody bitten?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah, just covered with batshit!</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Heads in that direction.</context>
      <utterance>They went out over there: must be some kind of exit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INTERSECTION Two walkways. BELL leads in, unwinding the thread, stops.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go back the other way.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY comes into view, equally frustrated.</context>
      <utterance>The fuck are we?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What time is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANOTHER MAZE of walkways. The three stop exhausted, faces blackened. BILLY, in utter rage and frustration starts kicking the wall.</context>
      <utterance>Two thirty.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit! Shit! Shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a dead end. The Turks musta' sealed it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SILENCE as the three pathetic escapees ponder their fate. BILLY, getting a grip on himself, thinking.</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck we gonna do?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We go back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? You gotta be joking.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Takes the THREAD and starts to follow it back.</context>
      <utterance>We go back, seal it up again, and come in tomorrow night - every night 'till we get out of here. There's gotta be a way. Those bats got out someplace.  Now let's go. Doubletime!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta have a lot of balls for this</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>BELL, suffering, can't help but grin.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MAX overhearing it.</context>
      <utterance>Count me out.  Who ever heard of anybody sneaking back into a fucking jail?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BELL starts to giggle.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, what if got caught?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context>MAX laughing, shaking his head.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Max, don't make the dummy laugh.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY can't go on, starts to giggle at the thought.</context>
      <utterance>Who's laughing? I mean I find this terribly depressing... Can you see old Hamidou's face when he tries to figure this one out?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANOTHER ANGLE - the THREE of them, spaced along the shaft, are all giggling hysterically. Echoing. HOLD ON them.</context>
      <utterance>We'll tell him we were checking out our escape route. We wanted to be completely sure before we tried it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OFF there is a lot of SHOUTING downstairs.</context>
      <utterance>Billy, wake up! They found it!</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ziat!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HAMIDOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all fall immediately silent. HAMIDOU continues his walk among them, bypassing: MAX who shifts his gaze onto: BILLY. HAMIDOU approaches, his eyes moving over BILLY with contempt, and shifting him aside with the stick. To him Billy is the same passive prisoner as before. He moves on, shifting OTHERS aside and then stops at: BELL. HAMIDOU swings his stick up slowly and taps him lightly on the chest. BELL realizes and is afraid.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMIDOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He punctuates this last with a theatrical tap on the chest and he gestures to the GUARDS.</context>
      <utterance>No do! No do! I tell you I see you again.. Finish!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMIDOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BELL, already broken by bad beatings, shivers.</context>
      <utterance>Take him!</utterance>
   <speaker>BELL.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>GUARDS grab him, hurry him out the Kogus behind HAMIDOU BILLY holds himself rigid, trying not to break. Bell's PROTESTS continue OFF. MAX unable to contain his anger, strides right up to ZIAT, collars him, livid.</context>
      <utterance>No! Oh no! No...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You bastard! This time I'm gonna kick your fucking brains all over this kitchen!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MAX is about to swing when BILLY grabs him.</context>
      <utterance>Fine. Good. Man to man. We fight now. And when finish I bring Hamidou and he kick you fuckinq ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ZIAT Glances from BILLY back to MAX fixing on him as BILLY walks him away.</context>
      <utterance>Max! Cool it!  Ziat's just doing his job.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="34">
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tears have formed in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Bell's gonna talk. They got to find out. Man, we gotta out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamn Gastro's killing me. Making me blind. Hey Billy!</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY looks away, not even considering. But MAX is caught up in the notion.</context>
      <utterance>I got some acid man. Maybe we can drop some on the guards huh? In their tea or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah I got it all worked out. Billy, listen to me.  That old guard likes you, You drop some acid on him. When he's Seeing rainbows yer know. walk out - tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then we're outside the kogus. Then what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After we're outside the kogus?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh we... we...</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MAX clumsily brushes the burning ash off his shirt where it's made a hole.</context>
      <utterance>Max... Your BILLY shirt's on fire...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes cloud with tears. He sits down, head between his hands.</context>
      <utterance>Oh shit! Oh Christ!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly shifts mood again, stands, pulling out a SHIV, resolute, eyes brightening.</context>
      <utterance>There just comes a time you know... you know you're never going to git it on.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I'm gonna do.  BILLY looks up wondering.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cut his fucking throat.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whose?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lurches against the bunk.</context>
      <utterance>ZIAT... What do I got to lose huh! What do I got to lose. And I'd really enjoy it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Max, sit down. You're in no shape to kill anybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to cut his throat.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's already been cut.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY smiles, shakes his head, then:</context>
      <utterance>Then I'll cut his balls off.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MAX slumps back down on the bunk, suddenly tired of killing.</context>
      <utterance>If you really wanted to hurt Ziat</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...His money - steal that, you steal his blood... Could you see his face when everything he worked so hard to get got snatched?  If we knew where he hid it.  Anyway, steal from him they'd pick up the whole prison and shake it sideways. We couldn't hide it anywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know where it is?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY glances at him, not sure whether he heard.</context>
      <utterance>I know where it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MAX gives him a goofy nod - and a grin. Imitating Robert Newton as Long John Silver.</context>
      <utterance>His money?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Dem dat hides can finds says I'... I seen him, the clever tit, sneaking looks at it late at night, talking to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MAX, distracted, let's his attention wander back. Inaudible his head bobbing now.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hishradyo.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Max - where?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lurches over gently on the bunk.</context>
      <utterance>His radio Back of his open, radio...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why he never plays it...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY surprised, then reflective.</context>
      <utterance>MAX Sleeps.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context>GUARD calling out from the STAIRS.</context>
      <utterance>Down here! Ziat springs up.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We found it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NEGDIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...He sell me tea business - everything. No the same. Ziat lose all...  Heart! Soul!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He never had one.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEGDIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soon he go back streets Istanbul. Thousand enemy. No money.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ZIAT enters the kitchen; he eyes Max with hatred, sits at the other TABLE and orders tea. Surprisingly, he is wearing a suit and clean shirt-unlike his usual grimy appearance. BILLY, looking shaken, enters the kitchen, glances at ZIAT sits with MAX.</context>
      <utterance>I'll drink to that.  Just as:</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just got some news on Bell.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bad. Sent to the City Hospital. They ruptured his hernia again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why the suit?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe he's changing jobs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HAMIDOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MATCHBOX Containing a small amount of HASHISH. HAMIDOU reaches over and pulls ZIAT out of the 'line roughly.</context>
      <utterance>Nebu?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMIDOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY glancing at MAX.</context>
      <utterance>Nebu? Starts to slap him around.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HAMIDOU smashes ZIAT again, but pulls the punch.</context>
      <utterance>What's going on? Maybe Ziat can't pay off; Hamidou's taking it out in trade.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMIDOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raises his arm again.</context>
      <utterance>Where did you get this hash?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From Max. Point at: MAX who stiffens, eyes like cracked eggs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HAMIDOU peers at MAX, advances.</context>
      <utterance>You got to be kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMIDOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indicates the matchbox in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>What's happening with this hash?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't sell it to him. I don't have anything to do with this,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HAMIDOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know your face. Where did you get the hash?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>) (He knows nothing about it. Ziat's lying.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get out of here! He's lying! That cock-sucker! Billy...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, will you listen to me? Will someone please listen to me? JUST LISTEN To ME!</utterance>
   <speaker>ATTENDANTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ATTENDANTS wrestle with him, but he throws them off, tearing around the room mindlessly. In the process we see that not much attention is paid him because everybody else is crazy! There are 50 other LUNATICS yelling at each other in fights over sheets, blankets, beds, cigarettes, jumping: screaming, pushing, shoving; some babbling to themselves, rocking, crying, chanting, singing. Several of them (the craziest) are stark naked. some, wrapped in torn blackened sheets, patrol the room like quick ferrets, sharp eyes open for anything they can steal. Others move in meaningless, blank-eyed silence. The walls are filthy black and join the ceilings in arches rather than angles, giving the look of an old dungeon. Fifty beds are lined up right next to each other so that you walk right into your bed. A constant nerve-racking NOISE.</context>
      <utterance>Hamidou! Get Hamidou! Get the Kiyisl!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY gobbles them up. He has changed. Lines in his face. No smile, no sense of humor; a brooding silence about him, a straight ahead look. He pays no attention to MAX off; he is in grubby white pyjamas and shower sandals. Rolls back onto hi&amp; bed with its filthy torn sheet, totally ignoring the surrounding commotion, and ANOTHER ANGLE - turning onto his shoulder, BILLY suddenly finds himself face to face with a dark saddened visage. The MAN is very young and stark naked but for an old black rag wrapped around his head and clutched under his chin. His eyes are yellow, the voice pleading.</context>
      <utterance>Hop! Hop! Full Moon - take your pills!</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY shakes his head sharply --too sharply --and barks, irritable.</context>
      <utterance>Cigare?  Cigare? Cigare?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go away! Turns on his other shoulder, trying to sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context>YOUNG MAN in a surprisingly meek tone.</context>
      <utterance>Cigare? Cigare?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY, really aggravated now, springs up from the bed, and in the quirky way the mad and the eccentric adopt walks determinedly away from the young man, looking back to shake his head bizarrely at him one more time.</context>
      <utterance>S'il Vous plait, Monsieur? S'il vous plait?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>AHMET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY is interrupted but keeps his eyes on the ground. AHMET doesn't wait for an answer.</context>
      <utterance>You're an American?</utterance>
   <speaker>AHMET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY doesn't notice, shuffles along.</context>
      <utterance>Ah yes, America! My name is Ahmet. I studied philosophy at Harvard for many many years. But actually Oxford is my real Alma Mata - I've also studied in Vienna. Now I study here.</utterance>
   <speaker>AHMET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY pays no attention, keeps shuffling on. Glances at him, smiles.</context>
      <utterance>...They put me here. They say I raped a little boy. I have been here very long time. They will never let me go.</utterance>
   <speaker>AHMET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The smug certainty of his manner reaches some chord deep inside Billy, because Billy glances briefly at this lunatic who is smiling. Billy looks back at his feet.</context>
      <utterance>They won't let YOU go either.</utterance>
   <speaker>AHMET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY plods on. grins and tries to explain the situation like a father lecturing a child.</context>
      <utterance>No, they'll never let you go. They tell you they let you go but you stay. You never go from here.</utterance>
   <speaker>AHMET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk on. Ahmet's expression changes.</context>
      <utterance>You see we all come from a factory. Sometimes the factory makes bad machines that don't work. They put them here. The bad machines don't know they're bad machines, but the people at the factory know. They know one of the machines that doesn't work...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ATTENDANT #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sixty two, sixty three, sixty four....</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMIDOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY plods without interest to the specified cabin, closes the door, sits in the chair. No one is there. He waits - indifferent to any sense of time. Dirty two glass panes separate visitor and prisoner booths; bars are between the panes. An erratic microphone is the method of communication, giving a weird and distant aspect to the voice. HAMIDOU opens a small peep-hole in the cabin door, looks in unseen as: TEE VISITOR DOOR opens and SUSAN tentatively walks in holding a large photo album; it takes several moments for her to react, and then her face shows the shock. BILLY stares at her, his face rabid, decaying; if he remembers her even, he doesn't register it because she is a shock to him as well. Reality, the outside world all at once. His mind is spinning, unbalanced, unable to grasp it.</context>
      <utterance>Kabin on-yedi</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God...!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The MICROPHONE makes her voice jarring, gagged. She looks silently. No sobbing, no big sad looks. Just shock. Shock of recognition, shock of time gone by. BILLY looking at her, his eyes moving down to: BILLY P.O.V. - SUSAN, her neck, her breasts straining against the thin shirt. SUSAN fingers the photo album nervously, speaking slow and distinct; not sure she is communicating.</context>
      <utterance>Billy, what have they done to you...my God!</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Billy, your family is fine. Senator Buckley just made a special plea on your behalf in the Senate. Newsday has written several big articles about you. They've called you a pawn in the poppy game between Nixon and the Turks. The letters are coming in, Billy. People care....</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SUSAN understands, startled. Looks around.</context>
      <utterance>Take it off. Take it off!  Take it off. Take it off! His voice is savage, demanding.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Billy - you'll just make yourself crazy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY tightens dramatically and comes right in his pants, slumps against the window. SUSAN realizes he has come, surprised. BILLY looks at her. Furtive, animal shame. And suddenly he starts to cry. A flood of feelings locked up too long come pouring out. He murmurs some words, Turkish SOUNDS sputtering out in his throat, then:</context>
      <utterance>Oh Billy, Billy, I wish I could make it better for you. Please don't... don't... Tears. Fear.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Softly, working his mouth finding it hard to speak. SUSAN yearning. Tears sprinkling her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>S.... Susan?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY straining, not out of physical weakness but an emotional one. Sputters, eyes closed.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Billy?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SUSAN is worked up to the limit, tries to hug him through the window.</context>
      <utterance>...I love you.... It sounds pathetic, lost.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Remembers something. Grabs the PHOTO ALBUM with all her strength, holding it up for him to see through the glass.Then remembering herself, looks around the room to make sure they're alone and in a contained voice:</context>
      <utterance>Oh Billy... Billy! Don't give up. Please don't give up. You'll get out. I know you will!</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HIS P.V.O - SUSAN holding the album open to PICTURES of his MOTHER and FATHER in front of the house, ROB on a bicycle, PEG in her cheer-leading outfit.</context>
      <utterance>Billy, your father gave me this for you. There's pictures of your Mom and Dad...Rob...Peg... BILLY looks at it listlessly.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A certain tone slips into her voice.</context>
      <utterance>And there's pictures in the back of your old Mr. Franklin. Remember him... From the bank?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY looks from the album to Susan. Possibly there is a gleam of understanding in his eyes but it is very faint. An Attendant BANGS on Susan's door, OFF.</context>
      <utterance>He's over in Greece now. He bought a ticket.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SUSAN quickly puts the album away as if it were a hidden weapon.</context>
      <utterance>Visiting is over.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She buttons her blouse but her eyes are worried, on Billy.</context>
      <utterance>I'll give it to them for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were right Billy don't count on them, you hear, don't count on anybody but yourself!</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ATTENDANT now swings open her door, annoyed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Susan stands, about to go, then suddenly leans up close to the bars, hard and practical.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LUNATIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tries to block Billy's way, but BILLY shakes his head, brushes by him - determined.</context>
      <utterance>Gower!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUNATIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>AHMET Slides up next to BILLY in his rags.</utterance>
   <speaker>AHMET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning, my American friend! There will be trouble if you go this way. A good Turk always walks to the right. Left is communist. Right is good. You must go the other way... It's Good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AHMET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To know oneself is to know God, my friend. The factory knows. That's why they put you here. You'll see. You'll find out. Later on you'll know. BILLY stops and turns to look at AHMET. His eyes glint with special knowledge and he takes AHMET into his confidence using the latter's tone of voice:</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eyes narrow. Surprise. Fear. He shuffles away. BILLY looks at him and turns up the STAIRS.</context>
      <utterance>I already know. I know that you're a bad machine. That's why the factory keeps you here.  You know how I know? I know because I'm from the factory. I make the machines.. I'm here to spy on you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HAMIDOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANOTHER ANGLE - HAMIDOU takes the money from BILLY like candy from a baby, then takes him by the ear and slowly lifts him up. Billy is like a vegetable in his hands.</context>
      <utterance>No do! No do! Reaches for and:</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMIDOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HAMIDOU leads BILLY roughly out of the lunatic room, pulling him by the ear. HAMIDOU still Pulling BILLY by the ear, guides him through the GUARD QUARTERS. HAMIDOU leads him up a narrow winding flight of STAIRS.</context>
      <utterance>I tell you I see 'gain...  I take you down to bath and your feet be big like...Breasts</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMIDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The tone of his voice indicates a severe reckoning this time. HAMIDOU pulls BILLY by the ear into a large echoing BATH. BILLY looking, bent over by the ear - a hint of awareness of new surroundings. ANOTHER ANGLE - the BATH is deserted, spooky with greenish Yellow fish light flittering down from holes in ceiling around damp mossy arches. Steam rises off a bath. Benches, buckets of water. HAMIDOU swings BILLY around until he is facing him. HAMIDOU makes an elaborate gesture of putting aside his falaka stick and holstered gun; he will use his hands.</context>
      <utterance>First you make mistake with Ziat, now you make mistake with money. You're not a new Prisoner, Vilyum Hi-yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HAMIDOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE BLOW, in SLOW MOTION comes sailing into: BILLY, and we see the brief boxer's distortion of all his face as he flies upwards and back into: THE BENCH smashing it. Echo like jarring F.X. BILLY is held up by the PAJAMAS, steadied. The Turkish words seem far away, incomprehensible.</context>
      <utterance>You go crazy here Vilyum Hi-yes. Many people go crazy here. Best thing for crazy people is this...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMIDOU</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context>HAMIDOU this time holds onto the pajamas using Billy like a punching bag.</context>
      <utterance>Vilyum Hi-yes. You die here, Hi- yes. WHACK - ANOTHER BLOW, but:</utterance>
   <speaker>WHACK - A REVERSE BLOW.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>HAMIDOU increasingly excited.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMIDOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WHACK - ANOTHER BLOW in SLOW MOTION</context>
      <utterance>Babba sikijam! I fuck your mother, I fuck your sister...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMIDOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RIP! - a loud SOUND as HAMIDOU moves with a blur of speed, and shreds BILLY's pajamas with his hands. BILLY naked, totally passive, semiconscious. HAMIDOU suddenly shifts position and snaps Billy into a strenuous wrestling hold across his knee on the steamy floor. He loosens him up by cracking his bones along his back. HAMIDOU - sweat pouring off his face, excited.</context>
      <utterance>...I fuck your father, I fuck your brother...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context>BILLY starts, clenches the falaka stick ready to spring, spins. A LITTLE SHOESHINE BOY is his case down the corridor. BILLY has not seen a child in a long time. get words out, then manages: Surprised. Can't get the words out, then manages:</context>
      <utterance>How about a shoe shine, friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE KID shrugs, moves on, looking At Billy strangely. BILLY goes up a flight of STAIRS. Ahead, VOICES passing. He stops. Goes on. BILLY goes through an empty GUARD QUARTERS. BILLY is in another CORRIDOR, approaches A SMALL PORTAL, daylight at its edges. Locked? BILLY, tense, tries it. It swings open on:</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context>BILLY is on the other side of the grill. A ill-fitting new Western style suit, a hat over his dyed black hair; totally paranoid. He hasn't slept in three days and the bruises from the Hamidou beating now show clearly black and blue on his face. His eyes are alert, darting around, his speech clipped and to the point.</context>
      <utterance>Edirne to Uzun Kopru? THE CLERK looks puzzled.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE CLEF!! Shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>What's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY taken by surprise.</context>
      <utterance>'What are you crazy? There's no train anymore to Uzun Kopru, it'd have to go through Greece. The border's closed.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No train?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context>BILLY Moves off a small provincial RAILROAD DEPOT - DAY. He looks at the: EMPTY TRACKS - No 'midnight express'.</context>
      <utterance>No more train.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DRIVER looks at him neutral.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, I have Swedish friends camping south of the town. I was supposed to meet them here this morning but I was late. Can you take me there?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know where they are?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How far?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About ten kilometers.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sixty Lira?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billy eyes:</context>
      <utterance>Sixty?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those mountains? are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY leaning back in his seat, casual.</context>
      <utterance>Very bad now. Maybe war. Those Greek pigs try to steal Cyprus again ) How'd you lose your friends?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DRIVER looking at him in the rear view mirror. His curiosity narrowing.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I drank a lot of raka last night in Istanbul. Got into a fight. Indicates the bruises on his face.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY casually glances out the window.</context>
      <utterance>How come you speak Turkish so good?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE DRIVER studies BILLY in the rear-view mirror. Then:</context>
      <utterance>Did twenty months in prison in Istanbul. Hash</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY looks at him hard. Something's wrong with this man.</context>
      <utterance>You want to score some? Cheap?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cutting off further conversation, he looks out at: THE MOUNTAINS of Greece - with longing. BILLY stares back at: THE DRIVER whose eyes now move away from the rear-view mirror under the pressure of the stare. SOUND OFF loud machinery. BILLY turning - in rear window, we see a TURKISH HALFTRACK pulling alongside the cab, SOLDIERS waving their arms for the cabdriver to get out of the way. ANOTHER ANGLE - the HALFTRACK pulls level. The CABDRIVER slows down, with a curse. BILLY - beads of sweat trickle his brow THE PERSONNEL CARRIER, disinterested, pulls past. BILLY breathes heavily with nervous relief.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANOTHER ANGLE - the DRIVER, exasperated, waves southwest.</context>
      <utterance>The Maritas River? Where is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two miles! Minefields over there. Do you know where this campground is or not?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not far. Just a little way.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! I'm not going any further! It'll wreck my car.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll pay extra</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANOTHER ANGLE - BILLY slips him fifty lira. The DRIVER takes it, muttering under his breath, jams the cab into gear. THE CAB follows rutted tracks into low HILLS. INTERIOR CAB - very bumpy.</context>
      <utterance>How much?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are the minefields?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All over. Turkish Army up there. It's against the law. They shoot us.  You sure you looking for your friends, man?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode>VERY SHARP NOW</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay! Ley me out right here. I'm getting tired of all this bullshit from you. I'll walk it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANOTHER ANGLE - TWO POLICEMEN and A SOLDIER come sauntering over, their collars open, beer bottles in hand, slightly drunk.</context>
      <utterance>Hey officer, we're looking for the campground. Do you know where it is?</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not supposed to be here</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FIRST POLICEMAN glances BILLY</context>
      <utterance>He's a tourist, what do you want, he says he's looking for friends at the campground.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Campground?  Never heard of one.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SECOND POLICEMAN meanwhile eases his arm down on the OPEN WINDOW bringing BILLY into foreground. The COP'S mouth is open and exhaling a wave of beer breath over-BILLY. BILLY P.O.V. - BEER FACE FOCUS PAST him to SOLDIER at tank reading "Hurriyet" - the picture of BILLY on page one, spread for all to see.</context>
      <utterance>Seen any Swedish foreigners in a camper-bus?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEER FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DRIVER turning around to address him.</context>
      <utterance>Noldu?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY motions to the DRIVER.</context>
      <utterance>Seen any foreigners in a camper bus? SOLDIER circles the cab from the other side.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE DRIVER ignores it. Calls out again, louder to BEER</context>
      <utterance>Okay, they haven't seen him, let's go back to town, it's getting late.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY rigid. This asshole of a driver! BEER FACE glances at BILLY, pulls his head out the window. Looks down the road. Takes a sip of beer. SOLDIER, disinterested, moves back towards the tank. BEER FACE looks in the other direction down the road, burps.Very conscious of his authority, shakes his head without looking at the driver. Moves away. BILLY nudges the DRIVER.</context>
      <utterance>Foreigners! KAMPER. VOLKSWAGEN</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE DRIVER impatiently turns and looks straight at BILLY, aware of his anxiety.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DRIVER leans out the window.</context>
      <utterance>Is no Volkswagen, man! Something wrong with you? BILLY hardening. DRIVER calling out. BEER FACE turns.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BEER FACE starts back lazily, half drunk, with the OTHER</context>
      <utterance>This guy's fishy...I think he might be trying to get to Greece. BILLY looks around fast.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes grow big suddenly As he sees the barrel of Hamidou's REVOLVER right in His cheek. BILLY all business, very quiet.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, there's</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BEER-FACE advancing looks puzzled, thinks he sees something, then crouches as: DRIVER gets out the door crouching, yells.</context>
      <utterance>Get out -- right now, move!</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY firing SHOTS off to distract them has climbed over the front seat, jams the cab into gear. It stalls! Again he tries, and now shoots off. THE CAB Roars past the roadblock. THE COPS AND SOLDIER, scattered by the shots, now scream at each other. They run. SHOTS are fired. BILLY guns the cab down the road, flying. CLOUDS OF DUST trail the cab. THE TANK starts to roll after it. Full speed. The HALFTRACK follows, the MEN riding it shouting. BILLY looks back, then looking ahead sees something. P.O.V - a speck in the far distance. Another ROADBLOCK. BILLY decides, then - THE CAB swerves right off the road and jumps into the gently rolling FIELD on the border of the road, pock marked with</context>
      <utterance>He's got a gun!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then yells in the recognition of it</context>
      <utterance>Pigs...! Pigs...!</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BILLY BILLY falls to his knees in the confined pen; the pigs run around squealing. Trying to reach out for one of them, he falls face first into the mud and lies there. Pause. A wooden DOOR squeaks open OFF. BILLY slowly turns his muddy eyes over his shoulder. BILLY P.O.V. - TWO SOLDIERS, khaki-colored uniforms, helmets, olive faces, mustaches, approach cautiously from the farmhouse, rifles ready. Following them is an OLD FARMER, Further behind in the doorway is his WIFE and</context>
      <utterance>Pigs... You... Beautiful...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHILDREN.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>BILLY muttering to himself, in Turkish.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE SOLDIERS approach close, stand above this strange figure, look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Greek?... Greek?...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(What is he saying?)</context>
      <utterance>Ti leei?</utterance>
   <speaker>2ND SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mou fainetai san Toupkika  BILLY with dimming strength.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
