<movie id="389" title="Milk">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>REVEAL: HARVEY MILK, 48, sitting at his kitchen table in a cluttered San Francisco apartment.</context>
      <utterance>This is Harvey Milk speaking on Friday November 18th. This is to be played only in the event of my death by assassination...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>During one of the early campaigns, I started opening my speeches with the same line and it sort of became my signature...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DIANNE FEINSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>GASPS from the REPORTERS. Dianne struggles to be heard.</context>
      <utterance>As President of the Board of Supervisors, it's my duty to make this announcement. Both Mayor Moscone and Supervisor Harvey Milk have been shot... and killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIANNE FEINSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Supervisor Dan White.</context>
      <utterance>Police are looking for a suspect...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. I'm Harvey.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Harvey...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Well, tonight. At midnight.</context>
      <utterance>Today's my birthday.  No, today is actually my birthday.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And, believe it or not, I don't have any plans. People took me out after work...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Work? So, that would be... Let me guess. Ma Bell or AT&amp;T.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Great American Insurance Company. I'm part of the big, evil, corporate establishment that, let me guess, you think is the cause of every evil thing in the world from Vietnam to diaper rash.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Falling for it, Harvey covers his mouth. Scott laughs. They both smile, realizing they share a wry sense of humor. A TRAIN IS COMING, Harvey has to work fast.</context>
      <utterance>You left out bad breath.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So... You're not going to let me celebrate my birthday all by myself are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Harvey, you're kind of cute for a suit... But I don't do guys over forty.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well then, I'm in luck.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I'm still thirty-nine...  And it's only eleven-fifteen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you from?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jackson, Mississippi.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, this isn't Jackson, but you still can't respond to every strange man you meet on a subway platform. It's too dangerous.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's nothing tougher than a New York City cop. They're arrogant, and they're everywhere. I'll show you the cruising spots, if you want, if you promise you'll be careful... little Scottie-san.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you on uppers or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. This is just... plain old me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're afraid of the cops?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just discreet. I know a lot of people here. If they found out, I could lose my job.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. You're one of "those."  I think you need a change of scenery. New friends.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need a change.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're forty now.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forty years old and I haven't done a thing I'm proud of.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You keep eating like this and you'll be a fat ass by fifty.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>an idea, half-jokingly,</utterance>
   <speaker>HALF-SERIOUSLY)</speaker>
      <mode> HALF-SERIOUSLY)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't we run away together?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where to?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I cashed my last unemployment check yesterday...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I hope you did something useful with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bought an ounce of pot. I was just wondering if you had any</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>plans, or thoughts... About us doing something to, you know, bring in an income.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey straddles Scott. He begins SNAPPING PHOTOS of him.</context>
      <utterance>Don't move.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose I can wait tables.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way. I want you right here with me... Did you see place downstairs is for rent?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was thinking we could open a shop together.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of shop?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One with very little overhead. Not too much work... A little one, just like Morris and Minnie Milk of Woodmere, New York...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The old liquor store owner from earlier, MCCONNELLY, crosses the street to watch. Harvey gives him a warm welcome:</context>
      <utterance>Just a little to the left...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello there. I'm Harvey Milk.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the new renters?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Welcome to Castro Camera.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>McConnelly looks from Harvey to Scott in the window.</context>
      <utterance>I want to join the, um... What is it? The Eureka Valley Merchant's Association. I want to help in any way possible. I'm no interloper. A Jew perhaps, but I hope you'll forgive that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think your application will be approved, Mr. Milk. This is a family neighborhood. Your kind are far more welcome on Haight street.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What "kind" do you mean, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Merchant's Association will have the police pull your license if you open your doors.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Based on what law?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's man's law and there's God's law in this neighborhood and in this City. The San Francisco Police force is happy to enforce either.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the warm welcome to the neighborhood!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey grabs Scott's hand... keeps him from heating up, from pouncing. It's not the time for them to bite yet.</context>
      <utterance>We pay taxes you know!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll form our own business association! Start with the gay- owned businesses... We'll take down the addresses of every customer that comes in for a roll of film. We'll ask them what they want to see done here... what they want changed... We'll get money rolling into this neighborhood. Revitalize it...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I come in now?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>They must have some gay customers.</context>
      <utterance>One more minute!  I'll go to the neighborhood banks.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey walks into the small dining room holding two plates of food. He sets them out on a small dining room table, still rambling on to Scott in the bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>Harvey. What's with all this political activist crap? I thought you were a goddamn Republican.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a businessman, Scott. I think businesses ought to treat their customers right. Even their gay customers. For God's sake, this is San Francisco!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harvey. It's just like every other city in this country. People hate us. Big surprise.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott heads toward the kitchen. The table is LAID OUT with a home-cooked meal, CANDLES and a huge bouquet of FLOWERS.</context>
      <utterance>We should have at least one block in one city right? Start there and take over the neighborhood.  Okay, you can come in now!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. This is--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MAN ON THE STREET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the party, Mr. Milk!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey arrives at A LONG LINE OF GAY MEN winding out of the Irish liquor store (from earlier). He squeezes past them, into the store, leaving Scott outside.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for joining the Castro Village Association!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>McConnelly, at the register, is overwhelmed with all the new business.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me gentleman... ladies.  Hello! Mr. McConnelly!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just wanted to stop in and see how business was doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnelly grins, uncomfortable. The line of gay men is curious about the hubbub. Point made, Harvey does a 180.</context>
      <utterance>So you don't mind all these homosexuals in here, do you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>ON DANNY NICCOLETTA, young, waif-like, somewhat helpless.</context>
      <utterance>There was Danny Niccoletta, a cute art student who I'd picked up at Toad Hall. Turns out he was also good at running the Camera Shop... something Scott and I found we had surprising little interest in...</utterance>
   <speaker>DANNY NICCOLETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Opera is passe, Harvey. It's about street theater, now.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Danny jumps up and IMITATES the LARGER THAN LIFE GESTURES of an opera diva, making Harvey laugh.</context>
      <utterance>What you're not getting is the spectacle of it, the bigger than life emotions...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>JIM RIVALDO flops down into the vintage dental chair that sits in front of Harvey's desk. He seems to be looking for something to occupy his keen mind. A sharply dressed young man, 20s, DICK PABICH, walks up to peek over his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Jim Rivaldo. A great mind. A great wit. A Harvard graduate, which nobody cared about, in those days, in the Castro... including himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>DENNIS PERON hands Scott a FREE JOINT.</context>
      <utterance>And somewhere along the line Jim picked up a protege, a cute political kid from Wisconsin... Dick Pabich... And of course there was Dennis Peron, who ran a very popular business with the new kids...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>ACROSS THE ROOM, Scott is waiting on a CUSTOMER, he's out of place: straight, gruff, a union man, ALLAN BAIRD, 40s.</context>
      <utterance>And on occasion we actually had a real customer. But only occasionally.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harvey... This guy wants to talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome. What can we do for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALLAN BAIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, I'm Allan Baird. Teamsters representative, and Director of the Coors beer boycott in California.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone, this is Allan Baird. He's a very big deal, so behave yourselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALLAN BAIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was told you were like the Mayor of the Castro, said you organized the CVA, you might know some people in the bars.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do have friends in awfully low places, but just so you know, it's not official yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALLAN BAIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Mayor part. I've considered gathering an army of queers to march up to City Hall and secede, but so far the young gays seem more interested in jeeps and jeans. But if I could be of any use, I'm all ears!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALLAN BAIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey pulls Allan aside, away from the audience, easing his nerves. It's Harvey at his best.</context>
      <utterance>We can't get Coors to go union. These guys are like me, they can't be out of work too long.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just curious. Are we your first stop or your last?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALLAN BAIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's been a tough one, Mr. Milk.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you seem to have noticed that my kind of people drink a lot of beer. If we're going to fast for your sake, I think we should get to deliver some of it when you win this fight, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALLAN BAIRD</speaker>
      <mode>INCREDULOUS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that what you really want?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And allies. I'll have Coors out of every bar in the Castro by the end of the week. Deal?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALLAN BAIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you Mr. Milk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No more Coors beer. It's gotta come out of every bar. Gay and straight.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he giving you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing for me. That's a convert.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A convert to what?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The cause.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>16.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A YOUNG GAY MAN runs into the store.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG GAY MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey and the guys race out of the store.</context>
      <utterance>The fucking cops, man, they're up on Castro Street! Toad Hall.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...if we had someone in the government who saw things the way we see them, the way the black community has black leaders who look out for their interests--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gonna run for Supervisor, is that the idea?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>HALF-JOKING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could go right for mayor, but I think I should work my way up to it... You'll be my campaign manager.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode>SARCASTIC</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I have so much experience in politics.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Politics is theater. It doesn't matter if you win. You make a statement. You say, "I'm here, pay attention to me."</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harvey, you do that every time you cross the street.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coors looks like it might cave. The union boys will owe me. Imagine if we get their vote... It'll be fun!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey starts kissing him all over.</context>
      <utterance>Fun?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll make it a spectacle.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Scott displays an old "Muscle Boys" magazine. Harvey does a well timed take. A few hoots from the eclectic crowd.</context>
      <utterance>School supplies, seniors, not what books I read--</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Scott unfurls three hand made "MILK FOR CITY SUPERVISOR" banners that lap over the sides of the shopping cart.</context>
      <utterance>My fellow degenerates, I would like to announce my candidacy for San Francisco City Supervisor!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey is distracted. A young, long haired CLEVE JONES passes. At 18, he looks 15. Harvey tries for his attention:</context>
      <utterance>Public dental care for retired people... Legalize pot, vote Milk.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I like the way your pants fit... Where are you from, kid?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode>LAUGHS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry old man, not interested.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's home?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Phoenix.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Harvey Milk. I'm running for Supervisor. What's your name?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cleve... Jones.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well Mr. Jones, we should walk up to my camera shop and register you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck that. Elections of any kind are a bourgeois affectation.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that right? Do you trick up on Polk Street?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I need the cash... But I'm selective about my clients.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me one thing before you get back to work then. What was it like to be a little queer in Phoenix?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I faked a lung disease to get out of PE. So what? What are you, some kind of street shrink?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes. But what I'm saying is, Phoenix can change. But we have to start with our street: rent control, police abuse, pot, parks, seniors.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, good luck with all that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what I think, Cleve Jones?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That you're gonna get somewhere if you keep talking?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. That you need to do what you're good at. Be a prick. Fight City Hall. Fight the cops. Fight the people who made you come here to do what you do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A GROUP OF CLEVE'S FRIENDS shout at him to join them. Harvey watches him dart across the street to his friends.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry old man, I'm leaving for Spain tomorrow. Europe. Got all the cash I need in my back pocket.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't come out until very late in life. There was nobody to--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>REVEAL: Harvey picks a blood stained whistle up off the street, the man's last attempt to call for help.</context>
      <utterance>The €œfruit€ was walking home with his €œtrick€ when they were jumped.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Name's Robert Hillsborough. Did you know him?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He used to come into my shop. Are there any witnesses?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just the "trick." Jerry Taylor.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jerry wasn't a trick. They were lovers.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call it what you will. He's our only witness and he says he can't identify the attackers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There'd be a dozen witnesses if they thought you boys had any real interest in keeping them safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HARVEY'S POV: The PARAMEDICS pull up the zipper on the body bag. We follow the zipper past the victim's bloody hands, his torso, his face.</context>
      <utterance>You're the Mayor of Castro Street now, right Harvey? You really wanna help? Get your people to show some discretion on the streets, huh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JIM RIVALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it looks like the big guns and the rich gays in San Francisco are going to back Dianne Feinstein and other straight candidates they consider "gay-friendly."</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott is laying down on THE BIG RED COUCH.</context>
      <utterance>Who cares about those old queens?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why isn't my campaign manager leading the meeting?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm beat, Harvey. I passed out flyers for seven hours straight.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the bathhouse?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott heads up the stairs to their apartment. A CUSTOMER comes in. Danny quickly gathers the REVEALING PHOTOS and puts them back in the envelope.</context>
      <utterance>People in bathhouses vote. I'm tired. I'm taking a nap.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just checking the exposure. That a new boyfriend? He's very cute.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUSTOMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um... Thanks, Harvey.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So who are these so-called "gay leaders?" And who appointed them? And what are you suggesting, Jim, that I'm supposed to go and solicit their endorsement? PAST HARVEY WE SEE A GRANDMOTHERLY VOLUNTEER, THELMA, opening the mail, casually reading a letter, then rising and approaching Harvey.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're down here, on the streets, trying to help people, so where they hell are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK PABICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>David Goodstein is the publisher of The Advocate and he has a house--</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM RIVALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A mansion--</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK PABICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--in Atherton.</utterance>
   <speaker>THELMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE ON THE LETTER as it goes from Thelma to Harvey.</context>
      <utterance>Harvey, you should read this.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Harvey Milk will have a dream journey and nightmare to hell, a night of horror. You will be stabbed and have your genitals, cock, balls, prick cut off."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm calling the police.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Could be just the push we need.</context>
      <utterance>They probably wrote it.  Hey, If somebody tries to kill me, I'll get the sympathy vote, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reluctantly, Harvey takes the letter from Scott.</context>
      <utterance>You think this is funny? Look at it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE ON THE LETTER: Someone has drawn a STICK FIGURE of Harvey being tortured - bullets, knives, fire, etc. Harvey makes a DECISION: He sticks the DRAWING to the refrigerator, the first thing he'll see in the morning.</context>
      <utterance>It's a complete joke. No rhythm. No humor. It's insulting.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you put it away, hide it in a drawer, it'll just get bigger and scarier. Now it's there. We'll see it every day. It can't get us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey wraps his arms around him.</context>
      <utterance>All this energy... to make yourself a target. And what for? Something we have no chance to win.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I keep telling you, it's not just about winning.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DAVID GOODSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I worked for a financial institution. I was very discreet. But someone spotted me at the opera, sitting in a box, next to my lover. And I was fired. That's when I decided to do something. So I bought The Advocate. And I use my money and my influence in quiet ways, to do what I can...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Endorsing straight candidates is what you think is best to help us?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID GOODSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, if they're friendly to our cause.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICK STOKES</speaker>
      <mode>DEFENSIVE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Politics is complicated in San Francisco, and Supervisor is a citywide office. Political alliances need to be built. You can't simply move here from across the country and run for office.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I am running for office. I'm on the ballot. I have the union rank and file, the seniors, and I could use your magazine's endorsement.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DAVID GOODSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harvey, we're like the Catholic church. We welcome converts, but we don't make them Pope the same day.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And why haven't you run?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID GOODSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott climbs out of the pool and sits at the table, naked and sopping wet.</context>
      <utterance>It's too early for a gay candidate for Supervisor. Especially one from the Castro. It's bad for the community's image.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with the Castro?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID GOODSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody works there. It's all sex and drugs and more sex and no one taking responsibility for their own problems.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The cops come into our neighborhood and beat us. They turn a blind eye if one of us is murdered.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICK STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then we file a lawsuit against the city. We go to our political allies in City Hall...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are no real gay allies. Yes, our friends may sense our struggle, but they can't feel it. It's not life or death for them. We need our own in office.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICK STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't demand acceptance overnight.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not? How can we ask them to respect us if we don't show ourselves some self respect, David.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DAVID GOODSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The more €œout€ you make us, the more you incite them. Step back and quiet down.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I don't have time to ask.</context>
      <utterance>Go back into the closet? Is that what you're saying? Because I know the closet. I lived in it for more years than I care to remember.  I don't need your endorsement. I'm not asking anyone for acceptance.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID GOODSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey turns around, ready for a fight.</context>
      <utterance>For you, politics is a game, a lark. Like putting on a rock festival or staging a "love-in." You're too old to be a hippie, Harvey Milk!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not a candidate, I'm part of a movement. The movement is the candidate. There's a difference. You don't see the difference. But I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the swim. I'm sorry I pissed in your pool.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Not cute. The shoes are hideous and I hate your hair. You're not fooling anybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott is horrified. Harvey pulls a pair of movie ticket stubs from its inner pocket.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not gonna let the Pacific Heights biddies write me off again because of a ponytail. I like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cabaret? For two? Lily, is this from one of my kind?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no. You won't run into the owner. He died in that suit.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey grabs Scott, kisses him. Then playful:</context>
      <utterance>This isn't sexy, Harvey.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too bad. No more pot, no more bath houses for me and little poo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a racket. It's 1976 and you still have to be straight, white, Catholic and male to get into the San Francisco police force. It's Racist. Homophobic.</utterance>
   <speaker>ART AGNOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Art smiles. Chuckles flutter through the audience.</context>
      <utterance>How many people do you consider enemies, Harvey? I've counted five already.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right, Art. And many are your closest friends. You see, I don't think State Assembly seats should be awarded on the basis of service to the Democrat Machine. Machines operate on oil and grease. They're dirty, dehumanizing, and too often unresponsive to any needs but those of the operator.</utterance>
   <speaker>ART AGNOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Milk, I've worked for years as a social worker in this city. I know Sacramento. I know how to get done what we all need done there.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me Mr. Agnos... right here in the Castro, Robert Hillsbourough was murdered for walking home with his long time partner. Stabbed,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ART AGNOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know Harv', your whole rap's a real downer.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God, you're handsome up close. I can't tell you how much I'm looking forward to licking you... in the polls.</utterance>
   <speaker>ART AGNOS</speaker>
      <mode>LAUGHS</mode>
      <context>Art gets into his car and goes. Harvey has no car. He stops and PONDERS ART'S WORDS... They stick with him.</context>
      <utterance>You talk a lot about what you're against. What are you for? In this town, you gotta give em' a reason for optimism or you're cooked.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harvey. Dinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... get some union boys in the audience, they love me...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM RIVALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't control who's in the audience...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now.</context>
      <utterance>Harvey, you need to eat something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>30.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scott steps back into the kitchen.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>CHASES the VOLUNTEERS out of the kitchen, out of his bedroom... down the stairs...</context>
      <utterance>Ladies and Gentlemen. Our apartment is officially off limits.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Harvey emerges, about to intervene.</context>
      <utterance>Downstairs. Time to go. Go. OUT!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>For once, Harvey keeps his mouth shut. Jim and Dick sneak past Scott, sheepishly. When Scott and Harvey are alone...</context>
      <utterance>Don't say anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Harvey and Scott eat dinner in tense silence.</context>
      <utterance>Sit down and eat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you say one thing about politics or your campaign or where you're speaking tonight or whose endorsement you need... I'll stab you with my fork I swear to God.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey gives a warm smile. Scott gives a laugh, but he looks like he's about to lose it.</context>
      <utterance>I just wanted to say... This is the most delicious meal I've ever eaten in my entire life.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott nods. That's exactly what he needed to hear.</context>
      <utterance>If we lose this one, it'll be just me and you again. I promise.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You staying up with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The election's tomorrow. I won't sleep... Was he good looking?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. He was hideous.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hard to tell what's worse. With me, my boyfriends usually find better looking ones to cheat with.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought we were gonna spend the rest of our lives together.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guess what, Cleve Jones.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going to meet the most extraordinary men, the sexiest, brightest, funniest men, and you're going to fall in love with so many of them, and you won't know until</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>the end of your life who your greatest friends were or your greatest love was.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that supposed to help?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe a little. Or not.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I went to Spain last month... long story. In Barcelona, there was this memorial march for gay people who died under Franco. The police tried to break it up. It started a riot. A bullet ripped through a drag queens scalp, his wig flew off, but he kept fighting. There was blood literally running in the gutter.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We could have a revolution here too. But you can't just use the Castro to cruise. You gotta fight.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think you'll win?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Winning isn't my strong suit.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode>BRAVADO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't "do" losing. Ever. Maybe I should run for office, and you can work for me.  If you can do it, I can do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you assemble a thousand people in an hour?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, if I run again, you're my man.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANITA BRYANT</speaker>
      <mode>SINGING ON TV</mode>
      <context>Harvey is alone in the shop, surrounded by remnants of a celebration party that never happened. Jim Rivaldo lets himself into the store. Jim has his maps rolled up under his arm.</context>
      <utterance>"Come to the Florida sunshine tree, great tasting orange juice naturally, orange juice with lots of vitamin c, from the Florida sunshine tree."</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM RIVALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jim starts laying out his trusty MAPS, color coded with precinct results from that night.</context>
      <utterance>We lost, but we lost by less! More votes than ever...  I remember when that used to work. I want to show you something. This is remarkable.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM RIVALDO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The red is where you did best tonight. If we can get the initiative on district elections to pass, and we can -- we can -- our new Supervisor's District will go right up Market. Right around the Castro.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>34.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The district Jim outlines is ALL BRIGHT RED.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM RIVALDO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you run for Supervisor with this new district, it's a potential landslide. You'll be the first up- front gay man elected to major office in the U.S.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Harvey's gaze deceives his words. HOLD ON HARVEY - contemplating a FOURTH run for office.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know if I have another one in me. Or Scott.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANITA BRYANT</speaker>
      <mode>ON TV</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gays can't reproduce, so they must recruit young people into their lifestyle...</utterance>
   <speaker>TV REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bryant, a spokeswoman for the orange juice industry, vowed to</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>TV REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Harvey's PHONE RINGS. He snatches it up.</context>
      <utterance>bring her campaign to the rest of the country...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scottie?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry sir. I um... I read about you in the paper.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I can't talk right--</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, I think I want to kill myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You don't want to do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do you live?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In Minnesota.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>How'd I look?</context>
      <utterance>You saw me in a paper in Minnesota?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My folks are taking me to this place tomorrow. A hospital. To fix me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's nothing wrong with you. Listen to me. You don't have to hurt yourself, okay? Are you there?  Here's what you have to do. Are you listening?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get on a bus. Go to the next biggest city. New York, San Francisco, LA, or even Minneapolis. It doesn't matter. Just leave.  You won't be alone. There are people out here just like you who will welcome you and love you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>God does not hate you. Just leave.</context>
      <utterance>You're not sick. You're not wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. You can. Just get on a bus.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey FORCES HIMSELF TO SOUND CALM...</context>
      <utterance>I can't... I can't walk, sir. I'm in a wheelchair... Sir. Are you there?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Over the phone, Harvey hears the SOUND OF AN ADULT VOICE, someone finding the BOY on the phone, then... The LINE goes DEAD. It's all too much for Harvey. There's nothing a speech or a pep talk can do to fix this. Harvey is overwhelmed. Dick comes upstairs.</context>
      <utterance>That's okay. It's going to be okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK PABICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Moving in a daze, stunned by the call, Harvey digs out A BULLHORN and heads out.</context>
      <utterance>Harvey, you better come down. There's gonna be a riot.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you can't control em', we will.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me permission to march them.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anywhere.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey jumps down and begins walking, not sure if the mob will follow. Finally, they do. Cleve catches up.</context>
      <utterance>I know you are angry. I am angry. Follow me through the streets of San Francisco to share our anger!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are they following in back?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Where are we going?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(off Cleve's concern) We have to keep them moving. Exhaust them. March them till they drop. We can't have a riot tonight. Harvey LIFTS THE BULLHORN. He starts a marching chant. The crowd starts following along. JUMP TO: Gays glare at cops. Cops beat their nightsticks against their chests and power poles. Anger burns as Harvey marches the mob toward City Hall. Dick and Jim catch up.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK PABICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They'll burn the joint down.</context>
      <utterance>They're still too hot in back.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We'll go all the way to Broadway.</context>
      <utterance>Help me turn them up Van Ness.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CROWD ROARS APPROVAL.</context>
      <utterance>My name is Harvey Milk... And I want to recruit you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The CROWD goes WILD. HARVEY'S SPEECH CROSSES THE CUT TO...</context>
      <utterance>I am here tonight to say, we will no longer sit quietly in our closets. We must fight. Not just in the Castro, or San Francisco, but everywhere the Anitas go. Anita Bryant did not win tonight. Anita Bryant has brought us together... She is going to create a national gay force!  And the young people in Richmond, Minnesota, or Jackson, Mississippi, or Woodmere, New York... Who are coming out and hearing Anita Bryant on television telling them that they're wrong, they're sick, that there is no place for them in this great country, in this world... They're looking to us for something tonight...  And I say, we have to give them hope!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>better place to come to if the pressures at home are too great...</utterance>
   <speaker>64 INT. UNION HALL - NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harvey speaks to a hall filled with TEAMSTERS.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PAN FACES OF TEAMSTERS - Several MINORITY FACES. CLOSE ON</context>
      <utterance>Hope for the worker who awakens from the American dream to find that all the jobs have left the country... We gotta give em' HOPE!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evelyn Lear's in town, at the Opera house in Tannhauser.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clearly.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if she strolls into the Castro for a cocktail?  Just one more. We can't let Rick Stokes take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Get us back on our feet.</context>
      <utterance>Let Rick have it. Nobody thinks you're a fraud here, Harvey. You're not in New York, you're not a closet case asshole anymore. People respect you here. Relax for a year.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If people are ever going to take me seriously, I have to win this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since when did you care if anyone took you seriously?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anita wants to put us all back in concentration camps. Rick Stokes is too weak to beat her back if she gets to California. I have to be in office to protect us from them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott picks up his box of clothes and starts out of the apartment. Harvey, not meaning a word:</context>
      <utterance>I can't do another one.  I'll be back for my sheets. If you're not here, I'll see you in the shop next week.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you leave me right now... I can find someone new.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott leaves. Harvey is in shock, unable to comprehend the loss. Unable/unwilling to reverse the choice he's made.</context>
      <utterance>I know. You're a catch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANNE KRONENBERG, 23, parks her motorcycle outside, WALKS INTO THE CAMERA SHOP, and plants herself behind HARVEY'S DESK. Cleve, Mike, Jim and Dick are STARING at Anne.</context>
      <utterance>--Ring out the old, ring in the new. This is over. Done. I don't want to see anything that say's fucking Assembly. This three-time loser faggot is running for Supervisor goddamn it!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM RIVALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the heck is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our new campaign manager. She called last week to volunteer and I asked her to help.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK PABICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Help or take over? What about Scott?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(introducing them)</context>
      <utterance>We need new blood.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guys... Anne Kronenberg.  She's a woman... A woman who likes women. Odd, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE KRONENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi guys. Mr. Milk... Rick Stokes isn't pulling out. He's officially filed to run against you. My friend at The Advocate says David Goodstein is backing him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL WONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A gay candidate against a gay candidate. It's unfortunate.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM RIVALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll split the gay vote. The straights will divide and conquer.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try to find out when they're going to announce.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK PABICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You replaced Scott with a lesbian?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anne worked on a recycling campaign up North. She's very organized.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM RIVALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know she's not a plant from Rick Stokes' campaign?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE KRONENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you guys always this paranoid?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL WONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. They take after Harvey.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shouldn't you be doing someone's laundry?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL WONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right after you redecorate my house.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE KRONENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, my girlfriends say you guys don't like women. Just asking, is there a place for us in all this, or are you scared of girls?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gentleman, we already have a tinker bell, a lotus-blossom, Jim and Dick in your three-piece suits. We need someone to manage things. A woman this time. She's the right price, and she has bigger balls than any of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE KRONENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OFF the group of misfits, considering the addition.</context>
      <utterance>Just give me whatever's left over in the register at the end of the day. So should I call the Chronicle about getting US an endorsement? No?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RICK STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is my night, not Mr. Milk's.</context>
      <utterance>Young lady, you must be confused.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE KRONENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir. I'm Harvey's new campaign manager. Anne Kronenberg.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICK STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A tough lesbian kisses Anne and stares Rick down as she heads in. Rick looks uncomfortable around all these women.</context>
      <utterance>Then you should know this race is for District 5, the Castro, not for all of your lesbian... compadres--</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE KRONENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dick runs up looking for more fliers. Taking Rick even more off his game, Dick is flirtatious.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. Are we distracting you, Mr. Stokes? I'd hate to screw you up on your big night.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK PABICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi Rick, handsome suit. Annie, do you have any more hand cards?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RICK STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These people are not from this area. They need to leave. Now.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK PABICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dick puts his arm around Anne. Rick is stupefied.</context>
      <utterance>Not true. Guess where we found them all, Rick? A slew of them. Way up on Valencia Street. Living right there in our district. And you see, as it turns out, Annie here is very, very popular with the ladies.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They've accused me of many things, but never as blatant a lie as this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE KRONENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First ever newspaper endorsement.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He'll piss himself.</context>
      <utterance>They endorsed you for being a good businessman? Has Scott read this?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(Cleve starts to go)</context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Go show him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cleve, maybe you should go find a boy to celebrate with. Just in case.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cleve goes. His energy is boundless. Harvey sits alone watching the bargoers return home through his front window. A bitter-sweetness lingers. A couple waves, one shouts out:</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to The Stud. Meet me out.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAY MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk on, not waiting for an answer. Then, a drunk, cute, Latino, JACK LIRA, 25, stops. He stares in at the political ads in the window. Harvey watches him sway drunk out of his mind, waiting for him to fall. The two make eye contact. Harvey smiles. Jack tries to. Harvey picks up a folding chair and walks it out to him.</context>
      <utterance>Gonna win this time, Milk?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK LIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're more handsome in the posters.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Where do you live?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK LIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack smiles, out of his mind. Then he sits/falls down into the chair, and slides off. Harvey stands above the passed out young man. A newcomer. A wounded bird. Perfect.</context>
      <utterance>...Palomino's are my favorite horse. They're smart. They're fast and compact. Do you think I'm more like a Palomino or a Stallion?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JACK LIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father beat me when he found out... So I came here. I stay in this man's house. But I don't like him.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long, comforting beat between them.</context>
      <utterance>Shh, it's okay, now. No one's ever going to beat you again.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK LIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you even remember my name?  Harvey.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK LIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you, Harvey.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. We're all full.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID GOODSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harvey! Harvey!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JACK LIRA shoves his way toward the door...</context>
      <utterance>It's too crowded. Sorry!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK LIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey PULLS JACK INSIDE, right past Goodstein and Stokes. Harvey CATCHES A GLIMPSE OF SCOTT OUTSIDE...</context>
      <utterance>Harvey!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Scott fades into the CROWD. Harvey (with Jack at his side) is pulled back into the party.</context>
      <utterance>Scottie--?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The new Mrs. Milk. I give it a week.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK LIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harvey, is this all for you? Are you this famous?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jim is calling out NAMES of the OTHER WINNERS.</context>
      <utterance>No, darling. We do this all the time. Do you like it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM RIVALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carol Ruth Silver... Gordon Lau... It's the most liberal Board in years!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Dan White? Did he win?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM RIVALDO</speaker>
      <mode>YES</mode>
      <context>Harvey is DOUSED with champagne.</context>
      <utterance>We'll deal with him tomorrow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHANNEL 5 REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does this mean, as many straights are concerned, maybe the gays are taking over San Francisco? Are you going to be a Supervisor for all the people?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to be. That's what I was elected for. I have to be there to open up the dialogue for the sensitivities of all people, all their problems, the problems that effect this city effect all of us.  Thank you San Francisco! Thank you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bulbs FLASH. A light rain begins to fall. Umbrellas go up.</context>
      <utterance>I, Harvey Milk, do solemnly swear that I will support and defend the Constitution of the United States and the Constitution of the State of California against all enemies, foreign and domestic; and that I will well and faithfully discharge the duties upon which I am about to enter and during such time as I hold the office of Supervisor, City and County of San Francisco.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cheers. Harvey is emboldened.</context>
      <utterance>Anita Bryant said gay people brought the drought to California. Looks to me like it's finally started raining!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HOST</speaker>
      <mode>ON TV</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This will be the first time in many years that we've seen so many new faces on the Board of Supervisors. Do you think such diversity will cripple the Board?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>ON TV</mode>
      <context>THE CAMERA REVEALS SCOTT watching the program. He's been up all night.</context>
      <utterance>The name of the game on the Board is six votes to get anything passed. So, like it or not, Dan and I are now in bed together... politically speaking.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode>ON TV</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've assured Harvey here that my brochure's comments about "social deviants" referred more to junkies than to his people. See, I'm about to have my first child. I have to make sure this city remains a decent place to raise him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long were you a fireman, Dan?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A couple of years.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dan studies Harvey suspiciously... What's his point?</context>
      <utterance>And before that... You were a police officer?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have something against cops?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. They tend to have something against me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But firefighters. Now those are true heroes... They supported me in the last campaign. I support them fully.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I appreciate it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dan hesitantly accepts Harvey's handshake. It's a step.</context>
      <utterance>I meant what I said. I'd like to work together.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Milk.</context>
      <utterance>I'll see you at the office, Mr.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think of my new theater?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A bit over the top.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's with the suit?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey leads Cleve from the elevator to the grand staircase.</context>
      <utterance>I got it from a friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When you come here, I want you to wear the tightest jeans possible. Never blend in. And no elevators. Ever. Always take the stairs, you can make such a grand entrance going up the stairs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>They arrive at his Lead Aide's desk: it's Anne Kronenberg.</context>
      <utterance>all that. It bugs the hell out of her.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morning Annie, let's set Cleve up on mail.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE KRONENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will do.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come into my office...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The first order of business that will come out of this office is a city wide Gay Rights Ordinance. Just like the one Anita shot down in Dade County. What do you think, Lotus Blossom?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL WONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it's good. Not great.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then make it brilliant. I want Anita's attention here. In San Francisco. I want her to bring her fight to US... This Bill needs a unanimous vote. We need headlines.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM RIVALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey puts his fingers to his lips and points down the hall, indicating Dan is down there. Harvey whispers:</context>
      <utterance>Dan White won't vote for this.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dan pops his head into Harvey's office.</context>
      <utterance>Dan's fine. He's just uneducated. We can teach him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harvey, committee meets at 9:30. Oh, hi Michael, Jim.  Hey, did you get the invitation to</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>my son's christening? I invited a few of the other supes as well.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be there.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All smiles, Dan leaves. Cleve mocks him. OFF Mike Wong's expression: THAT WAS BIZARRE.</context>
      <utterance>Great!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE KRONENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. I'll let him christen me, if he'll vote for my Gay Rights Ordinance. We need allies. We need everyone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK LIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome home, Harvey! I hope you're hungry. I only know how to cook one thing, but I make it good.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you... break in?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK LIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I asked the boy downstairs to let me in...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Danny?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JACK LIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wouldn't let me in. So I came in this way. Your friends aren't very nice to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a Town Hall meeting tonight, Jack.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK LIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You work too hard. I'm sorry about your window. I'll fix it tomorrow.  Are you surprised?!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack turns up the music, takes Harvey's hands and guides him through a simple dance.</context>
      <utterance>Jack, I have to go. I have an invitation to a party tomorrow. Lots of rich people, politicians. We could get all dressed up...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK LIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I could be the first lady?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK LIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I watched TV here today. All day. I saw All My Children. They killed Margo. I knew it was going to happen. They try and trick you but it never works.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You always see it coming?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK LIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack starts dancing with Harvey again. It's sweet, intimate.</context>
      <utterance>What? Killing the blonde? Every time. I'm good with that.  I think now the old lady is going to have an affair. Then she'll get killed or married. Always one or the other. Dead or married.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I make you a key, you won't break my windows again, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK LIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dance lesson is a lovely distraction. Harvey won't be going back to work tonight.</context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>87 INT. CATHOLIC CHURCH - LATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harvey and Dan have pulled themselves away.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm proposing a citywide ordinance. It ensures that a person who already has a job can't be fired for their orientation.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dan looks over to his WIFE and NEWBORN SON.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure my constituents would favor that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is anyone else here from the Board?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the only one who showed up I think.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were you christened here?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Right here. Same Parish. My grandma immigrated here when this was an Irish Catholic city. The City of St. Francis... A lot's changed here since then.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>an outsider.</context>
      <utterance>You're more like one of us now...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not like most homosexuals, are you, Harvey?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know a lot of "homosexuals?"</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, where do you stand on the Psychiatric Center the City's been pushing into my district?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'd have to study it...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Getting it out of my district was a key piece of my platform. It only attracts arsonist, rapists, all that, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, sure. A campaign promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A big one.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode>QUIET</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you say we watch out for each other's interests? I'd like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary Ann White approaches with their child. It's awkward, as if she's walked in on something intimate.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like that, too, Dan.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. Slipped into some shop talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Gay Rights Ordinance. My fault.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ANN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seems an inappropriate subject in here don't you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His attempt to break the tension goes down in flames. She cracks a polite smile. They're from very different worlds.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, don't knock it till you've tried it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DICK PABICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Supervisors Silver and Lau are asking you to vote to keep this Psychiatric Center in Dan's district. It'll go down 6 to 5 if you vote to get rid of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL WONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a Youth Campus, Harvey. These are kids that would be displaced from their families if it's moved.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't just dump Dan. The guy's got nothing going for him. No friends...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here we go, Harvey to the rescue. Isn't it enough we have to put up with Jack?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lay off. He registered 120 voters last week.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So do any of your volunteers, but you don't make them all first lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL WONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Really? Politically?</context>
      <utterance>What does Dan White do for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone groans. Cleve camps it up:</context>
      <utterance>He intrigues me... I think he may be one of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dear God, say it ain't so!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just a theory...</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK PABICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just think he's cute.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anne Kronenberg walks in. She's got that look in her eyes. Something's up.</context>
      <utterance>No... I know what it's like to live that life. That lie. You can see it in Dan's eyes... The fear, the pressure...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good or Bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE KRONENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pall falls over the room. This is worse than expected.</context>
      <utterance>Not great. State Senator John Briggs is Anita Bryant's go-to guy in California for sure. He's filed his petition for a statewide referendum to fire all gay teachers and anyone who supports them.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many signatures will he need to qualify for the ballot?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever. He can get them in two Sundays at church in Orange County.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This means the fight's coming here, where we can do something about it! Wichita's one thing, Kansas City. But Anita's heading for San Francisco! She's not going to know what hit her. Smile, children! This is the fight we've been waiting for.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOHN BRIGGS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>In the crowd is teacher TOM AMMIANO, 36, colorful, worked up:</context>
      <utterance>do it in our public schools. It's time to root them out.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM AMMIANO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And how are you going to determine who's a homosexual?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN BRIGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, my bill outlines procedures for identifying homosexuals.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER PROTESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How? Will you be sucking them off?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN BRIGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's getting ugly fast. Briggs is whisked away by TWO OFFICERS. He trips off the curb and is quickly scooped up.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, you can argue with me, but you cannot argue with God.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DAVID GOODSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Harvey... your boyfriend is in the closet.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, David?</utterance>
   <speaker>RICK STOKES</speaker>
      <mode>QUIETLY</mode>
      <context>We don't need a scene.</context>
      <utterance>The Latino, he's locked himself in the coat room... Mr. Milk, Phil Burton is here. He's likely the next Speaker of the House and a much needed ally against Prop Six.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right, I know, I was late by twenty minutes. I'm sorry, Jack.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK LIRA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who were you with? Scott? Some boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was at work. Come out, sugar pea.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK LIRA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You embarrassed me. I didn't know anyone. These are not good people. I don't want to be here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then go home, Jack.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK LIRA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>A tight smile from Harvey as he looks up to Cleve.</context>
      <utterance>No. I'll wait for you. Go away.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DAVID GOODSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Briggs initiative is polling at 75 percent for approval statewide.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>80 percent in other polls. Some even have us losing San Francisco.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DAVID GOODSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So it's important we not deceive people into thinking we can beat this, or we'll have riots and only increase this backlash.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rick and David are horrified. Phil Burton rises above it, passing out copies of his new Anti-Briggs Initiative flier.</context>
      <utterance>Good point, David. Let's just roll right over. Make it easier for Briggs to fuck us up the ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL BURTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We'll need money to do that.</context>
      <utterance>We're taking this very seriously in my office. We want to send one of these to every home in California.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Proposition Six is an affront to Human Rights. An invasion of the State into the private lives of California citizens."  Does it even say the word gay on this thing? Anywhere?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID GOODSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No Harvey, purposefully not.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL BURTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With the heat bearing down on your movement right now, we think it's best to dodge the "gay" bullet. Go for the human rights angle.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People need to know who's affected. This flier needs at least one old queen on it.  Why don't you volunteer for that, David?</utterance>
   <speaker>RICK STOKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Corey Wares is an out gay--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is shit. Shit and masturbation. It's a coward's response to a dangerous threat.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID GOODSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the face of Phil Burton, most the others seem to agree. HARVEY PUTS PHIL BURTON'S FLYER IN THE FIREPLACE on his way out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>I think you should leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack, it's time to go.  Get everyone together. I want young people, women, fresh heads. Fighters and organizers, not politicians.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OFF HARVEY, knowing Scott would be an asset. Jack opens the door and grabs Harvey's hand. They go.</context>
      <utterance>What about, S-C-O-T-T?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JIM RIVALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we can't afford infighting anymore, Cleve. We have to bring together every group. Even the old school Democrats.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>People start chipping in for the HANDSOME PIZZA GUY.</context>
      <utterance>Is anybody gonna pay the pizza guy, or are we just gonna stare?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we're gonna convince the 90% to give a shit about us 10%... We have to let 'em know who we are.  Everybody's coming out. The entire state. No matter where they live.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK PABICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Come out, come out, wherever you are!"</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm serious.  We're going to tell everyone in the state to come out. Every gay doctor, lawyer, teacher, dog catcher... We have to leave the ghetto, let all those people out there know that they do know one of us. And if people won't step out of the closet, we open the door for them.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE KRONENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The whole state is not San Francisco.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clearly, Scott.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM RIVALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It could be dangerous. There is such a thing as a right to privacy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Privacy's our enemy. You want real political power? Let's tell the truth for a change. Starting here. If there's anybody in this room, right now, who hasn't told their families, their friends, their employers... Do it. Now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE KRONENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. The room is silent. Dick looks ill.</context>
      <utterance>My folks know already.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK PABICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't told my father yet...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People vote two to one for us if they know just one of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cleve, show Dick where you keep your phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a moment, Dick RISES and follows Cleve out of the room. People are stunned by Harvey's outrageous demand. Harvey sees Scott GLARING at him.</context>
      <utterance>It's in the bedroom.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you were done with politics.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Politics. Not the movement. What the hell was that in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The movement needs people to be up- front. Why were you fighting me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were the biggest closet case alive in New York. You told me and all your boyfriends to keep our</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>traps shut. You were the hypocrite in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My parents are gone. My brother knows. I'm sure they knew.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had to listen to your phone calls home to Mom. Hear you deny that I existed. You want to be "normal" as bad as any of us. More than any of us... Those are kids in there. You're asking them to lose their families.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If their families won't love them for who they are, who they really are, then they should lose them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's fucking insane.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's he? Do you live together?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone I'm seeing. He's good for me. He makes me stay home at nights, out of the bars...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I miss you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Harvey, don't...  What's that about?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK LIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Har-veyyyyy!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott nods. THAT'S ALWAYS BEEN HARVEY'S ACHILLES HEAL. He walks away from Harvey, leaving him alone.</context>
      <utterance>He needs me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--I want it noted that I never promised to back moving any Mental Health Centers. I greatly respect Supervisor White, but I would like his remarks stricken.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIANNE FEINSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fellow Supervisor, CAROL RUTH SILVER, leans over to Harvey.</context>
      <utterance>Duly noted. We will take a recess before recording the vote.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROL RUTH SILVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey is preoccupied with Dan approaching. He leans back.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Harvey.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She politely recognizes the tension and gets up.</context>
      <utterance>Can I have a moment with Harvey? Alone, please, Carol?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you turning on me like this at the last minute? What did I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't have all the details. I'll help you craft a different version that doesn't displace any kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harvey, I can't go back to my family and to my folks and to my district without this. Don't do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm getting a lot of pressure, Dan.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You strung me along. And now you're throwing me to the wolves.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dan grabs Harvey. It's threatening. A new side of Dan.</context>
      <utterance>You only need one more vote, Dan. There are 5 other Supervisors you could convince besides me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'll get Quentin against it.</context>
      <utterance>I'll vote against your Queer Law.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll still pass. You can't keep alienating yourself here, Dan.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dan goes, the rage of a scorned adolescent under his suit.</context>
      <utterance>I gave you a chance, Harvey. I really did. You blew it. You really blew it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANITA BRYANT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>lifting her hand with</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGGS'S)</speaker>
      <mode> BRIGGS'S)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On to California!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're moving. I don't know where, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did Jim call the press?  Get out there with your camera!</utterance>
   <speaker>DANNY NICCOLETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Press is covered. But we don't have a permit to march.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I got Coors out of the bars, the Union gave me this. I want you to have it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do I do with this?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're an activist. Take it. March them.  March those people up to the front doors of City Hall. When it looks really bad, the city's first gay Supervisor will come out and play peacemaker. We save the city from a riot. We can turn this night into more political power for the cause.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't do it like you do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't always be here. Somebody else will have to take over.  I need you to be the scary one now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Initially Cleve is successful, but then the crowd turns, marching toward City Hall without him.</context>
      <utterance>Forty years ago tonight, the gay citizens of Germany found out they no longer had civil rights. Tomorrow morning, the gay citizens of Wichita will also awaken to find that they too have lost their civil rights. You have whistles. You use them when we have been attacked. Tonight we have been attacked.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cleve runs as fast as he can to cut through the crowd, to get to the front. He gets on his walkie-talkie.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck. Shit. Harvey!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>ON HARVEY: Ducking through EMPTY STREETS, trying to get AHEAD OF THE CROWD and beat them to City Hall.</context>
      <utterance>Get the press to the overpass!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>69.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cleve gets to the head of the crowd.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Move... Left... Move... Left...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM RIVALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing? Where's Harvey?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cleve looks up at the press that's arrived on the overpass above, and turns to two HIPPIE KIDS near the front.</context>
      <utterance>We're shutting down traffic, both directions.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The boys climb up a trolley and knock down the power arms. Sparks fly. Brakes squeal. The press snaps photos.</context>
      <utterance>Disconnect the power arms!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fuck. It came this close to a riot.</context>
      <utterance>They're calling it a "successful mediation." You're a God damn hero.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lose the note cards next time. Your job is just to say into that bullhorn what they're all feeling.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're just jealous it wasn't you out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey steps away, hot, pensive. Anne gets quiet.</context>
      <utterance>We're losing Prop Six by 60% and you're over there celebrating a riot. I need more visibility...  If we're going to beat this thing, we have to get Briggs to acknowledge us.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE KRONENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every paper's calling Prop Six the main event now. We lose this, we'll have anti-gay laws in all fifty states, and Briggs won't return our calls for a public debate.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK PABICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's ignoring us to death.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need something populist. What's the number one complaint about city life?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The piss smell in the Tenderloin.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Close.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK ROBINSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dog shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM RIVALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you cleaned up all the dog shit in the city, you could be elected Mayor.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Mayor Milk."</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Supervisor Lau?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORDON LAU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lau, Aye. Supervisor Silver?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAROL RUTH SILVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aye.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Silver, Aye. Supervisor White?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dianne Feinstein BANGS HER GAVEL down hard.</context>
      <utterance>White, No. Madam President, I have ten ayes and one no.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIANNE FEINSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The San Francisco Gay Rights Ordinance sponsored by Supervisors Milk and Silver is passed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAYOR MOSCONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't get my stories on page ten, you're getting page one?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a shit eating grin, Harvey offers up a powder blue pen.</context>
      <utterance>Doggy-doo's a real problem, George.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A beat between them. An alliance is forming. The Mayor sits behind his desk and turns to the press with Harvey's pen.</context>
      <utterance>Powder blue to sign they city's first Gay Rights law... George, we need your help with Briggs... The gay community will have your back from now on. On all issues. I hope you'll have ours.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you working on, Dan?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you have something to discuss, you can have your aide make an appointment with my aide.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What else do you have coming up?</context>
      <utterance>Listen, I know you're disappointed about the Psychiatric Center...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you need something from me. You want my me to join in with the Queers on this Prop Six business?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We prefer the word "gay," Dan. Just as I'm sure you prefer the word, "Irish-American" to "Mick."</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harvey, our society can't exist without the family, without the church.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not against those things.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not? Can two men reproduce?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. But, we keep trying!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>On something...</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Dan. You're channeling Anita and Briggs... we can work together.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. You introduce an initiative for Supervisor pay raises.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a bad time politically. I have an election next year.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dan's AIDE steps into the doorway. She seems surprised to see Harvey in Dan's office.</context>
      <utterance>You asked for something. Introduce pay raises. I can't take care of my family on our salaries. You don't have that problem, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dan goes.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Milk, You'll excuse me, I have a development meeting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong, Taco Bell?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK LIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anne and Cleve tried to cut me out of your table. You should fire them.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A kiss and Jack heads to the bar. Scott approaches.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take it under consideration. Why don't you get us a drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't let Cezar Chavez hear you calling him Taco Bell.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott wipes PIE CREAM from Harvey's jacket.</context>
      <utterance>He's getting better. He's enrolling in classes on Monday.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I remember when your birthdays were a bit less... lavish. More intimate.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who invited you? Anne?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My boyfriend got an invitation. I was his "plus one."</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Congratulations. It was a tough ticket to get.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Congratulations to you. Looks like you're part of the Machine now.  You can do better.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I come home to Jack, I don't have to talk politics or talk intelligently. Or even talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>SELF-DEPRECATING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And where's an old man like me going to get such a good looking young man, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott gives Harvey a BIRTHDAY KISS.</context>
      <utterance>You're not so old. You look handsome... Happy 48th. Looks like you're gonna make it to fifty after- all, Mr. Milk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry I missed the party, Harv...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No problem, Dan. Good to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dog poop?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's good! It's a good one.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. But it's a real problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah. I mean, God knows how many problems it causes. All kinds of diseases, birth defects probably, I mean, stuff you can't even...  Hey, I got you a little something.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't have to--</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't have to--</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode>LAUGHING</mode>
      <context>Dan's attempts to be witty and erudite (like Harvey) only leave him confused and tongue tied. Harvey HAS NO IDEA why Dan is here.</context>
      <utterance>Why do people always say that? "You didn't have to?" I mean, of course, right? But, that's what they always say. They always say things like that...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you okay, Dan?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dan PUTS HIS ARMS AROUND HARVEY for a sort-of macho but really weird birthday hug. Harvey stiffens, it's such a peculiar moment. Dan steps back, looks him over.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, what? Yeah, sure. Harvey, I just... I just want to say... Happy Birthday.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've really learned a lot from watching you, Harvey.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I doubt that.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's your advantage.</context>
      <utterance>No, I have. You gotta get out there. Get noticed. That's how it works. But, you have an issue.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack emerges from the bathroom, barely together and leans on Harvey. Dan steps back from Harvey and Jack, his moment alone stolen away.</context>
      <utterance>It's more than an issue, Dan.  Dan. I've had four relationships in my life. Three of those four tried to kill themselves. I know it was my fault they did it. I told them to stay quiet. To hide. Most of my life I've been closeted. That's what living this life is like for most of us. The way things are... This isn't just about our jobs, or any issue, it's our lives we're fighting for.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've learned a lot from you, Harvey. I'm going to get my picture in the papers, too. You'll see. I've got my own issue. That's right. Dan White's Got An Issue!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see naked men walking around, naked women walking around, which doesn't bother me as far as my personal standards of nudity, but it's not proper. We wouldn't allow it for any other parade in San Francisco, and it should not be allowed for the gay parade.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE KRONENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It came in the mail today.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"You get the first bullet the minute you stand at the microphone."  Looks like the publicity's working.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE KRONENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to go up there.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JUMP TO: POV shots of cops and loners amongst the massive audience hint at Harvey's paranoia. Like diving off a cliff, Harvey launches up to the microphone. The deafening cheers surely would have drowned</context>
      <utterance>It could happen any day, any night, any time...  The nation's eye is on us. I have to do this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Wild applause. He scans the crowd as he steps off stage. A bit surprised to still be alive. Cleve grabs him.</context>
      <utterance>My name is Harvey Milk, and I want to recruit you. I want to recruit you for the fight to preserve your democracy. Brothers and sisters, you must come out. Come out to your parents. I know that it is hard and will hurt them but think about how they will hurt you in the voting booth! Come out to your friends, if they indeed are your friends. Come out to your neighbors, to your fellow workers. Once and for all, break down the myths, destroy the lies and distortions. For your sake. For their sake. For the sake of the youngsters who are becoming scared by the votes from Dade to Eugene. On the Statue of Liberty it says "Give me your tired, your poor, your huddled masses yearning to be free." In the Declaration of Independence it is written "All men are created equal and are endowed with certain inalienable rights." For Mr. Briggs and Mrs. Bryant and all the bigots out there, no matter how hard you try, you cannot erase those words from the Declaration of Independence. No matter how hard you try, you cannot chip those words from off the base of the Statue of Liberty. That is what America is. Love it or leave it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He couldn't ignore us anymore.</context>
      <utterance>The Mayor says Briggs is on his way here. He could intercept him for us. We could get him face to face.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get the press.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOHN BRIGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The parade is the other direction.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're taking us another way, Sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JOHN BRIGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a right to be here, Mr. Mayor.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYOR MOSCONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finally face to face, Harvey extends his hand. Its a show for the FLASHING CAMERAS. Briggs is clearly uncomfortable.</context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid it's not in the interest of your safety, or my public's safety to let you into that parade grounds.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, I'm Harvey Milk. It's quite an honor to meet you, Mr. Briggs.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN BRIGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm aware. Sad you're too afraid to fight this out in public, Mr. Milk.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No sir. I would love to have a public debate. I'm very interested in the details of your argument.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN BRIGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know the details. As do the people. Look at the votes across this nation. The "public" is with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John nods, stiff. He can no longer avoid Harvey Milk. He gets back in his limo.</context>
      <utterance>Yes sir, today they are. But with my City's Mayor and the San Francisco press as my witnesses, I'm challenging you to a public debate.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Senator, as a Christian it's interesting that you don't seem to understand what Christ was about. He was about accepting people and giving love, not carrying a Bible in one hand and hatred in the other...  ...Now all the gay myths have been shattered, all the fears, all the--</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN BRIGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not in my mind they haven't--</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it. In your mind they haven't, and I'm wondering why--</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN BRIGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Milk, we don't allow people who believe in practicing bestiality to teach our children, and the reason we don't is because it is illegal. But it's not illegal to be a homosexual in California.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And your law goes even further. Any school employee who even supports a gay person will be fired--</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN BRIGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>True. But, gay people don't have children of their own. If they don't recruit our children, they'd all die away. That's why they want to be teachers, to encourage our children to join them.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>ON TV</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you teach homosexuality? Like French? I was born of heterosexual parents, I was taught by heterosexual teachers in a fiercely heterosexual society. So then why am I homosexual? And no offense meant, but if it were true that children mimicked their</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>ON TV - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The audience eats it up. It feel like "The Harvey Milk Show."</context>
      <utterance>teachers, you'd sure have a helluva lot more nuns running around.</utterance>
   <speaker>116 EXT. CITY HALL - DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Briggs makes a STATEMENT to the press.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN BRIGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If they're going to lead such an open life of homosexuality that they want a 21-gun salute every time somebody goes by them, those people are going to be in danger of being removed their job.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were really genuinely frightened by Proposition Six, and with the backlash gaining strength, we were very pessimistic. We didn't think there was any chance we could beat it. What we hoped to do was to organize to the point that when we did lose, there would be a revolt... That all hell would break lose.</utterance>
   <speaker>DICK PABICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People are coming out, though. We met with groups in Bakersfield, Redding, a dozen people showed up in a library basement in Fresno asking for our support if they came out. Last Sunday, the Reverend of St. Mary's came out to his entire congregation...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're still losing, 60 to 30. We have to take the show on the road. Call Briggs's office. Do a press release. Tell them he can pick the town, the audience, and I'll ask our supporters not to attend.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>DICK PABICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Their audiences are insanely devout. We'll get killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get me Orange County.</utterance>
   <speaker>118 INT. HARVEY'S APARTMENT - NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack is FLIPPING OUT, storming around the place.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK LIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just have to go down to LA and guess the right things on TV and they'll pay us... You have to use your fame now while you have it. We could have nice things.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This stops Jack cold.</context>
      <utterance>I don't have time to do game shows right now...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK LIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are horrible! I have worked on this surprise for you for weeks!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you drunk right now?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK LIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are an ungrateful asshole!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack, I'll have more time soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK LIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're ashamed of me!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not true. I think you're smart. You're capable. No matter what your family or your father said. I believe in you... We should figure out something for you to do. I could get you a job.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK LIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack THROWS A PIECE OF POTTERY AT HARVEY. It misses, CRASHING THROUGH THE WINDOW onto the street below.</context>
      <utterance>I'll never be good enough for you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If in your statements here you say that child molestation is not an issue, why do you put out literature that hammers it home, why do you play on that myth and fear?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN BRIGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Same thing with VD Harvey, we put out publications about VD so you can avoid it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Boos from the conservative audience.</context>
      <utterance>But you've even admitted that there's more molestation in the heterosexual group! So why not get rid of the heterosexual teachers?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN BRIGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are not talking about homos... child molestation, the fact is, at least 95 percent of the people are heterosexual. If we took heterosexuals out AND homosexuals out, you know what--</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN BRIGGS  HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--we'd have no teachers We'd have no teachers--</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--No child molestation... So you're saying the percentage of population is equal to the percentage of child molestation?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN BRIGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, I'm not saying that at all--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what you just said.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN BRIGGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey laughs in disbelief at the asinine argument. Briggs looks down to his notes, lost. Harvey takes the opportunity to rip into the State Senator:</context>
      <utterance>No. I'm saying that we cannot prevent child molestation so let's cut our odds down and take out the homosexual group and keep in the heterosexual group--</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd boos, rails. This isn't San Francisco, it's Orange County. In the audience, Dick Pabich sweats, taken aback by the level of hatred. Harvey tries to maintain his composure.</context>
      <utterance>--Sir, in your own drive for personal power, how many careers are you willing to see destroyed? How many lives will you destroy in your lust for power, and when will you stop?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JACK LIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing. I just want to know when you'll be home.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Did you do this on purpose, Jack?</context>
      <utterance>You just had them pull me out of my big vote on the dog shit ordinance.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK LIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's poop, Harvey. Aren't I more important than poop?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, but... I don't know when I'll be home. Maybe 6. 6:15.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK LIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey hangs up. His patience is slipping. He looks up in time to see Dan heading down the hall with his briefcase.</context>
      <utterance>Fine. 6:15.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dan? How's the baby?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't bring up Supervisor pay raises. In fact, I heard you plan to publicly oppose them.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard you planned to vote against them too, Dan. Were you trying to set me up?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not a good time for me to bring it up. Politically.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dan, there's a vote to approve the police desegregation settlement, give me that and I'll consider backing pay raises.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't trade votes... unlike you, the way I was raised, we believe in right and wrong. Moral and immoral.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Black skin and White in your police department?  Dan, even Ronald Reagan's come out against Proposition Six. You're looking more and more out of touch.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I come out against Prop Six, it's only for the invasion of State's rights issue.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dan tries hard to come up with a cogent response. He can't. His behavior is alarming. He sets down his briefcase.</context>
      <utterance>And the potential witch hunts against you "straight people," right?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You underestimate me, Milk. You're very, very wrong about me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A moment. Dan is on the verge of tears, hot angry tears.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it, Dan? You can tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't... You can't humiliate me. And you will not demean me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>125 EXT. CITY HALL - LATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harvey walks home. A PASSERBY shouts:</utterance>
   <speaker>PASSERBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the asshole that just passed that dog shit thing aren't you? What the hell do you have against dogs?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The young folks surrounding the PASSERBY laugh and hoot at Harvey's joke. Even the harassing PASSERBY can't help but crack a grin. Harvey beams.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, blind people can't see "shit." What the heck do you have against blind people?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harvey. Look at me. Look at me. You did everything you could.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I didn't. Not everything...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What else could you have done?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott puts his arm around Harvey. Harvey buries his head. Anne helps Cleve take down Jack's many hidden notes. Cleve quietly reads a prominently placed one:</context>
      <utterance>I could have come home at six o'clock, not six-fifteen.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Beware. The ides. Of November."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like to trade with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. What the heck are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, me? I'm an elected official. I run this city.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DICK PABICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>San Bernadino is coming in. Not good.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course not. How not good?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL WONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>60% for Briggs. Same in Fresno.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey is stunned. Other districts follow with similar results. They go up in red on the map.</context>
      <utterance>Dear God, little Lotus Blossom.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM RIVALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Imperial is 69% "for" so far.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey tries to stomach this major defeat, loss after loss. He starts reflexively tying his tie in a knot. Cleve comes up to Harvey, concerned.</context>
      <utterance>Put it up on the board.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The whole world is watching this. This is San Francisco we're about to lose. Are you ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can have 15,000 people in an hour. But there's gonna be riots if this thing passes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There goddamn better be.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you telling me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cleve is stunned, holding the weight of Harvey's words. Harvey's focus is interrupted when Anne brings him the phone.</context>
      <utterance>I can't say it because I'm a public official, but for God's sake, if this thing passes, fight back.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE KRONENBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don Amador down in LA.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kind of a bad time, Don.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG TEEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No sir, this is Paul. Don just gave me the phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul who?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG TEEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>REVEAL: The boy in his wheelchair on the other end.</context>
      <utterance>You talked to me on the phone a year or so ago. I'm from Minnesota... I'm in a wheelchair.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you were a goner, Paul.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG TEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I should have called. When I read in the paper that you won the Supervisor seat, I got a friend to put me on a bus to LA.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who did you know in Los Angeles?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG TEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody. That's the uh... I just didn't want to die anymore, sir.  I met your friend Don down here. I turned 18. I voted today against Prop Six... Thank you, Mr. Milk.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You did this all by yourself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>YOUNG TEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think I'd be alive right now without you, sir. You were right about LA. It's like gay Disney World.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you have to see San Francisco!</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG TEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey turns back to the map. Jim Rivaldo is now coloring in LA county with green. On the other end of the phone, Harvey's friend in LA, Don Amador, is back on the line.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. I will. Don wanted me to um... congratulate you on what he says looks like a big win for us tonight. Congratulations Mr. Milk.</utterance>
   <speaker>DON AMADOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It looks like we've taken LA County, Harvey. By 65%. It's huge.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The tone in the room is changing. Jim storms up.</context>
      <utterance>I gotta go, Don. Thank you.  LA by 65% put it up! Put it up!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM RIVALDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey takes a moment to absorb the map. Anne, Dick &amp; Jim, all the volunteers. What this apparent win means to him, to his people. To Cleve:</context>
      <utterance>The polls were off. Briggs is going down by more than 2 to 1. The only district where it's leading in San Francisco is Dan White's.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well crap Cleve, now what are we going to do tonight?!  Cover up Lady Liberty. The cameras will be coming our way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To the gay community all over this state... my message to you is... so far a lot of people joined us and rejected Proposition Six, and now we owe them something... We must destroy the myths once and for all, shatter them. We must continue to speak out... and most importantly, most importantly, every gay person must come out.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>CHEERS</mode>
      <context>The crowd goes WILD. Harvey BEAMS. Moscone walks up onto stage and lifts Harvey's hand. Harvey is now a member of the S.F. political elite. Cleve watches from afar as Harvey steps off and disappears into the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Tonight... Tonight it is clear that everyone out there does know one of us. And now that they do, they see we are not sick... they can feel we are not wrong... and they know we should have a place in this great country and in this world... A message of hope has been to sent to all the young people out there... to all those afraid of this wave of hate... to all those who have lost their homes and their hometowns... tonight we know there is a place for us! My brothers and sisters... we can come home again!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever heard of sore losers? Well, I'm a sore winner... I thought we were goners.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>HALF-JOKING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd started looking forward to the riots.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you, I don't "do" losing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think maybe we're best with our backs to the wall. It's too quiet.  I think we should march on Washington D.C. next year.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I can handle D.C.</context>
      <utterance>Milk, you're a decent politician, a mediocre businessman, but you're a lousy gay man.  Take some time off. Fifty's right around the corner.  Nobody will want you after that...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The people voted for us, Cleve Jones.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLEVE JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Turning back, they savor the moment, like father and son walking to Castro Camera, growing ever smaller in the frame.</context>
      <utterance>They did. There's nowhere to march tonight, Mr. Harvey Milk. Lets go back inside.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey doesn't know what to say. Dan's right, it does make him happy. But it's not that simple.</context>
      <utterance>I just resigned. Congratulations. I'm sure you're pleased.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll be the next President of the Board.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dan walks away from Harvey. He doesn't want to hear anything Harvey has to say. Harvey watches as Dan is met in the hallway by an OFFICER from the POLICE OFFICERS ASSOCIATION.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sure we could work together--</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Dan. Just got word. Can we talk to you for a minute?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dan heads for his office.</context>
      <utterance>Sure...</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey watches as Dan follows the officer down the stairs to an ASSOCIATION MEETING ROOM on the next floor. When the DOOR OPENS, Harvey sees SEVERAL REPRESENTATIVES from the Police Department wearing somber expressions. It looks as if Dan is about to get REAMED OUT.</context>
      <utterance>Downstairs. The Association meeting room...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DAVID FOWLER</speaker>
      <mode>ON TV</mode>
      <context>The news story transitions in the B.G. as Harvey gets up.</context>
      <utterance>--White gave up all of his political chits when he resigned without making any arrangements.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWS ANCHOR</speaker>
      <mode>ON TV/BG</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The city of San Francisco is in disbelief. Four-hundred bodies have been found thus far in Jonestown, Guyana. Leader of the People's Temple, Jim Jones...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MAYOR MOSCONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A man has the right to change his mind. Give me some peace.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many of our propositions has Dan shut down? We could finally settle this police desegregation nonsense. Cement rent control. It's his vote on this Board that stands in our way.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYOR MOSCONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I get it, Harvey. I've been lobbied all week. Enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me just remind you that you're up for re-election. If you re- appoint Dan, you lose the gay vote. They listen to me. You won't get elected dog catcher.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYOR MOSCONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll make my decision on Monday.  You know what you sounded like just now? Boss Tweed or Mayor Daly.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OFF Harvey. He's come a long way.</context>
      <utterance>A "homosexual" with a bit of power... rather scary isn't it, Mr. Mayor?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. This is Dan White.</utterance>
   <speaker>KCBS REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Barbra Taylor from KCBS. I'm interested in your reaction. I've received information from the Mayor's office that you won't be getting your job back.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dan hangs up on her.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I don't know anything about that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>REVEAL: Scott, half asleep.</context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry to wake you up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I went to the opera tonight. Guess who my date was.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bidu Sayao herself. She was in the first Puccini I ever saw. The crowd went wild. It was like I was young again, seeing my first live opera...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you go to the opera again, you should call me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott gets out of bed, considers his words. It's intimate.</context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I'd go with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey is quiet, a rare moment of reflection. An unexpected tear rolls down his cheek.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harvey?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look out the window, the sun's coming up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's late. You should get some sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to miss it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miss what?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harvey's single word answer means, "Life." OFF Harvey: Neither wants to hang up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>This.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, wait a minute, Mr.--</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My aide was supposed to come down here and let me in the side door, but she never showed up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you are?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's it gonna be? Is he replacing Dan with that God Damned liberal lefty Don Horanzy? That'll really shake up the Board, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIANNE FEINSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All I know is that we're getting a new Supervisor today. If Dan shows up, just avoid him. We don't need a scene today, right Harvey?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heaven forbid, Dianne.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Moscone has his back turned, pouring them cocktails.</context>
      <utterance>You can't take this away from me!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYOR MOSCONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The issue is what's fair, for the people of your district. Take some time off. Spend it with your family.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Dan arrives at Harvey's office door. Harvey is with a FRIEND, preparing to leave, surprised to see Dan in his doorway.</context>
      <utterance>This time next year we're marching on Washington D.C. It'll look like Market and Castro, but with a million people. Write that down. Tell President Carter we're coming after him next. I'm going to deposit this. I'll be back in 20 minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, Harve, can I see you for a minute?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dan walks Harvey down the hall to his old office.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCOTT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is everybody? Didn't anyone give a damn?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ask this... If there should be an assassination, I would hope that five, ten, one hundred, a thousand would rise. I would like to see every gay lawyer, every gay architect come out--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>As the thousands of mourners arrive at City Hall, they place their candles around the statue of Lincoln.</context>
      <utterance>--If a bullet should enter my brain, let that bullet destroy every closet door... And that's all. I ask for the movement to continue. Because it's not about personal gain, not about ego, not about power... it's about the "us's" out there. Not only gays, but the Blacks, the Asians, the disabled, the seniors, the us's. Without hope, the us's give up--</utterance>
   <speaker>HARVEY MILK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--I know you cannot live on hope alone, but without it, life is not worth living. So you, and you, and you...</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
