<movie id="391" title="Misery">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I wrote my first book, I used to carry it around in this while I was looking for a publisher. That was a good book, Marcia. I was a writer then.</utterance>
   <speaker>SINDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're still a writer.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't been a writer since I got into the Misery business--</utterance>
   <speaker>SINDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not a bad business. This thing would still be growing, too. The first printing order on Misery's Child was the most ever--over a million.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marcia, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>SINDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no. Misery Chastain put braces on your daughter's teeth and is putting her through college, bought you two houses and floor seats to the Knick games and what thanks does she get? You go and kill her.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marcia, you know I started "Misery" on a lark. Do I look like a guy who writes romance novels? Do I sound like Danielle Steel? It was a one- time shot and we got lucky. I never meant it to become my life. And if I hadn't gotten rid of her now, I'd have ended up writing her forever.  For the first time in fifteen years, I think I'm really onto something here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SINDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm glad to hear that, Paul, I really am. But you have to know--when your fans find out that you killed off their favorite heroine, they're not going to say, "Ooh, good, Paul Sheldon can finally write what we've always wanted: An esoteric, semi- autobiographical character study.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the word "tombstone"</context>
      <utterance>Marcia, why are you doing this to me? Don't you know I'm scared enough? Don't you think I remember how nobody gave a shit about my first books? You think I'm dying to go back to shouting in the wilderness?  I'm doing this because I have to.  Now, I'm leaving for Colorado to try to finish this and I want your good thoughts--because if I can make it work ...  I might just have something that I want on my tombstone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANNIE is quickly by his side.</context>
      <utterance>...where... am I...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shhh... we're just outside Silver Creek.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've been here two days. You're gonna be okay.  My name is Annie Wilkes and I'm--</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now the gibberish words make sense.</context>
      <utterance>--my number one fan.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She helps him to swallow, as Paul's eyes close.</context>
      <utterance>That's right. I'm also a nurse. Here.  Take these.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are they...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're called Novril--they're for your pain.  ANNIE applies a cool rag to his forehead.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shouldn't I be in a hospital?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PAUL tries to test his left arm.</context>
      <utterance>The blizzard was too strong. I couldn't risk trying to get you there. I tried calling, but the phone lines are down.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you mustn't tire yourself. You've got to rest, you almost died.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your legs just sing grand opera when you move, don't they?  It's not going to hurt forever, Paul, I promise you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will I be able to walk?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now suddenly she flicks off the blankets, uncovering his body.</context>
      <utterance>Of course you will. And your arm will be fine, too. Your shoulder was dislocated pretty badly, but I finally popped it back in there.  But what I'm most proud of is the work I did on those legs. Considering what I had around the house, I don't think there's a doctor who could have done any better.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SINDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Marcia Sindell calling from New York City. I'd like to speak to the Silver Creek Chief of Police or the Sheriff.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which one do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>SINDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whichever one's not busy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SMALL OFFICE IN SILVER CREEK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A MARVELOUS LOOKING MAN sits at a desk, by himself, holding the phone. In his sixties, he's still as bright, fast and sassy as he was half-a-lifetime ago. Never mind what his name is, everyone calls him BUSTER.</context>
      <utterance>...with a view of the mountains.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm pretty sure they 're both not busy, Ms. Sindell, since they're both me. I also happen to be President of the Policeman's Benefit Association, Chairman of the Patrolman's Retirement Fund, and if you need a good fishing guide, you could do a lot worse; call me Buster, everybody does, what can I do for you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SINDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a literary agent, and I feel like a fool calling you, but I think one of my clients, Paul Sheldon, might be in some kind of trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul Sheldon? You mean Paul Sheldon the writer?</utterance>
   <speaker>SINDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's your client, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>SINDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, he is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People sure like those Misery books.</utterance>
   <speaker>SINDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure you know Paul's been going to the Silver Creek Lodge for years to finish his books.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I understand he's been up here the last six weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>SINDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not quite. I just called, and they said he checked out five days ago. Isn't that a little strange?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Does he always phone you when he checks out of hotels?</utterance>
   <speaker>SINDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, of course not. It's just that his daughter hasn't heard from him, and when he's got a book coming out, he usually keeps in touch. So when there was no word from him...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think he might be missing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SINDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate that I made this call--tell me I'm being silly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a little over-protective, maybe.  Tell you what--nothing's been reported out here--  --but I'll put his name through our system.  And if anything turns up, I'll call you right away.</utterance>
   <speaker>SINDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I appreciate that. Thanks a lot.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he hangs up--</context>
      <utterance>G'bye, Ms. Sindell.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We actually got a phone call. Busy morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Work, work, work.  Virginia? When was that blizzard?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four or five days ago. Why?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it wasn't a miracle at all... in a way, I was following you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANNIE concentrates on shaving him with great care; she has wonderful, strong hands.</context>
      <utterance>Following me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it wasn't any secret to me that you were staying at the Silver Creek, seeing as how I'm your number- one fan and all. Some nights I'd just tool on down there, sit outside and look up at the light in your cabin--  and I'd try to imagine what was going on in the room of the world's greatest writer.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say that last part again, I didn't quite hear--</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't move now--wouldn't want to hurt this neck--  Well, the other afternoon I was on my way home, and there you were, leaving the Lodge, and I wondered why a literary genius would go for a drive when there was a big storm coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know it was going to be a big storm.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lucky for you, I did.  Lucky for me too. Because now you're alive and you can write more books. Oh, Paul, I've read everything of Yours, but the Misery novels...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're very kind...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you're very brilliant, and you must be a good man, or you could never have created such a wondrous, loving creature as Misery Chastain.  Like a baby.  All done.  ANNIE starts cleaning up.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When do you think the phone lines'll be back up? I have to call my daughter, and I should call New York and let my agent know I'm breathing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(her voice trails off)</context>
      <utterance>It shouldn't be too much longer.  Once the roads are open, the lines'll be up in no time. If you give me their numbers, I'll keep trying them for you.  Could I ask you a favor?  I noticed in your case there was a new Paul Sheldon book and...  and I wondered if maybe...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to read it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you wouldn't mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a hard and fast rule about who can read my stuff at this early stage--only my editor, my agent, and anyone who saves me from freezing to death in a car wreck.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll never realize what a rare treat you've given me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns and goes out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>Boy, it's like clockwork, the way your pain comes--I'll get you your Novril, Paul. Forgive me for prattling away and making you feel all oogy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your new book called?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have a title yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's it about?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's crazy, but I don't really know, I mean I haven't written anything but "Misery" for so long that--you read it you can tell me what you think it's about. Maybe you can come up with a title.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, like I could do that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LIBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing unusual about Mr. Sheldon's leaving, Buster--you can tell by the champagne.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you can, Libby.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, see, he always ordered a bottle of Dom Perignon when he was ready to go. Then he'd pay up and be out the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No long-distance phone calls, Federal Express packages--anything at all out of the ordinary?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think Mr. Sheldon likes for things to be out of the ordinary. Considering who he is and all, famous and all, he doesn't have airs. Drives the same car out from New York each time--'65 Mustang--said it helps him think. He was always a good guest, never made a noise, never bothered a soul. Sure hope nothing happened to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So do I...</utterance>
   <speaker>LIBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll bet that old Mustang's pulling into New York right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But you can tell he's not sure at all as we</context>
      <utterance>I'm sure you're right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops, fills the spoon up again.</context>
      <utterance>I know I'm only forty pages into your book, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, what is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, it's ridiculous, who am I to make a criticism to someone like you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can take it, go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's brilliantly written, but then everything you write is brilliant.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretty rough so far.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The swearing, Paul.  There, I said it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The profanity bothers you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It has no nobility.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, these are slum kids, I was a slum kid, everybody talks like that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There! Look there! See what you made me do!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands him his pills and starts to clean the soup off the coverlet. Then she makes the sweetest smile.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Paul, I'm sorry. I'm so sorry. Sometimes I get so worked up. Can you ever forgive me? Here...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flustered, she turns away as we--</context>
      <utterance>I love you, Paul.  Your mind. Your creativity--that's all I meant.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts her hand on his leg.</context>
      <utterance>This sure is fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Virginia, when you're in this car, you're not my wife, you're my deputy.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, this deputy would rather be home under the covers with the Sheriff.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop--stop right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? What is it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at that broken branch there...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could be the weight of the snow.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps off the road, starts down.</context>
      <utterance>Could be--or a rotten branch or a mountain lion could have landed on it. Could be a lot of things.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything down there?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. An enormous amount of snow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really think Sheldon's out there?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANOTHER CAR DRIVING BY--it's Annie in her Jeep--neither she nor Buster notice each other.</context>
      <utterance>Hope not--if he is, he's dead. Let's go to the newspaper office. As they get in the car--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PAUL'S ROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The door opens and ANNIE enters.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm sorry. I didn't mean to wake you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's fine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They had it at the store, Paul, there was a whole batch of them there. As soon as I saw it, I slammed my money down. I got the first copy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then the roads are open...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The one to town is, but that's about it. I called the hospital and talked to the head orthopedic surgeon. I told him who you were and what had happened. He said as long as there's no infection, you're not in any danger, and as soon as the road to the hospital is open, they'll send an ambulance for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The phones are working?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, mine's still out. But the ones in town were working just fine. I called that agent of yours.  Oh, Paul, I peeked at the very beginning.  What a wonderful first page--just to read the name Misery Chastain...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My daughter must be going nuts.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...it's like a visit from my oldest, dearest friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was supposed to be home for her birthday three days ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts to leave, stops at the door.</context>
      <utterance>Your agent said she would tell her you were okay. But I'm afraid you'll have to wait until tomorrow if you want to speak to her yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she leaves--</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Paul, what a poet you are...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess that means it's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. No, it isn't, it's--  --oh pooh, I can't think of any words. Would "great" be insulting?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can live with "great." He starts, with effort, to eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's not just great, it's perfect, a perfect, perfect thing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As PAUL signs the book:</context>
      <utterance>I'm up to page 185. I always get sad when I pass the halfway point. Will you do me a favor? I'd love it if you would autograph my copy. I already have your autograph on a picture, but it would mean so much to me to get it in person. I know you're right- handed, so don't worry if it's not so legible. I'll cherish it anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't mean to pry, but I've read in two magazines now where you were seeing this model who does those disgusting jeans commercials. And I said it can't be true. Paul Sheldon would never waste his time with a trampy woman like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you can't believe everything you read in magazines.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew it. I knew it wasn't true. Boy, how do they get away with printing stuff like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He finishes the autograph, hands the book back to her.</context>
      <utterance>You'd be amazed at what some people will believe.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you so much.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My pleasure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought it was time you two should meet. Paul, say hello to my favorite beast in all the world, my sow, Misery.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Misery?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I told you I was your number- one fan.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm getting to believe you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This farm was getting kind of dreary, what with just the few cows and chickens and me--  But when I got Misery here, everything Changed--she just makes me smile so.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's a fine... uh... pig is what she is...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm on page three-hundred now, Paul, and it's better than perfect--it's divine. What's the ceiling that dago painted?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Sistine Chapel?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PAUL watches as the pig skitters out of the room with ANNIE in pursuit, happily imitating the pig.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that and Misery's Child--those are the only two divine things ever in this world...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Woink! Whoink! Whuh-Whuh-WHOINK!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE WINDOW. DUSK.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>ANNIE'S VOICE is heard softly.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When my husband left me... I wasn't prepared, it wasn't an easy time...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For a while I thought I might go crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know how that can be.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a peeing sound.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know about you, but what I did to get through it was I dove into work--days, nights--night shifts can be lonely at a hospital. I did a lot of reading. That was hen I first discovered Misery. She made me so happy. She made me forget all my problems.  'Course, I suppose you had a little something to do with that too.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is embarrassed.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just kept reading them over and over. I know when I finish this one-- and I've only got two chapters to go-- I'll just turn right to the front page and start reading it again.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Done?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she takes the bedpan...</context>
      <utterance>No problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't get me wrong. I'm not against marriage per se. But it would take a pretty special guy to make me want to go down the aisle again.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's not something you should enter into lightly.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It boils down to respect. People just don't respect the institution of marriage any more. They have no sense of real commitment.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd love to stay here and chat, but I'm right at the end and I gotta find out what happens.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I hope you like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that, she exits.</context>
      <utterance>Of course I'll like it. Misery's about to have her child. What's it gonna be, a boy or a girl? Ooh, don't tell me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You...you dirty bird. She can't be dead. Misery Chastain cannot be dead! How could you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Annie, in 1871, women often died in childbirth, but her spirit is the important thing, and Misery's spirit is still alive--</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And you MURDERED her!</context>
      <utterance>I DON'T WANT HER SPIRIT! I want HER!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then who did?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one--she just died--she slipped away, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you were good, Paul, but you're not good, you're just another lying old dirty birdie and I don't think I better be around you for awhile.  And don't even think about anybody coming for you, not the doctors, not your agent, not your family--because I never called them. Nobody knows you're here. And you better hope nothing happens to me because if I die, you die.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>"HAVE YOU SEEN PAUL SHELDON?"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>BUSTER is on the phone with Marcia Sindell.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VIRGINIA enters, carrying some files.</context>
      <utterance>No, Ms. Sindell, there's no point in coming up here now. Everything that can be done is... Yes, we're working closely with the state police, and the FBI has been informed. Right... Right... As soon as we know anything we'll let you know. No, it's no bother. Call anytime. Bye, Ms. Sindell.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's the list of all Sheldon's credit charges. Nothing after the Silver Creek.  Any calls?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just from his agent.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing on the floor?  It's my fault. If I'd had a proper hospital bed, this never would have happened. Here, let me help you back in.  I know this hurts, but it'll only take a few seconds. There you go. Comfy?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perfect.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're such a kidder. I have a big surprise for you. But first there's something you must do.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't suppose I could have a little snack while I wait for the surprise?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now she turns, goes to the doorway, keeping on talking. She is never out of sight.</context>
      <utterance>I'll get you everything you want, but you must listen first. Sometimes my thinking is a little muddy, I accept that. It's why I couldn't remember all those things they were asking me on the witness stand in Denver.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But this time I thought clearly. I asked God about you and God said "I delivered him unto you so that you may show him the way."</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Show me the way?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She exits and re-enters wheeling something toward his bed. It's a charcoal barbecue, the kind you use in summer for cooking hamburgers. She holds several items in her arms: a box of Diamond Blue Tip wooden matches, a can of lighter fluid. And most noticeably, Paul's manuscript.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I mentioned a snack, I was thinking more along the lines of a cheese and crackers kind of thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands him the box of kitchen matches.</context>
      <utterance>Paul, this is no time for jokes. You must rid the world of this filth.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want me to burn my book?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want me to burn my book?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know this may be difficult for you, but it's for the best.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't difficult, my agent's made dozens of copies. There's gonna be an auction on this, and every publishing house in New York is reading it now. So if you want me to burn it, fine. You're not ridding the world of anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then light the match, Paul.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No big deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you've indicated. Do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know this is the only copy, Paul. When you were twenty-four you wrote your first book and you didn't make a copy, because you didn't think anybody would take it seriously. But they did. And ever since you've never made any copies because you're superstitious--it's why you always come back to the Silver Creek Lodge. You told that story to Merv Griffin eleven years ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, Annie, this book never would have survived without you. When it gets to new York, there will be a big auction, and whatever it brings we can split.  God knows you're entitled to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Paul. This isn't about money. It's about decency and purity. It's about God's values.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right. You're right. I don't know what I was thinking. I'll tell you what. It doesn't have to be published. Nobody ever has to see it. I'll just keep it for myself. No one will ever have to know it exists.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a long silence. PAUL doesn't move.</context>
      <utterance>As long as it does exist, your mind won't ever be free. I think you should light the match, Paul.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's holding the can of lighter fluid in her hand as she speaks and absentmindedly flicks a few drops of the fluid on the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Can't you see it's what God wants?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PAUL watches as the fluid continues to drop on the bed.</context>
      <utterance>You're so brilliant. I would think you'd certainly be able to see that.  We're put on this earth to help people, Paul. Like I'm trying to help you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please let me help you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do believe the winters are getting shorter and shorter every year. People say it has something to do with the ozone layer. What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, it's a theory. Here's your Novril.  How does tuna casserole sound for dinner?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She exits. PAUL takes the two Novril, stares at them, then deliberately tucks them under his mattress.</context>
      <utterance>Great.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, isn't this nice?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great. I've always wanted to visit the other side of the room.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And look what I've got for you. An electric razor so you can shave yourself now.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I knew this was gonna be the surprise, you could've gotten me to burn all my books.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANNIE exits.</context>
      <utterance>Now don't josh. This is a very big day for you, Paul. Here. You just sit tight, and I'll set everything up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Set what up?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the big surprise. Your new studio--after all, writers do need a place to work.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Work? You mean write? What in the world do you think I'd write?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, but Paul!  I don't think, I know! Now that you've gotten rid of that nasty manuscript, you can go back to doing what you're great at--  --you're going to write a new novel-- your greatest achievement ever-- Misery's Return.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Misery's Return?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you didn't mean it when you killed her, and now you'll make it right.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. It will be a book in my honor. For saving your life and nursing you back to health. I'll be the first one to read it.  Oh, Paul, you're going to make me the envy of the whole world...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just expect me to whip something off, that it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I expect nothing less than your masterpiece.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rolls him over to a table she has set up by the window.</context>
      <utterance>You do understand that this isn't the ordinary way books get written-- I mean, some people might actually consider this an oddball situation.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have total confidence in your brilliance--besides, the view will inspire you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just inhale that. I'll be right back.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess you don't get bothered by neighbors much.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about that. You'll have total solitude so you can concentrate on your work.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I got a great deal on this fifty- pound clunker--on account of it's missing an "n." I told the saleslady "n" was one of the letters in my favorite writer's name.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's two of the letters in my favorite nurse's name, Annie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You--fooler...!  Did I do good?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did great, except there's just one little thing--I can't work with this paper. It's Corrasable Bond, it smudges. Maybe you could go back into town and bring me some white, long-grained mimeo.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But mine cost the most so I don't see how it could smudge.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she approaches, he rubs his thumb over the pencil mark.</context>
      <utterance>C'mere, I'll show you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it does smudge after all--isn't that fascinating?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you'd be interested. I'd like you to be in on everything, Annie. Not just the finished book, but how it's written.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you for thinking of me.  Anything else I can get while I'm in town? Any other crucial requirements that need satisfying? Would you like a tiny tape recorder? Or maybe a handmade set of writing slippers?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, just the paper will be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure? 'Cause if you want, I'll bring back the whole store for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Annie, what's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that, she throws the ream of paper in PAUL'S LAP, causing considerable pain.</context>
      <utterance>What's the matter? I'll tell you what's the matter. I go out of my way for you. I do everything to try and make you happy. I feed you, I clean you, I dress you. And what thanks do I get? "You bought the wrong paper, Annie. I can't write on this paper, Annie." Well, I'll get your stupid paper, but you just better start showing me a little more appreciation around here, Mister Man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(nothing)</context>
      <utterance>Operator...</utterance>
   <speaker>...OPERATOR...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shakes the phone. It's terribly light. He picks it up, turns it over--it's hollow, just a shell of a telephone. He stares at it for a long moment, shaking his head, the disappointment plain.</context>
      <utterance>...Shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts the phone back on the table.</context>
      <utterance>You crazy bitch...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul, you're dripping with perspiration, your color is very hectic--what have you been doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know goddamn well what I've been doing--I'VE BEEN SITTING HERE SUFFERING. I need my pills.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Poor dear... Let's get you back in bed and I'll get them for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want my pills NOW!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll only take a second.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want my pain to go 'way, Annie-- make it go 'way, please Annie--  --please...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands him the pills. And rolls him over to the bed.</context>
      <utterance>...and I'm absolutely convinced that the main reason I've never been more popular is because of my temper. You must be so mad at me. The truth now.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't hold grudges. After all, who doesn't let off a little steam once in a while.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands him a pad and pencil.</context>
      <utterance>My genius needs his rest before he writes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here, in case you think of any ideas.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well I wouldn't expect too much.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be silly. You'll be brilliant. Think of me as your inspiration.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On that she turns--for the first time, a coquettish look comes to her face.</context>
      <utterance>I have faith in you...  ...my darling...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Catch this--  --ummmm-wahhhh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't think he's dead, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He might well be. But not the way they say. He didn't crawl out of that car by himself. You saw those dents on the door--someone pulled him out.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was an old car--those dents could have been there forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they drive off...</context>
      <utterance>There's two kinds of people that drive around in old cars: the ones that can't afford new ones, and the ones who wouldn't give 'em up for anything in the world. That second bunch don't drive around with twenty- five-year-old dents.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Paul. This is all wrong, you'll have to do it over again.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? What happened to "I'll treasure whatever you do?"</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul, it's not worthy of you. Throw it all out except for the part of naming that gravedigger after me. You can leave that in.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I really value your criticism, but maybe you're being a little hasty here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul, what you've written just isn't fair.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--not fair?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right--when I was growing up in Bakersfield, my favorite thing in all the world was to go to the movies on Saturday afternoons for the chapter plays...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--cliff-hangers--</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know that, Mister Man--they also call them serials. I'm not stupid, you know.  Anyway, my favorite was Rocket Man, and once it was a no-brakes chapter, the bad guys stuck him in a car on a mountain road and knocked him out and welded the doors shut and tore out the brakes and started him to his death and he woke up and tried to steer and tried to get out, but the car went off a cliff before he could escape and it crashed and burned and--I was so upset and excited and the next week you better believe I was first in line and they always start with the end of the last week and there was Rocket Man trying to get out, and here came the cliff and JUST BEFORE the car went off he jumped free and all the kids cheered--  --but I didn't cheer, I stood right up and started shouting, "This isn't what happened last week--have you all got amnesia?--THEY JUST CHEATED</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They always cheated like that in cliff--  --chapter plays.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she goes--</context>
      <utterance>But not you. Not with my Misery. Remember, Ian did ride for Dr. Cleary at the end of the last book, but his horse fell jumping that fence and Ian broke his shoulder and his ribs and lay there all night in the ditch so he never reached the doctor, so there couldn't have been any "experimental blood transfusion" that saved her life. Misery was buried in the ground at the end, Paul, so you'll have to start there.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PAUL slumps, staring barefully at the typewriter.</context>
      <utterance>Look at this, I've got Lizzie Borden for an editor, here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter, Paul? You haven't written a word.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't write this anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be silly. Of course you can.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm telling you, I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can--you have the "gotta"--</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The "gotta." Remember, you talked about it in Playboy magazine. You said there's a million things you can't do in this world; you can't hit a curve ball, you can't fix a leaky faucet or make a marriage work-- but there's one thing you always have, and that's the power of the "gotta."</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said you can make it so they gotta turn the page. You know, "I 'gotta' know will she live," "I 'gotta' know will he catch the killer." "I gotta see how this chapter ends." You said it. I don't usually buy that magazine. I only got it, 'cause they were interviewing you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about a bee...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, is it fair? Should I keep going?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You better. Oh, Paul, when Ian realized that the reason they'd buried Misery alive was because the bee sting had put her in that temporary coma--</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--and when Gravedigger Wilkes remembered how thirty years earlier, the same thing had happened to Lady Evelyn-Hyde--  --and then old Dr. Cleary deduced that Misery must be Lady Evelyn-Hyde's long-lost daughter because of the rarity of deadly bee-stings--my heart just leapt.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've known from the very first book that Misery had to be born of nobility and I was right!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, yeah...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Paul, can I read each chapter when you finish? I can fill in the "n"s.  Will she be her old self, now that Ian has dug her out, or will she have amnesia...?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...have to wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will she still love him with that special perfect love?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have to wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Not even a hint?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Misery's alive! Misery's alive. Oh, it's so romantic--this whole house is going to be filled with romance. I'm going to put on my Liberace records--  --you do like Liberace, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whenever he played Radio City, who do you think was right there in the front row?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to play my records all day</utterance>
   <speaker>LONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that, she starts to leave.</context>
      <utterance>--to inspire you--he's my all-time favorite.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops at the door.</context>
      <utterance>Annie?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She can't speak.</context>
      <utterance>Would you have dinner with me tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To celebrate Misery's return. I couldn't have done it without you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANNIE dashes excitedly out of the room. PAUL wheels over to the bed, pulls the packet of Novril powder out from the mattress and stuffs it in his pants. The sound of Liberace playing "Tammy" with orchestra and chorus booms in from beyond the door.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Paul. It would be an honor.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BUSTER'S OFFICE. DUSK.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>VIRGINIA is on the phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BUSTER enters carrying a bagful of books.</context>
      <utterance>No, he's not here. I don't know where he went. He never tells me anything anymore. He's probably out having an affair somewhere. Wait a minute. I think I hear him coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Jim Taylor. He wants to know who you've been having an affair with.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Jim, what's doing? Uh-huh... uh- huh... Jim, we've been over this. If you're gonna have benches in front of your store, people are gonna sit on them. I don't like him either, but I'm not going to come over there and tell him to move. Give my best to Denise. Bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, whoever she is, she sure likes to read a lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Virginia, I'm flattered you think I got that much energy. I just figured if I can't find Paul Sheldon, at least I can find out what he wrote about.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you expect to find? A story about a guy who drove his car off a cliff in a snowstorm?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, you see, it's that kind of sarcasm that's given our marriage real spice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope you like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It looks wonderful. And so do you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They eat in awkward silence. Finally:</context>
      <utterance>Oh...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never had meatloaf this good, what do you do to it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My secret is I only use fresh tomatoes, never canned. And to give it that little extra zip, I mix in some Spam with the ground beef.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After another pause:</context>
      <utterance>Oh.  You can't get this in a restaurant in New York.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Annie, I think we should have a toast.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A toast?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul pours more of the Gallo wine, then raises his glass.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, to Misery. Let me pour you some more wine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To Misery.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, let's do this right. Do you have any candles?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She exits into the kitchen. PAUL quickly pulls the packet filled with Novril powder from his pants. He empties it into her glass of wine, stuffs the empty packet back into his pants, talking the whole time:</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I don't know. I think so. I'll go look.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you study decorating, or do you just have a flair?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you. I just picked things up over the years.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it certainly says you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really think so?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANNIE re-enters with a candle.</context>
      <utterance>Absolutely. Listen, if you can't find any, it's okay. I just thought it might be nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding? If anyone ever told me that one day I'd be having a candlelit dinner with Paul Sheldon in my own house, I woulda checked both legs to see which one was being pulled. Will this do?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She places the candle on the table. With a slight tremor in her hand, she lights the candle. PAUL raises his glass.</context>
      <utterance>It's perfect.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANNIE raises her glass.</context>
      <utterance>To Misery and Annie Wilkes, who brought her back to life.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that, her emotions having gotten the best of her, she knocks over the candle. In trying to right the situation, she places her glass back down, and as she reaches for the candle, she knocks over her glass, spilling the wine.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Paul, every time I think about it, I get goosebumps. They clink glasses.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, God, what have I done? I'm so sorry, Paul. I ruined your beautiful toast. Will you ever forgive me? Here, let me pour another one.  Can we pretend this never happened? To Misery?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>So they drink their wine.</context>
      <utterance>To Misery.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul, this is positively the best Misery you've ever written.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you're right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PAUL'S ROOM. LATER.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>ANNIE, bringing a tray of food.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul hands her some new pages. As she exits,</context>
      <utterance>I think it's so wonderful that Misery would sacrifice her title to take up the cause of her people. That's true nobility.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When you first came here, I only loved the writer part of Paul Sheldon. But now I know I love the rest of him too. As much as Misery loves Ian.  I know you don't love me--don't say you do--you're a beautiful, brilliant, famous man of the world; and I'm...not a movie star type. You'll never know the fear of losing someone like you if you're someone like me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would you lose me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The book is almost finished. Your legs are getting better. Soon you'll be able to walk. You'll be wanting to leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would I want to leave? I like it here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's very kind of you, but I'll bet it's not altogether true.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slowly reaches into the pocket of her bathrobe and pulls out a .38 Special.</context>
      <utterance>It is.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have this gun, and sometimes I think about using it. She is absentmindedly clicking the empty gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robot-like, she crosses to the door and leaves. As she closes and locks the door--</context>
      <utterance>I better go now. I might put bullets in it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"There is a justice higher than that of man. I will be judged by Him."</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're hauling Misery into court.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"There is a justice higher than that of man--I will be judged by Him."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul, I know you've been out.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've been out of your room.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I haven't.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul, my little ceramic penguin in the study always faces due south.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PAUL looks up at her--he is totally honest and sincere. As he talks, his hand surreptitiously begins moving toward the mattress edge.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you're talking about.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that, she reaches down out of sight and comes up holding a 16-inch piece of 4 x 4 wood.</context>
      <utterance>Last night it came so clear. I realize you just need more time. Eventually, you'll come to accept the idea of being here. Paul, do you know about the early days at the Kimberly Diamond Mine? Do you know what they did to the native workers who stole diamonds? Don't worry, they didn't kill them. That would be like junking a Mercedes just because it had a broken spring-- no, if they caught them they had to make sure they could go on working, but they also had to make sure they could never run away. The operation was called hobbling.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Annie, whatever you're thinking about, don't do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now don't fuss, Paul.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANNIE picks up a sledgehammer.</context>
      <utterance>Why would I run away? I'm a writer, Annie--it's all I am--and I've never written this well--even you said that this is my best, didn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't you? Why would I leave a place where I'm doing my best work? It doesn't make any sense.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes the sledgehammer back.</context>
      <utterance>Shh, darling, trust me--  It's for the best.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As ANNIE swings, the sledgehammer makes contact with the ankle. It breaks with a sharp CRACK.</context>
      <utterance>Annie, for God's sake, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And as she breaks the other ankle, PAUL shrieks even louder.</context>
      <utterance>Almost done, just one more.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just leave it, all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I like that tone.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many times do I have to tell you-- I have a system here.  Where the hell is that thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That thing.  Here it is. Right where it's supposed to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure. Maybe nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIRGINIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's good you found it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As BUSTER leaves, VIRGINIA goes back to tidying the desk.</context>
      <utterance>There's that spice again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Punkin.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she exits our view--</context>
      <utterance>Give us a smile?  Such a kidder.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Pete.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buster.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Answer me a couple things?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I can.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have any of those new Paul Sheldon books?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We had a batch. Sold 'em all in three days.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wouldn't happen to remember if Miz Wilkes bought one, would you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BUSTER opens the cash register, drops his coffee money inside, closes the register.</context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding? Every time that fella writes a book, she makes me set aside the first copy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Has she been buying any odd things lately?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miz Wilkes? Same old stuff.  --Lest you call paper odd.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Newspapers?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, the typing kind.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul, don't you think it's time for you to start writing again? It's been over a week.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, it's weird, but a couple of broken bones hasn't done a lot for my creative juices. Get the fuck out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't talk to me like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, what are you going to do?  Kill me? Take your best shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you so mean, Mister you'd-be- dead-in-the-snow-if-it-wasn't-for- me?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, no reason, you keep me prisoner, you make me burn my book, you drive a sledgehammer into my ankles...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll drive a sledgehammer into your man-gland if you're not nicer--</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be my guest.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she exits.</context>
      <utterance>That's disgusting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, my!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, didn't mean to startle you. You didn't give me a chance to knock.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guess you can tell from my reaction, I'm not all that used to visitors out here. What can I do for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just wondering if you happen to know anything about Paul Sheldon.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want to know?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything you can tell me might help.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, he was born in Worcester, Massachusetts, forty-two years ago, the only child of Franklin and Helene Sheldon, mediocre student, majored in history...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, that's not exactly the kind of information I was after. You see, he's been missing for quite some time now, and...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. It's so upsetting. I'm his number-one fan...I've got all his books, every sentence he ever put down. I'm so proud of my Paul Sheldon collection...  ...here I am, prattling on and my manners have just flown away. I haven't invited you in. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANNIE lets BUSTER in, closes the door. They linger in front of Paul's door. Buster idly checks out the hallway.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BUSTER nods and wanders into the living room. ANNIE follows. He crosses into the study and checks out a bookcase that contains the complete works of Paul Sheldon. One shelf below contains Annie's infamous scrapbook.</context>
      <utterance>'Course you must know about that horrible accident.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Almost killed me, too. I prayed when I heard the news. I got down on my knees and begged for it not to be true.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BUSTER enters Paul's room. ANNIE follows.</context>
      <utterance>To try and be his replacement--he gave so much pleasure to so many people and there's a shortage of pleasure on this planet these days, in case you hadn't noticed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God told me, since I was his number- one fan, that I should make up new stories as if I was Paul Sheldon. So, went to town. And I bought a typewriter. And paper to type on. The same kind Paul Sheldon used. And I turned the guest bedroom into a writing studio. Would you like to see it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BUSTER takes a look in the bathroom. ANNIE waits for him.</context>
      <utterance>It's right this way.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's right here. I knew how he wrote, the kinds of words he used, the wonderful stories he told--  --I've spent the last four weeks trying to write like Paul Sheldon.  But I can't do it right. I try and I try and I know all the words--  --but it's just not the same.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well...  ...maybe it takes time to get the hang of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could give you a couple of hundred pages of mine, and you could tell me what you think.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not much of a critic.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I just thought--oh, look at me. You'd think I'd never had a house guest before. Would you like something to drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How does a nice cup of cocoa sound?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she exits into the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Sounds good.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BUSTER lingers in Paul's room for a beat, then goes into the hallway.</context>
      <utterance>There's some already made.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Must get lonely, living out here all by yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I always say if you can't enjoy your own company, you're not fit company for anyone else.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Buster moves up the stairs--</context>
      <utterance>You got a point there...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BUSTER heads down the stairs, ANNIE follows.</context>
      <utterance>Here you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Miz Wilkes, but I don't want to take up any more of your time. I best be going.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They cross to the front door.</context>
      <utterance>But you didn't even taste your cocoa.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BUSTER opens the door.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sure it's wonderful, but really should be getting back.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you don't mind, perhaps I could pay you another visit sometime.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that, she closes the door. We stay with BUSTER. He stands on the front porch for a beat, thinking, then starts heading down the porch steps. Just as he reaches about halfway down, we HEAR A LOUD CRASH coming from inside the house.</context>
      <utterance>I'd be delighted. Now that you know the way...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is no answer. He quietly moves into the house.</context>
      <utterance>Miz Wilkes, are you all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again, no answer.</context>
      <utterance>Miz Wilkes?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BUSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But before Paul can answer, there's the sound of a LOUD EXPLOSION. Seemingly from nowhere a hole is ripped through Buster's chest, knocking him out of frame, revealing Annie, smoking shotgun in hand, standing at the top of the cellar steps.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Sheldon?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANNIE walks toward BUSTER'S BODY and very casually takes his gun out of its holster.</context>
      <utterance>Don't feel bad, Paul. It had to happen. I've been waiting for this sign.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul's mind races desperately. He looks at the barbecue again. Next to it is a messy table with a dozen jars and cans on it.</context>
      <utterance>I've known for some time why I was chosen to save you. You and I were meant to be together forever. But now our time in this world must end. But don't worry, Paul. I've already prepared for what must be done. I put two bullets in my gun, one for you and one for me. Oh, darling, it will be so beautiful. With that, ANNIE turns and exits the cellar.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts toward him.</context>
      <utterance>Now don't be afraid. I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you do. I love you too, Annie.  And you're right. We are meant to be together. And I know we must die. But it must be so that Misery can live. We have the power to give Misery eternal life. We must finish the book.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But the time is now. Soon others will come.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANNIE stares at Paul. She could go either way on this. Then, without a word, she turns and goes back up the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>It's almost done. By dawn we'll be able to give Misery back to the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She exits. PAUL hesitates for a moment, then realizes he has no choice. He starts dragging himself over BUSTER and up the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Here, Paul. I'll fix you something to eat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Paul. It's beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him now, enthralled.</context>
      <utterance>Three more chapters to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The stranger staying at the Inn, is he someone from Misery's past?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is so exciting. It's Windthorne, her first love, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He taunts her with it.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe. Are you ready for the next chapter?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes the pages and goes.</context>
      <utterance>Oh you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It WAS Windthorne. I knew it--what does that do to her love for Ian?--  --of course, if she hadn't thought Windthorne was murdered she never would have fallen in love with Ian in the first place.  Sorry, it's just that this is so wonderful.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm glad you like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul, this will be our legacy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands her a few more pages, she starts reading as she exits.</context>
      <utterance>It will.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Paul. I'm dying. Does she wind up with Ian or Windthorne? You have to tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll know very soon. I'm starting the last chapter. And when I finish, I want everything to be perfect. I'll require three things.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What things?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was fooling, silly.  You need a cigarette, because you used to smoke but you quit except when you finish a book, and you just have one, and the match is to light it. And you need one glass of champagne.  Dome Pear-igg-non.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AS ANNIE exits.</context>
      <utterance>Dome Pear-igg-non it is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that, she enters.</context>
      <utterance>Annie! Annie!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Paul.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm almost done.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Paul, this is so romantic. Ian and Windthorne dueling for the right to Misery's hand. Does Ian win? Oh, don't me. It's Windthorne, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll know everything in a minute. Get the champagne.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She exits; PAUL adjusts the manuscript on the table and then types the last line.</context>
      <utterance>Ahh!!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did I do good?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did perfect. Except for one thing. This time we need two glasses. He takes the last page out of the typewriter.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As soon as she exits, PAUL drops the manuscript to the floor, pulls the lighter fluid from his pants, and starts dousing the manuscript with lighter fluid. He grabs the last chapter and twists the last few pages together torch style. He douses it with the fluid and holds the match out of sight. He smiles as we</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Paul.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all right here, Annie. Remember how for all those years no one ever knew who Misery's real father was, or if they'd ever be reunited? It's all right here. Will Misery finally lead her countrymen to freedom? Does she finally marry Ian or will it be Windthorne? It's all right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And as her hands fly out beseechingly--</context>
      <utterance>Paul, you can't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she struggles to her feet, she pulls out the gun and shoots at Paul, hitting him in the shoulder. Just as she's about to shoot again, Paul quickly wheels the chair up to her, throws himself out of the chair, and tackles her. The gun flies out of her hand and lands in the hallway, going off as it lands. They wrestle on the floor. Flames still around them, PAUL gets on top of her, grabs some burning pages, stuffs them into her mouth, shouting --</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to kill you, you lying cocksucker...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And as he forces more paper into her mouth--</context>
      <utterance>Here. Here. You want it? You want it? You can eat it--eat it--eat it till you fucking CHOKE--you sick, twisted fuck.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>YOUNGER COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the writer--the dead one--</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--right! I'm the dead one--</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Sheriff McCain?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's in the cellar. She killed him.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Annie Wilkes?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. She's in there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PALM COURT, PLAZA HOTEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARCIA SINDELL is seated at a table. PAUL enters, walking briskly, and he's never looked this good before. He's gained his weight back, his color is normal again. He appears to be, for the first time in the movie, a jaunty, happy figure.</context>
      <utterance>This legend appears: ONE YEAR LATER</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry I'm late. Jenny's basketball game went into overtime. If anybody ever told me I'd have a daughter who'd get a triple double, I'd...</utterance>
   <speaker>SINDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did they win?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. They're in the semis.</utterance>
   <speaker>SINDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she hands him a wrapped package. PAUL sits, begins unwrapping it. It's a book. A new one by Paul Sheldon. The Higher Education of J. Phillip Stone. Paul turns it over gently in his hands.</context>
      <utterance>Here it is.  Very first copy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SINDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The word I'm getting is the Times review is gonna be a love letter.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That'd be a first.</utterance>
   <speaker>SINDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And my contacts at Time and Newsweek tell me they're both raves. And don't laugh--for the first time, I think you've got a shot at some prizes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great.</utterance>
   <speaker>SINDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you'd be thrilled. You're being taken seriously.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm delighted the critics are liking it, and I hope the people like it, too. But it's not why I wrote the book.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like it. Remember how you once said I live my whole life as if I'm in danger of being found out? Well, I believe I've managed to get that guy down on paper.  Don't think I'm completely nuts, but in some way, Annie Wilkes, that whole experience, helped me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SINDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul, since you brought her up, I have to ask you this, or I'd be drummed out of the agents' union-- what about a non-fiction book? The truth about what went on in that house.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gee, Marcia, if I didn't know you better, I'd think you were suggesting I dredge up the worst horror of my life just so we could make a few bucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>SINDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Paul glances around...</context>
      <utterance>Now you've hurt me, Paul.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SINDELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you were over it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am. Well, maybe not completely-- He glances toward the trolley.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know if you can ever be totally over something like that--I just don't think about it as much anymore, and when I do, it's not so terrifying.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, once they found her body, my nightmares stopped.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you care for anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cut me something sinful...</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
