<movie id="393" title="Mission Impossible">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ANATOLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kasimov, Kasimov, good that you called us.</utterance>
   <speaker>KASIMOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANATOLY moves away from the WOMAN.</context>
      <utterance>I don't even know how I got here. I swear, Anatoly, I never touched her! I didn't lay a finger on her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANATOLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kasimov. Don't flounder.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, she's been under too long. Come on, come on!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KASIMOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Desperately he tugs at ANATOLY'S jacket. But ANATOLY hits his hand away and smacks him around the head.</context>
      <utterance>You're the only one who can help me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANATOLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, c'mon, tell the truth...c'mon.</utterance>
   <speaker>KASIMOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll kill me. ANATOLY paces up the room, away from KASIMOV.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANATOLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You asked for my help. You</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The name pal...give us the name.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANATOLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>KASIMOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His name is.....Dimitri Miediev.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANATOLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dimitri Miediev...Dimitri Miediev...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>ANATOLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pours them out and hands one to KASIMOV.</context>
      <utterance>Now, we drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANATOLY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>KASIMOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Anatoly, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drinks. He blinks. Something felt funny about that. Dizzied, KASIMOV swoons and passes out on the floor. ANATOLY moves to the closet door and opens it.</context>
      <utterance>Cheers.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did we get it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got it. On your feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to sleep. Can I sleep here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Walk, just walk. Start walking.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm walking.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Talking's good, walking's better.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meanwhile, MEN in overalls take apart the room. The ceiling lifts right off the walls, and the walls themselves start to come down, revealing the "hotel room" to be an elaborate set in the middle of an empty warehouse. JACK comes into the room from the closet. He hands CLAIRE her jewelry, including a watch and a wedding ring. ETHAN stops what he's doing, noticing. She looks up at him questioningly.</context>
      <utterance>Sleeping's better.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JACK comes into the room from the closet. He hands CLAIRE her jewelry, including a watch and a wedding ring. ETHAN stops what he's doing, noticing. She looks up at him, questioningly.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Claire.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She almost unconsciously slips the wedding ring onto her finger. ETHAN notices. He turns and SHOUTS to the room at large.</context>
      <utterance>Jack.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>A FLIGHT ATTENDANT makes her way between the seats, passing out menus.</context>
      <utterance>Ladies and gentlemen, we have leveled off at our cruising altitude of thirty-eight thousand feet-and we should be arriving in Prague right on schedule.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLIGHT ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A passenger takes one. The ATTENDANT continues on.</context>
      <utterance>Would you like to watch a movie Mr Rosen?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLIGHT ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The MAN with the wedding ring looks up. JIM PHELPS is in his mid-forties, good-looking, intense. He's a tired man, and not just now, it's a profound fatigue. He looks up at the ATTENDANT and smiles warmly.</context>
      <utterance>Would you like to watch a movie Mr Phelps?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A look crosses the FLIGHT ATTENDANT'S face; her tone becomes stilted.</context>
      <utterance>No, I prefer the theatre.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLIGHT ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you consider the cinema of the Ukraine?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ATTENDANT turns and walks away. PHELPS sits back, shakes a cigarette out of a pack, and taps it nervously on the armrest.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps you'd choose one for me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The screen shows an image of what such a list might look like, code names and other information scrolling by on a computer screen at high speed.</context>
      <utterance>-- a former KGB Line X officer now working the international black market selling intelligence. This morning, we learned that Golitsyn has stolen one half of a CIA NOC list, the list of our non- official cover agents working in Eastern Europe.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The Embassy itself comes on screen, a beautiful old building at the base of the Charles Bridge, which spans the Vltava River.</context>
      <utterance>For security reasons, the NOC list is divided into two encoded halves. Golitsyn already has the cryptonym portion, which contains agent code names and targeting areas. This portion is useless unless combined with the second half -- the true name list that is kept in the CIA station in our Embassy in Prague.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Still photographs come on screen, some of which we're already seen -- JACK KIEFER, CLAIRE and ETHAN.</context>
      <utterance>We believe Golitsyn plans to steal the true name list at an Embassy function tomorrow night. Your mission, should you decide to accept it, is to obtain photographic proof of the theft, apprehend those involved, and return the stolen list. I don't have to stress the importance of this matter, Jim. We're keeping it internally black. Because of its urgency, I've already sent to Prague a team selected from your usual group.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ethan Hunt will of course be your point man, as usual. He's in Kiev; we're getting word to him now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look to your right, then back to me. There's a camera built right into the bridge. Whatever you see it sees and transmits it back here. Can you hear me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course I can hear you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, in your...ear piece. You have a lovely smile . Can you hear me now?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Loud and clear.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you take a look?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack...that's spying.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what we do isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack you're so wicked.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too wicked to have a drink later?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ETHAN and JIM PHELPS are in a heated conversation.</context>
      <utterance>I think I might just take that look.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, Jim, fact is I've got more than ninety days leave coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A hundred and sixty-seven, I think it is. Take it all, if you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell's made you decide to take your leave at the worst possible time? Claire's in a weird mood too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh? What's the problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, I had to go to Chicago again. You were in Kiev. You tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell you what?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When you started noticing your short term memory loss. What</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, God, forget it. What are we talking burnout here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ethan, you</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLAIRE, who is at the computer behind them, somehow seems to be the reference point in the following exchange:</context>
      <utterance>Because I can't afford it. And because you'd burn up before you'd burn out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How was Chicago?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PHELPS laughs. ETHAN doesn't. The back of CLAIRE'S head is in his line of sight.</context>
      <utterance>Wonderful. Ran into a convention of auto dealers at the Drake Hotel. You hear the one about the astronaut who comes back from the first manned flight to Mars after two years? His wife's got a year old kid. So he says "All right. Who was it? My friend Harry?" She says no. "Oh, it was my friend Sammy." She says it wasn't Sammy. "Oh, I suppose it was my friend Lou." "No, what's the matter, don't you think I have any friends of my own?!"</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He leads ETHAN to the window, which overlooks the city.</context>
      <utterance>Boy, you really are grim. Come here, take a look.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>quicktime video image in a box on her screen. In it, an old edition of the McLaughlin Report, the PBS news show, is playing. ETHAN is distracted by it.</context>
      <utterance>Beyond Charles Bridge there is our Embassy. See it? Tomorrow night, if anything goes wrong, this guy will steal the names of our agents in every country all over Eastern Europe. Up for grabs to the highest bidders -- third world terrorists, arms dealers, drug lords -- any and everybody who'd love to get rid of long term coverts like us, and some very dear friends among them. If they're exposed, they'll be executed. Come over here. Take a lock at this. CLAIRE, who is working at a computer, has pulled up a</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>SENATOR WALTZER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll go you one further. I say the CIA and all its shadow organizations have become irrelevant at best and unconstitutional at worst. It's time we throw a little light on the whole concept of the Pentagon's "black budget." These covert agency subgroups have confidential funding, they report to no one --</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going to use Walter?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's our guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't he chairing the Armed Services hearing?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not this week. This week he's flyfishing at the Oughterard Slough in County Kildare, with one of our best Irish guides.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He won't be back in a hurry?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not in a hurry. What do you think? You think the plot'll work?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. If the main character does.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you were me, Ethan, who would</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JACK shows the gum to ETHAN.</context>
      <utterance>Always.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stick of gum. If you come up against a lock you can't pick -- Half the gum is red, the other half is green.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He offers the gum to ETHAN.</context>
      <utterance>Red light. Green light. Mash them together, asta lasagna. Don't get any on you -- you have five seconds.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLAIRE glances up from the computer and catches ETHAN's eye. PHELPS may have caught the glance, but is focused on ETHAN.</context>
      <utterance>Are you gonna take it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me the God damn gum.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just don't chew it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bet you don't remember me, do you, Senator?</utterance>
   <speaker>SENATOR WALTZER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans in and kisses her on the cheek, and as he does so SARAH whispers something in his ear.</context>
      <utterance>Of course I do. How are you, Miss Norman?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her tone, her words -- we realize she's on the team. The SENATOR pulls a pair of Visco glasses from his pocket (and if we didn't know the SENATOR was ETHAN before, this confirms it), puts them on, and looks up, over her shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>He's in pocket. Under the archway behind me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sarah, mark the package and go to two.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your advance team mentioned you'd want a tour of the facility, so I've gone ahead and set that up for you --</utterance>
   <speaker>SENATOR WALTZER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slips an arm around SARAH and they walk off, not into the party, but the other way, toward a staircase that leads further into the Embassy.</context>
      <utterance>Terrific. Let's get going.  Will you excuse us?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIPLOMAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, sir?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She also has a pair of Visco glasses, which she trains on the party below. She pushes a micro switch on the side of her glasses, activating an electronic filter, which tints the lenses.</context>
      <utterance>En route.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode>O/S</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hannah, pull the shade .</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Governor's in position. We have the elevator.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SARAH flashes an ID at the GUARD and keeps talking.</context>
      <utterance>-- which leads directly to the Denied Area, the only limited access area in the whole facility.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She walks up to the thumbprint analyzer on the elevator bank and slides her thumb inside. The panel lights up and flashes a message -- "ACCESS DENIED." SARAH and ETHAN trade a look.</context>
      <utterance>As you can see. this area has both a Marine guard and video surveillance, and is strictly monitored at all times.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Senator, don't you have a young man on your staff named</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack's pinned down Sarah. Should be a second. Keep dancing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Finally, the elevator moves down a floor and JACK is freed.</context>
      <utterance>We were forced to tie him to my best stallion and drag him around the barn a few times.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He quickly opens the gray metal box, revealing a maze of circuitry. He patches in his computer, climbs on top of the elevator, and hits the keyboard, beginning to download.</context>
      <utterance>Relax your crack, Foghorn, I'm workin' on it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>IDENTITY CONFIRMED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The GUARD, surprised, now catches sight of the SENATOR.</context>
      <utterance>-- and the elevator doors slide open briskly.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He snaps a salute. ETHAN and SARAH get into the elevator and the doors close behind them.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Sorry, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Higher. Higher.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Higher.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SARAH adjusts the glasses.</context>
      <utterance>Right, right. Good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack. Jack.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The elevator stops, the doors open -- -- and GOLITSYN gets on. GOLITSYN descends in the elevator with JACK on top and ETHAN and SARAH waiting down below!</context>
      <utterance>I didn't touch it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OK. Taking Golitsyn's exit. Jack, open the doors.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about my coat? I'll freeze.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He jabs ENTER on his keyboard.</context>
      <utterance>Opening the doors. Go under.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got it. Saved your ass again Jack.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me a break, Pops.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Such a nice ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And a lonely ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sarah's reconsidering. Claire, transport in five minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roger that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In position. Jack open the door, let the package roll.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roger that. Opening doors now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ETHANS voice comes over HANNAHS earpiece.</context>
      <utterance>Stairway, youre wrapped, go to transport.</utterance>
   <speaker>HANNAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HANNAH breaks off and goes up the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>En route.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He closes his eyes, knowing what that means.</context>
      <utterance>Jack. Jack.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets up and races out of the apartment.</context>
      <utterance>Man down. Stay where you are. Im on my way.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>En route.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The package is in the open.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim. Jim. Hes in the open.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ive got a shadow.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you lose him?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Over ETHANs shoulder, SARAH sees GOLITSYN getting away. Fog starts to roll over the river towards the bridge.</context>
      <utterance>No. Abort.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ethan. Hes out of pocket.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim we cant.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Abort. Thats an order.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, damn it, no, I said ABORT!</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sarah eye on the package. Jim, Im coming to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim gave an abort, we should walk away.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ETHAN takes off for the bridge, leaving SARAH to shadow</context>
      <utterance>No, were going to recover the disk, understand?! Now move!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About two hundred yards from the bridge.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>ETHAN continues to run toward the stairs to the bridge. Past CLAIRE who sits in the getaway car. He looks on his monitor and again sees PHELPS POV. Only ominous silence. Phelps is looking back over his shoulder. The bridge is deserted.</context>
      <utterance>Theyre covering this frequency, Ethan. Cut all radio communications. Repeat. Cut all radio communications.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FLAT VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Satcom seven.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Central Europe. Unsecured.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAT VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Designator?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bravo Echo one one.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLAT VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>There is a long pause and then familiar voice comes on the line.</context>
      <utterance>Switching.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Kittridge.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. A funny series of CLICKS comes over the line.</context>
      <utterance>Go secure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Theyre dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whos dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My team. Claire, Jack, even Jim - - Hannah, maybe, I -- dont know</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you damaged?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They knew we were coming. Golitsyns dead too. The disk is gone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dont think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dont</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Location green. One hour. Ill be there myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Youre in Prague?</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heard a lot about you, Hunt. Dont disappoint me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>He hangs up. ETHAN does the same. He stares at the phone for a moment, thinking. He checks his watch.</context>
      <utterance>One hour.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't tell you how sorry I am. I know how much Jim in particular meant to you, Ethan. Personally as well as professionally.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He spots a stack of documents on the table. ETHAN picks them up. There's a Canadian picture bearing ETHAN photo and the name Phillipe Doucette, credit cards, driver's license, etc.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Passport, visas - you know the drill. We'll work the exfiltration thru Canada, debrief you at Langley. Throw the Prague police a bone, you know toss them a few suspects. Follow me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I follow you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've lost enough agents for one night.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You seem hell bent on blaming yourself, Ethan.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who else is left?</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I see your point.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why was there another team?</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of IMF agents. At the Embassy. Tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't quite follow you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's see if you can follow me around this room.  The drunk Russians on the embankment at 7 and 8 o'clock...The couple waltzing around me at the Embassy at 9 and 11. The waiter behind Hannah at the top of the staircase - Bowtie, 12 o'clock. The other IMF team. You're worried about me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For a little over two years now we've been spotting serious blowback in IMF operations. We have a penetration. The other day we decoded a message on the Internet from a Czech we know as "Max."</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The arms dealer.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. Max, it seems, has two unique gifts -- a capacity for anonymity and for corrupting susceptible agents. This time he's gotten to someone on the inside - he's put himself in a position to buy our NOC list. An operation he referred to as "Job 314". The job he thought Golitsyn was doing tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But the list Golitsyn stole was a decoy.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Correct the actual list is safe at Langley. "Golitsyn" was a lightning rod, one of ours.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This whole operation was a molehunt.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, the mole's deep inside. And -- like you said. You survived. ETHAN stares at him levelly.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He now shoves the papers across the table. They're xeroxed copies of a Wisconsin bank account in the name of DONALD and MARGARET ETHAN HUNT. It shows a balance of $127, 000.</context>
      <utterance>I want to show you something, Ethan.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since your father's death, your family's farm has been in sub-chapter S and now, suddenly, they're flush with over a hundred and twenty grand in the bank. Dad's illness was supposed to have wiped out the bank account -- dying slowly in America after all, can be a very expensive proposition Ethan. So, why don't we go quietly out of here onto the plane...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about if we just go quietly into the bathroom and I wash your mouth out with soap - you pathetic button down bureaucratic asshole.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ethan, I can understand you're very upset.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ETHAN takes something from his jacket pocket. While KITTRIDGE talks, ETHAN unwraps whatever is in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Kitteridge, you've never seen me very upset.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see what ETHAN holds in his hand -- it's the piece of bubble gum, half red, half green. He squeezes the gum, mushing the two sides together. ETHAN lashes out, swatting KITTRIDGE'S glass of wine off the table in one quick motion. As he does, he hurls the piece of gum. Diners look up, startled at the sound of the breaking wine glass. KITTRIDGE follows the trajectory of the glass -- -- and sees the piece of gum, stuck to the tank. His eyes widen. KA BOOM! The tiny piece of plastique explodes, SHATTERING the fish tank. A hundred gallons of water flow over the MAN and WOMAN, knocking them to the ground. At the same time, ETHAN bolts for the door.</context>
      <utterance>All right, enough is enough Hunt. You've bribed, cajoled, killed - and relied on intimate loyalties to get away with it. You're determined to shake hands with the devil and I'm going to make sure you do it in hell.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The computer replies:</context>
      <utterance>Job. Job 3:14. March fourteen. Job 31 March.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEARCHING STRING NOT FOUND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>ETHAN tries again:</utterance>
   <speaker>max.com</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The answer:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ETHAN tries to speak but nothing will come out.</context>
      <utterance>Ethan, what are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>ETHAN reaches out to grab PHELPS but can't seem to touch him. PHELPS suddenly vanishes into thin air, ETHAN awakens from the dream and finds himself leaping to his feet, gun cocked and pointed at --</context>
      <utterance>I needed you, Ethan. 1 needed you on the bridge, and -- you weren't there. Ethan? Ethan?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ethan -- Ethan, it's okay. It's Claire. Ethan what's wrong with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her right hand has moved a fraction. She freezes again.</context>
      <utterance>Don't move.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were in the car!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wasn't. I heard that Jim was in trouble on the radio. He said someone was...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up! I saw you. You were in the car.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I got out of the car and I ran to the bridge.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't give me that! I was on the bridge.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to Jim?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was nobody on the bridge.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan grabs her wrists, shouting.</context>
      <utterance>What happened to Jim?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ETHAN releases her wrists.</context>
      <utterance>Dead. Dead. Dead! Wake up, Claire! Jim's dead, they're dead. They're all dead!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're dead. Jim's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take off your coat.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs a sleeve and literally tears the coat off her, half- spinning her around. The coat hits the floor like a dead body. CLAIRE'S instinctive move is to cover her chest. CLAIRE begins to shiver. ETHAN circles her, runs his hand cursorily across her body. It accentuates CLAIRE'S shivering.</context>
      <utterance>Take off your God damn coat!</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where were you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I walked away. He said abort. He was gone so I walked away.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was four hours ago! Who sent you? Did they send you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is "they?"</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did they send you...Did they send you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ETHAN grabs her by the wrists.</context>
      <utterance>Who is they, who is they?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who sent you?! Who sent you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why haven't they brought us in yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long moment while she stares at ETHAN's back.</context>
      <utterance>I've been disavowed. They think I killed Jim and everyone else. Somehow a hundred thousand dollars found its way into my parents' bank account. Kittridge assumes I'm a mole they've been tracing and I've been in the employ of an arms dealer, Max, for the last two years, to get him our NOC list.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you going to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to get it for him. Whoever the mole is, I think goes by the name of Job, at least part of the time. 1 can't find him, but if he knows 1 have the NOC list, he'll find me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ethan, you're not making sense. Let me go in and talk to Kittridge. I'm going to tell him you had nothing to do...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The computer blinks and makes a noise - ETHAN goes to it.</context>
      <utterance>Claire, Claire, Claire, if you're not dead, he's going to assume you're with me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MATTHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you remove your hat please?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reluctantly, Ethan pulls the hood over his head and the car takes off.</context>
      <utterance>You wish to meet Max? This is the price of admission.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought I was going to see Max.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You misunderstood. No one sees Max.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what am I doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Allowing Max to see you and hear what you've got to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't communicate very well through a shroud.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If Max doesn't like what you have to say, you'll be wearing that shroud indefinitely.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm willing to take the chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MAX'S figure into frame. MATTHIAS removes ETHAN's hood. When it comes off ETHAN finds himself looking up at a tall woman of indeterminate age. She's handsome to the point of severity.</context>
      <utterance>Very well.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you and what are you doing here?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need one hundred thousand dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? And you thought if you simply showed up I might give it to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not? You gave Job a hundred and twenty five thousand.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The penny drops.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whether you like a paradox. I want a hundred and fifty thousand dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's quite out of the question.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The disk Job sold you is worthless. It's bait, part of an internal molehunt.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And how might you know that? Are you another Company man?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like Job?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, but, we're asking about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm NOC. Was.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the question I want to ask Job.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know Job any more than he knows me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even so, I'm sure you could arrange an introduction.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why should I?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I can deliver the actual NOC list. The one you have is not only worthless, it's certain to be equipped with a homing device to pinpoint your exact location.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's easy to say the disk is worthless when you say I can't look at the information and</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mm - Hmmm...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell you what. How good's the RF scanner you used in the car?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very good.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, use it. But I suggest pack up first.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MATTHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty-six, twenty-seven. So far so good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the scanner, the digital read-out is now in the thirties.</context>
      <utterance>That's not so good for you, my friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirty-two and change.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forty-four. Forty-five.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MAX still doubts it. The OTHER MAN goes to the windows -- --nothing happens. He opens the French doors that lead out onto a balcony.</context>
      <utterance>I'd say you've got about two minutes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh dear, Gunther will never let me use one of his apartments again.  Phew, sorry I doubted you, dear boy. You're a good sport. Do accept the compliment.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Max. Or is it Maxine?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have to tell you what a comfort anonymity can be in my profession -- like a warm blanket.  My deal with Job was subject to a successful boot scan. Obviously it didn't pass muster. Deal's off.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was your deal with Job?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six million dollars. I'll give you the same. But I want the complete list now, not just Eastern Europe. I won't do this piecemeal, it's too dangerous. I want the</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How will you make sure Job will be there?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How will you make sure I'll have the list in three days? It's been a delight. Now where can I drop you dear boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MAX manages to laugh without coughing. Then, with an admonishing forefinger:</context>
      <utterance>I'm not being dropped anywhere without my money.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to have to front you personally. Don't lose that money without losing your life.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MAX settles back and regards ETHAN. A theatrical sigh. She fancies this guy.</context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't dream of it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The man's gone black, Barnes. He's under until he decides to surface.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look we can use someone from the Embassy and we can get the local authorities involved. Close off his transportation.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can we do, Barnes? Put a guy at the airport? How many identities do you think Hunt has? How many times has he slipped past custom, in how many countries? These guys are trained to be ghosts.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's not waste time chasing him. Make him come to us. Everybodys got pressure points. Find out something that's important to him personally and you squeeze.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Max made a deal with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I deliver the NOC list, Max delivers Job.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've got seventy-five rounds for your Glock 9, but only twenty for the Sig Sauer, one pair of Visco glasses with monitor, plenty of passports. You said it yourself -- if I'm not dead, I'm with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're sure about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim was my husband. I want to know who killed him.  I want to get the son of a bitch who did this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need help, and we don't have time. They have to be local.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of help?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Simple game. Four players.  Exfil opens the pocket --  -- cyber ops lifts the wallet.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIEGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bank?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>IMF mainframe.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIEGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where exactly is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In Langley.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In Langley? The one in Virginia, Langley?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIEGER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he serious?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Always.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIEGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we're going to Virginia, why don't we drop by Fort Knox? I can fly a helicopter right in through the lobby and set it down inside the vault and it will be a hell of a lot easier than breaking into the God damn CIA.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are we downloading?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Information.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Profitable.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Payment on delivery.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. This I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This doesn't sound like the Luther Stickell I've heard of. What'd they used to call you? The Net Ranger? Phineas Phreak? The only man alive who actually hacked NATO Ghostcom.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was never any physical evidence that I had anything to do with that.. that..  With that exceptional piece of work.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know what you're missing. This is the Mt. Everest of hacks.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're all kidding yourselves. Even with top of the line crypto. Cray access. STU 3's --</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Krieger can get it.  Right?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIEGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May take a little time.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May take a little time. That's not what Claire tells me about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thinking Machine laptops, I'm talking about the 686 prototypes --</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I get to keep the equipment when we're done.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luther, I guess you're all out of excuses.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't just hack my way inside. There's no modem access to the mainframe, it's in a stand-alone. I'd have to be physically at the terminal.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luther, relax, it's worse than you think. The terminal's in black vault lock-down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The ANALYST closes the vault door behind him and walks across the room. As he walks, the floor tiles light up under his feet, turning off again when he lifts the weight from them.</context>
      <utterance>The first system is sound-sensitive, anything above a whisper sets it off. The second system is on the floor and pressure-sensitive --</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A thermometer on the wall shows the temperature is 72 degrees. The ANALYST sets his glass down, boots up the computer, and starts entering data from the file folders.</context>
      <utterance>--and the third detects any increase in temperature. Even the body heat of an unauthorized person in the room will trigger it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All three systems are state of the art.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I come in?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's cash. And a second passport. If anything goes wrong when we're inside, if you sense even the slightest deviation don't look over your shoulder, you walk away - you hear me? Just walk away.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't think we're going to make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't say that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't have to.........</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just need you to be safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLAIRE's coolness causes ETHAN to hesitate just enough to take it in.</context>
      <utterance>What about me - Jim called an abort - I didn't comply. I lost the team. I just need you to be safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And they're suddenly, violently in each others arms, kissing and half-falling onto the converted bed. She suddenly resists. He senses it and pulls away.</context>
      <utterance>I wish I'd never laid eyes on you..</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rises and goes to the door. He's got his hand on the knob when CLAIRE wraps her arms around him from behind, turns him to her and kisses him, deeply. This time they sink slowly to the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LOWDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The alarm get louder as it goes off in another part of the building.</context>
      <utterance>Survival.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too short sighted. This guy's proactive, he</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, for -- do we have to evacuate?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's S.O.P..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The GUARD checks a screen in front of him.</context>
      <utterance>We picked up alarms in sectors three, seven, and twelve.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD RICHARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The FIREMEN look at each other. Who is this guy? But he seems to know what he's talking about, so --</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. That's what I've got too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What sector's the air conditioning?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD RANDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh -- twenty-one, but there's no alarm in sector twenty-one.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta go in there and shut it down!</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD RANDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody goes into any sector where the alarm didn't go off.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GUARD RANDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait! Hold it - it's on. Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ETHAN turns and looks at one of the FIREMEN behind them -- it's CLAIRE. CLAIRE and KRIEGER follow ETHAN/GUARD to corridor.</context>
      <utterance>Let's move!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The GUARD moves towards ETHAN, who kicks back at him, pushing him back to KRIEGER, who zaps the GUARD on the back of the neck. He twitches and slumps to the ground, unconscious. KRIEGER quickly grabs him around the neck. ETHAN turns. Holding the GUARD'S head with one hand, KRIEGER pulls a stiletto from the sheath in the back of his belt with the other. He jabs it toward the base of the GUARD'S skull - -- but ETHAN is on him in a flash. He grabs KRIEGER's knife arm shoving it up against the wall. Staring into KRIEGER'S face in warning.</context>
      <utterance>Where's the other guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zero body count.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIEGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll see.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ETHAN releases him and walks away.</context>
      <utterance>Time up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KRIEGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Merci.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not outta here yet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now it's coming together in KITTRIDGE'S mind and a horrible thought occurs to him.</context>
      <utterance>Okay!</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>There is nervous silence for a moment. Behind KITTRIDGE, on the other side of the room,</context>
      <utterance>And where is the list vulnerable?</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kittridge, yup?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You and I know about this -- and that's where it stops. Understand? It never happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gestures to the TECHNICIAN, who watches them anxiously.</context>
      <utterance>What about him...?</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaves. Barnes turns to the TECHNICIAN, who looks up at him anxiously.</context>
      <utterance>I want him manning a radar tower in Alaska by the end of the day. Just mail him his clothes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KRIEGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the desk, ETHAN glances up. Then goes back to the computer. KRIEGER continues to glare over the sofa back.</context>
      <utterance>You contacting your buyer?  Ethan?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIEGER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>ETHAN ignores him, working. His computer jams with static as it connects to a BBS. The screen blinks and displays the familiar Bible group service through which he's contacted Max. When it asks him which chapter and verse for the posting, ETHAN flicks through the Bible, looking for the next code. He begins to type.</context>
      <utterance>Ethan? Oh, 'scuse me Mr. Hunt?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>KRIEGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not going to any meeting without me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes back to the computer, his finger hovering over the "ENTER" button. LUTHER and CLAIRE watch this growing conflict closely. ETHAN sighs and stands up. KRIEGER pulls out the blue disk he took from ETHAN in the computer room and waves it in front of him.</context>
      <utterance>My contact is extremely shy.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIEGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think you're in any position to give orders, do you? Not while I'm holding this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Krieger.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIEGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay out of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>OR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lachez - moi</utterance>
   <speaker>OR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>T'agueue</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches into his briefcase and pulls out an identical disk. He puts it back in his jacket pocket. KRIEGER stares for a second.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you mean this?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRIEGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not it. That's not the list.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds the jacket pocket wide open, for KRIEGER to look into. KRIEGER does. The pocket is empty.</context>
      <utterance>What's the matter, you don't know this trick?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>ETHAN walks over to CLAIRE, reaches into the pocket of the trousers she's wearing and pulls out the disk.</context>
      <utterance>Where did it go?! It's GONE!</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But not</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KRIEGER just stares at him, shaken. CLAIRE laughs. KRIEGER looks at her. He turns completely red. When he looks back at ETHAN, ETHAN holds</context>
      <utterance>I thought you had it! Do you actually think I'd let you have the NOC list?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so sorry. Krieger was my call. I've never worked with him. I'm sorry, Ethan.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We did what we had to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leaves, closing the door behind her, leaving ETHAN and LUTHER alone.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to try and get some sleep.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Krieger</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What makes you trust me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because if you knew what you were getting into, you never would have done it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not letting this list get out in the open.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly, that's your job. Tomorrow on the train, you can't let this list get out into the open. What's the range of this thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's hard to tell. I'm gonna have to be close.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claire opens the door.</context>
      <utterance>I'll get you close.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ETHAN follows CLAIRE into her room where she shows him the television screen.</context>
      <utterance>Ethan I need to talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSERT - SCREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On the screen, an anchor in the CNN news center.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANCHOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CNN reporter speaks to camera, on the steps of a courthouse.</context>
      <utterance>The unlikely setting...a farm in the heartland of America...the State of Wisconsin, where federal agents claim to have broken the brain trust behind an international drug ring. For a report we go live now to CNN correspondent  in the state capitol, Madison. ...?</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Authorities have identified the couple as Margaret Ethan Hunt and Donald Hunt.</utterance>
   <speaker>BACK TO SCENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>ETHAN looks. CLAIRE behind him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>INSERT - SCREEN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>A public official exits the building. The reporter and other news crews charge up to him.</context>
      <utterance>Similar to methamphetamines, cat is seen by officials as one of the most powerful and dangerous drugs in the world. Some thirty-four cat labs have been seized so far, but the recently widowed Mrs. Hunt and her brother-in-law are believed to be involved in a global drug distribution network.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The image on the television changes to an interview with a PUBLIC OFFICIAL who faces a bank of microphones.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Fairchild, agent Fairchild, a comment please.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUBLIC OFFICIAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it's sad, really. Farmers, unless they're a conglomerate, are always operating on a paper-thin margin. I'm afraid what we have here is a case of a naive and lonely widow with a lot of financial problems who chose to make money through illegal means.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was John Fairchild, the DEA agent in charge of this investigation. Officials tell me that international law enforcement agents are expected to arrive here later today to question the Hunts. This is Joe Jones, CNN, Love in Madison, Wisconsin.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kittridge...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ETHAN switches TV off and paces away from it. His anger erupts and he kicks the old filing cabinets, then picks up a chair and throws it across the room so it smashes into the wall. CLAIRE tries to get hold of him, but he shakes her away.</context>
      <utterance>Bastard!</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA SWING PANS between them.</context>
      <utterance>Don't...don't touch me...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you going to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's expecting my call.  I'm going to the station...  And I'm going to call him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kittridge.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see you've been out visiting the folks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BARNES scratches England and 22 seconds on foolscap and waves it.</context>
      <utterance>He's in England.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The TECHNICIAN opens another line on his console and begins patching through to Whitehall.</context>
      <utterance>Get MI5.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The wall clock is thirty seconds and counting down. The TECHNICIAN is frantically signalling KITTRIDGE to keep talking. KITTRIDGE is momentarily stuck. Fortunately:</context>
      <utterance>Ethan, I want to reassure you that my first order of business after you come in is to get these ridiculous charges against your family dropped and eliminated completely from their files. Come in now, we can plea down the charges against you as well.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I ask you something, Kittridge?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Click. ETHAN has hung up. KITTRIDGE looks hopefully to the TECHNICIAN who says:</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, Ethan. Suppose you tell me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Surprisingly KITTRIDGE is not as upset as he is puzzled.</context>
      <utterance>Lost him. We needed three more seconds.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clearly that's the question that KITTRIDGE is turning over in his mind and he doesn't have a simple answer to it.</context>
      <utterance>He wanted us to know he was in London.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>..the next day I managed to drag myself to the safe house, must've just missed you..anyway, I checked our aliases.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- and picked us up in the States -</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- but you left before I could get there and I could check just so many places..</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, smaller countries don't computerize customs records -</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- so I watched Europe. Once you showed up in England..it was easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You knew I liked the rentals at Liverpool Street.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I showed 'em to you!</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PHELPS smiles warmly, has to steady himself to maintain an upright position. He opens a medicine bottle and takes the pain killers.</context>
      <utterance>I remember..</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim, who do you think you're kidding? A doctor's gotta look at that. You can't sit up straight.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can sit up straight. I just can't..sit up straight very well. It's not important! I saw who shot me. Ethan, I saw the mole. It was Kittridge.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did Kittridge do it?..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ETHAN VO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the Charles bridge PHELPS using the Visco glasses aims the gun toward them, fires, cants the glasses and tosses them into the Vltava River.</context>
      <utterance>- he shot you on the bridge -</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN VO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There on the embankment, in the night and fog, it is KRIEGER who takes out GOLITSYN and SARAH thru the fence..</context>
      <utterance>- he must have had back up take out Golitsyn and Sarah at the fence..</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN VO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Here it is CLAIRE with back to camera who presses the detonator and turns dreamily to face it, the explosion brilliant behind her...</context>
      <utterance>How did he do Hannah?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN VO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PHELPS presses the remote detonator and the car blows..</context>
      <utterance>No. No. He could've taken out Hannah himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, Jim?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whats going to make him do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What he didnt get in Prague. The NOC list.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Ethan. Good for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A meeting tomorrow on the TGV, enroute to Paris.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tight security. No guns. Real plus.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PHELPS looks away. Seems badly shaken.</context>
      <utterance>If I supposedly deliver the NOC list to Max, Max has agreed to deliver Job to me. Ill have Claire and Luther Stickell with me on the train. Marcel Krieger will have helicopter transport waiting in Paris.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim...?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PHELPS breaks off abruptly. Apparently some inner struggle over this threatens to overwhelm him. Then, controlling it:</context>
      <utterance>I was sitting in a cafe waiting for you and suddenly there she was, standing in the rain just outside the safe house..alive and beautiful..and thinking Im dead and gone. God knows what shes had to do forget about me to keep going and get the job done, I..</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- no. She cant know about me. No one can. Not til this is over. Theres too much at stake, Ethan.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Youre probably right.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I usually am.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Once we leave the safehouse, get in there and crash. Ill call you from Paris.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And get a doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good luck.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I sent the message to Max. Were on for tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this the only way?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her again, more fully. She wraps an arm around him and he holds onto the kiss. The room appears to revolve around them.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.......come here....viens pres moi... She draws him down by his hand to kiss her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long to the London Terminus?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty, twenty-five minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Youve got ten.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long until we reach the Chunnel?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty minutes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MATTHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes...  Its him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This wasnt what we discussed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ha, dear boy! I do hope this doesnt prelude a meeting in private.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesnt, dear girl. as long as you tell me where the money is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The possibility alone is worth ten million. Baggage car, rack 3. Silver briefcase. Combination 314.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Job?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldnt worry about him. Once youve got the money -- hell find you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if we dont find him - well search the whole train again.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whats Hunt doing on the TGV?</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>High speed train. No-one gets on. No- one gets off. High security. Good place for a pass off to Max.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But why tell us?</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hes putting on a show, Barnes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of show.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KITTRIDGE and BARNES go off back through the next coach. CLAIRE follows into the same doorway and stops to speak into her wristwatch to ETHAN:</context>
      <utterance>I dont know.  It didnt say on the tickets.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ethan...Kittridge is on the train.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kittridge is Job. Max delivered. How far is he from Luther?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two cars. Where are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves onto the next coach, going after KITTRIDGE and</context>
      <utterance>You are my eyes. Stay with him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hes in the baggage car.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode>O/S</mode>
      <context>MAX hangs up and hands the phone to MATTHIAS who slots it into the briefcase next to the computer. He dials a number on the keyboard and pushes send. The computer emits a DIAL TONE. Her computer flashes a message.</context>
      <utterance>Ill be there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whats the problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Connection denied.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try it again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Its not working.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is something wrong with the phone?  Well is something wrong with the batteries?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATTHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I always check the batteries.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Run it through from the top.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing but civilians, Gene.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is bullshit - we dont even know what Max looks like.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe we dont have to know what he looks like. If hes got that list, hes going to want to check it. We should be looking for laptops.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good idea.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MATTHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Its working.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Phew! Weve got five minutes...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Luther. Wheres Hunt?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Kittridge, the NOC list is being modemed off the train.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="34">
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No-one will believe him.</context>
      <utterance>Ethans right behind me. Listen to me Jim. Is it such a good idea to kill him? We take the money. Ethan takes the blame. No-one else has seen you alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course - Im sorry to hear you say that Claire.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ethan?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Here PHELPS pulls out his assembled pistol.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Ethan Hunt, darling. Remember him?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You knew about Jim?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Course he did. Just exactly when he knew is something of a question. Before or after I showed in London, mind telling me, Ethan?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Before London. But after you took the Bible out of the Drake Hotel in Chicago.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They stamped it, didnt they? Those damn Gideons. PHELPS watch alarm goes off.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Certainly quicker than youd like.</context>
      <utterance>Two minutes til Krieger shows. Thisll have to be quicker than Id like.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ethan, if you knew about Jim?..Why..</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why the masquerade? Why take the risk? Well, Claire, youve asked the question and you are the answer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew about Jim.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, he didnt know about you. In all fairness, Ethan, Claire was never convinced her charms would work with you. But I was supremely confident - having tastes the goods. "Thou shall not covet thy Neighbours wife", Ethan. Oh, Ethan is in love with you, Claire, make no mistake about it. And like all the worlds lovers, hes tortured by the same, one pathetic question - "does she feel the same way I do?" JIM turns to CLAIRE.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well Claire do you? Have you been exploiting his feelings or returning them?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim - lets just get the money and get out of here. CLAIRE goes to ETHAN.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>ETHAN hands her the money.</context>
      <utterance>The money Ethan.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLAIRE goes to Jim with the money.</context>
      <utterance>Youve earned it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLAIRE starts to count.</context>
      <utterance>Count it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me something Claire, that night in Prague, was it you or Jim that blew up the car and scattered Hannah all over town?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep counting Claire.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLAIRE hands PHELPS the money.</context>
      <utterance>It was me. I did it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Satisfied?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All ten million.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fold it. Fold it tight.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arent you going to thank me Jim. Ten million is better than six.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dont flatter yourself - six was for</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ETHAN throws JIM the Visco glasses.</context>
      <utterance>Youre wrong about one thing. Im not the only one whos seen you alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PHELPS and CLAIRE are stunned.</context>
      <utterance>Good morning, Mr Phelps.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PHELPS points the gun at ETHAN.</context>
      <utterance>You son of a bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dont Jim.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now we dont have to eliminate him? You like that, dont you Claire? Dont you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim, its over.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHELPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PHELPS shoots CLAIRE. Struggle between PHELPS and ETHAN. The gun is lost. PHELPS beats ETHAN to the ground. His watch alarm beeps rapidly. He turns, goes up the stairs and... ETHAN goes to CLAIRE.</context>
      <utterance>Ethan - Ive always taught you, nothing can be more dangerous than the truth. It can kill you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Claire...Hey...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This stuff is so sticky.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Claire.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAIRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Its all right, Ethan..youll bring me back...wont you...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLAIRE dies. ETHAN looks to ladder hatch and climbs ladder.</context>
      <utterance>I always have, Claire..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CONDUCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, it's</utterance>
   <speaker>CONDUCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll crash into us! Accelerate, accelerate.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MAX looks up, stunned. KITTRIDGE leans over and peers at her screen. He just smiles and sits down next to her, content to wait for her to speak. When she finally does, she's almost charming.</context>
      <utterance>I think this is what you're looking for.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KITTRIDGE leans closer to her and lowers his voice, just as friendly.</context>
      <utterance>My lawyers will have a field day with this. Entrapment, jurisdictional conflicts --</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe we'll just keep the courts out of this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure we can find something I have that you need.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I would</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reach your folks?  How they feeling?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About what?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The official apology from the Justice Department, the VIP treatment, you know, the whole nine yards.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LUTHER picks up his beer.</context>
      <utterance>Well my Mother was a little confused about how the DEA could mistake her and Uncle Donald for a couple of dope smugglers in the Florida keys.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They drink.</context>
      <utterance>Cheers.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's to you, Luther.  To being off the disavowed list.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I'm the flavour of the month!</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're more than that, Luther. They were mistaken about you and they're trying to show you they know it. They want you back in.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. They want me back in so I won't break in! They</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I figured I'd let 'em reinstate my back pay, give me a promotion, check out my office at Langley and</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you come back with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just don't know why I'd be doing it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really liked Phelps, didn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was a good guy for a long, long time. Just - not long enough.  Gotta catch my flight.. So. How's it feel being a solid citizen again?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh man...I don't know. I'm gonna miss being disreputable.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men understand one another and LUTHER will say no more. The two exchange slight gestures of farewell and in a moment ETHAN disappears from the bar, leaving a contemplative LUTHER looking after him.</context>
      <utterance>Well, Luther - if it makes you feel any better I'll always think of you that way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FLIGHT ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She then stops before ETHAN.</context>
      <utterance>Would you like to watch a movie, Miss Clarke?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLIGHT ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, Mr. Hunt. Would you like to watch a movie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLIGHT ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ETHAN just stares at her. This couldn't be what it's sounding like.</context>
      <utterance>Would you consider the cinema of the Caribbean?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLIGHT ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera moves into ETHAN's face. They found him. They want him back. He looks up at her and.....</context>
      <utterance>Aruba, perhaps?</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
