<movie id="392" title="Mission Impossible II">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this, then?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEKHORVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ashes of a colleague, I'm taking them to his family. If you wish to open it, please be careful.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You keep staring at that watch as if your life depended on it, Doctor..</utterance>
   <speaker>NEKHORVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, yes. I suppose I am a bit anxious.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're ready and waiting. You'll soon be with old friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEKHORVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm with an old friend now, Dmitri.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry it couldn't be under happier circumstances.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEKHORVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nekhorvich is overcome. Ethan puts a comforting hand on his shoulder:</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I'm sorry too.. 'You're sorry and I'm sorry..'  - you do know Gradski thought the world of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was quite a man. Did he know before the end you two had succeeded?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEKHORVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, he knew. Just..</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>..not in time to save him.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEKHORVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. After you've lived with</utterance>
   <speaker>NEKHORVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Good-natured laughter. Cut off by a flight steward who passes by, giving a sidelong silence in Ethan and Nekhorvich's direction. Oxygen masks suddenly deploy from the ceiling. Passengers are puzzled and alarmed.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, and you'll get us to a safe place with them, thank god!..left to my own devices, I'm an old fart too inept to read a railroad timetable!..</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You Captain again. We've experienced a slight but abrupt drop in cabin pressure..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INT - COCKPIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The flight crew now wearing their oxygen masks.</utterance>
   <speaker>CO-PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He passes out. The Captain, HUGH STAMP, turns to verify that the relief pilot is also unconscious at the controls. He then removes his oxygen mask, sets the auto pilot, inputting numbers to slow the plane and descend. As the craft titles downward...</context>
      <utterance>Captain, I don't..can't..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NEKHORVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>..it seems we have a problem, Dmitri.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nekhorvich's eyes narrow.</context>
      <utterance>You keep calling me Dmitri. You really shouldn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEKHORVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a lightning swift move Ethan breaks Nekhorvich's neck.</context>
      <utterance>You're not Dmitri?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wallis slashes the satchel handle open, takes the satchel for Ambrose. He peels off the latex mask, revealing SEAN AMBROSE. ETHAN (cont'd) Ulrich, pull the - He tears off the vocal oscillator at his adam's apple, clears his throat, now as Ambrose:</context>
      <utterance>- no. He grabs the satchel. ETHAN   Wallis, hold onto it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>STAMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All done, chief..</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- right -  - don't go too far ahead of me now -</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ulrich has rolled back the carpet over an access panel just beneath them that leads to the belly of the plane. Stamp pulls back the panel, hops into the compartment below which is four walls of electronic equipment. Stamp kneels and slides back the floor hatch. The wind howls, puffs of cloud zip by beneath them. As they descend into the belly:</context>
      <utterance>Not possible..</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Checkpoint Charlie plus 30, altitude minus two-zero-thousand. Airspeed one-seven- niner knots..</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They don goggles and, with Ambrose in the lead, the team leaps, one after another from the hatch, sailing off into the sky.</context>
      <utterance>It's that time. Go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The lizard scampers off, then a low beeping sound at his back attracts his attention. He turns to see the source of the beeping, a small package in day-glo colors with a day-glo streamer. Ethan looks to the sky where the helicopter is now ominously circling back. Ethan lifts the day-glo package and waves it in the direction of the copter. With a distinct lack of enthusiasm. The helicopter once again turns, banks and disappears. Ethan has opened the beeping package and finds a pair of sunglasses.</context>
      <utterance>You're welcome.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN'S POV SUNGLASSES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First, a retinal scan.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELECTRONIC VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Identity confirmed.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Swanbeck's face flashes onscreen. Over his introduction of Nyah is a series of satellite photographs whose subject is so elusive she never seems to give the camera a clean shot.</context>
      <utterance>Good morning, Mr. Hunt.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know me?</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Should I?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You just looked as if you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Just as if I'd like to.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Well. I think that can be arranged.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not tonight. Bad timing. Sorry -</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This stops her. Nyah moves closer to him, until they're nose to nose. Whispered but breezy:</context>
      <utterance>There's not enough time in the world for any of it to be bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, it's either you or the rent and I don't mind telling you it's not an easy choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if I pay the rent?</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Glancing at the gentleman making his way back with her drink then:</context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And purposeful creature that she is, she takes her frustrated desire upstairs, timing her footsteps so as to use the sound of the dancer's steps to cover her own. Once upstairs, a security guard near the master bedroom can be seen eagerly following her down the hall, both moving past a pair of windows, visible to Ethan. In a few moments, Nyah can be seen past the windows in the opposite direction, without the guard following. In another moment or two, a very puzzled looking security guard can be glimpsed in the first window, looking up and down the hall, clearly having lost sight of Nyah. Ethan smiles, moves out of shot.</context>
      <utterance>Go find the wealthy lady you came with and next time we meet - I'll pay your rent.  Now bugger off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She now steps into the tub and focuses on the grout between the tiles just above the sop dish. Her knee eyes search for any cracks in the grout and she spots one. Using a tweezers she pulls the silver of the grout out from between the tiles, revealing something that looks like a credit card wedged between the tiles. She slips the card into a narrow opening under the sop dish. There's the sound of hydraulics and two arms move the marble casing out from the rear of the tub. Nyah breathes a sigh of relief and anticipation: kneeling in the tub she finds herself looking down at an open safe, revealing some half-dozen locked compartments. As she studies them:</context>
      <utterance>Mmmm.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nyah looks up to see Ethan's reflection in the bathroom mirrors, looking down at her kneeling in the tub.</context>
      <utterance>Decisions, decisions.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think you're the only one who can pick a lock?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances up at the mirror. In it is the reflection of SENOR AUGUSTO DE L'ARENA, a big amiable Castilian in his fifties who's changing a white dinner jacket that's had wine split on it. He breaks into a heavily accented version of 'Now or Never', and disappears from the dressing room mirror.</context>
      <utterance>I take it you prefer tenors.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you mind if I'm on top?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a jaundiced look she rolls over on top of Ethan and begins working on one of the safe compartments, using a tiny torque wrench from a tube of lipstick and a carbide pick from a mascara brush. She glances down and is rather disconcerted. Continues working with the pick and wrench.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, either way works for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're never gonna find it there.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn it! Find what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His ex-wife's Bulgari necklace that goes up for auction Tuesday. Looking down to Ethan, a touch of indignation:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- right..where is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She immediately switches her efforts from top left to the bottom right compartment. She's utterly nonplussed:</context>
      <utterance>Far right.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's the bloody -</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- torque wrench.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- this is very disconerting..</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, you put me here. I just do what I'm told.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She unstraddles him and, with a few deft moves with the torque wrench and carbide pick - and it's open. She withdraws a velvet pouch and opens the pouch. Out spills the spectacular necklace. NYAH (cont'd) Lovely. (starting to close the safe) Who are you and what's it going to cost me?</context>
      <utterance>- right..</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The alarm goes off.</context>
      <utterance>Do what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The bathroom is suddenly filled with security guards, gun drawn Senor de l'Arena, looking highly upset, pops in.</context>
      <utterance>That.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENOR DE L'ARENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Senor Keyes, thank God it is you!  It's Senor Keyes, the security engineer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Senor de l'Arena the goods news is that the heat sensors were activated. But Miss Nordoff-Hall, my associate - Senor de l'Arena kisses Nyah's hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENOR DE L'ARENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mucho gusto, senorita.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- did feel that she had rather too long to work on the safe before they triggered the alarm, isn't that right Miss Hall?</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nyah's initial shock and panic slowly gives way to a wary, intensified curiosity - about Ethan.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yes. Absolutely. Much too long I should yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Under the circumstances I think we would recommend re-setting the senors to respond to a lighter load. How do you feel about forty kilos, Miss Hall?</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Indeed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He offers Nyah his arm. They start out. Ethan immediately stops. ETHAN (cont'd) Miss Hall. Haven't you forgotten something? Nyah looking genuinely puzzled.</context>
      <utterance>Well, Senor de l'Arena, there's no reason to disrupt your party any longer. we have some further concerns about the disposition of your security guards, which you'll receive in our written report by fax in the morning, hard copy to follow. Shall we?</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nyah slowly reaches into her dress and withdraws the glittering string of diamonds and rubies from her bust.</context>
      <utterance>The necklace?</utterance>
   <speaker>SENOR DE L'ARENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all laugh, and Ethan's got her out the door.</context>
      <utterance>What are you trying to do, senorita? Rob me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm missing something here, aside from a 500,000 pound necklace. Even after I botched the job, I could've walked out of there with the bloody thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least you walked.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you weren't going to let me get away with it, why did you let me go thru with it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm hoping we might work together.</context>
      <utterance>Wanted to see how good you were.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I say something, no offence? You look like a gigolo, you sound like a thief, you act like a cop - what the bloody hell do you have in mind?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Working under adverse conditions. Highly adverse conditions.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds smashing. I'm in. Muchacho, mi carro, por favor! Now be serious. You couldn't possibly want me off tonight's performance..</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her car arrives.</context>
      <utterance>You didn't do that badly.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're apologizing for me? Quite the gentleman..</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One foot on the floorboard she freezes, back to Ethan.</context>
      <utterance>Not really. I triggered the alarm..</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slides behind the wheel.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, the Bulgari job last week was flawless. And I've always been partial to pale yellows.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes off, spewing bits of gravel and dust in her wake. Ethan smiles and shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>I don't do laundry, or put up with cheeky bastards who set me up on their territory so they can poach on mine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hola..</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. Would you mind slowing down?</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did you get this number? I don't even have it!</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN' VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hits the End button and disconnects. The phone immediately rings again. She refuses to pick up. Ethan pulls alongside hers. She looks at him. They speak through the open cars.</context>
      <utterance>Would you like it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just listen..</context>
      <utterance>Pull over and listen to me, will you?</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need your help and I thin you can use mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your help? What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scotland Yard, Interpol, every Dutch authority. I can make them go away.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She floors it and shoots ahead of Ethan, nicking his car as she takes off.</context>
      <utterance>Oh bloody hell. You're a spy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I deserved that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns up a mound and loses control. She spins out and heads toward the edge of the cliff.</context>
      <utterance>Slow down, slow down.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan cuts her off and sends them both into a 540 degree spin. Her car stops just at the cliff's edge. Furious she wrenches open the car door and gets out.</context>
      <utterance>Uh-oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly there's no Nyah. Ethan leaps over to Nyah's car and sees Nyah dangling over the ocean and rocks hundreds of feet below, holding the door handle.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taking a firm grip on her wrist.</context>
      <utterance>Oh..oh..</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls Nyah up to the car, across the seat and half into his arms. For a long moment it looks like she's in shock. Then:</context>
      <utterance>Don't look down. Just..look at me. That's it..that's it..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's you name?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ethan Hunt.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thru the veil of morning fog, Nyah looks at Ethan. Her dark eyes suggest wit, and willingness, and longing.</context>
      <utterance>Well, Ethan Hunt, what is it you want to talk to me about?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...more than I thought..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awfully short notice..</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Care to wait a decent interval?</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who wants to be decent?..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nyah smiles.</context>
      <utterance>So what've you got against spooks?</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When they've got your recruiting technique? Not a thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Well..this isn't exactly by the book.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They've got a book for this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They've got a book for everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The only other spook I knew was a liar. Charming but absolutely incapable of telling the truth. He'd lie about his favorite color. But then I reckon it's an occupational hazard. All spies really do is conceal the truth and tell lies.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not revealing information doesn't necessarily make someone a liar.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not the point. In the end what spies rely on is the one thing they think they know that you don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which is?</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nyah shoulder and moves into Ethan.</context>
      <utterance>That they're lying. Ethan laughs. NYAH  ..once they know that they can get very very..crosee..</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So where did I got right?</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not a liar. Or you're an awfully good one..  ..this thing these blokes pinched..</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nyah stops to think about this.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know that they 'pinched' it. Don't even know that they're blokes.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, then, what I am I doing here? I assume I'm meant to be some sort of thief-to catch-a-thief..</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nyah looks at Ethan, a little worried.</context>
      <utterance>So do I. Sort of.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spoken like a spook..you ever afraid?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nyah laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Of what?</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ask a question, you get an answer!..</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn, you're beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quick as a cat Ethan flips Nyah over so she's looking down at him.</context>
      <utterance>That's because I'm on my back.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sinks into his arms.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think so.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VENDOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Si, senor.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan enter the bar and goes upstairs to the second floor where he passes security at a pair of double doors.</context>
      <utterance>I'll pick'em up on my way out, okay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A moment where it's impossible to tell which way the wind is going to blow between these two. Then civilly: SWANBECK (cont'd) Sorry I barged in on your vacation.</context>
      <utterance>Fetival's a pain in the ass. Honoring saint by setting'em on fire.  Sit down, sit down. Ethan sits. SWANBECK  Let's you know what they think of saints, doesn't it? Damn near set me on fire on my way over here. As if I haven't been burned enough today.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry I didn't let you know where I was.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be. Wouldn't be on vacation if you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well. You're sorry and I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did you phrase it like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'You're sorry and I'm sorry.'</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Swanbeck turns to his computer and begins play on a DVD, and projected onto a computer screen staring back at Ethan is:</context>
      <utterance>You gotta be kidding.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="44">
   <speaker>NEKHORVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nekhorvich pauses as if waiting for reply. Ethan smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Well, Dmitri! How are you?..</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>..I'm fine..and you?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEKHORVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan laughs.</context>
      <utterance>I'm fine..</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With Ethan simultaneously whispering:</context>
      <utterance>I'm fine and you're fine..</utterance>
   <speaker>NEKHORVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm fine too.. I'm fine and you're fine - do you remember, dear fried, how you got Sergei and I to repeat those lines from Dr. Strangelove and we gave you the name of that silly Soviet Premier because we didn't know your name?..In those days, you not only saved our lives, you saved our sanity. 'Now, then Dmitri - we have this little problem': Every search for a hero must begin with something that every hero requires; a villain. Therefore, in a search for our hero, Bellerophon, we created a monster Chimera. I beg you, Dmitri, come to Sydney and accompany me to Atlanta immediately. However we travel, I must arrive at me destination, within 20 hours of departure. Forgive this fanciful explanation, but for now prudence dictates that I communicate nothing but the gravest urgency. I fear I can entrust this to no one but you, Dmitri. as we say, 'I'm sorry and you're sorry'.. Swanbeck stops the DVD.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Let me ask you something. You have any idea what the hell he's talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An idea, yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like it's a good idea to pick him up in a hurry. And a bad idea to fly him on a commercial carrier. So let's get on with it. He's still in Sydney?</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Vladimir Nekhorvich is dead. So is his colleague, Gradski, but that happened earlier. We had Nekhorvich on a flight from Sydney that crashed in the Rockies.. Ethan sits back, heavily. SWANBECK  - Hunt, are you listening?.. Slowly looking up:</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If he didn't want to go anywhere without me, how did you get him on the flight?</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Swanbeck clears his throat. He turns back to the computer and punches in:</context>
      <utterance>You were there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I couldn't find you, I had to replace you. Sean Ambrose was the obvious choice. He double you, what? Two, three times?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twice.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you think of him?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know we had reservations about each other. Isn't it a little late in the day to be asking me that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Swanbeck shows Ethan a photo of airline Captain.</context>
      <utterance>Not necessarily.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another photo of an open suitcase, the body in it partially obscured by a ring of police and customs officers. SWANBECK (cont'd) Someone on that flight planned an operation designed to down the plane and make it look like an accident. Someone skillful enough to bring the whole thing off without a hitch but - they don't always get your luggage on the plane, even when you fly first class.</context>
      <utterance>Airline record list Captain Harold Macintosh as the pilot for Flt 2207. as far as the media and all governmental agencies are concerned, Captain Macintosh died on the flight, but in fact he missed it. He did, however make the next flight - in cargo, stuffed into a rather small suitcase considering his size.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So there's one thing we know Ambrose doesn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan gives Swanbeck a look.</context>
      <utterance>Then you do think it was Ambrose. Ethan barely nods. SWANBECK  And you're not surprised.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever Nekhorvich was carrying Sean wanted and he wanted to conceal the fact that he took it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enough to kill Nekhorvich and two hundred innocent passengers? Ethan smiles.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sean feels he hasn't done the job unless he leaves a lot of hats on the ground.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan rises and moves to the window.</context>
      <utterance>The question is why? What was this Chimera Nekhorvich was carrying?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right now only Ambrose knows that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In any case, you've got to recover Chimera and bring it to us.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In order to do that, I've got to figure out how he plans to make money with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- right. In fact since the plane went down our banking sources have confirmed a marked increase in the stock pilling of cash in terrorists accounts.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Terrorists?'</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well you know Nekhorvich's history. You're the one who got him out of the Soviet Union was it still in bio- weapon business.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If that's what you're thinking Ambrose would have set up a bidding situation with any number of buyers before he got on the plane. Locating him in time to stop something like that -</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- is where Miss Hall comes in.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miss Hall and Ambrose had a relationship which he took very seriously. She walked away and he's wanting her back ever since. We believe she's our surest and quickest way of location him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then makes sure she continues to see him. Gets him confide in her and report to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You made it sound as if I was recruiting her for her skills as a thief.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, then I mislead you. Or you made the wrong assumption. Either way we're asking her to resume a prior relationship, not do anything she hasn't already done.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's got no training for this kind of thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan's anger flashes but does his best to contain it.</context>
      <utterance>Go to bed with a man and lie to him? She's a woman. She's got all the training she needs.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think I can get her to do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean it'll be difficult.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well it's not mission</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STREET VENDOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The vendor holds up the spring bouquet. Ethan seems genuinely surprised by them.</context>
      <utterance>Senor, senor! Your flowers.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he's lost in the crowd, leaving a very puzzled vendor holding the bouquet.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. They're very nice..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the population of Seville any idea?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five, six-hundred thousand.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's nearly 2 million in London.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And six billion in the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's lot of people out there..how many of them, I wonder, are capable of something like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long shocked moment. Nyah laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Sean Ambrose, for one.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not that it matter much but..I seem to recall you staying something like, 'I was hoping we could work together.'</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This wasn't what I had in mind, Nyah.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it is what you'd like me to do. so tell me to do it.. She approaches Ethan. They're inches apart. NYAH  Come on, out with it. Tell me to go and insinuate myself back into Sean's life.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go and insinuate yourself back into Sean's life.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like a little more conviction..</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So would I. But it's not mine to give.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've either got it or you don't. Let your conscience be your guide?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a smile and a wink.</context>
      <utterance>Something like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I don't have a conscience. I'm a bloody thief.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can be a thief and have a conscience.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You can be a thief and have a conscience: Not me. Why did you have to tell me about this!  What do I have to do to get away from this guy? When you're with him, he messes about with your head every waking moment..even now I'll be at some out-of- the-way-place, a tin of caviar and a bottle of Crystal shows up at the table, with two glass, God knows how he finds out at any given moment where I am in the world but he does. And it looks like he's done it again. You know his definition of a true paranoid?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone in possession of all the facts.  Are you telling me I have to do this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Generally, I don't favor coercing someone. Not when there's a chance my life could end up in their hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that's the only reason?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you think of a better one?</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not me. I was just hoping you might..or that..somehow in the course of business this got personal as well as physical.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, would it make you feel better if I didn't want you to do this?</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Much.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan walks out onto the balcony. She looks at his back.</context>
      <utterance>Then feel better!.. Long moment while she looks at him. ETHAN  Well. That made all the difference in the world, didn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sean will never be anything but suspicious if he picks up some sort of 'yoo-hoo-I'm- not-nad' message. Not after the way we broke up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What wouldn't make him suspicious?</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably that I needed him in some urgent way..destitute - in serious trouble..the kind I couldn't possible sort out myself.. Ethan's been smiling slightly.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Serious trouble, Nyah, is something I can always arrange..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the screen of the GPS computer, a little yellow blip appears pulsating on the screen.</context>
      <utterance>This little chip sends a coded signal that can be picked up only by our computer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When it's in your ankle we can track you within three feet of anywhere in the world.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I can't run your arrest in CNN, but I guarantee he's monitoring every law enforcement agency in the world, for what they might be saying about him, if nothing else - he's got the ability and, we assume, the desire to get you out of there.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This doesn't seem to be accomplishing much.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I mean it's not a total loss. It is keeping a very capable thief off the street..</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her guard, b.g. is handed a note.</context>
      <utterance>Very funny..maybe he has heard and doesn't want to know. Maybe he's lost interest.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your lawyer to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What lawyer?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SECTOR: AUSTRALIA, moving into NEW SOUTH WALES, and then to: Sydney. Here Ethan pulls up names, photos and profiles of potential candidates. They scroll past, one face morphing into another. Ethan punches in on WILLIAM A. BAIRD. EXPERTISE: Qualified in virtually every mode of transport, land, sea, air. ORDINANCES: Small arms and automatic weapons authority, edged and impact weapons. PROCUREMENT: Resourceful. EXPLOSIVES: Precision detonation, diffusion. Ethan punches:</context>
      <utterance>Well, here we go.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She does. They're effectively blocked from the street.</context>
      <utterance>Stop and look for something in you purse..kneel down..</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan hands her a key chain with what appear to be a car-key.</context>
      <utterance>Limo's waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes the key chain. Her hands are shaking.</context>
      <utterance>- Ambrose will have counter-surveillance second to no one's. When and if he contacts you, push this button before you actually end up under his roof it'll scramble your transmission to us.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When will you be there?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Before you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you possibly? I've got to get right on the plane. I'm leaving now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't trust me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I do. But as we know I'm a very poor judge of character.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got you on Qantas flight 2735. It's going to be delayed.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll be fine. I'm going to lose you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ethan, you take care of yourself, I'll take care of myself because if push comes to shove, I'm gonna bail - and without giving two week notice.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They rise. A quick squeeze of her hand and he's gone. A look of something like longing replaces the toughness as she gazes after him, then starts across the street toward the limo and driver. MI music theme kicks in and continues over:</context>
      <utterance>Well, forewarned is forearmed. And while we're at it, be especially sensitive to any sudden change in Ambrose's plans, especially any involving you..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ETHAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look up to a smiling Ethan who points to the ground beneath Luther's feet. Luther looks down to see that he is standing in a pile of sheep-shit.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome to Australia, mate.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both men laugh and all three move to:</context>
      <utterance>Thanks - mate.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the transponder.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put in the coordinates and let's get a visual. The visuals aren't coming up.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The satellite doesn't work as fast as I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Billy speaks, the visual come on line and Nyah has become visible.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I've heard about you, Luther, and I just want to tell you it's an honor and a pleasure to be working with you blokes, whoaa! That's some transponder!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan pointedly ignore the question.</context>
      <utterance>It certainly is. How did we get so lucky?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WITH ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode>INT. SHEEPFARM SAFEHOUSE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The picture abruptly goes dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn. Just when it was about to get interesting.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luther punches in. The signal - and the global coordinates are given. They wait.</context>
      <utterance>It's okay. She scrambled the transmission. Luther, continue feeding the GPS her position.</utterance>
   <speaker>INT - SPACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The satellite positions itself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luther shoots him a disgusted look.</context>
      <utterance>Can't we speed this up.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With what? This is the only computer that'll do this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan's look suggests he's worried about lapse in recruiting judgment.</context>
      <utterance>- right. Now there's a bloke who knows how to deliver a proper welcome. Don't get me wrong, mate. You were quite hospitable. Is it him, then?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is, Billy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then we got'em!</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan strides away from the screen, the edge in his voice and the move not altogether lost on either Luther or Billy.</context>
      <utterance>We don't know what we've got because we don't know what he's got, where he's got it or what he's doing in Sydney with it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not much luggage.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I left in a bit of a hurry. I'm terribly grateful, Sean.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How grateful?</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well that depends.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On what.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How hard you had to work to get me out of there..how in the world did you ever find me?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How I usually find you, Nyah.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you that.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Magic...</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahh..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No flies on her.  No bugs either. She's clean.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All cats are.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>NEKHORVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan then flips through a series of pictures on the computer depicting the myth of Bellerophon attacking Chimera. Billy moves up behind him.</context>
      <utterance>...therefore in a search for our hero, Bellerophon, we created a monster, Chimera.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you got there, mate?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A myth..just a myth...shouldn't you be checking out their countersurveillance?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well you know his blokes'll place the OSCOR in his annex, where else if you're pinpointing transmitters, video signals, covert chip cameras, anything radiating, oscillating..</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>..or hard wired..</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Basically impenetrable, I'd say.</context>
      <utterance>- or hard wired, right. First line of perimeter defence'll run from the back of the dock to the front of the house. Whatever moves burps or bleep is gonna be picked up to a height of twenty feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luther scans an entry from the IMF database with newspaper clippings, sidebars of still of McCloy and Nekhorvich. LUTHER (cont'd) McCloy, Jon Chaddick, CEO Biocyte Pharmaceuticals..D.O.B. September 30, 1952, Manchester, England.</context>
      <utterance>Ethan, here's Nekhorvich, and here's his boss</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well do you disagree with that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not at all. But how about going into town and confirming your intuitions on site?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh well, if that's how you feel about it. Billy leaves.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On Ethan's screen appears the Biocyte website; where among he various icons one offer McCloy's proud detailing of Biocyte's philanthropic efforts:</context>
      <utterance>..then Cambridge..Harvard..entrepreneurial efforts..in efforts..in 1989, acquired Biocyte in hostile takeover.. As Luther transfer info to Ethan's computer: LUTHER  Ethan, have a look at this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your room.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmmm.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long moment. Ambrose walks to a mirrored wall. The mirrors are sliding doors. With a sweeping gesture, he slides one of the mirrors back and reveals a wardrobe of beautiful designer clothes.</context>
      <utterance>And my room?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nyah stares at the spectacular wardrobe. Ambrose pulls out a slinky Armani and drapes it on the bed. AMBROSE ( cont'd) Try it on.. Nyah hesitates. AMBROSE (cont'd) Go ahead. I'm dying to see if I remembered your size.. Nyah picks it up.</context>
      <utterance>Thought you could use a little something to wear.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ambrose sits on a chair by the window and waits. Her blouse, belt, skirt, fall on the bed. As her slender arm reaches down to pick up the Armani:</context>
      <utterance>No changing room?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CLOSE - NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>meeting Ambrose's look.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not interested in seeing how it looks.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Armani falls in a fragile heap on the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I am. Later..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nekhorvich specialized in recombining DNA molecules. In the myth, Bellerophon killed Chimera, a recombinant monster with the head of a lion and the tail of a serpent who plagued the ancient world. I think Nekhorvich has created a monster virus in Chimera and apparently the means to kill it in Bellerophon.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That simple, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>AMBROSE'S VOICE/ETHAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nyah reacts as if she'd been rapped on the nose, her eyes moist. She turns abruptly to camera.</context>
      <utterance>Damn, you're beautiful..</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you say something?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>leaning on an elbow, looking down.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said you're beautiful, Nyah.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ambrose, amused, lights a cigarette and inhaling:</context>
      <utterance>Only because..it's spring..chalk it up  - to spring fever.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Won't do, love. It's not spring. It's nearly autumn..You're in Oz. everything's upside down and backwards here.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe that's it, then. Everything's upside down and backwards...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luther..get us everything you can on the outbreak of influenza on Bruny Island last month, including photos of the victims.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luther resumes working on his computer and sees Ethan is locked on Ambrose's compound on his computer screen, thinking of Nyah.</context>
      <utterance>Right. I guess there aren't many flu epidemics in the middle of summer.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>LUTHER  She did it, Ethan. Nyah's in the compound.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? I've just rolled up a snowball and tosses it into hell. Ethan stands.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ambrose's hands shift to another photo of another newspaper, the LONDON TIMES, this one piled high with English pounds and the written amount: 37 million pounds.</context>
      <utterance>Twenty-four mil..</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The third photo is of the AFTERNOON ARUBAN, with $14 million packaged on it. Ambrose, wearing a robe and seated at a glass-topped table, sets this last photo on the table on top the others. He picks up Nekhorvich's digital camera, removes the film disk, and snaps it into its plastic case. He places the case into an envelope (NOTE: The same envelope seen at the track) and hands it to Stamp.</context>
      <utterance>Thirty-seven million pounds. That's a promising bid.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stamp is seated near him. Glances toward Ambrose's bedroom and Nyah asleep in Ambrose's bed.</context>
      <utterance>We'll need this at the track. Well then. Sorted.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not everything. Why do you think she's really here?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From her point of view or mine?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he speaks, Ambrose pulls a cigar case and a cutter out of his robe. Takes a cigar out of the case and clips the end of the cigar; the razor-sharp cutter decapitates the tip of the cigar like a guillotine.</context>
      <utterance>Wasn't exactly gagging for it when she left you six months ago..The question is, do you trust her?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One considers her timing, of course - getting nicked within a week of the plane going down. Suggestive, even borderline suspicious, but hardly conclusive.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ambrose opens the cutter again to clean off the fragments of tobacco trapped by the cut.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you've thorough about it, at any rate.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sean touches the nail of Stamp's left pinkie finger. Stamp reacts by slightly withdrawing his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me, Hugh. You don't exactly hang on Nyah's every word and gesture, do you? Fairly ratty nail, that.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With his left hand Ambrose grabs Stamp's left wrist.</context>
      <utterance>Sean..</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not scrutinizing any casual shrug for some hair-splitting nuance, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sean pulls Stamp's hand closer.</context>
      <utterance>Sean, please..</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ambrose twists Stamp's wrist so that Stamp drops to one knee trying to alleviate the pain.</context>
      <utterance>Suppose she is some sort of Trojan horse sent in by IMF to spy in us, why should I deny myself the pleasure of a ride or two? Or don't you think I can learn more from her than she can from me?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ambrose leans in close to Stamp's face as he places the cutter around Stamp's pinkie.</context>
      <utterance>I do!..</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ambrose closes the cutter on Stamp's finger and cuts the nail, just nicking the top of the finger and drawing blood. Stamp cries out. Ambrose tosses Stamp a napkin, light his cigar and exhale. AMBROSE (cont'd) Don't ever question my judgment again.</context>
      <utterance>Now Hugh, you must realize that some of us have the burden of sex to deal with..and my dear chap. I may or may not know why she thinks she's here, but I'm willing to take the risk, because Hugh, I am gaging for it..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You won.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What made you pick</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say no more. I'm off to grab a drink. Still favor Bellinis? She smiles, a little shakily. Ambrose leaves.</utterance>
   <speaker>A VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's Billy passing behind her.</context>
      <utterance>Naturally Vain..</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pardon me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billy hands her a chest sheet and moves on. She opens it to the fourth race. Taped onto 'Naturally Vain' is a small plastic piece with the note. she regards the note, places the plastic piece in her ear.</context>
      <utterance>'Naturally Vain.' In the fourth. Check her out. She's due.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can speak as if I'm right by your side.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At the mounting enclosure, just off the tracks at two o'clock.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CLOSE - NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>a swift intake of breath as she see him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's it going? Everything okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just like old times.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just like old times?</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She appears to be the picture of unruffled sang-froid.</context>
      <utterance>Just about..</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me who you've run into at Ambrose's.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>shoulder, looking right at you as you go on..</context>
      <utterance>We know him. He's over your left</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- Michael, his driver's an Aussie, new to me. Then there's the blokes in the annex at the back of the house.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you met them?</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Annex is strictly off limits to me and they never come to the main house, Michael even takes their meals to them all but shoves them under the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've no doubt.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nekhorvich's boss?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ambrose has photographs of newspapers with loads of money piled on them -- thirty- seven million on the London Times. What's that about?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bids from possible Chimera buyers -- to prove that as of the date on the newspaper those bids are back up by earnest money --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McCloy puts the camera down. The two men have words. McCloy shakily leave the table. Ambrose opens the camera.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever McCloy's looking at, he's not happy about.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ambrose just pulled the memory card out of the digital camera and put it into an envelope, put it in his inner left jacket pocket...</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Left jacket pocket?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roger that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Confirm. Left jacket pocket.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Left jacket pocket confirmed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nyah, Ambrose is heading back. There's an enveloped inside --</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- his left jacket pocket.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Affirmative.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do I meet you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nyah, are you up to this?</context>
      <utterance>Betting table twelve off the paddock.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll muddle through.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See anything you like?</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>While Ambrose is still juggling the drinks, Nyah reaches into his trouser pockets, and rummages around.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Naturally vain -- but they're about to close the betting table and I haven't a sou..</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nyah!</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Billy, make sure Nyah's not followed.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls out a fifty-dollar note.</context>
      <utterance>No worries, mate.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you mind terribly? AMBROSE   - not at all. But you'll pay for that and with interest..</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She heads up the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>I've no doubt..</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ambrose grabs her arm, and she almost drops the envelope she's just lifted. (NOTE: It is important not to see her actually lift it). She's holding it, pinned between her right arm and side. As it's slipping, she notes Stamp above her, looking down and has to conceal what she's holding from him as well: AMBROSE (cont'd) Put down a couple of hundred for.</context>
      <utterance>Hold on.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To win?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes it and as she does the envelope falls, but she manages to catch it with her left hand, blocking the move with her body as she does.</context>
      <utterance>What else?</utterance>
   <speaker>WIDER ANGLE - NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>moves along the aisle.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luther, smallest digital you got. Ready to transmit. Betting table twelve.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>STAMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say again?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aggrhh-aggrhh-aggrhh...</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stamp looks around, Nyah's nowhere in sight. He's lost her. Sees his hand's bleeding and lets Billy go, who nearly drops to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever you're about in future, watch your step. Never know who you might run into...</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's the loo then?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stamp heads up the men's room.</context>
      <utterance>- aggrhh-aggrhh-aggrhh...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>ETHAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nyah turns and looks Ethan dead in the eye.</context>
      <utterance>How'd you do? Don't turn around.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I managed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slips Ethan the envelope. Ethan himself returns the look, holding it in spite of:</context>
      <utterance>You noticed. What're you going to do? Spank me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luther arrives, with the camera, opening for Ethan. Nyah turns away. Ethan pulls out the tiny memory card, slips it in the camera.</context>
      <utterance>Stamp's out of the loo.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is going to take a couple of minutes..</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>is racing back to the van.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There in twenty, Ethan..</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH AND ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode>IN LINE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>edge toward the window.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stamp's a little shaky, but headed your way, mate.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Copy that.  Who do you like? In the race?</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What race are we talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>INT - VAN</speaker>
      <mode>DAY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A sweaty Luther:</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm booted up. Go, Ethan.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan places the digital camera on play and begins to go thru the stills. As they cliff off, Ethan is visibly affected.</context>
      <utterance>He's heading down the stairs, now..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you out of Ambrose's place.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan glances over to the bottom of the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>He's one tier from the bottom.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he lowers camera and removes the memory card.</context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slipping card back into envelope.</context>
      <utterance>Thirty steps..</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nyah, you've done more than enough. Even the best of snake charmers get bit.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ethan, tell me -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BILLY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan's been talking to someone he's been urging to walk, not run to the nearest exit. Now he drops all pretence:</context>
      <utterance>Twenty, nineteen..</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you out of Australia!  ..I don't know how much more plainly I can put it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you suggest I go about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She just gets it out of her hear and gives it to Ethan when she reaches the bookie who warns her to get down her bet. She gives him her money and gets the tickets just as the buzzer goes off - no more bets. Flustered by it she picks up her tickets but drops the envelope. She quickly kneels and scrambles to recover it, tucking it away and looking up - to see Stamp standing over her. almost exactly where Ethan had stood when she looked away.</context>
      <utterance>He's touched your heart. You're overwhelmed. You need to think it over. You'll meet him somewhere in a month. If You're not out in 48 hours I'm coming in and getting you out. Give me the ear piece.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STAMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get your bet down?</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rises. Stamp waits only a moment then follows.</context>
      <utterance>Just..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's momentarily startled. Then:</context>
      <utterance>Your nag is making a run for it on the outside!  Bloody hell, Nyah!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You picked another winner!</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's good, isn't?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The photos is coded with the data in the lower left hand corner, 01.27.99, the time in the right, 10:02:56 A.M. Burned into the photo is '20 hours, 03 minutes after exposure.' Ethan paunches in. ETHAN'S VOICE (cont'd) Twenty hours and three minutes after exposure. (sotto voce) Twenty hours. Ethan doesn't say anything for a moment, then goes on to the next photo on the card: '25 hours, 40 minutes after exposure.' It's Gradski again. Gradski's eyes are darkly circled, his skull look mottled.</context>
      <utterance>Dr. Segi Gradski, Nekhorvich's colleague and lifelong friend..</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another photo: '31 hours, 30 minutes after exposure.' Gradski's bleeding from nose, mouth and ears, the skin eruptions are pervasive, his body an open wound. ETHAN ( cont'd) Six more hours. The next photo. '34 hours, 25 minutes after exposure.' Gradski's body at rest. ETHAN (cont'd) Three hours after that, Gradski was dead..</context>
      <utterance>Six hours later.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The victim's face shows a devastation undeniably like Gradski's. A long, long moment as Ethan, Luther, and Billy sit in silence.</context>
      <utterance>Here's a victim from the Bruny Island outbreak.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan looks again at the first photo of Gradski.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, happy day.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>must arrive at my destination within 20 hours hours of departure.'</context>
      <utterance>Nekhorvich said 'However we travel, I</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To Australia. It's made so many convicts feel at home. Here's hoping it does the same for you.. He laughs. She doesn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sean, there's something I've been meaning to talk to you about... Isn't going to be easy for me to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then don't say it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what to do about you, Sean. I'm more than a bit muddled. I need time.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To do what?</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sort it all out.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you're going to have time. There's been a change of plans.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A change of plans?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. We won't be able to have dinner tonight. Something's come up. I hope you don't mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, no, not at all. Maybe just a bit.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ulrich will be about. He'll look after you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lovely.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STAMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you were going to dinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hugh, take care of the Nekhorvich memory card.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stamp leans over and pulls out the envelope. As he does he sees Ambrose has pulled up and started to play McCloy's informercial. AMBROSE (cont'd) (calmly) We've got an opportunity here. I'm not going to miss it..</context>
      <utterance>In the envelope in my pocket. My right.. jacket..pocket..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One more shot. A lavender stained group of spiky objects amid exploding the green ones. ETHAN (cont'd) Bellerophon attacking Chimera.. On an adjacent screen is a frozen frame of McCloy looking thru the digital camera at the racetrack.</context>
      <utterance>Chimera attacking human blood..</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ambrose obviously got these from Nekhorvich on the plane.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What manic invents disease like that in the first place? Why would he do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, but Nekhorvich was not a manic. Get me a twenty on Nyah.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She must still be on the property.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MCCLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He can't resist. Opens them to look up thru the plastic to see:</context>
      <utterance>Bloody room..just..shut your eyes, shut your eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEKHORVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>a shimmering blur coming in and out of focus. MCCLOY  I'll be buggered!..What's this then?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEKHORVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A visit from an old friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's happening here? You're dead!</utterance>
   <speaker>NEKHORVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fatigued, certainly. But dead is a little extreme. On the other hand, when me dear Gradski had your pulse and blood pressure he has less than ten hours to live.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was in the bloody papers, on the telly..what's this about Gradski?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEKHORVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are infected with</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>reservation on the next available flight tonight.</context>
      <utterance>International, please. I'd like to make a</utterance>
   <speaker>OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where to?</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The operator answers.</context>
      <utterance>Where is next available flight going?</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hangs up, goes to the door. The house is eerily silent.</context>
      <utterance>Fine. I'll take it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy, easy, easy, shhh!</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She throws her arms around him.</context>
      <utterance>Oh Ethan!..</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am now. Get me out of here. Just get me out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds her.</context>
      <utterance>It's going to be okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>NEKHORVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McCloy stares at Nekhorvich for a long moment.</context>
      <utterance>No use, my friend. The medical staff wants no part of this. Doctors don't fancy the idea of dying any more than anybody else.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How could I</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have Bellerophon.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEKHORVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You took it! All of it! And what if I need it?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEKHORVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'If?' My, my, my...the five hundred people on Bruny Island that you deliberately infected with</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NEKHORVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By asking me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You still don't get it, do you? You want to make an omelet, you break a few eggs -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MCCLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, the thought had occurred to me. I needed Chimera in order to peddle Bellerophon. For hero to be appreciated, you need a monster. Now that's not so difficult to understand, is it? Look, time was a shot of penicillin could knock off every bloody bug in the zoo! Not anymore!..have you any idea the R&amp;D money it takes to float one little pissy boutique antibiotic that's barely effective against one strain of one bacterium? If I couldn't makes money killing the microscopic little shits that are out there, you'd help me put one out there I can make on!..there it is. I've confessed. I, John C. McCloy, am in business to make money. Lilly's making billions feeding Prozac to depressed dogs. Pfizer doesn't even know where to put the money they're making on Viagra, and let me tell you that shit didn't do a thing for me even at twice the recommended dose, Jesus, who do I have to screw to get a a break!..now get me out of here, get me treated and let's go back to work!..</utterance>
   <speaker>NEKHORVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I think it's a little late for that. Do give my regards to Gradski if you see him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>EXT - ANNEX  NYAH</speaker>
      <mode>NIGHT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>holds tight in her embrace with Ethan.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ethan, you know what frightens me most when I'm with him?..the thought of never seeing you..how are we getting out of here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nyah, it's very important not do anything to alarm Ambrose..</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? You told me to get out of here. I thought you were here to collect me. I was so relieved.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives her an affectionate smile and she reluctantly heads back to the house, her expression troubled, even suspicious.</context>
      <utterance>No time to explain. You've done well, and we're so close. So close. It's critical that you do whatever Ambrose asks. Don't worry - it'll be over soon.. That's a promise.. Come on, now off you go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So Ambrose has Bellerophon and McCloy's got Chimera.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There guys are walking around with different halves of the same dollar bill?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ambrose got Bellerophon from Nekhorvich on the plane, but he didn't get the Chimera virus.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Why else would he come back to Australia? If he had them both, he could sell them anywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I kill Chimera at Biocyte and he's sitting on a cure without a disease.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got the voice print, I'll get us in..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STAMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ambrose looks up slowly to Stamp who's been standing by.</context>
      <utterance>You were right. Hunt stung McCloy tonight. He knows. They'll be going into Biocyte...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good..then we go where he'll be, don't we? Well done, Hugh. Well done.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHAUFFEUR'S WINDOW</speaker>
      <mode>INT. LIMO - EVE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>being rapped on by the driver.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's taking time to register. Then:</context>
      <utterance>You're home, guv'ner. Home..</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Where is he?</context>
      <utterance>- where's George. My regular driver.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Still dazed, McCloy manages to nod and exit the limo. Billy drives off.</context>
      <utterance>Took ill, guv'. Touch of the flu. They say it's going around. Nasty business. Mind you don't catch a chill now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luther punches in and up comes a squat little island a hundred yards off shore, connected to the mainland by a wooden bridge. ETHAN (cont'd) That's not exactly it.</context>
      <utterance>Luther, do you have the building up and running?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, that it a Biocyte facility, their storage structure..</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nyah still on the property?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then:</context>
      <utterance>She hasn't left it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Luther speaks, the building - on his computer graphics, one with the BIOCYTE PHARMACEUTICALS ELEVATORS AND RENDERINGS, is being rapidly morphed to three dimension existence off the rendering specifications by Luther, as if the building itself were being constructed at a madly rapid pace, from its foundation to its reinforced steel structure, to its honeycombing of floors, to its outer skin. Luther's reconstitution of the building lot static, but moving around and above it even as he proceeds.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, here you go -</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's start from the inside out.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All storage and production of Chimera is done here, in this lab on the forty-second floor, the heart of the building.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LUTHER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chimera itself is kept in two places: in production vials in an incubation room and housed in a small airtight chamber - inside three injection guns.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mate, you kill it in both places, we're laughin' and we go home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now how to get in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan watches the rendition of the Biocyte lobby on screen</context>
      <utterance>No garage entrance. Lobby's protected by five guards on rotating patrol.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you look at Hunt's operational history, he invariably favors misdirection and deception. For a start he won't go into Biocyte from the ground where he has to risk confrontation with security.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not going in from the ground. Show me the atrium.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LUTHER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The atrium? One of a kind. Runs down the center of the building. Provides 24-hour natural light via mirrors and daylight storage cells. Optimal growing conditions for the virus. Ends in a glass floor which doubles as part of the lab's ceiling.</utterance>
   <speaker>WITH LUTHER AND ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luther sees the glint growing in Ethan's eye.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, atrium roof closes at sundown.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LUTHER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if the louvers are open for more than thirty seconds at night, the Civil Emergency alarms are tipped. Those even I can't stop. Thirty seconds total to get you in and the cable out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Security?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirty-second opening in the roof and a 250-foot drop.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not waiting 48 hours. When we're done at Biocyte, if she's not out of Ambrose's, I'm going in and getting her out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>two..one...</context>
      <utterance>Package away in five..four..three..</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not ready!</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan plummets towards the atrium.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gone..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LUTHER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan unhooks the cord and flips to the atrium floor. An alarm goes off. LUTHER'S VOICE (cont'd) There it goes.. Still confused and concerned, the guard doesn't immediately react to the alarm or the ringing phone. He finally answers the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Gotta get that cable out.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD #2'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The first guard gives up what's confused him.</context>
      <utterance>AY! what's the matter with you? Can't you hear the alarm's gone off in cosmetics?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Then I guess I'll have to trot off to see who's pinching eyeliner, won't I.  I'll even check the stairwell on the way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Retracting cable.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three..two..one..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BILLY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cable's clear.</utterance>
   <speaker>INT - ATRIUM FLOOR - ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>reaches down and presses a silent beeper.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ethan, the generators are about to go active. We'll be out of contact for eleven minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE - GENERATORS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>dark and silent.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERATORS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>turn over and roar to life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ONE OF THE GUARDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this, then? Reinforcements?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not exactly, mate.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly where is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>..in the building...</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say again. Sounds like you're saying 'she's in the building.'</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am. She is.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ethan does it the hard way to avoid confrontation. Neutralizing security guards is simply too distasteful to him..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Well, then. She's not likely to be alone. is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The question Is 'how many of 'em?' I can't get thru to Ethan. Not 'til the generators go off.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not for another eight and a half minutes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It looks like Nyah's headed toward an elevator.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>working meticulously an a computer monitor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's in the elevator heading toward Ethan.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much longer before you can reach him?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five and a half minutes.  He's breached the hot zone..</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On the other hand we know where Hunt will be and he doesn't know we're coming..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FIRST COMPUTER VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alert. Chimera-working-seed-stock-pH-at- unacceptable-level..</utterance>
   <speaker>THIRD COMPUTER VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alert. Chimera-in-vitro-pH-and- temperature-level-outside-optimal range..</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST COMPUTER VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The X-Ray microscope shows the individual seed-cells sticking together, some exploding, then all movement ceasing. The Liquid itself is suddenly shod thru fluorescent sparks before it congeals to an opaque mush. FIRST COMPUTER VOICE (cont'd) Alert. Chimera stock life..terminated.. Simultaneously with the seed stock, Ethan's damaging both the working seed in-vitro virus.</context>
      <utterance>Alert. Chimera-working-seed-stock-pH-at- critical-level. Alert. Stock-life threatened. Alert.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BILLY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How're we doin', then?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He should've have killed the virus in the incubation area..Nyah's exited the elevator on the same level as the lab.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can we do' mate?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hope he kills all the bugs before the yellow dot gets to the red one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Ethan hits and dives for cover, Ulrich goes for the gun Ethan shoots Ulrich in the leg. Ulrich hops back in pain.</context>
      <utterance>Get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan's crouching on the ground protected behind a series of vertical metal sheets.</context>
      <utterance>Those were two explosions, your van and your safehouse, in case you didn't hear them both -- I believe that means you've also lost a friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan moves to pick up the injection gun which lies in the shattered glass on the floor. Ambrose, Wallis, and a couple of other Ambrose team members fire, kicking up broken glass. Ethan backs off.</context>
      <utterance>And you couldn't walk to tell me about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two spot one another in a mirror on the far wall of the hot zone.. AMBROSE (cont'd) Well, Hunt. How've you been?</context>
      <utterance>Hold your fire, dammit!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fight a bit of a cold..</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you're happy about that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beats fighting the flu, I'm here to tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, that was the hardest part of having to portray you. Grinning like an idiot every fifteen minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would've thought the hardest part was exercising restraint. Curbing that pressing need of your to get your gun off. You were in such a hurry to knock off that 747, you never figured out where the virus really was.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew where it was.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan has been using this exchange to ease a fresh seventeen round clip into his weapon and he punctuates this last with a spray of gunfire, attempting to cover his own effort to the reach the injection gun. The return fire nearly hits the injection gun, kicking up glass and dust and making it move around on the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. then you knew the only way could smuggle the live virus to the CDC scientists in Atlanta was by injecting himself and using his own bloodstream as a Petri dish, doing it inside of twenty hours so he could take the anti-virus and still have it be effective. You knew that while you were knocking him off and destroying the very thing you came for.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everybody's regained cover but the injection gun remains out of everybody's reach.</context>
      <utterance>Stop! Put a sock in it! Hit that bloody gun and you'll spray the bloody virus all over the place!</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There it is, guys, the last of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep. You've provided us with a golden opportunity to have both the bug and the bug killer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was the top bid?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, you going to make me a better offer?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Than thirty-seven million pounds? Not really.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She doesn't belong here, Sean. Let her go.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pregnant pause.</context>
      <utterance>She wouldn't be here if it wasn't for you, Hunt. from this moment you're responsible for what happens to her, and if you're looking out for her well-being, I suggest you advise her to pick up the gun and bring it to me. Ball's in your court, Hunt. What've you got to say? Nyah's waiting for your answer.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ethan, Nyah's in the building! Do you copy?</utterance>
   <speaker>WITH LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode>EXT. BIOCYTE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>a mess amid the rubble of the construction van.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. ETHAN  Sure he won't shoot you the minute he's got it?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Hunt, please! One can't hold Nyah responsible for her actions..</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In other words, you're calling her a flake.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE - NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>listening.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know women, mate. Like monkeys, they are. Won't let go of one branch til they've got a grip on the next...get it, Nyah. I'll cover you. Ambrose cocks his weapon. AMBROSE  I'm waiting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's been laughing away with Ethan:</context>
      <utterance>You..bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not going to shoot, Sean. Not this bitch. She's worth thirty-seven million pounds.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you think you were doing!</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This hits Ethan with the force of a blow.</context>
      <utterance>I wasn't thinking! Just..trying to keep you from getting hurt, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- you who don't have a conscience.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess I lied..You can't get both of us out of here, can you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you'll have to kill me before it's too late. Before I start killing people.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm infected with Chimera. You know you don't have a choice. Just do it now. She puts Ethan's gun to her forehead. NYAH  For god's sake, get it over with.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE HAMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pulls back.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE - ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He can't fire, lower the hammer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan runs from the cover of the tanks toward the exploded wall once in the open, he exchanges direct gunfire with Ambrose's team, wounding a couple men. He reaches the wall and dives thru, camera with him as he drops 25 stories, the sound of gunfire in the air all around him. Less than a hundred feet from the ground a small dark chute deploys and Ethan is lost from view beneath it.</context>
      <utterance>We've got 19 hours and 57 minutes before you start killing anybody. I'll get Bellerophon into your system by then. Just stay alive. I'm not gonna lose you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet. We did manage to pull any sensitive equipment and material out of our safehouse wreckage.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We could lock down passport control and all ports of authority, but that won't stop Ambrose, and beyond him, we don't know who else we're looking for -- all terrorist bank accounts of which we're aware are stable. No deposits, no withdrawals. Therefore no suspects.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We think we've got our finger on the buyer.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you? Even assuming you're able to prevent Ambrose selling Chimera, you've now got an additional problem. You destroyed all of Chimera at Biocyte. If Ambrose is going to sell Chimera now, he'll have to do it by taking a pint or so of Miss Hall's blood to market.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I believe that's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But that leaves another seven or eight pints of Chimera.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean that leaves Miss Hall.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan glances at his chronometer. Swanbeck sees it.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I believe that's right. Now my understanding is that 20 hours after exposure, the victim becomes infectious. Highly infectious.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ethan nods.</context>
      <utterance>You noted the time of exposure?</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- good. Then if you manage to get hold of Ambrose, and obtain what he's got, you've got -  - 8 hours 57 minutes and twenty-three seconds to destroy the largest remaining source of Chimera on earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She sacrificed herself..</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan's staring at Swanbeck.</context>
      <utterance>Brave girl. If you can get hold of Bellerophon with the time limit, you may spare her the ultimate sacrifice. But in either case you've got less than nine hours to kill her or cure her. After that it's out of our hands and a matter of worldwide material law. And Hunt. However you obtain it, we want you to preserve a sample of Chimera. Bring it back alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something else?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't you even curious? About why she did it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the eerie wail of the didgeridoo seems to mount in volume and intensity, the overcast sky filtering into the loft seems particularly oppressive. Ethan's up against it and he knows it.</context>
      <utterance>No. I can't afford to be curious. And neither can you, Hunt..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Feel like pleading for your life?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God damn it, Nyah! Why did you do it? Why did you save that bastard?</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It doesn't. Full of pain and rage, he gets out of the car.</context>
      <utterance>If it'll make you feel any better I won't do it again.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it'll make you feel any better, you're going to take a lot of Aussies with you and make me a lot of money.</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A nameless guard from Michael's car idling nearby gets into the back seat with Nyah. Ambrose shuts the car door in Nyah's face, gets in Michael's car takes off.</context>
      <utterance>In just a few hours you can be assured of going down in history as the typhoid Mary of Oz. G'day.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luther drops a tiny part into his computer board and, as he tries to fish it out with the aid of a magnifying glass:</context>
      <utterance>Luther?..Luther.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>and running! How much time does she have left?</context>
      <utterance>Ethan, I keep telling you there's not a chance of locating Nyah til I access the satellite and there's not a chance of doing that til I get this thing booted up</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ninety-seven minutes, twenty-seven seconds.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Before we kill her or cure her..</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wrong. All we've got to worry about is Ambrose. Nyah will take care of Nyah.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unless we dose her with Bellerophon on the next ninety-seven minutes, Nyah will kill herself. So, first things, first. Swanbeck said there's no cash movement from any monitored terrorist accounts.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXT - BEAR ISLAND CAR PARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>McCloy's black limousine is in the car park.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Confirms what Ambrose is gonna do -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BILLY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ethan's out from under the bridge and on the south-east face..</utterance>
   <speaker>EXT - CLIFF/VIEW OF TUNNEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ethan climbs the side of the cliff.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ethan, Ambrose and his tem have over the bridge -</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan reaches the clifftop and sees armed guards patrolling.</context>
      <utterance>Copy that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You all right, mate? From here it looks like very security. What's it look like like from there?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's over the top and moves swiftly to cover. Ethan surprises and kills a perimeter guard, then runs to a length of grating and lifts one of the panels. Ethan climbs down through the grating in the roof of the tunnel. Using a bar to swing down, he breaks a second guard's neck and drops to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Risky.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More like two-two point two million.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In any case we don't want your cash.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ambrose picks up a mobile phone and dials.</context>
      <utterance>Then what do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stock, Mr. McCloy. Stock options, to be a little more precise..  - cut her loose..right in the center of town..the more crowded the better..  How quickly can you manufacture more of the antivirus.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LUTHER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ethan, just picked up an Ambrose call - Nyah's been dropped off. I think she's alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is she?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LUTHER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ethan? Do you copy?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Somewhere in Sydney?' Care to harden the target?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't. Until I can get the GPS up on our computer..it's still down..</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Back to the matter at hand, Ethan completes the move on the guard and knocks him out.</context>
      <utterance>The clock is ticking..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MCCLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bellerophen? No time at all once I've got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. Biocyte stock is just a week or two away from going through the roof.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An outbreak of</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In downtown Sydney for a start. McCloy is stunned. AMBROSE  You create the supply, Mr. McCloy, we've just created the demand. Three million people in Sydney and 17 million people in Australia are going to need Bellerophen within a matter of days..not to mention the rest of the world..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- now here's the way it's going to work..Wallis, the shares outstanding are..</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ninety-three point four million.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which means, Mr. McCloy, we have to get our hands on four hundred and eighty thousand options. We'll borrow your thirty million to buy those options. Your stock's never sold above thirty-one dollars a share. We'll agree to buy at fifty.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>AMBROSE  When your stock goes north of two hundred, and it will, those options will be worth billions. We can borrow whatever we need to buy the 48,000,000 shares, fifty-one percent of Biocyte.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Outrageous. I won't let you take control of my company.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sit down. You'll be a billionaire. Better than being broke. I've got terrorists and other pharmaceutical companies standing in line. Ball's in your court, Mr. McCloy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McCloy pauses only a moment before nodding to his accountant.</context>
      <utterance>We're running short on time, Mr. McCloy. We've got to conclude our business.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The accountant begins working on his laptop.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, start the transfer.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Follow it. Let me know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You broke our deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Ethan raises his hands, he pulls the pin on a grenade and then kicks it between Stamp's legs. The handle flies off: It's live. When Stamp looks down in surprise at the grenade, Ethan kicks out his gun. Trying to escape the grenade, Stamp smashes into Ethan and seems to have hit him in the jaw. Both hit the ground as the grenade explodes, with Stamp appearing to have the upper hand.</context>
      <utterance>You're too trusting. Raise your hands slowly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep it going.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sean, this rat's reached the end of the maze.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he alive?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAMP'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More or less.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bring him to me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're due to take off.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not for seven more minutes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luther hears nothing in response but while noise. He looks to Billy and indicates there's no answer.</context>
      <utterance>Ethan? Ethan? Do you copy?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, mate, maybe this is one of those times we shouldn't follow orders.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXT - HELICOPTER</speaker>
      <mode>DAY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>the rotor blades turn over.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STAMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Afraid he's got no choice. I believe I broke his jaw.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ambrose has picked up a pair of Berettas, and is proceeding to load both full seventeen round clips.</context>
      <utterance>Hugh, I'm impressed..</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCLOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ambrose favors McCloy with a glance of genial exacerbation.</context>
      <utterance>What do you intend to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You needn't watch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan indeed makes some considerable effort to speak but can only manage a few guttural, progressively desperate sounds which continue as:</context>
      <utterance>- right. We don't have a lot of time, Hunt. whatever you've got to say, say it now.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sorry mate, I can't understand a bloody word. How about giving us a big smile to remember you by? (hearing the helicopter) No? Well, then. This is what's known as getting your gun off. With that Ambrose empties thirty four rounds from the two Berettas into Ethan whose body jerks crazily on the floor. McCloy nearly faints, and Ambrose laughs at his squeamishness until something on Ethan's body catches his eye: the top of the little finger on the right hand is bleeding. Ambrose grabs Ethan's face, and rips off a latex mask: revealing Stamp, eyes wide open and thoroughly lifeless. His jaw, under the mask had been taped carefully close with the same heavy tape Ethan has used to mount the drain-pipe shotgun on the tunnel wall. AMBROSE (cont'd) Bloody hell! He looks around, but Stamp is gone. So is the cannister and kevlar vest that had been on the table moments before.</context>
      <utterance>AMBROSE</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clear that bridge for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER' VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roger that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're tracking you on the left, Ethan. Prepare for some fire.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GPS COMPUTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The target is located.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ethan, the computer's up. I've got Nyah. She's moved out of the city.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luther, say again.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's on the North Head Bluff - approaching the cliffs. One klick away.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULRICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before an intersection, Ethan both revs and brakes, spinning the bike and creating a smoke screen. Wallis' car enters the smoke. ULRICH (cont'd) I can't see him, mate. Slow down!</context>
      <utterance>I can't get a good shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wallis breaks hard, but not hard enough: he stops just in the path of an oncoming 18-wheeler. His car's demolished.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up. I know what I'm doing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FROM COPTER TO GROUND</speaker>
      <mode>MOVING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>rapidly approaching the North Head bluff.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There she is. I got visual.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're down to seven minutes 23 seconds..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Ethan. I don't quite know where to begin. Any suggestions?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd like me to conduct my own debriefing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not? You've done just about everything else on this operation.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd thank you -- but I'm not sure that was a compliment.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course it was. Anyone whose operations requires the level of disinformation that yours do, is bound to get a little flak here and there. You try flogging the stories on CNN I've had to come up with about what's been going on around here the last few days. At any rate, it's been most instructive -- what they'll swallow, or what they'll broadcast with a straight face.  Miss Hall's blood, it appears, has absolutely no elements of the Chimera virus. Not even antibodies.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I gathered as much.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the only other remaining sample was in the canister you recover from Ambrose.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that appears to have been destroyed. It also contained the anti-virus, Bellerophon.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Bellerophon, it turns out, was only really effective against Chimera.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you were under specific instructions to bring back a living sample of the Chimera virus. I'd be very interested to know how, after you'd managed its recovery intact, it subsequently got destroyed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By fire. That's the best way, really.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you didn't fail mission, you simply changed it. Ethan doesn't respond. SWANBECK  It's no longer enough for you to execute and implement IMF policy, you now wish to go in the business of creating it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I don't. But in this case -</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In this case, it wasn't a bad idea. In face, it was a pretty damn good idea. Just don't make a habit of it. And, as for Ms. Hall, in light of her efforts, her criminal records will certainly be expunged. I'm assuming you approve.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is she now, by the way? Do you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't. No exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Hunt, what are your plans?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not sure. Some sort of vacation. I'll let you know where I'm going.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANBECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ethan and Swanbeck exchange one final, knowing glance.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, you don't have to do that. Wouldn't be a vacation if you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKY NEWSCASTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This incident in the wake of rumors suddenly surfacing about Mr. McCloy and Biocyte's financial difficulties -- including criminal allegations of insider trading, embezzlement, conspiracy to commit fraud, and stock parking -- have, understandably, sent stock prices of the pharmaceutical company plummeting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what did he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good job. And thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it? That's it? That's it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the check's in the mall.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Billy's gone. Ethan and Luther remain alone, both reluctant to say anything, both reluctant to leave. One quick bear hug, then:</context>
      <utterance>Right. Just remember, mates. Billy Baird's the name. Anything you need to get, move or watch, I'm your man.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Luther's off. Ethan looks after him, a bit wistfully. Then, curiously tentative he moves off into the crowd. After a half- dozen steps, something catches his eyes. He stops. One quick bear hug, then:</context>
      <utterance>Always nice hearing from you man. Stay in touch..</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know me?</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>is inches from him. Without batting an eye.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Should I?</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You just looked as if you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She wraps her arms around him and kisses him with considerable conviction. ETHAN (cont'd) ...just as if I'd like to.</context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
   <speaker>NYAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her with a conviction that is more than a match for hers. NYAH (cont'd) ..I think that can be arranged. Looks around at the swirling crowd:</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Well..</utterance>
   <speaker>ETHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And in a moment they've vanished from the frame and into the crowd. Camera begins to pull back, the bustling crowd ever filling the frame - and in the distance, perhaps, just a splash of a bouquet of flowers can be seen, appearing to bounce along on its own, the rising beat of the MI theme:</context>
      <utterance>Let's get lost.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
