<movie id="394" title="Mission to Mars">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CHILDREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My turn! My turn! No, I was next! No, me! Uncle Phil, Uncle Phil, can I do one? I want to do one!</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Derisive GROANS from the kids, more SHOUTS. Phil grins. There's little danger NASA will ever use him on a recruiting poster: he's messy, very hyper. Phil waves his hands for silence.</context>
      <utterance>Guys, guys, please! This is risky stuff here. And I'm a highly trained professional.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another astronaut, RENEE COTE, a tall, very fit French woman, is walking by with a fresh six-pack. She tosses a beer and Phil catches it.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay! Uncle Phil will launch another booster...</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...just as soon as he completes his fuel intake.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="30">
   <speaker>WILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Passing the banner, Cote lobs a beer to another astronaut, NICHOLAS WILLIS, who snags it neatly. He's got his other arm around the waist of a PRETTY GIRL. As Cote moves OUT OF FRAME, ANGLE LINGERS on these two. Willis, a very young astronaut, early 20s, is recruiting poster material, and knows it all too well.</context>
      <utterance>It'll take us six months just to get to Mars. Another year on the surface, then six months back. That's two years...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess what I'm trying to say is, since this is my last night on Earth, it's gonna be a very precious memory to me. Y'know?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRETTY GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the Pretty Girl slips out of his grasp, laughing, and walks away, Willis shrugs philosophically. He pops open his beer, swigs it. ANGLE FOLLOWS THE PRETTY GIRL As she swerves around an open- pit barbecue, where other ASTRONAUTS are gathered. Cote has paused here, too, distributing the last of her beers. SERGEI KIROV, a Russian cosmonaut, is watching some kids nearby as they play a game of wiffle ball. He turns, grinning beerily at the chef.</context>
      <utterance>Nice try, Nick.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIROV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WOODY BLAKE, late 30s, is a big, rangy guy in a cowboy hat over a Hawaiian shirt and a "KISS THE CHEF" apron. An entire pig is turning on a spit over the flames, and Woody is basting this as he smiles at Malik.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Woody, our Mars One crew won't be heading back to Earth till ten days after you guys land at our base camp with Mars Two. That's a pretty good long rendezvous.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you suggesting, Sergei?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIROV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you should bring a baseball bat. Yes? American baseball? Our two crews could have ourselves a little Solar System Series.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. Half you guys are foreigners. We'd crush you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIROV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grins teasingly at Cote, who makes a face at him.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, we have equal crews. Three men, one woman. Same handicap.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DR. TERRI FISHER, early 30s, passes by with a platter of corn-on-the-cob. Short, sturdy body, a face made attractive by its alert, questing intelligence. She pauses to kiss Woody's cheek; there's a wonderful, sexy spark between them. Then she glances at Kirov, all business now.</context>
      <utterance>Easy now, you're talking about my wife.  And Terri just happens to be one helluva shortstop.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's a bit rattled by her cockiness, and looks at Cote, who smiles, nods her cool agreement.</context>
      <utterance>Fast pitch, no steals, batter calls his own strikes. Thousand bucks make it interesting?</utterance>
   <speaker>COTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eh bien. Winner take all.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other men ooooh at this, busting on Kirov and Cote, as Terri moves on. Woody, watching her go, has a thousand-watt grin.</context>
      <utterance>Good.  Bring some balls.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE FOLLOWS TERRI as she dodges a PACK OF KIDS -- they run by her, shrieking happily - before she finally reaches a picnic table, where ASTRONAUTS' WIVES are opening containers of baked beans, coleslaw, and potato salad.</context>
      <utterance>You wanna know the sad part? Technically I outrank her. But if we want any peace at all on Mars Two, I'm gonna be saying a lot of "Yes, dears." The others laugh.</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of the other women raises a warning eyebrow, and the 1st Wife turns, sees Terri setting down her platter.</context>
      <utterance>...just not sure how I feel about NASA allowing couples to go on this type of mission together.</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing personal, Terri. It's just that, well, it's kind of a funny feeling for those of us staying behind.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All the research shows that marriage will provide stability on these long duration trips.</utterance>
   <speaker>2ND WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laughter at this. Terri smiles politely -- she doesn't really have much in common with these women -- before moving on. ANGLE LINGERS on the wives, who watch her go with a slight tinge of jealousy. One of them is looking around.</context>
      <utterance>Then they haven't studied some of the couples I've known.</utterance>
   <speaker>3RD WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anybody seen Jim McConnell?</utterance>
   <speaker>4TH WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think he's coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, that poor man. How's he doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>2ND WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Totally losing it, from what I hear. Can't sleep, can't eat. Visits her grave almost every day.  They say he could lose mission status.</utterance>
   <speaker>3RD WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, that's so sad. That is just so tragic. You go to a routine physical one day, and wham.</utterance>
   <speaker>4TH WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After all those years of training, too. It was their whole dream.</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes her head, awed by the thought. The others nod in agreement, following her glance... In the distance, a lone MALE FIGURE stands by the garage, his back to them, facing the parked cars, vans, and SUVs which stretch down the driveway and along the street. Another figure, a WOMAN, can be seen approaching him. CLOSER ANGLE FOLLOWS the moving woman -- DEBRA GRAHAM, early 30s, very attractive -- until she reaches her husband. LUKE GRAHAM, mid 30s, has the lean, fit body of an astronaut, the restless intellect of a scientist. He's unaware of her approach until she touches his shoulder. He looks at her with an apologetic smile.</context>
      <utterance>Must be a pretty funny feeling for Luke Graham. Y'know? Now he's gonna be in the history books. First man on Mars...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not coming, Luke.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim deserves this, too. All his friends are here. And it's my last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you, Deb.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you too, baby. But maybe you should spend some time with Bobby.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I will. Where is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her again, then goes. Debra's eyes follow him, with a mixture of pride and sadness. ANGLE FOLLOWS Luke away from the garage, into</context>
      <utterance>Up in his fort.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke shakes his head. Willis is incorrigible. Finally he reaches a tall redwood playset. He looks up the ladder. A SMALL BOY sits on the platform of the tower, arms around his knees, staring up at the stars. A telescope rests nearby on a tripod. He looks lonely. Luke climbs up, sits down on the wooden deck next to him. BOBBY, 7, glances over at his dad, his idol, then back at the sky.</context>
      <utterance>Deep space is so lonesome. So cold. But I guess I'll have my memories to keep me warm...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke is surprised by the question. A pause.</context>
      <utterance>Who's gonna read to me now, at bedtime?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mommy will.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His voice is unexpectedly fierce. He's fighting back tears. Luke is moved. Another brief silence.</context>
      <utterance>I like when you do it. Now we're never gonna finish our book.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bobby manages a smile. He nods, feeling a little better. Luke is proud of his son's courage.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I'll tell you what. I've been thinking about that. And what I thought was -- how 'bout if I bring along my own copy?  Then every night, wherever I am, I'll read a little bit more of it. And I'll know that you and Mommy, wherever you are, you're reading it too. That way, it'll feel like we're still reading it together. 'Cause I don't know about you, but I'm pretty anxious to find out how 'ol Ben Gunn got marooned on that island. What d'you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bobby's arms go around his father's neck. He hugs Luke fiercely, and Luke hugs him back. His eyes, over the thin young shoulders, are brimming with love and impending absence. Then, from the distance, the sound of an APPROACHING CAR. They both turn. An open Jeep is coming down the street. Its DRIVER is alone. Luke's expression changes. Recognition, then happiness.</context>
      <utterance>Good deal. Can I have a hug?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DEBRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were afraid you wouldn't come.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I caught a whiff of your barbecue. After that I was helpless.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All the way out in Galveston?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something like that.  It's his night, Deb. I didn't want to spoil it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Over her shoulder he sees Luke approaching, his arm around Bobby. The two men look at each other, the bond between them so strong it needs no words. Finally Luke smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Spoil it? He's been going crazy looking for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell comes towards him, accompanied by Debra, and together the four of them move OUT OF FRAME, heading towards the party. ANGLE HOLDS on the parking area, as we...</context>
      <utterance>C'mon. A whole lot of folks here are gonna be mighty glad to see you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you've got a short memory. Think back to how we were by the second week of lunar training.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you're not gonna bring that up again --</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm trying to remember, let's see, which one of us scored the lowest ranking up there?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just can't let that go --</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, man, three commanders, on the same ship? If they sent us off to Mars together, there wouldn't be enough fuel to lift all those egos.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bullshit, we would've made a great crew.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was never gonna happen. I was always teamed with Maggie, and we were mostly chalkboard jockies. You know? Systems. Payloads...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to him. Mr. Cover-of-Time Magazine!</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, who landed the crippled Block II Shuttle?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, and who scored highest on the lunar rankings?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let it go, Luke.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, I made a little noise. But putting the first footprints on Mars? Nah. That's for guys who...  ...wrote their Ph.D. thesis on how to colonize the place. And guys who...  ...read too much science fiction as a kid and still wear little Flash Gordon rocketships around their necks. He grabs playfully at Woody's neck. Woody smacks his hand away, laughing.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls from his shirt a little Flash Gordon rocketship emblem hanging on a chain, and waggles this tauntingly at McConnell, as Luke and McConnell laugh.</context>
      <utterance>You read the same damn science fiction books that I did! You're just not man enough to wear jewelry!</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke grabs Woody's arm to give McConnell a better shot at the emblem, but Woody cuffs his hands away, laughing. McConnell, watching their horseplay, shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>You want Flash. You know you want him. Well you'll have to come through me!</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tries to smile, but his face reddens. Then all at once his chest is heaving as he struggles to control his emotions. Woody sees this, reaches out a reassuring hand, but McConnell shakes him off, rises abruptly. He turns his back on them, walking away a few steps. Woody and Luke exchange a worried glance.</context>
      <utterance>God, she would've loved to see you two clowns. Just one more time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Woody revs the engine, which ROARS lustily. He grins.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Woodrow, isn't it about time you donated this thing to a museum?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke laughs. Woody looks at McConnell.</context>
      <utterance>Internal combustion, boys. Accept no substitutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim, if there's ever... if there's anything Terri and I can do --</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Woody reaches out to shake Luke's hand.</context>
      <utterance>I'm okay. Really. Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See you when I get to Mars, Luke. Don't solve all the mysteries of the universe, okay? Leave a little something for the next guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll see what I can do. Just make sure you bring some fresh beer.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a final glance at McConnell, Woody slips the car into gear. McConnell and Luke watch as he drives away. A silence. Luke glances at his old friend, growing more serious. We sense he's been waiting all night for a chance to say this.</context>
      <utterance>You got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell, looking after Woody's car, becomes very still.</context>
      <utterance>Should've been your mission, Jim. Yours and Maggie's.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>None of us ever wanted Mars the way you two did. Not even Woody. Twelve years of hoping for this assignment, training for it --</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all over now.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell turns to him, his eyes flashing danger. He will not tolerate pity. Luke sees this but presses on.</context>
      <utterance>If Maggie hadn't gotten sick -- if you hadn't pulled yourself out of the rotation to take care of her --</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell is deeply moved, and for a moment doesn't trust his own voice.</context>
      <utterance>No, I'm gonna say this. I have to say it...  I wanted Mars One. Hell, I battled you for it every step of the way. Never wanted to beat anybody so bad in my life. But not like this... Jim, I'd give this all up in a second, if it would bring Maggie back to us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know that, Luke. You don't have to say it... Mars is yours now. Go get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take care of yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke nods. They grab hands for a second, then let go. Luke walks back towards his house. McConnell watches him for a moment, then turns, walks over to his Jeep. He opens his door, then pauses. He turns. Looks up at --</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. You too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>COTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luke, you read me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Renee.</utterance>
   <speaker>COTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke, though reluctant to break off work, is intrigued.</context>
      <utterance>Luke, I just got ARES-8 on line and... Well, we think you're gonna wanna see this for yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Luke turns away, headed for the rover</context>
      <utterance>Copy that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>COTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No idea, boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cote glances at the others. They're all smirking, as if they share some secret joke Luke's not yet in on.</context>
      <utterance>Where is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't wanna know.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans over to read a digital gauge, but Cote covers it with her hand, enjoying the tease.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, what's so funny? Gimme the coordinates.</utterance>
   <speaker>COTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Latitude 41 degrees north, longitude 9 degrees west.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all laugh as the other shoe drops. Luke's expression is incredulous, exasperated.</context>
      <utterance>The Plains of Cydonia. So?  Oh no. You're not telling me --</utterance>
   <speaker>COTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oui. Exactement! It's Kirov's fault, he picked today's sector.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIROV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke sits, taking over the Ares remote control from Cote. They all watch as he fine tunes the image, trying without success to coax more resolution.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, c'mon! We've got a scientific duty to check that thing out.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great. That's great. The first anomaly we hit, and it's gotta be in the one place guaranteed to make NASA look ridiculous... You know how many books have been written about that damned mountain?</utterance>
   <speaker>COTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Egyptians put it there.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIROV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, the Amazons.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it was little green men!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And all because a couple of lousy impact craters happen to look like eye sockets. If this gets out, we'll have every UFO kook on Earth spouting off on the six o'clock news... C'mon, people, gimme a read here. Is that a cinder cone?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIROV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah, too smooth. Too angular. Volcanic upwelling?</utterance>
   <speaker>COTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No fissures. No caldera.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others look at him, puzzled. Luke leans in closer, with growing excitement. He points to the screen.</context>
      <utterance>It's an upwelling, for sure. But maybe not volcanic...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at the color. And see how shiny it is? I could swear that's ice...</utterance>
   <speaker>COTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This far south?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at each other, Luke's excitement now leaping from one to another of them. They're almost trembling.</context>
      <utterance>Impossible. You can't have ice at this latitude. Not unless...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How far away is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIROV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sixteen kilometers northeast. Take us twenty minutes to get there.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's send a packet to Micker. Then we'll go check it out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at his crew. They beam like cats who ate canaries.</context>
      <utterance>We're all trying not to go too nuts up here, but -- we think there's a good chance this could be an extrusion from some subsurface, geothermal column of water. And if we're right...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...then we've found the key to permanent human colonization.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyone else hear that?</utterance>
   <speaker>COTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds like our antenna's out of phase.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you fix it?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, skip, I can fix anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they go to their jobs, the deep, barely audible rumbling tone continues.</context>
      <utterance>Big talker. Renee, Sergei, let's break out the radar, see what this thing's made of.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, actually, that's Jim McConnell, the CAPCOM. Our voice link to the astronauts? Jim's been with the manned Mars program since its inception. One of our real pioneers.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBASSADOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will he be going to Mars, too?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, no. This is as close as he gets.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cote clears her throat, gives Luke a look. The others can barely conceal their grins.</context>
      <utterance>...anyway, that's about it. We'll send another packet when we get back.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell looks at the screen, worried. What's Luke up to?</context>
      <utterance>Oh, right. One more thing. Today is a very special day for a good friend of ours, and I know he's there right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A look of relief comes over McConnell.</context>
      <utterance>Now, he hates it when any fuss is made, so I won't mention his name...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell winces -- Dear God, no -- as, on the screen, Kirov appears from OFF CAMERA holding a cupcake with a burning candle stuck in it, and the Mars One crew starts SINGING "Happy Birthday" to him. Loudly. And very off-key.</context>
      <utterance>...because the last thing in the world I'd ever want to do is embarrass someone like Jim McConnell.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Soon most everyone in MMCR is singing along -- even some of the jolly ambassadors -- with the noticeable exception of Beck, who stiffens unhappily. McConnell is mortified.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, you Micker weasels, sing!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck looks over at McConnell, who indeed is red in the face with a fake "I'm-a-good-sport" grin.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Ray! Take a look at him! Is he all red with one of those fake "I'm- a-good-sport" grins?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indeed, Beck's smile is thin, sour, disapproving.</context>
      <utterance>And hey, you guys, check out Ray! Does he have on one of his "This- wasn't-in-my-mission-plan" faces?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke and the crew finish singing the song. Luke raises the cupcake in a toast.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing you can do about it, Ray! We're a hundred million miles away!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He and his crew lean in, blow out the candle. They laugh and applaud, then wave goodbye.</context>
      <utterance>Happy Birthday, Jimbo! Make a wish!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke reaches out, turns OFF the CAMERA, and the display screen</context>
      <utterance>Catch you again soon. Take care, buddy. End of transmission.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well? What's under there?</utterance>
   <speaker>COTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Je ne sais pas. I... I think there's something wrong with the equipment.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>COTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke doesn't understand. He walks up to look at the display screen.</context>
      <utterance>I mean, it can't be right. It says... it says there's metal under there.</utterance>
   <speaker>COTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's ten, twelve meters of rubble and sand, and then... solid metal.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That doesn't make any sense. You're reading a vein of ore.</utterance>
   <speaker>COTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The deep pulsing tone continues. Luke frowns.</context>
      <utterance>No. It's under the whole mountain.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick, could the problem with the antenna be interfering?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could be.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try it closer and up the power. I'll watch the screen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick, how we coming on that antenna?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cote and Kirov are having some trouble with the switches on the radar gun. They turn towards Luke and Willis.</context>
      <utterance>Goin' as fast as I can, boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIROV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Willis looks at Luke. Luke nods -- Go help them. Willis starts towards the radar gun.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Nick. Come show me how stupid I am. I can't get this to work.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KIROV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke sidles over to the display screen on the rover.</context>
      <utterance>All set here, chief.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Crank up the juice and let's see what's in this sucker.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Problem: Hatch door malfunction, backup power fail, manual override fail. Solution: Replace circuit breaker 907B." He straps into the pilot's seat, staring at an electrical junction box at one end of the console.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He swings open the housing, revealing a bewildering tangle of fuses and wires. He sighs heavily, as Terri drifts up beside him, also in a jumpsuit, and straps into the co-pilot's seat.</context>
      <utterance>Okay... Piece of cake.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, who dreams up these nightmares?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't try to change the subject.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not! We're talking about your sister's wedding, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very funny. We're talking about dancing lessons. Before my sister's wedding.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He peers into the housing with exaggerated concern. But Terri's not so easily sidetracked.</context>
      <utterance>Honey, do you mind? I've got a catastrophic power failure here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Woody, we're a married couple. Would it kill you to invite me out on the floor once in awhile?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I danced with you at our wedding.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not talking about shuffling your feet around while you grab my butt. I mean real dancing. Cha-cha, rhumba, jitterbug --</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Face it, honey, some couples dance, some go to Mars. That's life.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm serious. We've got two more months in this training rotation, but just as soon as we get home, we're starting lessons. If we never dance, people will think there's something wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reaching past him, she pulls out the required breaker. As he reacts, surprised, she smiles, despite her exasperation.</context>
      <utterance>If they see me dance, they'll know there's something wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are such a lug. Overhead, an intercom CRACKLES. We hear PHIL.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cockpit, this is Control.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Control, this is Cockpit.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, Terri, they want us all back in the Station. Report to Micker.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who says report to Micker?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The little men who live in my head.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Phil, c'mon! We just started this drill.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Woody and Terri exchange a worried look. What's wrong?</context>
      <utterance>Woody, it was Ray Beck. He told me to round up the team. Now.</utterance>
   <speaker>OMITTED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then, at 1417, the X-band continuous data stream from Mars went silent. All data -- med, environmental, everything -- suddenly stopped. While we were trying to figure out what the hell went wrong, we got a signal from the folks at the Large Array at Soccoro.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At the same moment we lost the data stream, they picked up an intense burst of energy from Mars.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, "intense"?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looks are exchanged among the Mars Two crew.</context>
      <utterance>Catastrophic.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the crew?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The level of energy in the pulse... didn't seem survivable.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the REMO? It went into Mars orbit last week. Maybe that could give us some clue.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good thinking, Woody. That's just what we tried next. He leans over, punches buttons on a keyboard.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Resupply Module checked out fine. No instrument failures, no change in status. Orbit holding steady. But there was something else. The REMO'S computer contained an uplink message -- a very faint, highly distorted transmission from Mars One Base Camp.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone's alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The message is almost indecipherable. Two teams are still working on it. You better see for yourselves.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still concentrating on the audio. We managed to bring out a couple more words, but we've got a long way to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The technician nods, then gestures to his assistant who hits a play button.</context>
      <utterance>Show us whatever you've got.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Woody, Terri and Phil look at each other -- Oh, God.</context>
      <utterance>...make this quick... may be only ch--  ...to the site, when we... hit us just as we... --thers are all dead...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The monitor screen GOES BLACK.</context>
      <utterance>...low sound that we couldn't understand. Then all of a sudden there was this terrib...  ...--stems are holding up for now, but I don't know how long I can...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PHIL'S EYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He looks back at her, haunted.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did Luke mean by a "low sound?"</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="45">
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If this was a earthquake, as we're now assuming, there's usually an auditory component.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But that energy pulse they picked up in New Mexico...</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Electromagnetic emission. Not uncommon with large-scale geophysical phenomena.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell and Woody exchange a glance... Woody's right.</context>
      <utterance>Causing this kind of damage? I don't buy it. We're missing something here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luke must be in pretty bad shape if he hasn't blasted out of there in the Earth Return Vehicle. That thing's designed so even one crew member could fly it back to Earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even if Luke was in great shape, he couldn't get home. That energy pulse would've fried the ERV'S computers.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Other than the computers, how do we think the ERV fared?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, so far our modelling says it should be in pretty good shape.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell looks at him, nods. They're on the same wavelength. But Beck is more cautious.</context>
      <utterance>Which means it's gonna be up to us to get new motherboards, drives, and software to Mars. As fast as we can.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa, slow down. It's gonna take us weeks just to analyze this data.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right, but meanwhile, we've gotta be working up a mission plan.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luke needs us now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luke may already be dead. And even if he's not, it's doubtful he's going to be able to transmit again. So we wouldn't know whether it's safe to land until you were almost there.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terri looks at Phil -- SIMA?</context>
      <utterance>What about SIMA?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Saturn Imaging Probe. It's going to slingshot around Mars on its way through the solar system. It could be retasked to take pictures, read radiation levels at Mars One Base Camp.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good idea Phil. If SIMA tells us Luke hasn't survived and it's not safe to land, we swing around Mars and come right back home.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. We can design the mission to have a free return capability. It's a long trip, but if you don't land it's the best option.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're getting ahead of ourselves. You're forgetting the bigger problem.  The orbits are all wrong. Our first decent launch window is almost eight months from now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we can go earlier and get there faster if we reconfigure the payload for extra fuel. We've modelled that, Ray. I've modelled it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On paper, yeah. But those stresses have never been tested in space.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ship can take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A tense beat. Again we sense the test of wills between these two tough-minded men, once good friends.</context>
      <utterance>I wasn't thinking of just the ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know the protocols for a Mars Recovery Mission better than anybody, because I helped design them. And I'm saying these guys can do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause with beck weighing the odds. He looks at Woody.</context>
      <utterance>He's right, Ray. We've got a real shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me an updated mission plan by 0800 tomorrow. Then I'll put it in the works.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at Woody, Phil and Terri, who are just as eager.</context>
      <utterance>You'll have it by 0600.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell exits followed by Terri and Phil, but as Beck starts out, too, Woody stops him.</context>
      <utterance>Let's get to work.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck looks at him a moment, nods.</context>
      <utterance>Chief, could I have a word?</utterance>
   <speaker>OMITTED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've no longer got the right crew.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean? Bjornstrom can be up here on the next shuttle.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bjornstrom is a geologist. He's good, but not for this. My people just lost eight months of training. This is a different mission, with a different objective.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't been given authorization for a mission yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck's expression hardens.</context>
      <utterance>But when you are, it ought to be given the best chance for success. I want McConnell to fly right seat.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's no longer on mission status.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Because you washed him out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He washed himself out. He only had to pass a few more psych evaluations, but he refused to take them.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ray, he's the best pilot I ever saw, and you've got him benched at a desk.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody has to pass the psych prelims. No exceptions. Jim knew that.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maggie was his wife. He didn't want to lie on a couch and share her with strangers.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was his call. But I had to make one too. It was tough as hell, but I'd do it again.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His wife wasted away in front of his eyes. What was he supposed to do? Suck it up? Get with the program? What was his crime? That he was upset? That he cried...?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck and Woody stare at each other. A long tense beat.</context>
      <utterance>I couldn't trust him!</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not in a crisis... I'm sorry Woody, but Jim lost his edge. Are you gonna stand there and tell me Jim McConnell is the same man he was two years ago? You want me to bet four more lives on that? This stops Woody, just for a beat. Then makes him press on harder, with even greater intensity.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck looks back at him, his features taunt.</context>
      <utterance>When Maggie died, yeah, it knocked the shit out of him. It knocked the hell out of all of us. But you know and I know that he's still the best we've got. He and Maggie wrote the book on Mars. He's got more hours in the sims than the rest of us put together. Ray, we can do this. Give me McConnell as co-pilot, and we will bring Luke home. And that's a promise.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That... is the exact chemical composition of my ideal woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He plucks out a couple of the M&amp;Ms as he drifts by.</context>
      <utterance>Used to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell grins, snacking on the M&amp;Ms.</context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phil looks sadly at his floating model.</context>
      <utterance>Now what is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell and Terri laugh as Phil starts scarfing down the rest of the M&amp;Ms. Swooping at them with both hands.</context>
      <utterance>A frog.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess now we have our answer to the effects of long-term interplanetary travel on the human mind. The answer is Phil.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Skip.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell pulls himself forward.</context>
      <utterance>Take a look.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you make of that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dust storm. Southern hemisphere, coming from the east... Big fella, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Headed for Chryse Planitia.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell pulls back from the screen, looks at Woody.</context>
      <utterance>Yup. Could get a little hairy just about landing time...</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. They both hope he's wrong.</context>
      <utterance>We'll have to be ready to move fast. Maybe even advance our ETA. Those things can cover the whole planet, and last up to a year.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When does SIMA do her fly-by?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They exchange a glance. Woody's right, but the thought is too terrible to dwell on. McConnell looks back at Mars.</context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow morning, about 0600. That's when we find out whether we came all this way for nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My money's on Luke.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What brought this on?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zero-G. My last chance to be graceful. Once we're in Mars gravity, it's back to shuffling my feet and grabbing her butt.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grins, kisses his ear, as Phil turns, sees</context>
      <utterance>I'll take what I can get.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COMPUTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all look at each other. This is it! Woody spins over to a console, shuts off the music.</context>
      <utterance>Attention. Incoming packet.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's SIMA.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks deserted.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's still standing, though. So is the ERV. And look, there's the greenhouse.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all scan the screen. Phil spots something.</context>
      <utterance>We know Luke survived for at least a few hours. Question is, are there any signs of recent activity?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs a stylus and touches the screen. They all look.</context>
      <utterance>There.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell gets it first.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell are those?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all realize he's right. They sit back, stunned. But then Phil has another thought.</context>
      <utterance>Graves.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold on. There's only three. That means --</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Phil --</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It means Luke must still be --</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This quiets everyone for a long moment.</context>
      <utterance>No. It just means there was nobody left to bury him.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phil keys in some commands and data pops up onscreen.</context>
      <utterance>Check the radiation levels.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Normal.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phil uses the stylus to bring MORE IMAGES into view. The frame moves over the terrain in the direction of the Face, first in SWIFT BLURS, then slowing. Scattered rock debris come into view. The IMAGE ARRIVES where the mountain was, and they see... Debris in every direction, NEAT SPIRALS of it now, dropped uncannily into place, like some massive earth sculpture. As if - but this makes no sense -- it had been swirled towards a LARGE CRATER. The crater itself is a perfect circle. They FOCUS on the CENTER OF THE CRATER, but the image gets distorted by STATIC.</context>
      <utterance>Go to the disaster site.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phil tweaks the stylus, but the image won't clear up.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Magnetic interference?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phil works the keyboard.</context>
      <utterance>Go to infrared.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>THE ASTRONAUTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sit back, exasperated.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Must be a problem with SIMA. I don't see how an earthquake, six months ago, could give us this kind of distortion.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans closer, staring intently.</context>
      <utterance>That was no quake.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell shakes his head. But his every sense is engaged; he's like a predator just sighting his prey for the first time. We see in his eyes an utter determination to unlock this secret.</context>
      <utterance>Then what the hell was it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck takes a breath, smiles.</context>
      <utterance>We're going to continue analyzing this data and try to determine what the problem is with those images. Frankly, we're just as stumped as you guys, but we'll keep on it.  We agree that the evidence of the graves is inconclusive and that a ground search is advisable. Be aware there are little sand storms kicking up near Mars One Base, but the big one you spotted is turning south. It shouldn't be a factor.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're all pretty excited here and we're sure you must be feeling the same. Enjoy your meal and get a good night's sleep. We anticipate that tomorrow morning you will be Go for Mars Orbital Insertion.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if you opened up your meal packs and found that, instead of putting in everything but red ones, they'd made a mistake and put in only red ones?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, that's a funny notion. And what if in your meal packs, instead of brown rice, there were spring-loaded spikes that shot into your eyes?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you ever pass the psych evaluation?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He touches the screen to roll the dice.</context>
      <utterance>When you're schizophrenic, they take the higher score.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More LAUGHTER, plus some digs about the nerdy eyeglasses and braces. VIDEOCAMERA swings around the room, REVEALING the adult JIM and MAGGIE. They sit side by side on the hearth, leaning into each other, looking very happy.</context>
      <utterance>Maggie was always starstruck...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More LAUGHTER. Everyone's having a great time. The VIDEOCAMERA swings back towards the TV screen as</context>
      <utterance>I'll get you guys for this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>GROANS and LAUGHTER from the offscreen watchers.</context>
      <utterance>When they met at the Air Force Academy, it was "love at first flight."</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After that, NASA training was tough. All Jim could think about was exploring a heavenly body. More ribald LAUGHTER, as</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both men raise champagne flutes.</context>
      <utterance>Today we celebrate a new chapter in their story. And guys, it's a pretty historic one.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHEERS at this, repeats of "Jim and Maggie!" Luke grins, giving a little signal, and we see</context>
      <utterance>Let's hear it for the newly-announced Captain and Co-Captain of Mars One. To Jim and Maggie!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More hoots of LAUGHTER, CATCALLS, but Maggie jumps in to protest, as the VIDEOCAMERA SWINGS TO HER AND JIM. Terri sits nearby.</context>
      <utterance>When you guys land, it'll prove once and for all there's no intelligent life on Mars.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, c'mon, what if I'm right?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSORTED VOICES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no, here we go! Don't get her started! Somebody put on some music!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's our sister planet!</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LAUGHTER at this, and Maggie joins in. She's a good sport.</context>
      <utterance>Oh brother!</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maggie, why does this have to be about us? Mars is a great opportunity for pure science.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The mood of the party is changing, as everyone is caught up in Maggie's spell. She has a radiant simplicity. The VIDEO CAMERA DRIFTS IN ON HER; we are caught up, too.</context>
      <utterance>We'll do the science. And we'll do it very well. That's what we've trained for. But what if there's more...? In all our myths, in every human culture, Mars has always held a special attraction. What if that means something? Only we don't understand it yet...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at McConnell, smiles. He takes her hand.</context>
      <utterance>The universe is not chaos. It's connection. Life reaches out for life...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A silence; the guests are enchanted by the purity of her passion. She smiles, suddenly self-conscious. She hadn't meant to get so carried away.</context>
      <utterance>This is what we were born for, isn't it? To stand on a new world, and look beyond it to the next one. It's who we are.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Woody glances at him. It's true. Rather than being saddened, McConnell seems to have taken on new strength. A renewed sense of wonder.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I'm good to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Woody nods, smiles.</context>
      <utterance>After all these years... Can you believe it? Tomorrow we'll be standing on Mars.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>You know what? She may have been right.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If that wasn't a quake down there, then something else caused it. Or planned it... You're thinking the same thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's never been out of my mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell nods. Looks again at Maggie's face on the screen.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus. You realize what this means?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She knew, Woody. She was the only one of us that ever thought there might be something down there.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell nods. They clasp hands briefly. Deal. Then Woody turns. Before leaving, he hesitates just a moment, turning back. One last thought, and he doesn't know he's going to say it until it comes out.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, and we're not leaving until we find out... Deal?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell looks at him, silent but grateful. Woody goes. McConnell turns back, looking at her smiling face, frozen on the screen.</context>
      <utterance>Maggie was the best of us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Range 6783 and closing. 35 minutes till Mars Orbital Capture.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, people let's look sharp. If we overshoot, there's no coming back.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>In the cockpit, Woody and McConnell are in the pilot and co- pilot's wearing space suits but not yet helmets. AS CAMERA PULLS BACK AND AWAY, we see them making instrument adjustments in preparation for MOI.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, and drifting through eternity will ruin your whole day.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Delta V systems initialized.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charge primary APU.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Engaged. Charged.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Select HPU fuel cells for run.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Engaged.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tie main bus to systems.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Power ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Select H2/O2 HPU and fuel cells for open.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>H2/O2 control valves open.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charge flow.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charged and on-line</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reset PW.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Set</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Transfer protocol data from EVA station.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a sudden LOUD, BRITTLE POP from somewhere overhead, and Phil's gloved hand, hovering over a computer screen, is punctured through and through. The screen itself is holed and spiderwebbed with a loud CRACK!</context>
      <utterance>Transferred. Awaiting track confirmation.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uhhh!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Micrometeoroids</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Breach hits in the hull!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Outgassing! Losing pressure!</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Woody, seal the breech!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still outgassing in the lower Hab! There must be another hole down there, even bigger.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Losing pressure fast! We're gonna decompress!</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Computer, how long until zero atmosphere?</utterance>
   <speaker>COMPUTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four minutes, nine seconds.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we get below 20% atmosphere, the power will shut down!</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Positive! A vacuum inside the ship would cause a total electrical failure. The nav computers will fry!</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Woody looks back at his crew, struggling to project more calm than he really feels.</context>
      <utterance>It's already starting. The primary L- 1 hub has been smashed. The systems are crashing.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stare at him, stunned by their immense task.</context>
      <utterance>Everybody switch to suit oxygen. We beat this in the simulator, we can do it here. Jim, you've got the ship. I'm going EVA.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, people, let's go! Let's work the problem!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, it's still bleeding.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep the pressure on!</utterance>
   <speaker>COMPUTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eighty percent atmosphere...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim, you've gotta get your spare helmet from storage.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No time. Phil, can you keep the nav computers on-line?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't get this damn machine to re- initialize! And the automated systems just went down. We can't shut down the hab rotation from here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll do it from below.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're losing pressure. You could embolize.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMPUTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell looks at her, knows she's right. But he starts off anyway. Phil reaches out his good hand.</context>
      <utterance>Seventy percent atmosphere...</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is a radical, incredibly risky notion. McConnell stares hard at Phil. So does Terri.</context>
      <utterance>Jim, I've got an idea. If you guys can save enough atmosphere, I'll disconnect the power in the main computer bay, then jump start the systems. I'll do a hard boot.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Has that ever been tested?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell looks from Terri to Phil. It's life and death.</context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding? These machines are much too valuable.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then he turns, and the CAMERA FOLLOWS MCCONNELL as he pushes away from the console and dives down into the core tunnel, heading towards the</context>
      <utterance>Do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>OMITTED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just one goddamn second. Come on, c'mon...</utterance>
   <speaker>COMPUTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Voice print identification.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>McConnell!</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell grabs onto a counter edge as...</context>
      <utterance>Hang on!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COMPUTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sixty per cent atmosphere...</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get some light on the hole so I can locate it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts rooting through Phil's storage area -- bags of M&amp;Ms, comic books -- looking for what he needs.</context>
      <utterance>I've got a better idea.  Stay there!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm topside, Jim, do you know which sector?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm workin' on it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shake out the liquid.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim, I don't --</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terri shakes out soda from the open can. She and McConnell watch the brown stream of fluid swirl up into the air, caught by escaping oxygen. It rises towards the "ceiling" of the outer hull, like a miniature tornado.</context>
      <utterance>Shake it out near the hull!</utterance>
   <speaker>OMITTED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, c'mon, where are you...?</utterance>
   <speaker>COMPUTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fifty per cent atmosphere...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Woody, the breech is in sector four! Sector four, copy that?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Terri turns, excited by McConnell's triumph; she's just in time to see him collapse to the floor below her, as he starts to lose consciousness. He's deathly pale.</context>
      <utterance>Copy, I' heading there now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a dramatic click, he throws the switch, hard-booting the computer system back on. He stares at the screens. Nothing happens!</context>
      <utterance>OK... OK now...</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frightened, furious, Phil bangs on the switch with his cordless screwdriver. When all else fails, hit something.</context>
      <utterance>Come on. Come on...!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COMPUTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell's eyes widen, as he realizes this is the same as the last reading.</context>
      <utterance>Twenty percent atmosphere...</utterance>
   <speaker>COMPUTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terri and McConnell look at each other. Tears of relief in her eyes. He is exhausted, nearly spent, but manages a grin. She holds the 0-2 mask up to his face, and as he grips it, breathing deeply, they hug one another.</context>
      <utterance>Pressure stabilizing... Atmosphere level increasing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Forgetting his injury, he pounds his gloved fist on the console in triumph.</context>
      <utterance>Yes! Awriiiight! Had it all the way. Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He wrings his injured hand, then his gaze is caught by</context>
      <utterance>Shit!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PHIL'S EYES WIDEN IN FEAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As he keys his mike urgently.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get back in here, guys!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim, there's a lot of scarring... I'd better check for other punctures while I'm out here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Negative, negative. Woody, get back inside. We've gotta start the checklist for orbital insertion.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Woody jets back towards the open EVA hatch. But as he reaches this, about to re-enter the ship, he's captured momentarily by a breathtakingly beautiful sight below him.</context>
      <utterance>Copy, I'm heading there now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Piece of cake?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He scoops her into his arms; they kiss passionately. Phil is blinking; something seems to be getting into his own eyes. His voice catches for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Well. Easier than the cha-cha.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you're getting so cocky about. We scored better times in the sim at least twice.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terri separates from Woody, looks down at Phil.</context>
      <utterance>How's his hand?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phil starts curling up his fingers. The middle digit remains extended in the universal gesture. They all consider this for a moment. Then Phil looks up cheerfully.</context>
      <utterance>Seems OK. Couple of the tendons are going to be a little tight for awhile. Try to close your fingers, Phil, nice and slowly.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a split-second they get it, and the whole crew roars with LAUGHTER, which builds and builds; they're almost giddy with the relief of the tension...</context>
      <utterance>Well, at least I'll still be able to drive.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Systems.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nav.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He flips three switches, in rapid sequence, and...</context>
      <utterance>We are Go for the burn. I'm fueling the engines.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Woody hesitates, then glances at McConnell.</context>
      <utterance>Four... Three...</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell, moved by this honor, nods. He reaches out to throw the switch himself.</context>
      <utterance>Jim?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the countdown indicator reaches "0000.00.00", a final signal PINGS, and he flips the switch.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go to Mars.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the --</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He and Woody both reach out, straining against the incredible G-forces, and manage to grab a red emergency lever, yanking it down hard.</context>
      <utterance>Shut down engines!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Engines negative! No response! I've got no attitude control!</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Manual separation! Blow the bolts!</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Negative! The CM doesn't have enough thrust to correct this rotation!</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're too steep! Falling into the atmosphere...!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much time've we got?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell's mind is racing furiously, desperately.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know! Three minutes? I don't know!</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's the REMO?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Resupply Module? Why? That's not --</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phil punches buttons. ON THE SCREEN a second ellipse appears: a blinking orange dot labelled "REMO." It appears to be soon intersecting with their own trajectory.</context>
      <utterance>Where is it?!</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, it's close...</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn it, how close?!</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I-I don't know. It'll take time...</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phil frantically types in commands on the computer.</context>
      <utterance>We don't have time! Figure it out! Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim, we're dead stick, there's no way to maneuver this ship into a link-up!</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not the ship. Just us. We have to go</utterance>
   <speaker>EVA.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They look at him, stunned. Leave the ship?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want us to transfer in suits?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Jim -- if we don't make it -- if we miss the REMO...</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no other choice! Phil, how close?!</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stare at Woody. We feel the full, terrible weight of his responsibility. Four lives hang on his call.</context>
      <utterance>One kilometer, that's the best I can do!</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Prepare to abandon ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>OMITTED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All four astronauts fire a brief, simultaneous burst from the tiny attitude control thrusters in their suits. This stops their rotation, bringing their travel under control. The ship continues spinning in the background. Woody takes a final look at the charred, doomed Mars Recovery. The only home they've known for six months. He exchanges a silent glance with the others. They all expect to be dead in the next few minutes. Woody takes a breath, nods.</context>
      <utterance>On my mark, seven percent left thruster. Three, two, one, fire.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pops the big thrusters on the MMU and starts heading away from the ship. The cord between Woody and the others pulls taut and they start to follow.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you looking for?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tries to smile. So does she.</context>
      <utterance>Hey. When we get back? We really will have to try this in the sim.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Woody eyes a small display screen on his forearm.</context>
      <utterance>How we doin' on fuel, Woody?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm at fifty percent.  But I don't see the REMO.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Happens to glance directly below.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There she is!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus. She's not where I thought she'd be.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to miss her.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks again at his display screen, frustrated.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't catch it. Not like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From a compartment on the side of the MMU, Woody pulls out...</context>
      <utterance>Use the tether.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll only have one, maybe two shots before she's out of reach.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll be better if I leave you the gun while I run out to the REMO. I've got enough fuel left for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll be going too fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell looks at him. They both know how risky this is, and they also know it's their only chance. Woody flips a switch on the gun and pulls on the hook. Off it comes, trailing wire. Woody clips the hook to the MMU, then hands McConnell the gun.</context>
      <utterance>I'll aim to overshoot, then brake like hell; arc it in.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell nods. Woody and Terri exchange a look -- tender, loving -- then Woody turns around and fires the MMU jets at full throttle. As Woody pulls away, line unspools from the tether gun.</context>
      <utterance>Seeya in a few.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WOODY'S EYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Show alarm. He checks his display.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Woody hits some buttons and the MMU's latches snap open. He grabs the hook connected to the tether line, then pushes himself free of the MMU, starts firing his small suit jets.</context>
      <utterance>I'm out. Coming in hot. Still long.  Abandoning the unit. I'll brake with suit jets.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY'S POV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's still going very quickly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Suit jets gone. But I'm gonna make contact...</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL, TERRI AND PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stare at Woody's distant figure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At what velocity?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Impact's gonna be a little rough.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At what velocity?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A look between McConnell and Terri; her face is stricken.</context>
      <utterance>Thirty-two.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna use the gun to slow you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! You slow me and I'll fall short.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's too fast, Woody.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No choice. I'll be okay. Here we go...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HIS GLOVED HANDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are ripped from the line.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Slides over the hull of the REMO.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is past the REMO, freefalling toward Mars.</utterance>
   <speaker>BACK ON MCCONNELL, TERRI AND PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As Terri screams.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell hits a button on the tether gun and starts to reel them quickly in towards the REMO.</context>
      <utterance>Woody!!</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tries his suit jets again -- they're empty.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIS POV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Falling away from the REMO.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, well, no suit jets and I'm still carrying a good deal of velocity.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As soon as we get hooked up, I'll come get you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, I'd have to say negative on that, Jim.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Negative on the transmission?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell and Terri share a quick, anguished look.</context>
      <utterance>No, I heard you. Negative on the maneuver. I am not retrievable.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Woody, that's not possible. You're not going that fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It comes down to the amount of fuel, honey. The suit jets were designed for attitude control, not travel. Retrieval just won't work.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It has to work!</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, believe me, I don't like it any more than you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Woody --</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Run the numbers, Jim.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell finishes looking over the numbers on his display pad. Terri is staring at him. When McConnell's eyes meet hers, they are red-rimmed. Haunted.</context>
      <utterance>I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Woody, you hang tight. We'll get into the REMO, fire her up, drop her into a lower orbit and come scoop you up.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds good, Jim.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's gonna take half an hour to get the REMO reoriented! Woody'll be... He'll be in the atmosphere by then!</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then we'll have to get her moving faster.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't have time!</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You listen to Jim, honey. It's a good plan.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! We are going to --</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phil points. McConnell and Terri look.</context>
      <utterance>Oh Jesus, look! The ship!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look out!</utterance>
   <speaker>THEIR POV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They are drifting quickly into the REMO.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brakes!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, let's get inside! Phil, start dumping the cargo, or there won't be room for us.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we need those supplies for --</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dump the cargo. Hang on, Woody!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But it's too late. She's already out of reach, and now fires her suit jets, pulling quickly away from the REMO.</context>
      <utterance>Terri, no!</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is reaching to activate his own jets, when</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you what I'm not doing, Woody. I'm not going to watch you die.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Terri --</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd do the same for me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I wouldn't come for you. Not if it just wasn't possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No response from Terri.</context>
      <utterance>No, Terri, you can't! You don't have enough fuel to get me, stop us both, and get us back. Hell, you come any farther and you won't have enough to get back yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to me, goddammit! You have to stop! You have to stop now!</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terri looks at her armpad display.</context>
      <utterance>He's right, Terri... It's no use.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Releases her thumb from the toggle control.</utterance>
   <speaker>HER SUIT JETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop firing.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drifts, staring towards Woody.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, honey...? You gotta go back now.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terri raises up the tether gun and pulls the trigger.</context>
      <utterance>The hell I do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna jet a little closer and try again.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No response from Terri.</context>
      <utterance>Terri, you spend any fuel getting closer, you won't get back, and if anyone tries to get you, they'll die too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The hook slams back against the muzzle of the gun. Terri resets the gun quickly, in an anguished fury.</context>
      <utterance>Honey, please go back. Go back and help everyone get down to the surface.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am not losing you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't let you do it. I can't. I'm sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He unscrews the ring, pops the seal. The outrush of air pushes his helmet all the way off. Woody shuts his eyes and opens his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>I love you, Terri. God how I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ice crystals bloom with Woody's last breath. There's nothing to suck in. He doesn't fight it. He lets death come.</context>
      <utterance>Woody, nooooooo...!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Woody, oh Woody, please God, no!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sees no movement from the distant, small figure of Terri.</context>
      <utterance>He's gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, Terri...  We need you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is worse. A thousand-yard stare. She's in shock.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Knows he has to occupy them. Speaks softly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phil looks up at him dully.</context>
      <utterance>Phil?  Hey, Phil...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a moment Phil releases his strap, pushes towards McConnell. He stares numbly at the monitor for a few beats, then takes the little computer from McConnell. He begins to tap the keys, slowly at first, but then with more confidence.</context>
      <utterance>We're going in blind. We'll deploy the chutes by laptop. I need to get on the data bus, put in a software patch, and try to soften this tin can's landing. I could use your help with the patch.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terri hesitates a moment, then looks at the strap in her hand, as if she's never seen it before. Dully she reaches for another one, begins looping them together.</context>
      <utterance>That's great. Good job.  Hey, Terri, I was wondering. Think maybe we could rig some kind of seatbelts out of those cargo straps?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>NEW CAPCOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck looks up, his eyes red-rimmed. The CapCom shifts uneasily. He's holding a computer printout.</context>
      <utterance>Ray...? We've got some new data, just coming in.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEW CAPCOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We just -- it doesn't make any sense. We're not sure how to read this.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Data?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEW CAPCOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir. Telemetry reports the REMO has left its orbit and reached the Martian surface.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crashed?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEW CAPCOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck snatches the paper, staring at it. For the first time we see some life coming back into him.</context>
      <utterance>No sir. Under power.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEW CAPCOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beck suddenly understands. And it's a joy to see his face, the tears of happiness that spring into his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Sixty-three minutes after Mars Recovery went off-line. Sir, the graph reads like a controlled descent. But that doesn't make any --</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CapCom stares back at him, feeling the same surge of hope.</context>
      <utterance>They used the REMO as a lander.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's McConnell, it's got to be! Nobody else could have pulled this off. Son of a bitch! They're alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>OMITTED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He catches himself. Phil and Terri look at him.</context>
      <utterance>Terri, let's see if that oxygen still is operational. Phil, you better check out the ERV. I'll take the Hab. If you find Luke's --</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just keep in touch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see a flash of uncertainty in Luke's eyes. Then he yanks his arm free, and his hammer arcs up even higher, trembles in the air.</context>
      <utterance>Luke, it's me! Jim McConnell!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not here!</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luke, it's Jim!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, you're not... you can't be here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he stares down at McConnell, Luke's eyes finally light up with recognition. but before he can move, he is seized from behind and flung backwards to the ground, the hammer ripped from his grasp, as Terri and Phil pinion his arms. McConnell scrambles to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>Your wife is Debra! Your son is Bobby! You were reading Treasure Island with him...!</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell kneels beside Luke, signalling to Terri and Phil that it's okay to let him go. They stand back, pulling off their helmets. Everyone is panting, out of breath. Luke sits up, slowly studying their features, one after another, as if still not quite certain whether they might vanish. His voice is hoarse, rusty from disuse.</context>
      <utterance>Don't hurt him!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Phil... Terri... Luke looks with incomprehension at McConnell.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim... I don't understand. You're not supposed to be here... Why are you here? Where's Woody?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke stares at McConnell, trying to absorb everything. He looks to Terri, who looks down.</context>
      <utterance>He didn't make it Luke.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke shakes his head in dismay. He seems to shrink in on himself. It's all too much for him to take in. McConnell kneels and puts his arm around Luke, comforting him.</context>
      <utterance>Oh no.</utterance>
   <speaker>OMITTED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A flash of fear in Luke's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Luke, what happened here?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We fired the radar. It came. They all died.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What came?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His voice drops to a conspiratorial whisper.</context>
      <utterance>They all died, but I was spared. Why? Had to be for a reason. Then, all of a sudden, I knew why I was spared.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He taps his forehead, significantly, then nods once or twice. The others exchange an uneasy glance.</context>
      <utterance>So somebody would be left to figure out the secret.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luke, we still don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rises quickly and scuttles off, waving an impatient hand, without waiting to see if they'll follow. McConnell, Terri and Phil stare after him for a long moment. Phil breaks the silence.</context>
      <utterance>Come. Comecomecome.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it just me? Or is he about two mealpacks short of a picnic?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Long term exposure to low gravity can have an adverse impact on the brain. He could be suffering from a form of asphyxia.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell and Terri follow in the direction Luke went. Phil, trailing, mutters to himself.</context>
      <utterance>Or maybe his whole crew died and he's been marooned alone on Mars. Let's give him time to adjust.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Greatgreatgreat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell and the others are silent, embarrassed. Then McConnell nods. Luke looks at him, a cracked grin.</context>
      <utterance>So... let me be sure I understand this. Your ship blew up, with all its supplies. Then you emptied the cargo out of the REMO, and it was totalled on landing. You've got no food, no water, no spare oxygen, nothing but what I see here...?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kinda rescue mission is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to the computer repair case, as Phil lifts it off a sledge. Luke turns, looks at the case, then Phil.</context>
      <utterance>That kind.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Check it out. New nav boards for the ERV. I got four round-trip tickets, baby, right in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In some mysterious way, this reminder of Woody's death seems to bring him fully back into himself. He takes Terri by the shoulders, deeply saddened. She meets his gaze.</context>
      <utterance>Four.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Terri... I'm so sorry. He was a good man.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Luke.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods, grateful. A beat. He looks at the others.</context>
      <utterance>When there's time, we'll talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts off across the sand, and they follow.</context>
      <utterance>This way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has to pause, collect himself.</context>
      <utterance>...When I came to and dug myself out of the sand, my faceplate was cracked. Leaking badly. I barely made it back to Base. It was weeks before I could work up the nerve to go back out there and look for their...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is an emotional silence. Luke turns, takes a few steps. He stares into the distance, observing the swirling dust around them. McConnell hesitates, notices Luke's gaze.</context>
      <utterance>Renee was the only one I could find. But it didn't seem right, somehow, to dig just one grave.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke looks off into the distance, studies something only he seems to see.</context>
      <utterance>Has it been blowing like this for a while?  We saw a big storm from space. But Micker said it was turning south.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell pulls his gaze away from the horizon, looks at Luke.</context>
      <utterance>If it holds course.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This -- whatever it was -- this force. You say it came directly out of the top of the mountain?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell isn't quite sure how to reply to this.</context>
      <utterance>You don't believe me. That's okay. But I'm not crazy, Jim.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you mean by its "secret?" What secret?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You better see for yourselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>OMITTED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others turn, looking at him. Luke is aiming an electric space heater at his computer. As the coils glow red, he rubs his hands together, poised over the keyboard.</context>
      <utterance>See, where they made their mistake was, they must've planned for it to be visible from Earth...</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke reacts to their blank stares. He has a kind of jittery feverish intensity, a secret excitement.</context>
      <utterance>Who's "they"?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others exchange worried glances. Is he totally nuts?</context>
      <utterance>Don't you understand? Hundreds of millions of years have gone by. You've got erosion, sand storms, lava flows, meteor impacts -- hell, in that much time, the whole surface would've changed. So no wonder we never saw it before. Well, I mean, we saw it, but not like they meant us too. Too much dirt on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Saw what?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the computer screen they're looking at...</context>
      <utterance>This.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus...</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is that...?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A few moments of silence while they try to absorb this.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. But whatever it is, somebody built it. And not us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the sound? That signal you heard before the explosion?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A click of the mouse and they all HEAR, over speakers, the</context>
      <utterance>Good, Jim, good. That's the key.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hear the pauses? That's what made me realize it's a pattern -- a repeating pattern.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke is trembling with excitement. His words tumble out very quickly. He's been waiting so long to share this.</context>
      <utterance>Mathematical?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I thought. There are distinct blocks in the pattern, and within each block the tones come in groups of three. Threethreethree. For months I struggled to analyze it, trying different constructs... Then I thought about dimensions.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>X-Y-Z coordinates...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He types another command. They all look at the monitor, the glow reflecting on their faces. They are amazed again.</context>
      <utterance>Right! Three groups equals three dimensions... So I tried assigning different graphic values to each block, group and tone. And finally I got... this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God... Is that what I think it is?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>DNA... that's a model of DNA!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances at him, surprised that he overheard her earlier diagnosis. But he smiles, not offended.</context>
      <utterance>You see it, too. Thank God. I was afraid I was just suffering from a form of asphyxia.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, okay, so -- somebody left this thing here, somebody -- other than human. But what the hell is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My guess is, it's a signature. A self-portrait of whatever species created the Face.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But that DNA looks human.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way. It's missing the last pair of chromosomes. See?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but it's close. Damn close.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The difference between a man and an ape is less than three percent of genetic material. But that three percent gives you Mozart. Einstein.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at him. Then all four turn, stare again at the slowly rotating DNA, pondering its awesome mystery.</context>
      <utterance>Or Jack the Ripper.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others nod in weary agreement. As they start out, towards the relative warmth of the greenhouse, Terri looks at Luke, at his scraggly beard and his long, lank hair. She smiles, brushing some locks off his forehead.</context>
      <utterance>It's been a long day. Let's get a couple hours sleep, then tackle this thing when we're fresher. Phil, your first priority will be to get the motherboards over to the ERV. Concentrate on getting communications up first.  Soon as we've got the juice, we'll send a packet to Micker, tell them Luke's OK, and that... everything else that's happened. The rest of us will take an inventory of supplies, see where we stand. Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon. There's a pair of scissors in my medkit.</utterance>
   <speaker>OMITTED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you feel?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell smiles. Terri enters through the hatch, removing her helmet.</context>
      <utterance>Like I just got back my other three percent.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The backup generator is salvageable, and two of the solar panels. I'm pretty sure I can get the oxygen still back into production, too. So we're not in such bad shape, considering.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell, rummaging through Phil's backpack, drops an already- opened bag of M&amp;Ms. The CANDIES scatter and bounce all over the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Good work, Terri.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke and Terri smile. McConnell scoops up the fallen M&amp;Ms. He slows down as he does it, looking at the scatter of little round CANDIES. Something tugging at the back of his mind...</context>
      <utterance>Look at that. Phil's idea of absolute essentials.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not a signature.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke and Terri stare at him.</context>
      <utterance>That noise from the Face... It's not a signature. It's a test.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's asking us for the right answer. It wants us to put in the missing pair of chromosomes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But why?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terri and Luke look at each other, starting to understand.</context>
      <utterance>To prove that we're human.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We fired radar into that thing. Concentrated sound waves...</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which it interpreted as a wrong answer... Yes! It's like a, a security alarm. When it gets an incorrect response, it defends itself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what happens when it gets the right answer?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. But we've got to find out.  Can you work this the other way? Figure out which tones would be equivalent to the missing chromosomes? Then dub them into your recording of the signal?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think so, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke stares at him, startled by what he's implying.</context>
      <utterance>What about the radar gun? Will it accept that input? Can we transmit a completed signal back to the Face?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa, whoa, hold on, Jim. What if you're wrong? Whoever goes out there... I mean, what if you're wrong? Three people have already died over that thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>Four.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terri shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>Terri, if we leave here without getting some answers, they all died in vain.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We just don't know enough about that -- that thing out there to take any more chances.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His passion startles them; they've never seen him so emotional. He points at the computer screen.</context>
      <utterance>What are we here for, if not to take chances...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This means we're not alone. It means we're on the brink of the greatest discovery in mankind's history. But we've still got to prove it. Who knows when someone else will get back here? Or if they ever will? You know what Congress is like. They'll say it's too dangerous, too much loss of life, let's go back to unmanned flights. We could be the last explorers to come here for decades. We're it, guys.  We're it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at him, surprised.</context>
      <utterance>We don't have to go out there. There's a better way.</utterance>
   <speaker>OMITTED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How close do we need to get?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure. Maybe we better stop by that boulder.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It worked... It worked!</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke punches buttons, waits anxiously for a readout.</context>
      <utterance>Check for radiation.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Normal. Seismic... normal. Anemometer steady. No sign of the vortex.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what we did, but guys -- does that look to you like a hostile gesture?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. More like an invitation.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell is staring at the mysterious opening. On his face, a growing look of determination.</context>
      <utterance>Or another test...</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others look at him, their expressions changing as they realize what he's implying.</context>
      <utterance>Luke, the four-man rover. Does it still work?</utterance>
   <speaker>OMITTED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long before it hits?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An hour? Maybe less.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell stares at him.</context>
      <utterance>A storm like that? It could go planetary. And last a year.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell turns, staring off towards the killer storm. The others look at him with questioning gazes. He turns again. There's the four-man rover, ready to go. Waiting.</context>
      <utterance>It'll sock us in, Jim. We won't be able to take off. If that happens, with what few supplies we've got left...? We'll starve to death.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Phil, how much longer to prep the</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe forty-five minutes. It'll be tight, but we can make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks a question at Luke and Terri, one after the other. Their eyes, tense but excited, signal agreement.</context>
      <utterance>Then there's still time for us to get out there and back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay here. Continue the repair. If something goes wrong, you get out of here before that storm hits.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go back... alone?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we're not back in forty-five minutes, I want you to prep and launch.  That's 1950 hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim --</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not a suggestion, it's an order. You understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand. But --</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You understand what?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell nods, satisfied. Looks at Terri and Luke.</context>
      <utterance>If you're not back by 1950, I prep and launch.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start towards the four-man rover. Dust is swirling more thickly through the air, and the WIND IS LOUDER NOW. Phil stands watching them go, a lone, rather forlorn figure.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Phil, do you read me?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Jim. Your signal's breaking up a little in the storm, but I read you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're at the Face. We're gonna need a few minutes here. Same deadline, launch at 1950. With or without us. Do you copy?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terri and Luke exchange a tense glance.</context>
      <utterance>Copy that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim, are you sure you want to do this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke smiles. The three of them stare into the portal. McConnell, between the others, reaches out and grips each of them by a gloved hand. They take a sort of collective breath. Then they walk forward together, into the light.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure of anything anymore. But I didn't come a hundred million miles just to turn back in the last ten feet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Surface seems firm and level.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roger that. Texture is smooth.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind them, there is an abrupt WHOOOSH, like a giant airlock sealing shut. They turn, startled and nervous. Letting go of each other's hands, Luke and Terri run back the way they came, but almost immediately are stopped by a wall of some sort. The vast hangar-type door has closed behind them.</context>
      <utterance>I've got good footing and no obstructions. Let's check our --</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's solid again! We're trapped.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three scared, helmeted faces seem to float in the brightness, some twenty feet apart.</context>
      <utterance>Don't move! Keep this orientation.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Phil? Phil, can you still hear me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances out the cockpit window at the blowing dust. Then realizes that he's hearing only silence over his radio.</context>
      <utterance>Computers are online! Ready to load software. But guys -- we're losing visibility here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guys...? Jim? Luke? Terri? Is anyone there...? No answer. Phil stares at his radio in dread.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't leave me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim, what're you doing? You'll depressurize!</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell makes the final twist on his glove and there's the hiss of rushing air.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim, seal it!</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke looks at his sleeve. McConnell's right.</context>
      <utterance>No. That was air going into my suit, not out. Look at your own suits -- they're not rigid anymore. We've got pressure in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Above Mars atmospheric? That's impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terri types on her arm keypad. She's amazed.</context>
      <utterance>We're millions of miles from Earth and we're inside a gigantic white face. What's impossible?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's six psi in here...  Nitrogen and oxygen.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terri nods. McConnell starts unscrewing his helmet ring. Luke follows suit.</context>
      <utterance>Otherwise known as air?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terri starts taking off her helmet. In a few moments, all three helmets are off. They hold them, glowing softly, against their chests, as they breathe deeply and gratefully. Air. And then, at this very moment, as if they have just passed another kind of test...</context>
      <utterance>Hey, there may be some lethal trace gasses I haven't picked up yet, or... or... oh, the hell with it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that what I think it is?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. It's Mars.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUDDENLY A HUGE ASTEROID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tumbles through space towards the planet...</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her voice is soft.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Earth, when it was still Pangaea. Before the continents separated.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're us. We're them...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're Martians...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what she means.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell and Luke look at her.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God. The Cambrian explosion.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Almost six hundred million years ago, there was a sudden expansion of life on Earth. The first multi-celled plants and animals appeared. No one has ever understood why...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear a BELL-LIKE TONE, a single lingering high note, and simultaneously the outermost ring of the circle on the floor begins to glow brightly. It is an intense chromium yellow.</context>
      <utterance>They seeded Earth.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terri picks up her helmet, leans into its mike.</context>
      <utterance>...in, please. Can you... me?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Even through the scratchy interference, they can hear the relief in Phil's voice. And then the desperation.</context>
      <utterance>Phil, we're here! We read you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then they hear only STATIC. His signal is lost.</context>
      <utterance>Thank God! Listen, this storm is really --  -- few more minutes, I can't --  You've gotta get back to the ship!</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly the BELL-LIKE TONE REPEATS, at a lower register, with a more sustained note, and simultaneously, the last of the yellow circles of light begins to fade, as</context>
      <utterance>Phil? Phil...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terri looks at Luke, alarmed.</context>
      <utterance>We are in a ship. This is a ship. And the countdown has already started.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She scoops up Luke's helmet, tosses it to him. As he catches it, she's already starting back out, in the direction they came from, and Luke follows her. Until they both become aware that McConnell isn't with them. They turn back. He's still rooted to the spot, his gaze locked on the indigo core of the colored rings.</context>
      <utterance>Then let's get the hell out of here!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell doesn't turn.</context>
      <utterance>Jim...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim, we gotta go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not coming with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Coming back, she sees how calm he is. How certain.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about? We've got to get home.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks into their faces. Terri is trying to grasp this idea, still incredulous. Luke has the beginning of a half smile.</context>
      <utterance>That's where I'm going. Don't you see? That's what all this is for.  You were right Terri. This is an invitation. To follow them. To follow them home.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke nods at the memory of Maggie's words. Terri remembers too. McConnell's passionate conviction is affecting them both.</context>
      <utterance>I have to go. This is the mission now. To find out who we are. Isn't that why we came here? Like Maggie said, "To stand on a new world and look beyond it to the next one."</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terri looks at Luke. Luke is smiling. He understands.</context>
      <utterance>You know, when you think about it -- I wasn't even supposed to be here -- all the accidents, everything that got us to this point, it's just... it's just... I just know it's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm okay. I know what I'm doing. But you're running out of time. You've gotta get back to the ERV and get off this planet. Now please go. Luke steps closer, looking at his old friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They clasp hands for a moment. But in this moment is a lifetime of camaraderie, an eternity of farewell.</context>
      <utterance>I once felt like I was taking your turn. But now I think maybe you're taking mine. Guess I'm a little jealous.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for saving my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke nods, deeply moved. He turns away, picking up his helmet, as Terri comes closer, looking at McConnell, a long unspoken beat. Her eyes are glistening.</context>
      <utterance>My pleasure.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terri smiles. She is starting on the road to recovery. She's going to be okay.</context>
      <utterance>I wish Woody were here to see this. He would've wanted to go too, Jim.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terri nods. She digs into one of her suit's pockets, pulls something out. She hands it to McConnell, and his fist closes around it.</context>
      <utterance>He's here, Terri. We wouldn't have made it without him.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McConnell smiles. Terri smiles back at him. Then she turns, picks up her helmet, and crosses to where Luke has paused, looking back.</context>
      <utterance>Take care, Jim.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Jim...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have a great ride.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke and Terri exchange a final silent farewell with him, then hurry away, into the darkness.</context>
      <utterance>Always do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks down at what Terri gave him.</utterance>
   <speaker>IT'S WOODY'S NECK CHAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With the little Flash Gordon rocketship.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grips this tightly as he looks up.</utterance>
   <speaker>OMITTED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Phil? Phil, do you read?  He's not reading.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can barely read you. Let's get the hell out of here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phil gets no response. He is shaking, almost crying. He hesitates, then starts hitting some keys.</context>
      <utterance>Is anyone there? Can anyone read me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON HIS COMPUTER DISPLAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which reads: "PRE-LAUNCH CHECKLIST."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HIS GLOVED HANDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Slide helplessly across the smooth surface.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCCONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks down again.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COBALT LIQUID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is up to his knees. Now his thighs...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No good! We're driving blind.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll try to keep on a straight line! It's our only chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry! I've worked with Phil for four years! I know Jim gave him a direct order, but he won't leave without us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phil waits a second, then reaches slowly for a blinking red switch that reads "LAUNCH." He hesitates, then actually has his fingers on it, about to flip it, when he hears a crackle of static on the radio. Phil keys his mike.</context>
      <utterance>This is ERV, do you read? ERV to Rover, do you read...?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is ERV, do you read?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, Phil's not here right now. He left for Earth five minutes ago. Please leave your message at the beep.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Jim?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Phil stares at her, bewildered.</context>
      <utterance>He got another ride.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell you on the way. Let's go!</utterance>
   <speaker>OMITTED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PUSHING IN QUICKLY ON THIS.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We see three figures in the cockpit.</utterance>
   <speaker>OMITTED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TERRI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Through their cockpit window, they watch the Martian ship hurtle by them at a hundred times their speed.</context>
      <utterance>Dear God. Look at that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke nods. Their eyes are glistening. Luke's voice is a whisper, both of prayer and farewell.</context>
      <utterance>Is that him?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Godspeed Jim McConnell.</utterance>
   <speaker>OMITTED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
   <speaker>OMITTED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
