<movie id="396" title="Monkeybone">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>As MISS HUDLAPP pulls her sweater off, TWO MASSIVE ARM-FLAPS - fifty gallons of flab apiece - SPILL OUT and SMACK INTO THE FLOOR. MISS HUDDLAPP claps two erasers together, kicking up a cloud of dust. Young STANLEY watches, transfixed by her massive ARM FLAPS. We TRACK IN on the gigantic ARM FLAPS as they swing hypnotically back and forth, with a loud SLAP each time they collide.</context>
      <utterance>You know how some teachers have those, kind of, flaps on their arms - those big sacks of limp flab that like, dangle?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Now we TRACK IN on the mesmerized STANLEY. A SONG comes up underneath: Donna Summer, "I FEEL LOVE."</context>
      <utterance>It sounds weird...but for some reason, as I watched those big old flaps of hers, I began to feel...well...oddly...</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>And then the horror began. DOINK! STANLEY looks down at his LAP in horror. The boys and girls around him are pointing and tittering. Grimacing in embarrassment, he discreetly places a heavy TEXTBOOK onto his lap, suppressing the bulge in his pants. But SPROING!! - the BOOK goes flying across the room. The BULGE is fighting back! The kids DUCK AND COVER beneath their desks as STANLEY slams a STACK of textbooks onto his lap. It's no use - the WHOLE STACK goes flying, and BOOKS come raining down on the entire class! Now MISS HUDLAPP is staring directly at him...</context>
      <utterance>...aroused.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS HUDLAPP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She marches toward him. STANLEY pulls his BACKPACK over his lap.</context>
      <utterance>Young man. What's that in your lap?</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The BACKPACK bucks and wriggles, as if something inside is trying to GET OUT. And then - with a flourish of rousing disco strings - IT DOES!</context>
      <utterance>It was useless. Like putting a baseball cap on the Washington Monument. And then...all at once ...there he was.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The libidinous cartoon monkey BURSTS OUT of the backpack, POINTS at MISS HUDLAPP - and announces, in his Barry White baritone:</context>
      <utterance>Monkeybone!!</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KC and the SUNSHINE BAND comes up underneath as MONKEYBONE DANCES to the front of the class. He grabs MISS HUDLAPP by the hands and begins dancing The Bump with her ARM FLAPS. Butt left, WHAP. Butt right, WHAP. The KIDS are bug-eyed - agog. With each WHAP their little heads turn back and forth as if they're watching a nude tennis match.</context>
      <utterance>Oooo-oo-ooh, baby. I love your way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about it, Doc? Can you help me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHRINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the desk is a CATALOGUE, open to a two-page spread depicting a 40- foot CABIN CRUISER. "NEW FOR SUMMER! ONLY $229,999.95!" With his free hand, the SHRINK is working a CALCULATOR...</context>
      <utterance>Not overnight. These imaginary monkey cases take time. I vould estimate...roughly...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHRINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SHRINK hustles STANLEY to the door and shakes his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Twelve years and three months ought to do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One question, doc - what did you mean when you said "imaginary"?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHRINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SHRINK shoves STANLEY out and slams the door behind him. Two beats. Then he doubles over, WEEPING with LAUGHTER.</context>
      <utterance>All in good time, my boy. All in good time.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHRINK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vot a crackpot! Monkey on ze back - HAH!! ROLL</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STANLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, Monkeybone! At this rate I'll never find a good shrink.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MONKEYBONE sticks his thumb in his butt as he and STANLEY toddle off into the sunset.</context>
      <utterance>Those guys are a waste of money! I'll show you how to stop sucking your thumb...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HERB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HERB leads a round of APPLAUSE. JULIE nudges STU - the only guy in the room who's still in his seat.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you...that's our pilot...the good news is, Comedy Channel has just picked us up with an order for six new episodes!</utterance>
   <speaker>HERB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A SPOTLIGHT hits him, and he STANDS to tumultuous applause. He looks genuinely stunned. He can't believe it's happening. JULIE surreptitiously PINCHES him on the bottom, giving him a start. She WINKS at him. He shoots her a small private smile - then turns to WAVE at the adoring crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Now, let's give it up for the guy who started it all. Creator of America's most disturbed comic strip...the man behind the monkey...Mister Stu Miley!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beautiful, heavily-pierced FEMALE FAN hands STU a marker.</context>
      <utterance>I don't actually draw all the animation, no. We have sweatshop workers who couldn't get jobs at Nike doing that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAUTIFUL FAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Miley, would you draw Monkeybone on my belly? As a guide?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guide...?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAUTIFUL FAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She exposes her taut midriff. STU thinks for a moment, then goes to work. When he's done, Monkeybone appears to be climbing out of the girl's pants and WAVING to her. Nearby FANS APPLAUD.</context>
      <utterance>For my tattoo artist?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAUTIFUL FAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She begins unbuckling her belt so STU will have enough room to draw Monkeybone's bottom half. STU demurs...</context>
      <utterance>Wait! You have to draw the rest of him -</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I - I have to, uh, check in with my doctor. DO-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See these doors? The cool thing is, you go out ...they close...you can't get back in! He opens one door and holds it for JULIE.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to leave? But Stu - you're a big hit! Everyone loves you!</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't love me. They love Monkeybone.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was you who got the standing O. It was you drawing on the belly over there...</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was especially Monkeybone. Come on, Doc, I don't want to be stuck here with this bunch of media creeps. I just want to be us. Home. Alone!  I have something I have to give you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't you give it to me later?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives up trying to explain...pulls her close and kisses her. For a moment they completely forget about the party in the next room. Then HERB appears behind them, trying to catch STU's eye as he waits for the clinch to break up. Finally he pries them apart:</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I could, but the thing is, if later got here sooner, it would be...better.</utterance>
   <speaker>HERB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Julie - won't be a minute. Now Stu - I know you don't like the idea, but you really ought to talk to these guys -</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But before STU knows what's hit him, HERB is leading him back to -</context>
      <utterance>Julie and I - we were just gonna go...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>HERB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go? There's a potload of money here, pal. You got three major toy companies...you got the guys from Burger God over here...</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Burger God. The ones that found the pig hair in the french fries?</utterance>
   <speaker>HERB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The MERCHANDISERS shoot STU an expectant wave. STU waves back and turns in the opposite direction. HERB grabs him by the sleeve.</context>
      <utterance>Never proven. They're ready to pop for a pre- emptive endorsement. Kids love Burger God -</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Herb, it's too much. It's all out of hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>HERB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know what kind of opportunity you have here? You gotta strike. I'm talking mansions. Lamborghinis. Champagne for mouthwash when you brush your teeth!</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to be rich. It's just a trap!</utterance>
   <speaker>HERB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Being rich is not a trap. That is a dirty lie perpetuated by rich people to keep the failures from killing them.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Herb. I have to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>HERB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tonight's the night, Herb. Tonight's the night. He nods toward JULIE, who's at the open bar grabbing two glasses of punch. HERB realizes a proposal is in the works.</context>
      <utterance>I got the ring.</utterance>
   <speaker>HERB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God...you're proposing?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My life was totally crappy, Herb, and she... fixed it. She made me happy. Which I'd never been. She loves me the way I am - right now.  I don't want everything to change. I don't want her saying yes to some big success. I just want her saying yes to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HERB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JULIE's over by the punchbowl. She sees the two boys staring at her conspiratorially - MAKES A FACE at them as she waves back.</context>
      <utterance>...In some weird way I respect that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HERB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay then. If I get you out of here - you pop the question - tonight. Or else. Get me? STU nods gravely.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HERB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STU GLOWERS at HERB as he opens the car door for JULIE.</context>
      <utterance>They're just prototypes...take 'em home and look at 'em before you say no...  If you could just hold on a minute or two, we're expecting a couple more trucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>HERB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay! You're a beautiful couple. Go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at this! He won't let us leave!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The monkey!! He's everywhere! He'll take over both our lives if we let him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stu - stop it. That monkey is good luck. You thought him up, and everybody loves him, and he's probably going to make you rich. So relax! Enjoy it!</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm trying. It's weird, that's all. I never had any good luck, until I met you...what if it's all just another bad dream?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the "bad" part?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I might wake up.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He says it so solemnly that she cracks up. After a moment he joins in.</context>
      <utterance>I am happy. It just so happens this is the happiest night of my life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did we just - hit something?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She thinks it over, nods. STU takes a moment to catch his breath, then opens the door gingerly. A HORN BLARES as a car speeds past in the opposite lane, nearly taking STU's door off. He jumps back inside, waits, opens the door again...</context>
      <utterance>Are you okay??</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Are you guys all right in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEENAGE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That stupid monkey banner! It fell on my windshield - it practically killed us all!  God, Julie, if anything had happened to you -</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm fine, baby. We're all okay. We were lucky.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He spots a PHONE BOOTH and starts across the street. On the way there he plucks a STUFFED MONKEYBONE DOLL off the pavement and CHOKES IT with both hands. JULIE stays behind with the prom kids. The TEENAGE BOY in his tux is glassy-eyed, miserable beyond description.</context>
      <utterance>I'd better go report this...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The BOY begins to SOB softly. JULIE nods in sympathy. Then: EVERYONE WINCES. The air is full of a horrible CREAKING noise, like nails on a blackboard...</context>
      <utterance>Dad's car?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEENAGE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The horrible CREAKING NOISE continues. JULIE turns. Behind her, the TELEPHONE POLE that the car slammed into is beginning to TEETER. Then it TOPPLES. Directly toward...</context>
      <utterance>What was that? Did you hear that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All at once he seems to be RECEDING from JULIE and the others - as if SINKING THROUGH the bottom of the stretcher, and BEYOND - through the floor of the ambulance! JULIE's voice grows weaker, more distant:</context>
      <utterance>Stu? I'm here, baby. It's me. It's Julie. I love you. You're gonna be okay, baby, I promise -</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>And then all trace of the ambulance is gone, and he's floating down through some strange LIMBO, surrounded by the silhouettes of billowing SHROUDS, with the sound of BIRDS CALLING all around him... An AWFUL MECHANICAL RATCHETING NOISE fills the soundtrack. STU's eyes close - and when they reopen, he finds himself in:</context>
      <utterance>I'm here, baby. I won't leave you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SNAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STU looks down and sees a SQUASHED RABBIT humping his leg.</context>
      <utterance>Cigars, mister? Genuine Coobans!</utterance>
   <speaker>RABBIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>These bordertown types are known as ROADKILL, and they're sporting the tire tracks to prove it. STU SCREAMS, shakes them off, and RUNS.</context>
      <utterance>Wanna meet my sister?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The humans just YAWN. They're COMA VICTIMS, just like STU. He ditches one of his SUITCASES as the ROADKILL come after him.</context>
      <utterance>Help me. Please. There's animals. They -</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and spots a helpful-looking fellow in a COWBOY OUTFIT. The COWBOY is in fact a CENTAUR - rider and mount rolled into one! The characters who run this place - the BARKERS, TICKET-TAKERS, and RIDE OPERATORS - are all weird HYBRIDS, part human, part ANIMAL. They could be the ancient Gods of some primitive culture - reduced to working as street entertainers in this ramshackle resort town. STU pinballs down the street, bouncing from one shock to another: - JOE CAMEL, doing community service as a STREET SWEEPER -</context>
      <utterance>Pony ride, Mister?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE CAMEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>- a YETI selling SNO-CONES from a cart outside the MORPHEUM THEATRE. The marquee reads:</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Mister. Mister! Got a smoke?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HEAD #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, aren't you Stu Miley?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're big fans.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reduced to babbling hysteria, STU ducks into the nearest building. Above the door, an ANIMATED NEON SIGN shows a happy boozer lifting his martini glass, then falling over flat on his back, at which point his eyes are replaced by the traditional cartoon X's. This is the COMA BAR.</context>
      <utterance>Could we have your autograph?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chasing me - animals - horrible -</utterance>
   <speaker>BULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STU GAGS. BULL is a full-fledged MINOTAUR, body of a man, head of a BULL. His features are CUBIST - weirdly squashed over to one side.</context>
      <utterance>Animals? What kind of animals?</utterance>
   <speaker>BULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I know - Picasso. Guernica, right? That's what everybody says - although personally, I don't see the resemblance. What are you drinking?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uhh - martini?</utterance>
   <speaker>BULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Olive or eyeball?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Olive. - Where exactly am I?</utterance>
   <speaker>BULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dark Town. Land of nightmares. I'm Bull.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stu Miley.</utterance>
   <speaker>BULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STU gives him a cockeyed look. BULL points to a MONITOR mounted over the bar, on which a panicked man in pajamas is trying to run barefoot through a great sticky SEA OF MOLASSES.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I've seen a few of your dreams. You're quite a celebrity down here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He changes channels with a remote. Now we see a guy falling through midair, arms and legs flailing, falling, falling, falling...</context>
      <utterance>I told you, it's the land of nightmares. Same on every channel...all the stuff people dream, after they have the extra anchovies.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeez, it all looks like bad late-night cable.</utterance>
   <speaker>BULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now a small muffled VOICE speaks from the area of STU'S BACKPACK: DISEMBODIED VOICE (o.s.) "Bull," huh? That's cute. What's your last name - "Shit"??</context>
      <utterance>Sad commentary, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>BULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I beg your pardon?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nice face. Lemme guess. You were in a bullfight ...with a Mack Truck!! STU claps both hands over his mouth to prove he's not the one talking. BULL glowers at him, snorting STEAM out of both nostrils.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't say anything. VOICE</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was, uh, just getting ready to leave...</utterance>
   <speaker>BULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ELEPHANT GOD from the Wurlitzer organ comes lumbering over. VOICE (o.s.) Well, hello, sailor. Get a lot of dates with that ding-dong on your face?? BULL and JUMBO rear back to PUNCH STU'S LIGHTS OUT. He's saying his prayers when his BACKPACK begins to BULGE and QUIVER - and a SMALL FURRY BEAST pops out, CACKLING HIS HEAD OFF!!</context>
      <utterance>Yo, Jumbo. We got us some kind of ventriloquist here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BULL and JUMBO back off, STUNNED. The monkey grabs STU'S FACE and plants a big wet SMOOCH right on his NOSE. STU SCREAMS.</context>
      <utterance>Just kiddin', folks! Drinks for everybody -  On him!! HIYA, BOSS!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a spike, ma'am. It happens. It's perfectly natural with coma patients.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JULIE strokes STU's limp hand. He's COMATOSE, cocooned in a tangle of wires and tubes. His head and shoulders are heavily bandaged. He's hooked up to as much machinery as you can cram into one room.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a doctor too. I know this man's brain -</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go home, Doctor. Rest. Come back when you can do us some good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now don't pick a fight. I'm staying over.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ALICE kneels to play with the dog. She hears a sudden GASP from the kitchen. JULIE is standing by the open refrigerator, wearing an absolutely stricken expression...</context>
      <utterance>Oh, poor Buster. He hasn't been fed in a day and a half. Let me get some food...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Special occasion?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She bursts into tears. ALICE sits her down at the kitchen table and takes the champagne from her.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I guess it was...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>bottle on ice. When he comes around you're going to need it.</context>
      <utterance>Don't get all poignant. We're keeping this</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who did this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stu. That was right about the time we met.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When he first came in to the sleep lab?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The canvas depicts a group of SURGEONS with the faces of wolves. They're standing over a HUMAN PATIENT, replacing his internal organs with MACHINE PARTS. The style is at once cartoony and unsettling.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah...before your time.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, honey...he always joked about you curing him, but I never realized what you cured him from.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ALICE's gaze goes from the nightmare paintings to the MONKEYBONE strips tacked up over the drafting table.</context>
      <utterance>He hadn't gotten a good night's sleep in years. The nightmares would wake him up, and he'd start right in painting...  That boy looked like pluperfect hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you get from here - to there?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Switch hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A smile comes to JULIE's face. She settles in on the floor beside ALICE and digs through the various portfolios until she comes up with a quickie CARTOON on the back of a napkin - the prototype for...</context>
      <utterance>I'm serious. It was bicameral disjunction - right brain and left brain out of balance. He was a rightie, so I made him switch the pencil to his left hand. Just to see what'd come out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monkeybone?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Left-handed, he was funny. He'd been doing all this scary, intense work...then he found out he could draw this stuff, and make me laugh, and he liked that.  And then the nightmares just...stopped.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow - two guys in the same brain. - Which one did you fall in love with? JULIE smiles at the cartoon. She isn't telling.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've put a ton of work into that boy, Alice. I am not going to let him get away from me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIMMY looks up. She's crying so much she can barely recognize JULIE.</context>
      <utterance>Kimmy...?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Julie...my poor Stu...my poor baby brother...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When'd you get in?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I tried to prepare myself, but I didn't know he would be like, like this. I can't even bear to look at him... How about you? You're okay?</context>
      <utterance>An hour ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm fine, Kimmy. Fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had so much I always wanted to say to him. At least he had a chance to give you the ring.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ring...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JULIE turns to look at STU in the bed. The certain knowledge that he was about to propose is like a knife in her heart. KIMMY feels bad as well, having let the cat out of the bag, but before they can hash it out -</context>
      <utterance>Grandmama's ring. The engagement ring. He asked me to send it to him -</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE FROM BEHIND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cheery DR. EDELSTEIN enters. He shakes hands with the women, then checks STU's readouts, making notations on his clipboard.</context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Brewster? Julie? I'm Dr. Edelstein.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EDELSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vital signs have stabilized. That's good.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you give us a realistic sense of my brother's chances?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EDELSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's held on this far. We can't do much but wait and see.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This remark sends a shiver down JULIE's spine, but she keeps silent.</context>
      <utterance>But these...machines are what's keeping him alive, is that right?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EDELSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At the moment, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you give me a realistic idea...of how long this is going to last?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EDELSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Comas are unpredictable. He could wake up today, tomorrow, a month from now...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey, I have to clarify this. The thing is, Dr. Edelstein, my brother has an absolute horror of doctors - hospitals - needles - all of it -</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kimmy, he doesn't know what's going on. He doesn't even know he's in a -</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, Julie. This is not easy for me. Our father took a long time to die. A long time. It just about killed us all. And Stu and I made a pact that when our time came - we wouldn't let it drag out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's too soon even to - talk about that!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me a date, Doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. EDELSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's always some brain damage. But at three months...the chances of coming back shrink dramatically with every day.</context>
      <utterance>Three months.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No one says anything. But both women look at STU, and then at each other, and everyone knows exactly where everyone else stands. JULIE has a sinking feeling that STU is working on a 3-month deadline.</context>
      <utterance>I want him to have every chance, Doctor. We can certainly give it...three months.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EMCEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>GEORGE is a pudgy shmoe with a small pencil mustache who's wearing glasses, a necktie, and NOTHING ELSE. He steps forward, holding a briefcase in front of his crotch, looking EXTREMELY MORTIFIED.</context>
      <utterance>And now the last of our five finalists...Miss Michigan...GEORGE T. WILLOUGHBY!</utterance>
   <speaker>EMCEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And now George will give us his analysis of Heisenberg's Uncertainty Principle as it pertains to third-world economics!! CAMERA PULLS BACK - and we realize we're in:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In fact he goes into a little softshoe, keeping the briefcase poised over his crotch. Unfortunately, THE CASE POPS OPEN, dumping frilly LINGERIE all over the stage. The weeping GEORGE must crawl around on all fours to retrieve it... By now the onlookers at the bar are CRACKING UP. All except one - the lonely, disconsolate fellow on the last stool, nursing a martini - STU.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna wash that man right outta my hair!</utterance>
   <speaker>BULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Stu, why so glum? Everybody loves a good humiliation nightmare.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three months, Bull. Three months tonight. Three months since the accident - and I'm no closer to going home than I was then.</utterance>
   <speaker>BULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, buck up. Have another 'tini.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He GRIMACES at MONKEYBONE, who's stretched out atop the mighty Wurlitzer at the other end of the room. The MERMAID CHANTEUSE is singing a Dietrich number, "The Laziest Gal in Town" - or at least trying to, because MONKEYBONE is caterwauling behind her. By the time she gets to the grand finale, he's practically BAYING AT THE MOON. Pissed off, she SHAKES her FIST at MONKEYBONE and pulls the lid of her clamshell SHUT. This suits MONKEYBONE just fine, as it leaves him alone in the spotlight to soak up what little applause there is.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sick of martinis. I'm sick of the waiting, and the carnival rides, and watching people's nightmares. And of course, I need not add -</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gestures to JUMBO, the elephant organist, who begins to vamp.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, thank you for that very modest response. I know you're all in comas, but still. And now...it's dedication time!</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MONKEYBONE begins STRUTTING across the top of the piano, bumping and grinding and shaking his booty to the tune of -</context>
      <utterance>We've got a special dedication tonight. This one's from my ever-lovin' boss, Mr. Stu Mopey - I mean Miley - and we're sendin' it up to a very special lady in the land of the living. Yes, I do mean Julie - the beautiful Miss Julie - who, if she has a brain in her head, is shacked up right now with some good-lookin' doc she met in the E.R.!  JUST KIDDING, BUDDY! Because if we know anything about Miss Julie, we know she is faithful, loyal, and true. Even if her boyfriend is an eggplant. Which is why we're dedicating...this very special tune...to her. Jumbo? JUMBO's tasteful vamping gives way to a RAUNCHY ROCK BEAT - and</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MONKEYBONE sings the same poignant line over and over until STU comes storming over from the bar and YANKS HIM off the Wurlitzer by the scruff of his scrawny NECK. A trouper to the end, MONKEYBONE WAVES at the crowd even as STU drags him off to an empty table in the farthest corner of the room.</context>
      <utterance>MAH baby does the Hanky-Panky! UNHH! MAH baby does the Hanky-Panky! UNHH!</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have humiliated me in public for the last time.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I doubt that. Besides, I can't help myself. I'm just a figment of your imagination.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you can learn to act normally. I had to!</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, come on. You know you love me. You're a masochistic pain freak. You gotta love me.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MONKEYBONE waves and winks at every female who passes by. STU whacks him upside the head.</context>
      <utterance>I am not. And I don't gotta.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are too! Mooning over Julie when we could both be gettin' some o' this fine local action. It's not like she's gonna know. Out of town, under five minutes, and in a coma don't count.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cocktail waitress KITTY, a seven-foot cat-faced feline sex bomb, arrives in her skimpy black dress and shows STU a Cheshire-cat grin. MONKEYBONE reclines, Odalisque-style, on the table.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry. The women here aren't my type. Most of them aren't even my species.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hellooooooooo, Kitty.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hiya, Stu. Refill on that martini?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like something with an umbrella in it and a really smutty name. Like a...Sex Behind the Sofa with Your Parents in the Same Room Watching "The Brady Bunch."</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing for him! He's being repressed.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is something wrong, Stu? You seem so tense.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aaah, it's the same as always...poor mope's just wishin' he was me.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been trying to get through to the head guy - the nightmare god - what's his name?</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hypnos?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A softie at heart, KITTY sits across from STU and takes his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. To see if he could expedite my case. But I wait, and I wait, and...I'm starting to think I'll never see her again.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leans forward sympathetically. From this particular vantage, MONKEYBONE has an unobstructed view of KITTY's cleavage. And so does STU - although he's not quite as obvious about staring.</context>
      <utterance>I shoulda proposed, Kitty. That way at least she'd know how I feel. That way she'd...wait for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MONKEYBONE slinks over behind STU - up onto his shoulder - and whispers into his ear:</context>
      <utterance>She is waiting for you, Stu. I know she is. Guys like you don't come along that often. Believe me, I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My Fellow Americans. I have a dream. Let us boldly go where no man has gone before.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Kitty - what were you saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KITTY is holding the cleavage pose for an unnaturally long time. Her furry tail begins to swing back and forth playfully in the air. It's hypnotic - like a windshield wiper. STU stares at it. MONKEYBONE stares at it. And MONKEYBONE'S TAIL responds by straightening...stiffening...bending upward slightly.</context>
      <utterance>I mean it, Stu. You're one in a million.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STU is suddenly aware of something LONG, RED, and WET unrolling onto his shoulder. It's a TONGUE...dangling out of MONKEYBONE'S OPEN MOUTH. STU lets out a YOWL OF SHOCK. Blushing bright red, he GRABS THE TONGUE and shoves it manually back into the monkey mouth whence it came.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not so special. I'm just - kind of -</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, pal! It was a compliment! You'da done the same if you had the equipment!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm reportin' this to my union!!</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What union?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STU grabs a CHAIR and swings it at the chandelier. MONKEYBONE makes a series of SUBMARINE NOISES -</context>
      <utterance>The sidekicks' union! Me, Tonto, and Robin the Boy Wonder. You top bananas better watch your ass!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I left my phone number in your undies. Try not to lose it in traffic.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MONKEYBONE runs under the pool table. STU is giving chase when - suddenly - a DOOR blows open in the chill night wind. EVERYONE IN THE BAR freezes in place. For there, in the doorway, is a looming, ominous figure - the most dreaded figure in all of Dark Town - - a GRIM REAPER, nine feet tall and swinging a scythe, come to take some hapless coma victim to the land of Death! EERIE WINDS WHISTLE and the shroud FLUTTERS in the night breeze as the REAPER looks from face to face. For a moment he focuses on STU. STU backs away involuntarily, with a mounting sense of dread...and MONKEYBONE jumps into his arms, clinging to him fearfully. But the REAPER moves on - past each COMA VICTIM in turn - finally STOPPING in front of a TINY, WIZENED, PRUNELIKE OLD GENT in a wheelchair, who looks to be 110 years old at least.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Kitty! I'll be right back after I choke my monkey.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Him. Whew. About time!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't hear you, young fellow. Speak up!</utterance>
   <speaker>REAPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>GASPS OF ANTICIPATION all around the room as the REAPER hands EARL a long white ENVELOPE. EARL opens it slowly and removes... ...an oversized rectangular TICKET...the size of a Hershey bar, made of SOLID GOLD, with the letter "E" stamped upon it. VARIOUS CHARACTERS around the barroom react, in hushed voices:</context>
      <utterance>EARL BIEGLER, I'VE COME TO GIVE YOU - aw, hell. Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An E-Ticket!</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He got a reprieve.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>EARL throws his crutches aside, jumps out of his chair, and DANCES A JIG, waving the ticket over his head. STU stares at him with naked envy.</context>
      <utterance>Good for him! He's gonna wake up!</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. No. Not him.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>EARL does an end-zone dance toward the door. One by one, OTHER PATRONS get up from their seats to watch EARL's departure.</context>
      <utterance>So long, suckers! See you in the funny papers!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's ninety. He's practically dead already. How come he goes back and I stay here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe he wanted to pick out his own casket?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He got an E-ticket. Where's mine? When do I get to wake up??</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stu? Stu? Let's not disturb the nice Reaper.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been stuck down here for months. Somebody had better start paying attention, or I'm gonna - I'm gonna kick ass!</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MONKEYBONE practically swoons. But the REAPER just stares at STU:</context>
      <utterance>Let's not kick the nice Reaper's ass.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STU BOOTS MONKEYBONE aside. They're at a GAME STALL manned by Elsie the Cow - the one where you throw baseballs at milk bottles. STU picks up a baseball and HURLS IT at the departing REAPER. The ball hits the REAPER smack on the head, knocking him off his bike!</context>
      <utterance>Stu? Stu? Let's calm down, talk things over. How about some comedy relief? Okay. Brontosaurus walks into a gay bar...</utterance>
   <speaker>STU/MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MONKEYBONE cowers in fear as the REAPER gets up, shaking a fist at them. But STU isn't intimidated. He grabs another ball and winds up.</context>
      <utterance>Damn.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The REAPER, scared shitless, jumps back on his bike and PEDALS OFF as the ball whizzes past. STU starts chasing after him! The REAPER turns down a side street and pedals up an incline - one of the "fingers" of the hand that holds Dark Town. When the bike hits the end of the finger, it TAKES OFF into the void and KEEPS ON GOING.</context>
      <utterance>Stu? Stu? I think weve got this backwards. Your behavior...is disturbing me.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The REAPER vanishes. STU sits dejectedly on the edge of the curb.</context>
      <utterance>That's right. Run! And don't come back unless you've got my e-ticket!!</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, a multi-armed MESSENGER BOY in royal livery toodles past on a CHILD'S SCOOTER. He stops...</context>
      <utterance>Who am I kidding? I'm never gonna get out of here. I'll never see her again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MESSENGER BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STU looks up. Six arms reach into six pockets. Finally the MESSENGER finds an ENVELOPE and hands it over. Inside is an ENGRAVED INVITATION: YOU Are Invited to a</context>
      <utterance>Miley? Stu Miley?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAJAMA PARTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STU'S EYES widen with excitement as the MESSENGER scoots off.</context>
      <utterance>at HYPNOS' HIDEAWAY Penthouse Suite - 10 PM Sharp "If You Snooze, You Lose"</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hypnos! The god of nightmares! Do you know what this means, Monkeybone? He's finally going to hear my case. I'm going home!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens up the entertainment section of the daily newspaper.</context>
      <utterance>I think we can go another day without shaving. Long as you don't look like you're growing one of those stupid little goatees.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She refolds the paper and reaches into a bedside drawer for a paperback entitled The Book of Raunch. She pages through it for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, there's an article about the Monkeybone show. They've run that one episode about eight times now. Herb says it gets higher ratings every time...they're hoping you'll give 'em some new material soon...  Wanna hear another joke?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She whacks him on the arm with the book. No response at all.</context>
      <utterance>Okay...let me see...here we go. A plane full of explorers crashlands in New Guinea; they are captured by a cannibal tribe and taken to the chief's hut, where...wait a minute. I know this one...  You stinker! You swiped this joke for a Monkeybone strip!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sound of SOBBING interrupts her joke. She looks up and sees KIMMY standing in the doorway, red-eyed and crying.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Let's try again. Why did the pervert cross the road?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kimmy! What's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JULIE just stares at her for a beat or two, refusing to understand. Then it sinks in. Her hand goes to her mouth in horror and grief.</context>
      <utterance>This is hard for me, Julie...very hard...but it's been three months now, and...  I gave the order.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Of course, a party needs party animals - and the DARKTOWNERS on the scene are in fine fettle, working up a sweat on the dance floor. DJ SLEEPY ZZZ'S has three turntables spinning at once. As STU wanders through, he gets a big surprise. Reproductions of his old NIGHTMARE PAINTINGS are hanging on the walls! They've been turned into ONE-SHEETS for the coming attractions at the Morpheum.</context>
      <utterance>Now this...is livin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'call that art? Why, my three-year-old can paint better than that.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scowling at each other, the boys turn their backs and part ways. We follow MONKEYBONE to the wet bar, where he almost immediately bumps into a statuesque GORGON with a full head of writhing SNAKES.</context>
      <utterance>Like you'd know. You started out on the back of a napkin, you little...doodle.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Like the do. So tell me, are you a, uhh... natural snakehead?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORGON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only fifty dollars to find out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fifty dollars?! Bite me!</utterance>
   <speaker>GORGON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grins and shrugs: what the hell. As they head for a back room, the BARTENDER hands him a SNAKEBITE KIT. A look of apprehension crosses MONKEYBONE's face. But before he can change his mind, the GORGON'S HAND yanks him out of frame. STU, meanwhile, is crossing the dance floor, moving among glittering animal-people who DANCE in their bizarre, uninhibited way. A FIVE-LEGGED WOMAN - the bottom half of her body a big human HAND - SMILES at STU as he passes. He tries to talk to her, but she's dancing, and with five constantly moving legs it's difficult to get in close.</context>
      <utterance>You got it, big boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, have you seen Mr. Hypnos?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAND WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STU grins meekly, nods yes. She pulls him over to dance.</context>
      <utterance>Hyp? He was here a while ago. Aren't you Stu Miley? The nightmare guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAND WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JUMBO the ELEPHANT GOD is dancing in ungainly fashion nearby. His trunk swings out and hits one of the HAND WOMAN'S arms - which SNAPS OFF like marble statuary. Before she can let out a squeal, he does it again. Now she's armless - a regular Venus de Milo!</context>
      <utterance>I heard you were going to be here tonight. This is so cool!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAND WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You fat slob! Watch what you're doing!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you slap me? Go on, slap me!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAND WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leads him over to the sunken living room. Among the other guests, we see a CYCLOPS, a YETI, a BBQ PIG. A number of sofas and lounge chairs are arranged around a big crystal ORB in the center of the room. The ORB is where nightmares happen. Although the perspective shifts and the locales change abruptly, as in a movie, all the nightmares have a 3-D quality - as if they're taking place right here in the room with us!</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Stu. Let's go where the real fun is.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. Live feed, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAND WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STU grins in anticipation. He finds an empty chair and starts to sit down - but there's a SLUG with a MAN'S HEAD already in it!</context>
      <utterance>You bet. Hyp gets all the best stuff before it goes out to the theatres.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STU picks another seat. The HAND WOMAN sidles up alongside him.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAND WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shh! There's a new one just starting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That - that's me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYCLOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice shirt, dude!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this? Who's dreaming this??  Julie??</utterance>
   <speaker>YETI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, keep it down!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JUMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who invited this schmuck, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAND WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, it's my fault. I thought he was cooler than that.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But just then a hush falls over the room, and someone screams...</context>
      <utterance>Listen. Please. It's my girlfriend. I've gotta get a message to her...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shakes the bottle, pops the cork, and SPRAYS SPURTING BUBBLY at HYPNOS, the GIRLS, and everyone else within firing range!</context>
      <utterance>I knew I left it in there somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>HYPNOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Haw! I like a monkey with vision!</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hilarity all around. STU snatches MONKEYBONE off the bed -</context>
      <utterance>You said it, partner!</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd you get in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stu... It's a party.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Hypnos - sir - I needed to talk to you -</utterance>
   <speaker>HYPNOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute. Stu Miley, right? Boys and girls ...Mr. Stu Miley, in the house!  This is an honor. We see a lot of nightmares down here, but yours are like caviar, man. You da shits!!</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Hypnos, I saw a dream. My girlfriend was having it. She dreamed they were pulling the plug on me. She was watching me die.</utterance>
   <speaker>HYPNOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh huh. And?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A vaguely embarrassed look crosses HYPNOS's face. All the nearby DARKTOWNERS stare at their shoes, clear their throats.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I have to get a message to her. I have to let her know I'm okay. Until I can get out of here...</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a brusque gesture, HYPNOS sends the party girls packing. He slings one arm around STU's shoulder and pulls him aside.</context>
      <utterance>...which is actually what I wanted to talk to you about. See, I've been here three months -</utterance>
   <speaker>HYPNOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kid - didn't they tell you about this party?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me what?</utterance>
   <speaker>HYPNOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a special kind of party. A farewell party. Do you...get what I'm saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STU EXPLODES WITH JOY. He practically dances a jig.</context>
      <utterance>Farewell? You mean - you mean I'm -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I...I'm about to... Am I mistaken, or don't I get to... Is there some...</utterance>
   <speaker>HYPNOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MONKEYBONE's jaw drops. He slaps himself across the forehead.</context>
      <utterance>Y'see, Stu, as I understand it, you made this pact with your sister...no life support?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pact? Pact? NO LIFE SUPPORT??</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MONKEYBONE marches back and forth across the bed, wearing a dimwit's expression as he MOCKS STU in a singsongy voice...</context>
      <utterance>Well - yeah - but that doesn't...apply. It was different then. I was depressed. My life is great now. I'm in love!</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STU grabs the monkey and clamps a hand over his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Pull the plug! Pull the plug! Take my organs! I don't need 'em! I don't need no! Life support! I'm an idiot! Pull the pl--</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Besides, Julie wouldn't...she'd never...</utterance>
   <speaker>HYPNOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, Stu, Julie doesn't get to decide. That's why she was having the nightmare.  They're pulling the plug at nine AM.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In checking his watch, STU removes his hand from MONKEYBONE's mouth. The singsong resumes...</context>
      <utterance>Nine AM! But that's - twelve hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so dumb! I deserve to die -</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Hypnos, you run this place. I'm begging you. There's gotta be something I can do.</utterance>
   <speaker>HYPNOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stu, I like you personally, I admire your work, but I'm just the God of Sleep. This is Death's bailiwick.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you could talk to Death!</utterance>
   <speaker>HYPNOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HYP shuts up. Looks around the room, as if he's afraid of being overheard. Then he gestures to the boys to join him on the bed. They climb aboard eagerly. HYPNOS hits his remote...</context>
      <utterance>Me? Me, go crawling to Death? My friend, it will be a cold, cold day in Las Vegas, Nevada, before I go crawling to that piece of -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>HYPNOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now Death is not what you would call a people person, like me. Death is a putz - and I should know. I'm his little brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're Death's brother?</utterance>
   <speaker>HYPNOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah. Mr. By-the-book, Stick-Up-the-Ass, My- Way-or-the-Highway Death. Believe me - over the course of eternity, you get pretty damned tired of that schtick.  So I need a job. He sticks me in this broke-down amusement park, with a buncha animals to run it. I'm supposed to be grateful?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The penthouse is pretty swank, though.</utterance>
   <speaker>HYPNOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. I decorated it myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guys, I don't mean to be rude, but I only have eleven hours and fifty-three minutes to...</utterance>
   <speaker>HYPNOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, right. Cheating Death. There's one thing you might try. Only one guy in history ever pulled it off. Well, actually two. Actually, no, there was that other guy who...well, very few people have done it.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hyp, I'll do anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me too. And I mean anything. Ask the chicks in the back room.</utterance>
   <speaker>HYPNOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've seen those E-tickets, right? Well, what you gotta do...is go into the Land of Death... and steal an E-ticket right out from under Death's nose.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Land of Death. How do I get there?</utterance>
   <speaker>HYPNOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HYP hits the remote. The bed begins to ROTATE OUTWARD again.</context>
      <utterance>Kid, listen: that's all I'm saying. And you didn't hear it from me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HYPNOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've heard of a fate worse than Death? That's what's waiting for you if you screw up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine! Don't put yourself out. I'll go to the land of Death alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stu, you have my absolute confidence. - DEAD</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. Aren't you gonna talk me into it?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stunned, MONKEYBONE scurries along behind him, PLEADING.</context>
      <utterance>No. Goodbye. Thanks for nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta talk me into it. You'll screw up on your own. I mean, a guy's gotta have a sidekick. For moral support! Wisecracks - snappy banter -  It's the land of Death, Stu, the Land of Death! Don't go in there without your comedy relief!!</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. You can come.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LULU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She ditches FRED and throws her arms around the REAPER. Repulsed, he pushes her away, props her against the nearest wall - - and TOUCHES HER with one bony finger above the heart! It's like throwing a switch. Her body stiffens. Her EYES cross. Her TONGUE droops out of her mouth. She makes a noise like a DIAL TONE. The true horror of death is that it makes you look like a total idiot. The REAPER pulls a collapsible HAND TRUCK from beneath his shroud and starts maneuvering LULU onto it.</context>
      <utterance>Shay, you're kinda cute.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The REAPER ignores him. FRED holds up a cocktail glass.</context>
      <utterance>Say there. How 'bout one for the road?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The REAPER heaves a sigh and takes the cocktail glass. FRED grabs a pitcher filled with some luminescent tropical concoction... ...and POURS IT down the REAPER's front!</context>
      <utterance>Hold this for me, pally.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ooopsy daisy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The REAPER wrings out his shroud and grabs the hand truck. As he wheels LULU past the boys, MONKEYBONE pops up with a helpful hint:</context>
      <utterance>Is that what they call "death with dignity"?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STU claps a hand over MB's mouth as the REAPER turns down a hall.</context>
      <utterance>Two words for you, my friend: club soda.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's taking her to the land of Death, right? So all we've gotta do is...hitch a ride!  Stop shaking! I'll protect you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The REAPER approaches the GATES. He presses a remote-control BEEPER and the meshing teeth of the gates slide back far enough to let him pass through. STU realizes they've only got an instant to make their move. He DIVES through the gates at top speed. As soon as he's on the other side, he hears a nasty CLANG behind him... MONKEYBONE is caught - his body contorted like a pretzel, woven in and out among the meshing teeth! STU gives him a good hard YANK, and he slips out like a strand of fettuccine. They hear RUMBLING on the tracks outside. A CAR is arriving!</context>
      <utterance>Oh, sure. Mr. Action Hero! Why couldn't I be Arnold Schwarzenegger's figment?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd he go??</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's no trace of the REAPER - except for a rumpled shroud, a wristwatch, and a St. Christopher's medal on the floor of the car. The boys exchange a puzzled shrug. MONKEYBONE tries on the watch.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She points to a series of EASELS where HUTCH and ALICE have been tacking up EEG printouts, engram maps, etc.</context>
      <utterance>Six hours. That's when they pull the plug. That's how long we've got to wake him up.  Now these are Stu's old charts from five years ago, when he first came to the sleep lab...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The lower chart shows a JAGGED SPIKE virtually identical to the one on the upper chart. JULIE pauses for effect - then pulls on the edge of the lower chart, OPENING IT UP like a gatefold - The onlookers GASP. Opened accordion-style, the lower chart shows the SAME SPIKE recurring again and again, TEN TIMES OVER!</context>
      <utterance>...they show incredibly intense nightmare activity. The chart below is his new chart...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's stuck in a loop - a nightmare loop.  Anybody here know what Oneirix is?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARISSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure - it's an enzyme. The brain secretes it during violent dream activity...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's nightmare juice. Julie and I were on the team that learned to synthesize it. If those charts are right, Stu's swimming in the stuff.  Are you thinking we can decrease the levels?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I want to give him more. I want to give him a massive dose.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not going to stop his nightmare -</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The group exchanges nervous glances: it's risky. JULIE claps her hands:</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to stop the nightmare, Hutch. I want to crank it up. I want to take it right off the charts. I want to scare him awake.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the group swings into action, HUTCH pulls JULIE aside.</context>
      <utterance>All right! We have a plan. Let's move!</utterance>
   <speaker>HUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, Julie, even if this works - which it probably won't - that stuff is tricky. You don't know what it'll do to his brain.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'll it do if they pull the plug?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>REAPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Batch of souls - just back from Processing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH'S ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He unloads the crates in a corner of the room, where SCORES of crated souls are already piled up.</context>
      <utterance>Put them over there with the others.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH'S ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We can't see DEATH himself - just the back of a tall swivel chair. With much creaking, it rotates around - bringing us face-to-face with...</context>
      <utterance>Your Grimness? We have a new shipment - DEATH  Yeah, yeah, yeah... I'll get to it...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last Days of Pompeii...now there was a Great Moment in Death.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH'S ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DEATH, grumbling, digs into the box and pulls out another soul. His eyes light up. He clutches the sheet with trembling hands.</context>
      <utterance>If I may point out...it is 12:05...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sure enough, the doll on the sheet is Ol' Blue Eyes. DEATH digs in a desk drawer and pulls out a SHOEBOX DIORAMA...DINO and SAMMY standing at microphones, with a third, center mike conspicuously open.</context>
      <utterance>I can't believe - oh, man, I - SINATRA!! Do you know how long I've been waiting for this?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH'S ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grumpy, DEATH shoves FRANK, DEAN, and SAMMY back in the drawer.</context>
      <utterance>Make that 12:07, your bleakness...the dispatch team is waiting...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay, send 'em in. Jeez.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DEATH checks the name against the master list in his big ledger. He pulls out a document and puts his STAMP on it - the DEATH WARRANT. This he gives to the REAPER at the head of the line.</context>
      <utterance>Chakasandra Singh, New Delhi. Snakebite.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the line moves along, we notice an odd-looking REAPER nearing the desk. His gait is wobbly. His head bobs independently of the rest of his body. There's a big, luminescent STAIN on the front of his shroud.</context>
      <utterance>Mulrooney, Lavinia P., Dearborn, Michigan. Head crushed in a pants press.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the customer, okay? You're about to die. It's a big occasion. A formal occasion. And as you shuffle off this mortal coil, the last thing your eyes behold is a Grim Reaper covered with...  What the hell is that?? TWO VOICES come out from under the shroud at once:</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...What??</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well - whatever it is - you get that shroud to the dry cleaner ASAP! Now where were we?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Complications resulting from coma...</context>
      <utterance>Clarke P. Devereaux, San Francisco.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A loud chorus of "A WWWWW's" from the disappointed REAPERS. DEATH stamps the word "REPRIEVE" on Clarke's warrant. His ASSISTANT crosses the room. In the far wall is a steel-reinforced VAULT DOOR with a hydraulic wheel - the kind you see at banks. The ASSISTANT dials in a combination, turns the wheel, laboriously pulls the door open and STEPS INSIDE... ...returning, a moment later, with a priceless gold E-TICKET!! The UPPER HALF of the STAINED REAPER begins to gyrate wildly.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, wait. Says here he's supposed to recover.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ASSISTANT hands the REAPER a YELLOW MAILMAN'S POUCH containing the E-ticket. But before he can depart, the STAINED REAPER - aka STU and MONKEYBONE - jumps to the front of the line.</context>
      <utterance>Take this to Dark Town. Sad to say, he's gonna live another forty years.  Sorry. Nobody said this job would be easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DEATH is stunned by this unprecedented breach of protocol. The other REAPERS in the line are ABUZZ.</context>
      <utterance>Say, Death, just out of curiosity, could we maybe swap jobs with that other guy? See, we've been meaning to drop in on Dark Town - I mean I've been meaning to...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I beg your pardon?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got relatives there. I...EEP!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now what were you saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU/MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands and gestures toward a side room. The boys follow. The little HELLHOUND scampers out from behind the desk... ...and GRABS THE HEM OF THEIR SHROUD in its teeth! The boys keep on walking, but the shroud stays behind. Somehow they go three or four steps before they realize they've been exposed. DEATH jumps a foot in the air and SHRIEKS. PANDEMONIUM ERUPTS.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like to have a word with you in private.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a SCREECH, MONKEYBONE LEAPS into the air, BOUNDS OVER the heads and shoulders of the advancing REAPERS, and SNATCHES the yellow E-ticket pouch from the guy Death gave it to. He bounds over a table and into STU's arms, with the precious pouch in hand! DEATH lets out a great rattling BELLOW OF RAGE. His features begin to JITTER VIOLENTLY. HIS HEAD EXPLODES!!!</context>
      <utterance>HYPNOS! That little twerp! He's the one who put you up to this!</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nothing to lose at this point. With a CRASH, the boys DIVE THROUGH THE BIG WINDOW overlooking the trainyard! The headless DEATH gropes around blindly, waving to his ASSISTANT.</context>
      <utterance>Yowie.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ASSISTANT opens a cabinet containing a half-dozen identical HEADS. He pulls out a spare and screws it onto DEATH's neck.</context>
      <utterance>Head. HEAD!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MONKEYBONE fiddles with the ignition switch. A BLACK CLOUD OF EXHAUST belches violently from the rear of the bike, almost pitching them off their seat. The batwings start to flap faster... SPUT. BLAP. The engine BACKFIRES and DIES. STU fiddles with the switch, but it's no go.</context>
      <utterance>There's a thing here! There's a switch!</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stu...LOOK!</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LULU is still sitting in her little car at the edge of the tracks, eyes crossed, mouth agape. MONKEYBONE waves brightly. Then a mob of REAPERS appears on either side of LULU's car, swarming out onto the tracks! STU starts pedaling for his life. He makes for the TRAIN TUNNELS in the far wall of the station. ILLUMINATED SIGNS over the tunnels read: Calcutta...Hong Kong...Waco, TX ...and directly ahead... Dark Town!! By now they're well out onto the turnaround. STU pedals frantically, BOUNCING over tracks and ties. MONKEYBONE bites his fingernails down to the quick as he watches the column of REAPERS pursuing them onto the tracks.</context>
      <utterance>Isn't that Lulu?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STU jerks the handlebars HARD RIGHT and JUMPS THE TRACK he's on. He WINCES IN PAIN as the bike BOUNCES over a series of rails...</context>
      <utterance>Weren't we just here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd I tell you? You go to the Land of Death, wear a jockstrap!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the maximum safe dose?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Most we've ever used is half a CC.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five CC's.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You saved my life, Monkeybone. I never would've made it without you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Move it. We got exactly five minutes left.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just...now that I'm leaving, I feel like there's lots of things I haven't said. Who's gonna look out for you? Are you gonna be okay when I'm gone?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, don't you worry. I'll be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The gates slide open. STU passes through. But MONKEYBONE lingers behind a moment - just long enough for one of the SINGING SPHINXES to slip him a big, nasty BASEBALL BAT.</context>
      <utterance>You've been a hell of a figment, pal. I sure wish I could take you home with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awwww. Worried about my feelings, are you? Well, there's a new twist.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns - and MONKEYBONE MARK McGWIRES HIM upside the head! STU crumples in a heap...</context>
      <utterance>Don't joke around, little buddy. I mean it. I really do love y--</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laughing maniacally, MONKEYBONE STEALS the E-TICKET and goes RACING OFF</context>
      <utterance>Love you too. Boss.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STU blinks and looks about the room, disoriented. It could be because he's just come out of a coma after seven months. Or it could be because he's a MONKEY unaccustomed to hanging out in a human body.</context>
      <utterance>Oooie! That smarts!!! KIMMY sighs and FAINTS DEAD AWAY.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stu?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A BURST OF LAUGHTER from the others in the room. Weeping TEARS OF JOY, JULIE flings herself across the bed and hugs him tight. While JULIE is hugging him, STU is checking out his new fingers and toes, RUBBING his sparse patch of CHEST FUR. DOCTORS and NURSES look on in amazement from the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>Julie?... Hey, you are a looker.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a miracle. It's a miracle.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STU is almost oblivious to JULIE. He lifts up the sheet, sneaks a quick peek at his CROTCH, and grins delightedly. JULIE gives him another kiss, WHISPERS in his ear:</context>
      <utterance>Two more ticks of the clock...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What she doesn't know is that, although he still looks like STU, his body is now occupied by MONKEYBONE. Since he's now a hybrid character, man on the outside and monkey within, let's call him...</context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Thank you for coming back to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, I don't know about you guys, but I'm starving.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A MONGOL WARRIOR with a droopy mustache looks up at him.</context>
      <utterance>Who are y-- WHAT DO YOU WANT??</utterance>
   <speaker>GENGHIS KHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a moment STU realizes that the DARK FIGURES have almost no interest in him - instead, they've been grabbing at the half-eaten SNACKS that cascaded down onto his head. A long-haired SLAV - RASPUTIN - dives on a Hershey bar with only one bite out of it, but an oddly familiar FAT MAN gets there first. STU gapes at him...</context>
      <utterance>Dinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alfred Hitchcock??</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR ALLAN POE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A fat bastard, but damn quick on his feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYPHOID MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's how he keeps his girlish figure.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gotta move fast in this crowd, or you'll starve. Here you go, pal. Have some popcorn. He offers STU a box of popcorn soaked in Dr. Pepper.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this stuff?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They feed us the slops from the Morpheum Theatre. You hope for Jujubes, settle for goobers. - I'm Steve. Steve King.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Various OTHERS emerge from the shadows to shake STU's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Stephen King? What are you doing in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK THE RIPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Jack the Ripper.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYPHOID MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Typhoid Mary.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>RAT GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All hail the most glorious! Most eminent! Most esteemed all-powerful God of Sleep...his Royal Lassitude -</utterance>
   <speaker>HYPNOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As HYPNOS passes, the DUNGEON DWELLERS race up to the WALL OF BARS that separates the entry area from the dungeon proper.</context>
      <utterance>Enough, enough, I'm hung over.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYPHOID MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hyp! Did you bring me the cough medicine?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you remember the night light I asked for?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR ALLAN POE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>King, you pussy.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bite me, Poe! I hate waking up in the dark.</utterance>
   <speaker>HYPNOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Steve, maybe next time. And how's our new guest settling in - ?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>HYPNOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy, pal! I was coming to congratulate you. It ain't easy snatching one of those E-tickets. Steve here was the last guy to pull it off, and that musta been, what, 25 years ago...?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why'd you do it? What'd I ever do to you?!?</utterance>
   <speaker>HYPNOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's simple, Stu. We need nightmares - lots of 'em. So whenever we can swing it, we send a guy up to stimulate the flow...a nightmare maker! Like Steve here. Poe. Rasputin...we've been doing this all the way back to Atilla and Genghis Khan!</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But why me? Why'd you pick on me??</utterance>
   <speaker>HYPNOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The monkey, of course. It was his idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monkeybone...!?</utterance>
   <speaker>HYPNOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody wants to be a sidekick, Stu. So one day he comes to us - he's got a proposition. We help him get your body...in return he gives us all the nightmares we want.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're nuts! I'm a comic strip artist! What's he gonna do - draw really scary cartoons??</utterance>
   <speaker>HYPNOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STU's face goes white as he realizes the point of the master plan.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no, no, no. Y'see, Stu, as it happens, that girlfriend of yours figured out the chemical basis of bad dreams. And she just whipped up a big old batch of nightmare juice!</utterance>
   <speaker>HYPNOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HYPNOS marches off, chuckling. STU's head sinks into his hands.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, we're predicting a record box-office. It's like I always say...nightmares are your best entertainment!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>suffering. I love you so, I would never have... forgive me, Stu. Please forgive me.</context>
      <utterance>I just couldn't stand the thought of you</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He climbs out. KIMMY is so rattled that she smacks bumpers with the car parked in front of her. She PEELS OUT with the hand brake still on.</context>
      <utterance>Kimmy. Chill. We've still got a pact. If anything ever happens to you, I'll be right there to return the favor.  So drive carefully! From now on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STU-BONE grins insipidly. She kisses him, pulls him into a tight embrace - and then, overwhelmed by emotion, begins to SOB.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome home.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, baby, I can't believe you're back.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Home sweet home, huh? Actually, I was expecting something a little swankier. How much loot does old Stu rake in, anyway? She gives him an extremely puzzled look.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meaning me, of course. I'm referring to myself. You have to assume Monkeybone would be a pretty lucrative franchise...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes into the kitchen as STU-BONE plops onto the sofa. He spies a bowl of FRESH FRUIT on the coffee table and immediately tries to pick up a banana with his FOOT. But he can't. He's got shoes on. Frowning, he unties his shoe, peels off his sock. His bare foot is in the fruit bowl when JULIE returns from the kitchen with a TRAY holding a chocolate cake and the bottle of CHAMPAGNE Stu bought three months ago. The cake bears the message "WELCOME HOME - I LOVE YOU" in pink icing. She sits beside him with the goodies. He removes his foot from the bowl, crosses his legs, WIGGLES HIS TOES at her. She smiles uncertainly. Then she opens the bottle of champagne and pours two flutes full.</context>
      <utterance>Baby? Why don't you just...rest on the sofa for a minute. I'll be right back.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She finishes pouring, hands a flute to STU-BONE. His face is smeared with CAKE and ICING. He's scooped out a big fistful and crammed it right into his pie hole. He GRINS at her.</context>
      <utterance>Here's to a bottle...we should have opened... three months ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bitchin' good cake.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stu, are you...feeling okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're acting kind of...odd.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then: we hear TINY NAILS skittering across the hardwood floors at high speed. And BUSTER THE DOG races into the living room!</context>
      <utterance>In what way?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STU-BONE tenses instinctively. The dog is yipping, wagging his tail insanely at the sight of his long-lost master - until he gets just a little bit closer, and senses that something is very, very wrong. BUSTER sizes STU-BONE up and GROWLS. STU-BONE bares his teeth and HISSES. The dog LUNGES - and STU-BONE jumps up on the sofa!</context>
      <utterance>Buster! Look who's here!</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bends down, snatches up the cake, and CRADLES IT under one arm as he KICKS AT BUSTER from the sofa.</context>
      <utterance>Oh shit, the cake!</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The frazzled JULIE pours herself another jolt of champagne - a stiff one.</context>
      <utterance>Mine. Get back! MINE!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you watching?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tries to pass, but he grabs the belt of her robe and spins her around. He delicately unwraps the turban, then opens her robe and pulls it closed around the two of them. They kiss...</context>
      <utterance>Ohhh, nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure this is...medically advisable?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got a doctor on duty.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STU-BONE almost lets out a gasp of shock. What does she mean???</context>
      <utterance>Well. As long as it's okay with Monkeybone -</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STU-BONE does a take. The good news is, she doesn't suspect. The bad news is, he's apparently named after his creator's penis.</context>
      <utterance>- which it seems to be.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How was it? I don't recall.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they pass, BUSTER lets out a little growl of satisfaction from behind his gate. HOLD ON THE DOG's satisfied expression as STU-BONE loses his balance and topples down the stairs O.S.</context>
      <utterance>It was great, baby. Let's get you to the ER.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JACK THE RIPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was Jack the Haberdasher.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But how? Did you all have sidekicks? Figments? ...Monkeys??</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPHEN KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TYPHOID MARY runs past, GIGGLING, pursued by a huffing HITCHCOCK.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, I got screwed over by my own dog. Go through hell to get that E-ticket, and who winds up in my body? That darn Cujo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>RAT GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miley. You got a visitor.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the sight of STU behind bars, she breaks down CRYING.</context>
      <utterance>...Kitty?!?</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so sorry, Stu. I wanted to tell you what was going on. I really, really liked you.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kitty...my situation is really not important. The thing is, my girlfriend is now living with, and possibly engaged to, a demented monkey.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're such a beautiful man. Look at you - stuck in this place, and only thinking of her.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to me! Is there any way I can warn her what Monkeybone is up to??</utterance>
   <speaker>RAT GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The RAT GUARD pushes STU back with a prod. KITTY reaches out...</context>
      <utterance>Time's up! Break it up, you two.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she gazes at him, love struck, the overhead PANEL opens and a deluge of CRUD from the Morpheum lands directly on STU.</context>
      <utterance>No! Give me a moment. Just to look at him. Oh, Stu. Oh, my sweet, sweet Stu.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAT GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KITTY BAWLS inconsolably as the RAT GUARD leads her away.</context>
      <utterance>Feeding time!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Priceless! Priceless! This stuff just kills me!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm heading in to work, baby. Are you sure you'll be okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah. There's just one thing I don't get. "Monkeybone Creator Awakens from Coma" that's a big story! That's front page news! But I can't find a word of coverage in this stinkin' rag!  Hey. Don't I have a TV show?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They only made the one episode. They've shown it about nineteen times.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JULIE grins, plants a goodbye smooch on his forehead, and exits. He waits a minute, then reaches for the PHONE.</context>
      <utterance>I need a new PR guy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The front door opens. A stunned JULIE pushes her way inside...</context>
      <utterance>Yes, being in a coma taught Stu Miley a thing or two about life. Buckle your seat belts, for one. But seriously, Stu Miley is a different man today. I'm much homier.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And speaking of which, here's the light of my life, the pert and saucy Miss Julie McElroy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls her to his side for a photo op. FLASHBULBS go off.</context>
      <utterance>I had to park two blocks away. Is something -</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I took the liberty of calling a little press conference. We're on TV, so don't say "shit."  Shit! I said it. Shit! I said it again!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pauses for a photo op with MIKE CACHUELA and MIKE MITCHELL.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it's partly that he punctures all the phony pretensions of our modern society...and it's partly that he's a breathtakin', heartbreakin', rump-shakin' sex machine!  Ask these gentlemen here. They're an important cog in my media machine. They'll be doing six new episodes of the Monkeybone show under my personal supervision.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all synergy. The show synergizes the strip, which synergizes the merchandising, which synergizes the religion, which synergizes the Barbara Walters special; and then, baby, we are all in the United Empire of Monkeybonia.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HERB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tell you, he's ready to merchandise. We've gotta move quickly. Get the toy guys, the burger guys, the lunchbox guys -</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HERB holds up a finger. He's too busy talking. STU-BONE enters with the video crew in tow. JULIE somehow manages to sideline him.</context>
      <utterance>Herb...what in God's name -</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this about merchandising? You always hated merchandising!</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, baby, I do, but to look at it from another angle...there's a potload of money here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HYPNOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STU-BONE tries to speak. All that comes out is a slo-mo DRAWL.</context>
      <utterance>You two-bit simian stooge. WHAT THE HELL IS THIS? We didn't send you up here to shake your booty and chase broads. We sent you up to make nightmares!!</utterance>
   <speaker>HYPNOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He winds up - throws a ROUNDHOUSE PUNCH at STU-BONE'S FACE.</context>
      <utterance>Now find that nightmare juice and get to work. 'Cause you may be a free man during the day... but when you dream, your monkey ass is mine!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FEMALE BABOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and spots a SEDUCTIVE FEMALE BABOON who's confmed to a CAGE in the corner. The conversation continues in MONKEY TALK.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, handsome.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE BABOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you. Come here, good-looking.  Why don't you let me out of this cage?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I'd love to, baby, but...it'd put me in hot water.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A LIGHT goes on suddenly in the outside hallway! STU-BONE tries to dive for cover, but the FEMALE BABOON grabs him by the belt and pulls him against the cage. Startled, he drops the ONEIRIX BEAKER - which rolls out into the hall!</context>
      <utterance>Tell you what, angel. When you get out, give me a call...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stu? Is that you? Where did you go?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me? Nowhere. I was asleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Baby, don't lie. I know you went out.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls the covers back. He's still wearing his topcoat, shoes, socks, and shorts...but NO PANTS.</context>
      <utterance>Not me. Nope. You must've been dreaming.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're wearing a topcoat, Stu. - Where are your pants?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls the covers up to his chin. The two of them lie there in the dark staring up at the ceiling.</context>
      <utterance>Well, Miss Smarty, if I didn't go out, I wouldn't need any pants. Now would I?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>BURGER GOD REP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STU-BONE takes a bite out of his Monkeyburger - looks pleased at first - then begins PICKING something out of his teeth.</context>
      <utterance>As you know, Burger God has 1700 outlets nationwide...we're prepared to back a major TV buy to launch our Mega Monkey Meal.  Go ahead. Try a bite.</utterance>
   <speaker>HERB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it's a pig hair.  How much is McDonald's offering?</utterance>
   <speaker>HERB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STU-BONE immediately signs the contract and shakes hands with the BURGER GOD REP. HERB consults his agenda.</context>
      <utterance>Less.</utterance>
   <speaker>HERB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, here's something. The city zoo is kicking off a fund-raising campaign. They wonder if you'd be willing to appear at a benefit.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much?</utterance>
   <speaker>HERB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>probably get People and Entertainment Tonight to cover it.</context>
      <utterance>Well, nothing. It's a benefit. But we could</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>charitable. Brilliant!!</context>
      <utterance>I get it. We could give the public the impression that we were doing something...</utterance>
   <speaker>HERB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The TOY REP sets a LOCKBOX on the table. A stencil on the box reads "TOP SECRET." He pulls out a key and opens it to reveal... ...a tuxedoed, collector's-edition MONKEYBONE DOLL lying on a bed of CRUSHED PURPLE VELVET. He carefully removes the treasure from its chest. Its right hand is hinged. The doll's thumb is UP ITS REAR.</context>
      <utterance>And last...you remember Bill here, from the Bazoom Toy Company? He's got a little something I think you'll like.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAZOOM TOY REP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STU-BONE stares at the doll - cautiously yanks its thumb out. We go to SLO-MO as the rising arm causes a NOXIOUS AEROSOL SPRAY to shoot out of Monkeybone's ass! And we STAY in slo-mo as STU-BONE stares at the doll in wonderment and awe...a man in looooove. Still in slo-mo, the EXECS crack up, gag, hold their noses at the awful stank of it. STU-BONE is the only one not laughing. He reaches out to touch the doll - to fondle it adoringly - - and suddenly we're back to REAL-TIME.</context>
      <utterance>It's a prototype. Code name "Little Jack Horner." Go on - pull out his thumb.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAZOOM TOY REP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know kids - they love anything gross...</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kids? Kids?! This is a work of genius. This is art. This is the answer to all my prayers!  Say - just a technical question - could you fill these babies up with a particulate solution of one part chemical enzyme to ten parts water?</utterance>
   <speaker>BAZOOM EXEC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well - I guess...</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He breaks into RIOTOUS LAUGHTER and begins blasting monkeyfarts at HERB and the EXECS, who dive for cover under the conference table.</context>
      <utterance>Aww righhhhht!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So here's my idea. We do a giveaway at the zoo benefit. We get a big piata. We fill it with Monkeybone dolls - hundreds of 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>HERB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A piata. That's a great idea!</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a big grin, he pantomimes sticking a thumb up his ass, in obvious imitation of the doll, and then gives the thumbs-up sign. The unnerved EXECS gape at him as he goes back inside - he's developed an odd, loping gait, and his arms swing outward in wide arcs as he walks.</context>
      <utterance>You guys don't know it, but you just saved my ass!</utterance>
   <speaker>BURGER GOD EXEC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Interesting fellow.</utterance>
   <speaker>HERB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Head trauma.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The thing is, I'm responsible for the way he's acting. It's the nightmare juice. It's got to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Julie, that stuff probably saved his life.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't explain this, Alice, but I'm not so sure it did. It's as if...he's not Stu any more. The Stu I love is gone!  He spends all his time in the garage. He says he's...autographing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JULIE lifts the curtain - and sees STU-BONE in his gas mask, bent over in a weird crab like stance, chasing BUSTER around the yard with the Monkeybone doll. JULIE doesn't seem especially surprised - but ALICE's mouth falls open.</context>
      <utterance>Listen. Let's bring him in for some tests. I guarantee you're overreacting.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, no, I don't think I'm overreacting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HYPNOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A FELINE BEAUTY embraces him from behind, pulls him onto the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Dog dreams!! That stinkin' monkey. I can't believe it. We give him a body, and he sends us ...dogs.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She draws ONE SHARP CLAW lightly down his chest. He gives her a now- you're-talkin' grin and hits a switch - causing the big circular bed to ROTATE off the dance floor and into the boudoir. As it turns, we see KITTY'S PAW closing discreetly around a KEY CHAIN on the nightstand...</context>
      <utterance>Let's not think about dogs. Let's think about pussycats. Meeowwwwwwrrrr....</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Glancing back at the GUARDS, she pulls a KEY from her cleavage.</context>
      <utterance>Shh! You'll need it when you're traveling.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't ask where I got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't do this! You'll get in trouble!</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the only true-hearted man I ever met. You find a way back to that girl of yours and make her happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How am I gonna get past the guards?</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(loudly)</context>
      <utterance>I'll worry about the guards.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KITTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go. Just go.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks up at him, feline eyes aglow. There's a three-foot-long RODENT'S TAIL dangling out of her mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Kitty, I'll never forget you for th--</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He races off as KITTY resumes her feast. The sound of fighting has roused the other DUNGEON DWELLERS, and when they realize the dungeon door is open they come rushing out en masse. Then the PANEL opens. They hear FOOD raining down behind them. HITCHCOCK is the first to turn back - then STEPHEN KING - then ATILLA. A moment later they're back to their old habits, climbing over one another to get at a half-empty box of Raisinets.</context>
      <utterance>I'll really...never...forget you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"4/17: Subject, when unaware of observation, prefers to hold eating utensils...with feet. Successfully carves turkey roll holding eating utensils...with feet."</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They had a case like that at Johns Hopkins. Wires got crossed between hands and feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARISSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great lead. I'll try and find it on the net.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DEAD SILENCE from the mortified group. They never had a case like that at Johns Hopkins. JULIE somehow keeps a stiff upper lip - deeply embarrassed for STU, but a scientist nonetheless.</context>
      <utterance>"4/18: Subject climbs backyard tree...to perform elimination. When confronted with product... blames it on family dog."</utterance>
   <speaker>HUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others all GLOWER at HUTCH for this egregious display of bad taste.</context>
      <utterance>Seems perfectly obvious. He's been possessed by a monkey!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HERB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're really gonna pop the question?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got the ring. Got the airline tickets. Soon as they break that piata, we'll grab a cab - and it's off to the land of palm trees and coconuts.</utterance>
   <speaker>HERB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe you. You used to hate being the center of attention. Now you're proposing, in public, at a benefit.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HERB wonders if this is a joke, decides it is, and forces a chuckle.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I was thinking...I mean, I'm a celebrity now, do I really want to get married? But on the other hand, if you're married, they can't testify against you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Nightmare Juice! It's gone! Somebody switched it for a beaker of grape Kool-Aid!!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes move to the WINDOW - to STU-BONE out by the garage.</context>
      <utterance>Kool-Aid!? But who'd would want to -</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Call the police. I'll be right over.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The technical name is Oneirix. It's an enzyme. It's present in the brains of -</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, yeah...Nightmare juice.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE II</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And there's been no sign of a break-in?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The janitor found a pair of torn-up pants. It was the same night the monkey tipped her cage over. Remember that, Julie?</context>
      <utterance>Holy shit...the pants.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...I remember it vividly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The party he's addressing is STU - who's stretched out horizontally, strapped to a medieval TORTURE RACK, with a whole posse of GRIM REAPERS standing guard around him.</context>
      <utterance>Now, if I may ask - what kind of idiot sneaks into the Land of Death twice?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're mad at me. Great. You have every right to be. But we're both mad at Dark Town. We're both mad at Hypnos.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, sure. Now you're gonna tell me it was all his idea. You were completely innocent -</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not going to tell you that. I wanted that E- ticket. I wanted it so bad I'd stare you right in the face to get it - and I'd do the same again.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why??</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>should've - I just want to tell her I love her.</context>
      <utterance>I have a girl up there. And I never - I</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a simple man. I'm just doing my job. I enjoy my job. Why does everyone want to make it difficult for me? Stealing tickets, switching bodies...it is so irresponsible.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Death, I'm trying to make things right. Take my soul. Turn me into a paper doll. But give me just one lousy hour.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DEATH gestures for the REAPERS to unshackle STU.</context>
      <utterance>Well - you'd need a body.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it wasn't for that comic strip of yours, I wouldn't be doing this. But a good chuckle is darned hard to come by.  That one where Monkeybone stole the soap cake out of the urinal - I thought I would die.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coming from you, that's quite a compliment.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>De nada. Now, come here...bend over...before I change my mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DEATH rears back and KICKS HIM, full-force, SMACK IN THE ASS. The supernatural might of the blow sends STU ROCKETING UPWARD THROUGH THE</context>
      <utterance>Bend over?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SURGEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCREAMS ALL AROUND as the ORGAN DONOR sits BOLT UPRIGHT! The startled SURGEON drops the kidney back into place.</context>
      <utterance>Okay...detaching the left kidney...</utterance>
   <speaker>ORGAN DONOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the - who the hell am I??</utterance>
   <speaker>SURGEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're an organ donor!</utterance>
   <speaker>ORGAN DONOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I dead?!?</utterance>
   <speaker>SURGEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The chute didn't open. We kind of assumed -</utterance>
   <speaker>ORGAN DONOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ORGAN DONOR grabs a lab coat from a nearby rack and races out. (And since STU is temporarily occupying the DONOR's body, we will henceforth refer to him as O.D. STU.)</context>
      <utterance>I need this body. Just for a few minutes. I'll bring it back, okay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Might have someone take a look at that.</utterance>
   <speaker>O.D. STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The DOCTORS move on. O.D. STU spots a JANITOR'S CART with a roll of DUCT TAPE on one shelf. He WRAPS IT TIGHTLY around his midsection to keep his innards from falling out. Then he runs for it. Now the TEAM OF SURGEONS rounds the corner in hot pursuit. The lead SURGEON spots O.D. STU at the end of the corridor and takes off after him. But he SLIPS on the PANCREAS and goes sprawling! The pancreas goes flying down the hall, where it gets SQUASHED in rapid succession by a GURNEY and by a little old lady's MOTORIZED WHEELCHAIR. When the SURGEONS retrieve it, it's a hunk of pulp.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Yeah. Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAD SURGEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it can still be saved. Put it on ice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever he's done, I'm responsible for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARISSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not true, Julie. It's not true.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is not about your guilt, Julie. There could be innocent people in danger.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARISSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not the same guy. He's not your Stu.  I didn't want to tell you this, but the other day he pinched me on the butt.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't want to tell you this, but the other day he tried to mount me from behind! Look, you have to tell the police.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All of a sudden, they hear SHOUTS and LAUGHTER from the area of the reptile house. In the distance, ZOO SECURITY GUARDS are chasing a NAKED MAN through the crowds of formally-dressed partygoers.</context>
      <utterance>Tell them what? I don't know anything concrete. All I have is a feeling.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARISSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God, we've got a flasher.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The GUARDS catch hold of HERB and drag him away past JULIE, ALICE, and CLARISSA. He doesn't recognize any of them. He's PSYCHOTIC:</context>
      <utterance>That...that's Herb!</utterance>
   <speaker>HERB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>CLOTHES! Beware of clothes. They're working together. All of them. Shirts...pants...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As emcee I want to thank you all for joining us at this swingin' bash...it's a special night for the birds, and the lions, and the monkeys, but it's also a special night for -  - this monkey. And it's special because of a very special lady. Her name is -  Julie McElroy. Just kiddin', Julie. Stand up. JULIE stands reluctantly. The CROWD APPLAUDS.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'd like to do a special number...especially for you. A DISCO BALL lowers. STU-BONE turns to welcome a group of BACKUP SOUL SINGERS who are just joining the band on stage. The TENT begins to ROCK with a throbbing beat. And STU-BONE launches into a wild-eyed, hip-shaking parody of Mick Jagger singing the Rolling Stones' "MONKEY MAN"! As he sings, STU-BONE gyrates over toward JULIE, bumping and grinding like the cartoon-monkey sex machine he is. He waves his mike to the crowd, urging everyone to join in. JULIE gasps in disbelief, but the crowd is eating it up - clapping and singing along with STU-BONE. He gestures for pretty women to join him out on the floor. He opens his shirt at the neck, exposing a hitherto unseen plenitude of chest hair. He pulls out a hanky to mop his brow and tosses it to the crowd. He wipes his armpits with a second hanky and tosses it to the crowd. He blows his nose into a third and tosses it to the crowd. Then he JUMPS UP ON THE TABLES and shakes his booty wildly, strutting in and out among the dessert plates. If the real Jagger could see him, he would creep home a sad and broken man. For the big finale, he jumps off the table and SLIDES ACROSS THE FLOOR to JULIE'S table - arriving ON HIS KNEES.</context>
      <utterance>And to make this special night extra-special,</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls out a RING BOX and hands it to the beet-red JULIE. The crowd lets out a collective GASP - followed by WILD APPLAUSE. She stares down at the ring - a big vulgar sparkler. She can't speak.</context>
      <utterance>I am just a Monkey Man! I'm glad you are a monkey...woman...too.  How about it, Julie?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll hop a plane tonight. An island ceremony. An Abba Dabba honeymoon!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It looks so...new.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is new. Why wouldn't it be new?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But the heirloom ring. Your grandmother's ring...</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No reply. She's taking a long time to say yes. The audience is muttering.</context>
      <utterance>Heirloom? Huh? You want a used ring - ?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly a GORE-STAINED FIGURE bursts into the tent.</context>
      <utterance>Ju-leeee... Operators are standing by... Offer expires at midnight, December 31...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, the nuts are out tonight. What'd that creep call you - ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>- which STU-BONE never does. Someone in the crowd yells...</context>
      <utterance>He called me "Doc."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The GUARD points to an ANIMAL CONTROL VAN. JULIE sees O.D. STU peering out through a small barred panel. Their eyes meet...</context>
      <utterance>Please. Where did you take that man...?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you? Why did you say those things?</utterance>
   <speaker>O.D. STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JULIE digests this, nods professionally, and turns to walk away.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Doc, it's all a mixup. We were in the land of death. He stole my e-ticket. That's how he got my body, see? All they had left for me was this corpse!</utterance>
   <speaker>O.D. STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This stops JULIE cold. Her spine is tingling. She turns slowly, a single tear rolling down her cheek. And then...</context>
      <utterance>Don't walk away, Doc! He's only here to give people nightmares!  Doc! Please! Don't you remember the dream? They were pulling the plug - I called out to you - and you heard me. Remember?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stu...how?</utterance>
   <speaker>O.D. STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THROUGH THE BARS he hands her the little box containing Grandma's antique ring.</context>
      <utterance>I had to come back, Julie. I had to give you this.</utterance>
   <speaker>O.D. STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slips the ring on her finger - looks up at O.D. STU with TEARS WELLING in her eyes. He makes an odd SNORKELING kind of noise.</context>
      <utterance>I meant to give it to you before. The night we crashed. I was so happy, Julie, I...try to remember me like that, okay? Not like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>O.D. STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JULIE TURNS. The two DETECTIVES we saw in the sleep lab have just arrived at the gate, and ALICE and CLARISSA are leading them over.</context>
      <utterance>I'm crying too. I just don't have any tears. I'm all dried up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Detective, please let this man out of the van.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The next contestant is a GORGEOUS WOMAN. He blindfolds her and embraces her from behind to help her with her grip on the bat.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, folks, it's piata time - you know the rules - five bucks a pop - and remember, it's all for the benefit of our friends the animals!  Oooooh! This one's on me!</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly he notices the COPS marching up with JULIE, O.D. STU and co. in tow. He freezes, terrified - BACKS AWAY from the BABE - - and catches a BAT IN THE FACE. Several people rush up to help him as the COPS consult with the BENEFIT ORGANIZERS...</context>
      <utterance>Choke up, baby. That's right. Choke up!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>O.D. STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STU-BONE bends over - jerks and twitches - becoming more SIMIAN by the moment as O.D. STU approaches.</context>
      <utterance>I mean it this time. Back in the pack.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stu...I can explain...I was sick of being a figment, see? It's awful being a figment. It's degrading! And I never really wanted to give people nightmares. I just told 'em that so they'd help me get a body.</utterance>
   <speaker>O.D. STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah - my body. Back in the pack, you simian shitbird! The COPS are tres confused by all this -</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>- but JULIE holds them back so the scene can play itself out. Now STU- BONE is doing a weird little monkey dance - PLAYING UP to the puzzled crowd, who laugh and snicker, wondering what to make of all this.</context>
      <utterance>Ma'am, can you give me some idea of what's going on here?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU-BONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns suddenly - GRABS THE BAT from the puzzled BABE -</context>
      <utterance>Laugh, damn you...laugh at the sidekick...the happy little monkey. He doesn't have any feelings. He's just a figment of your immagination!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dress up when I want to make an impression. - So how'd it go?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine, thanks. Saw my girl, said goodbye, everything's gonna be okay.  I guess I'm yours now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONKEYBONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DEATH lets out a MIGHTY ROAR and CLAPS HIS GREAT METAL HANDS together. Man and monkey are surely squished. But when DEATH opens his hands, STU is still there, cupped safely in his palms.</context>
      <utterance>Death, I'd like to point out that none of this was my fault. The roots of this tragedy go back to a callous, uncaring society that -</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. Where's Monkeybone?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No offense, Stu, but on your own you're kinda vanilla. I didn't want to send you back without him.</context>
      <utterance>Back in your head, where he belongs.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Back? You're sending me back?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's irregular, but...I just love that strip of yours. I figure I'll take the "Family Circus" guy instead.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Death! Thank you!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sends STU ROCKETING UPWARD INTO THE STRATOSPHERE with a single flick of his finger. Then he turns...</context>
      <utterance>Thank me next time you see me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A BUNCH OF FRIGHTENED DARKTOWNERS pitch the quivering satyr out into the middle of the town square.</context>
      <utterance>Ohhhh, Hypnos??</utterance>
   <speaker>HYPNOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up tremulously. A GIANT SHADOW falls across him...followed by a</context>
      <utterance>Death! So nice to see you. I can explain -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SURGEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me. We lost a corpse - we saw him heading this way...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SURGEON pulls the sheet off CORPSE 1 - aka O.D. STU.</context>
      <utterance>I got a couple of fresh ones in the back. Help yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>SURGEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SECOND CORPSE sits up abruptly. His sheet falls away, revealing STU ...the real STU...now back in his own body! The SURGEON and his TEAM run away from the ambulance SHRIEKING.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be. It's him all right. Still dead...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls her close and kisses her long and hard, quelling all doubts.</context>
      <utterance>Is it you? Is it really you this time?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Stu. Tell me I'm not dreaming.</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They wander off, arm in arm. STU TUGS at the seat of his pants.</context>
      <utterance>Baby...you're asking the wrong guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>STU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He DOES A TAKE as he realizes what he's just said - but JULIE smiles, and he shrugs it off. Johnny Mercer's "DREAM" comes up underneath as the reunited lovers walk off into the moonlight, and we</context>
      <utterance>My tail itches.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
