<movie id="399" title="Mr Brooks">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you fight it so hard, Earl?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Courage to change the things I can...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Our view moves back up to the Woman's breasts.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, you've been a good boy for a long time, you deserve a little fun.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picking up speed against the hunger in his head:</context>
      <utterance>... and Wisdom to know the difference.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>From far away comes the sound of applause.</context>
      <utterance>Living one day at a time, Enjoying one moment at a time, Accepting hardship as a pathway to peace...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Taking, as He did, this sinful world as it is, not as I would have it. Trusting that He will make all things right if I surrender to His will. That I may be reasonably happy in this life, And supremely happy with Him forever in the next. Amen. The Man at the microphone raises his arms to quiet the Audience.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone laughs.</context>
      <utterance>I could go on and on about what a great guy Earl is, how he cuts his toe nails...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks kisses Emma, stands and after accepting congratulations along the way, arrives at the podium.</context>
      <utterance>... how he gives freely of his time and money, but let's get Earl up here to speak for himself. Ladies and Gentlemen, I give you a businessman, a philanthropist, a great friend and the Evanston Chamber of Commerce Man of the Year... Mr. Earl Brooks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Applause and laughter from the Audience.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you all very much. The first thing I would like to say is... I don't even know how I cut my toe nails.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty years ago when I started the Brooks Box Factory I never dreamed I would one day be standing here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>EMMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks is only listening to his Wife with one ear and underneath what she is saying we can barely hear:</context>
      <utterance>You could see her nipples. At her age she should keep those things hidden.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God grant me the Serenity to accept...</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The only thing that would have made this evening more perfect is if Jane had been here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She called. She has mid terms coming up.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's dropping out, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll see.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks doesn't rise to the bait.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing she does is wrong to you, is it?...</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she continues, we look at Mr. Brooks and Emma's voice fades to a murmur.</context>
      <utterance>Well she missed a good party...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Earl, give yourself a break, you know you want to do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tonight's the perfect night.</context>
      <utterance>You're the fucking 'man of the year', you deserve it. It's not like it's not set up. You already know how to by-pass the alarm, you know how to pick the locks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Marshall, I said 'no'!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Emma feels Mr. Brooks's distance.</context>
      <utterance>I heard you, Earl, but you don't mean 'no'.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks pulls himself back into the moment.</context>
      <utterance>What's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were frowning.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was thinking of what I didn't say in the speech.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They laughed, they were touched, I don't think anyone felt left out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They have their dance class tonight. What if we go by and just look at them. There's no harm in just having a look.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No means 'no', Marshall.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please... pretty please.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The food tonight was very good, but I wasn't crazy about the dessert. Would you like to stop somewhere and get something sweet?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>EMMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Labradors are supposed to be nice, or maybe a rescue mutt...</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Pound's a pretty sad place; if you want me to, I'll go with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks turns his attention back to the Dancers and again Emma's voice fades to a murmur. Both Mr. Brooks and Marshall who is seated on the other side of Emma are focused on one particular COUPLE. The Man and Woman are not great dancers nor are they especially attractive, but Mr. Brooks and Marshall are fascinated with them. Marshall leans forward and looking slyly around Emma at Mr. Brooks:</context>
      <utterance>There's an Irish Lab I read about, and I think the breeder is...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Emma is putting on her sleep-wear. Mr. Brooks steps into the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>... I can't do this, I can't do this, I can't do this, please don't let me do this, God grant me the Serenity to accept the things I cannot change... In the DRESSING AREA</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to stay up a while, maybe go to the studio and play with some glazes.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks comes forward, puts his arms around Emma and hugs her, then easing back, kisses her.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, I'm going to read. If I'm not awake, wake me when you come back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you were wonderful tonight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Lordy, Earl my boy, I've missed this! We are going to have so much fun!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Understand me?! The very last time!</context>
      <utterance>This is the last time, Marshall.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>piece of shit. I want to see what they're doing. Mr. Brooks's spine stiffens and he's going forward again. Entering a HALLWAY, he reaches into his jacket. When his hand reappears it's inside a Ziplock bag, his fingers around the butt of a silenced pistol. He brings the hand and bag to his mouth and tightens the Ziplock against his wrist. The two Men arrive at a door that's slightly ajar. Behind it the sounds of the love-making are becoming more intense. Mr. Brooks nudges the door with his foot. It opens enough for he and Marshall to see the Couple inside. The Man and Woman from the Arthur Murray dance class are naked on the bed. As much as Mr. Brooks hates himself for it he loves watching. He can now hear his heart beating in his ears. He begins to breathe in unison with the Couple, but his expression is distant almost clinical. When the Couple climaxes, when they come, Mr. Brooks's face goes blank. On the bed the Woman rolls off her Partner and the two of them lie there basking in the afterglow. Behind them Mr. Brooks pushes the door fully open and slips into the ROOM. They don't know he's there until he speaks.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you dare quit on me, you</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both the Man and Woman jump with surprise and look. The Woman screams and scrabbles at the sheet to cover herself.</context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then he sees the gun.</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, man, don't...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These pigs liked to fuck with the blinds open, you should have known that, Earl. This is a big mistake for you, Earl.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Almost like I want to get caught, huh, Marshall?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, don't fucking do that. I don't think either of us would enjoy spending the rest of our lives in jail or a lethal injection.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As we look closer at the Photographs we realize by a smear of blood here and there and the distortion of the limbs that these tableaus were arranged after the Couple was killed. One by one, Mr. Brooks picks up his souvenirs. He lingers over the last image; and from where he's sitting on the edge of a table:</context>
      <utterance>Please forgive me... Please forgive me...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reluctantly Mr. Brooks throws the Polaroids into the fire of the kiln.</context>
      <utterance>Don't even think about it. You know the rules.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaves. In the kiln, the Polaroids burst into flame.</context>
      <utterance>Now go up and make love to your beautiful wife.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>OLDER DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where the fuck is Atwood?!</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I called ten minutes ago, they said she was on her way.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A Uniformed Cop standing guard at the tape:</context>
      <utterance>She doesn't get here soon, these bodies won't even be dead anymore?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You looking for the lady Cop?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's here. She's been sitting in her car right over there for the last half hour.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Christ.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she gets out of the car, the Men notice the bandages on her wrists and falling into step with her on the way to the house.</context>
      <utterance>I really hated yesterday, Snyder, and then today came along.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode>OLDER DETECTIVE</mode>
      <context>Atwood holds up her hands to reveal the extent of the bandages.</context>
      <utterance>What happened to your wrists?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Young Detective laughs. Atwood whirls on him.</context>
      <utterance>I tried to commit suicide.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's so funny?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Atwood sticks her finger into the Young Detective's chest.</context>
      <utterance>Eh... I... I don't know, I heard it was because you were drunk and got into a fight with a fish tank.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you gonna believe? Me or the fucking fish?!</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eh... you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Atwood turns and leaves the Men.</context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's nuts!</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They catch up to Atwood who has squatted down to examine the lock on the front door.</context>
      <utterance>And rich.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are some scratches in the side door cylinder. Other than that no signs of forced entry. The alarm was armed and we even had to cut the security chains to get in.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She enters the house.</context>
      <utterance>This guy hasn't been active for over two years...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Detective Snyder points her down the Hall toward the Bedroom and follows.</context>
      <utterance>... we think he's either dead or in jail on some other charge. This is probably a copycat.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why we called you. You're the God that tells us peons if we have a simple murder here or something we can dump on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Atwood arrives in the doorway of the BEDROOM where the murders took place and stops. The Bodies of the dance Couple are now on the floor. The Man is propped up against the bed in a sitting position. The Woman has her head in the Man's crotch. Almost like Mr. Brooks, Atwood's nostrils flare, but in Atwood's case it's not the scent of death that arouses her but it's like she's searching for the scent of her prey. In a glance she memorizes the Room, then steps inside.</context>
      <utterance>Bite yourself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He always rearranges the bodies, but this is out of character. He has never left them in such a crude position. Usually it's more romantic with their arms around each other, kissing, their mouths open, their tongues touching.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So we have a copycat?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Snyder points to a bare space of wall above the bed. Atwood leans in to look at two bloody 'thumbprints' placed side by side.</context>
      <utterance>Where are the thumbprints?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One his one hers?</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what it looks like.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There are two holes gouged into the plaster of the wall.</context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Atwood unfolds and after another look around the room goes to the window and cracks the curtains. There's the four story Apartment Building across the alley, its windows staring down at her.</context>
      <utterance>The bullets went completely through the victims. The killer recovered the slugs.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were these open or closed when you got here?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Atwood tries the cord, the curtains are stuck.</context>
      <utterance>Closed.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She returns her attention to the murder scene.</context>
      <utterance>Hmm...</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It has never been revealed to the public that the Thumbprint Killer retrieves the slugs.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So this one's yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She doubles back and cracks the curtains for another look at the four story Apartment Building.</context>
      <utterance>I don't fucking need this.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you checked the tenants of that building?</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Atwood nods and turns back to the bodies.</context>
      <utterance>Only a few of them are home, they say they didn't see anything. We checked the whole neighborhood, so far nobody saw a thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches down and runs a hand over the carpet.</context>
      <utterance>Leaving them like this, he must have been angry at them for some reason.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where would they keep their vacuum cleaner. A puzzled Snyder follows her out of the room.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll bet you a hundred bucks, Snyder, there is no bag in that vacuum cleaner.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Atwood unzips the cover. There is no bag inside.</context>
      <utterance>I have no idea what you're looking for.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He vacuumed the house and took the bag.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, shit. That is scary smart.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He releases her. She hops down and directs her attention at the four story Apartment Building.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A MAN comes out from behind the next door fence and strides purposefully toward them.</context>
      <utterance>Our best hope is if someone in there saw something.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Detective Tracy Atwood?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She accepts the official looking document being offered.</context>
      <utterance>This is for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have been served.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You fucking asshole!! I'm in the middle of a fucking murder investigation!!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, take it easy lady, I'm just the messenger.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamit!!</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My soon to be ex-husband's scumbag lawyer is trying to show me how painful she can make my life if I don't give them what they want.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is not the Doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This one is my stupid mistake.</context>
      <utterance>The doctor was a couple years ago.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A WOMAN comes forward.</context>
      <utterance>Are there any new members?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rejoins the circle. Mr. Brooks separates himself from the Others.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, my name is Vaughn and I'm an alcoholic.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When he rejoins the circle, Marshall is there to greet him.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, my name is Earl and I'm an addict.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're such a fucking hypocrite. If you were honest you would step out there and say 'Hi, I'm Earl. I killed two people last night and I really got off on it, but I need your help to be cured.'</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm different Marshall, I won't argue that with you. This is the only place that has ever helped me be normal and I've been straight up until last night for the past two years. I'm not going to kill again and I'm not going to quit coming here because it upsets you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah but for the next 29 days you're going to have to step out there and say 'Hi, I'm Earl, I'm an addict.' And everybody will know you fell off the wagon. Don't you feel stupid doing that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I feel good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Mr. Brooks talks the Men pass the box between them.</context>
      <utterance>This is not the top of the line or the bottom, but for the money we're talking about this is the quality I can provide you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your packaging is the first impression your customers will have of your product...</utterance>
   <speaker>PA SYSTEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A surprised Mr. Brooks grabs a quick look at the PA Speaker, then continues.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Brooks, your daughter is waiting for you in your office.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... We'd love to work you with on the design. It's fun to challenge our machines. If you check around, you'll find we're not the cheapest, but we are the best.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sunday, did Jane call and say she was coming?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUNDAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would have given you that message, Mr. Brooks. She has boxes and suitcases downstairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold my calls.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks kisses Jane on the forehead and goes to sit at his desk.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Daddy, please don't be angry with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can guess what you've done, but why don't you tell me and then I'll decide.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dropped out of school.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Have you told your mother this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I wanted to speak to you first.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll have to tell her, I'm not going to do that for you, and then together the three of us will decide where to go from here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>College is a waste of time for me.</context>
      <utterance>I've thought a lot about this, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know how you know that half way through your Freshman year, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sitting on the couch:</context>
      <utterance>You didn't go to college, Dad, and you're successful. I want to come and work for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's not telling you everything, she's hiding something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.  I'm not hiring right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just listen to me. What would happen to the business if, God forbid, something happened to you? Mom would probably have to sell to strangers. I'm willing to start at the bottom, you can treat me as a regular employee, I want to learn everything there is to know about running the box business, and then when the time comes, the business would stay in the family.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's sweet, but you're talking about emotion, not business. In fact your mother and I came very close to selling out last year.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we had been offered a little more money, and they may come back to us, we will sell.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a knock on the door.</context>
      <utterance>What would you do without...?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sunday, the secretary, comes in and crossing to Mr. Brooks:</context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUNDAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands Mr. Brooks a letter-size envelope.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, I know you didn't want to be disturbed, the Man in the waiting room insisted I give you this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SUNDAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said you would find what's inside very interesting.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is he? A salesman?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUNDAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He won't say. I've never seen him before. I can tell him to go away if you want me to.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leaves. Slicing the flap of the envelope, Mr. Brooks picks up with Jane.</context>
      <utterance>That's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks can now see the contents of the envelope. Two snapshot-size PHOTOS taken with a high speed digital camera. One shows the right side of Mr. Brooks's cheek. He is in no way identifiable, but that blur of flesh appears to be looking at the dead dance Couple. The second Photo is a clear shot of Mr. Brooks closing the curtains with the dead dance Couple behind him. Neither Mr. Brooks's voice or his face betray the enormity of what he's looking at.</context>
      <utterance>Part of spending the four years in college is to...</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... eh... to give yourself the chance to find out who you are and what you want to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll talk to Mom, but I'm not going back to school.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where would you live?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To save money I would move back home, but no rules, no curfew, I want to be treated like an adult.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CONTINUED:</speaker>
      <mode>4</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Brooks allows himself a slight smile.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you pay for your food, would you pay rent?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks presses his Intercom.</context>
      <utterance>No, dad, you're a very wealthy man, you can afford to keep me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sunday, would you show the gentleman who gave you the envelope to the conference room, and tell him I'll meet him there and...  What happened to the BMW?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A friend is driving it across country, it'll be here next weekend.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up the phone and holds it out to Jane.</context>
      <utterance>And get Jane a cab.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call your mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you going to give me a job?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it were up to me, and I think your mother will agree with this, you should go back to school.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>And then we're back to the original angle and Marshall is again in the picture.</context>
      <utterance>... I like them! I don't want to lose them!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... That's why I didn't want to do the dance Couple!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop your fucking whining, Earl, you enjoyed doing that Couple just as much as I did, and look on the bright side, he came to us he didn't go to the Cops. If he tries to shake us down we kill him. Period. We make it fun but we kill him. End of story.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can I do for you, Mr...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Let's say, 'Smith'.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks motions him to a seat.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, Mr. Smith.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode>MAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Before you get the wrong impression, Mr. Brooks, I'm not here to shake you down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then these are the only copies of these photos and you have no others.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I have other copies and other photos, and if something were to happen to me...</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you find me, Mr. Smith?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're 'Man of the Year', Mr. Brooks. Your picture was in the paper. If it hadn't been, I don't know what I would have done.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lucky me. What is it that I can help you with?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the end of the table, Marshall cackles a laugh.</context>
      <utterance>I've been watching that Couple for months, they liked to make love with the blinds open. Sometimes I would take pictures, you know, visual aides for later. It was fun, it was a great way to get off; I thought, until I saw you kill them. I have to tell you I have never ever felt a rush like that ever. I know you're the Thumbprint killer, you've done this before. What I want is to go with you the next time you kill someone. And I would like that to be soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you were worried that this was going to be unpleasant. The answer is simple. Just tell him you've decided never to kill again and he'll go away.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You enjoy watching me suffer, don't you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In a word, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do you think he has the other pictures?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Smith who has grown uneasy under Mr. Brooks's stare swallows:</context>
      <utterance>He put them in a safety deposit box but I'll bet the box is at the bank where he has his checking account and the key is on his keychain. He really wants to do this, he's not going to go to the cops.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So do we have a deal?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From the angle of these pictures...  ... you live on the third floor of the apartment building across the alley from the Couple's house.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... eh.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Smith nods 'yes'.</context>
      <utterance>Yes or no, Mr. Smith?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What time do you get home from work?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six thirty, seven, depending on the traffic.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can never come here again, you can never call me. Do you understand that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'll pick you up.</context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow night, not tonight, tomorrow night, at eight o'clock, leave your apartment and walk east.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're thinking of doing anything to me, Mr. Brooks...</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're both aware of the rules, Mr. Smith, but I feel I must warn you. If it turns out that you enjoy killing, it can become very addictive. It could ruin your life.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have I covered everything?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks stands up and opens the door.</context>
      <utterance>I can't think of anything else.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On his way out, Mr. Smith nods. Mr. Brooks closes the door. His chin drops on his chest and he sighs.</context>
      <utterance>I'll see you tomorrow night, Mr. Smith.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please God, please help me find a way not to do this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ASIAN ATTORNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can have a check for that amount in your office by 6 o'clock.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEILA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We told you at the beginning what we want and that hasn't changed.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAY-HAIRED ATTORNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know as well as I do, Counselor, if we go to court you're not going to get a million five.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEILA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds up the front page of the Chicago Tribune. "THE HANGMAN ESCAPES" story is circled in red.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Let's see.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEILA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the front page of yesterday's paper...  'Hangman Escapes'... eh... now, here it is... 'after torturing the young women, Thorton Meeks would hang them in public places - church steeples, balconies, Freeway overpasses'... Your client captured Mr. Meeks. This is just one example of the cases my client lived through when he was married to your client.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASIAN ATTORNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your client knew Detective Atwood was a homicide detective when he married her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SHEILA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But he had no idea of the mental anguish that being in close proximity to her work would cause him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the mental anguish I went through being in close proximity to him. Who's gonna pay me for that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASIAN ATTORNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't need to get into this, Tracy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, we do. I was the one who paid for everything while we were married, and now I'm being asked to give him a bonus for spending time with me when I've already paid for it in the first place.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tracy, this is not a lot of money for you, and you know how upset I was when Meeks said that he was going to escape and he would come back and kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEILA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're quite willing to find out what a court would think that mental anguish is worth.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesse... Darling?... you know the best thing that could happen to me right now? That you get hit by a truck and die.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEILA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it! Mr. Vialo and I are leaving.  You've threatened my client, we're going to ask for a restraining order, and we'll see you in court.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CONTINUED:</speaker>
      <mode>3</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The door closes behind them.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAY-HAIRED ATTORNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's going to cost you, Tracy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck it. It felt good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The beam from the penlight hits him in the face. He raises his hands to shield his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Ahhh!!! Ahhh!!! Ahhh!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The penlight leaves Mr. Smith and Mr. Brooks places it deliberately under his own chin casting long sinister shadows up his face. He's sitting on the bed next to Mr. Smith.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, if I were here to kill you, you would already be dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After you left today, I realized our friendship was a little one- sided.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He squints into the black.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Brooks?...</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finally he gathers the courage to extend a shaky hand. The bedside lamp goes on. The room is empty. Cautiously Mr. Smith swings his legs out of bed and stands up. He forces himself to go to the door and from there curls his arm around the jamb into the darkness. The HALL light is dazzling. A peek into the BATHROOM shows there is nobody there. He continues on into the LIVING ROOM. His camera equipment is on the table. The tripod is still set up. There is no sign of Mr. Brooks. Mr. Smith eyes the front door. It's closed and the 'security chain' is in place!! Another quick scan of the room. It sure seems that he's alone. He opens the front door the length of the chain and looks up and down the hallway. It's empty. Slowly he closes the door. Standing in the light of his LIVING ROOM, Mr. Smith is more scared and strangely more excited than he's ever been in his life.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Brooks?...</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow!...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ask your daughter what the real reason is she dropped out of school.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I keep telling you it's not the reason.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>EMMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanted to go to college, you had good grades in High School, your father helped you get into Stanford, we're paying a ton of money, if this is not the reason, then please dear God tell me the reason.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why does your mother think you dropped out of school?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm pregnant.  And it's not the reason I dropped out. Being pregnant wouldn't stop me from going to school if I wanted to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's the father?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some guy I was seeing.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does he know?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, he's a married man and he doesn't want to have anything to do with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Honey, I'm so sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks looks directly at his Daughter.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to have an abortion anyway, so there is nothing to get upset about. I wasn't even going to tell you guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There will be no abortion.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks's eyes find Emma's. Almost imperceptibly she shakes her head 'no'.</context>
      <utterance>Daddy, you are not going to tell me what to do. It's my body and I will do what I want to do with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right. I'm sorry. I said it wrong. I'm not trying to tell you what to do. I'm trying to say that a grandchild would be a wonderful gift for your mother and me.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, Honey, don't have an abortion.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you really want to have a grandchild, even though I'm not married?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. The child is what's important. We would love it and cherish it completely and help you raise it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it means that much to you, I'll think about it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we were right, she was hiding something.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pregnant's not all of it. She's hiding something bigger. Much bigger.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think so?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not what's here, it's what's not here that's interesting. There's not a trace of anything foreign. If I didn't know better I'd say these people were killed by a ghost.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN LISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The autopsy found a tiny piece of plastic in the female victim's brain.</utterance>
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're checking with the ammunition manufacturers.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a dead end, he bags the gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He ziplocks a one gallon plastic freezer bag to his wrist over the gun. Bang. Bang. A little bit of plastic is carried by the first slug, the ejected shells go into the bag and it limits the powder residue.  I hear you were looking for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN LISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sigy...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So far they are Mr. and Miss Normal.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's gone.</context>
      <utterance>If you find anything, call, it might help me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN LISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I received a subpoena from your husband's lawyer for your work records, where you were, date and times for the past two years.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's blackmail.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN LISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Almost three quarters of your cases are current. I can't let that information go into open court. So until you settle your divorce, I'm going to have to put you on a desk.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's also blackmail.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN LISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's one of your big problems, Atwood, you don't know how to ask for help.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know what he did to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN LISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't grow old as a woman without having at least one lousy man in your life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was so stupid. While we were married, while I paid for him to live, the son of a bitch fucked every woman he could get his hands on. He fucked my friends, he even fucked a cousin of mine. Everyone knew but me, and they were laughing at me behind my back. He made me look like an idiot. I was a joke.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN LISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And?...</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN LISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get over it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I made him an offer. I'm not going to give him one red cent more.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN LISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hear what he's asking for, you could take out of pocket change. Do that and go on with your life.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I couldn't live with myself if I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN LISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll spread your work among the other guys and the FBI will be here on thursday...  ... they'll take over this case.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This one's mine.</context>
      <utterance>Please, these are my cases. Nobody knows them like me. Don't give them away and don't give the Thumbprint Killer to the FBI. He's killed people in twelve other states, let them fuck up those investigations.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN LISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You heard Meeks escaped?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN LISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want a detail on you in case he comes after you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can take care of myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN LISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a good cop, Tracy, I don't want to lose you, but you have to help me if you want me to help you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She steps into the KITCHEN. On the way across she bumps into a chair.</context>
      <utterance>How did you know where they were in the house?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's darker tonight than it was on your night. But still how did you manage not to bump into the furniture? Did you have a little light? That would be too dangerous. I'll bet you were in the house before.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She steps into the HALL.</context>
      <utterance>Once again, how did you know where they were? Did you check the rooms before you found them? She had his semen in her vagina, they had just made love, did you hear them or was there a light on?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She continues down the HALL to the BEDROOM.</context>
      <utterance>And when did you bag the gun? Because even though I'm sure you're an expert at it, there's still a chance of noise from the plastic.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens the door and goes in.</context>
      <utterance>Was the door open or did you have to open it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns on the overhead light.</context>
      <utterance>Were they asleep or awake? Was the light on, or did you turn it on? Because I know you, you wouldn't risk a shot in the dark.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns on a bedside light and goes back to the door and turns off the overhead. If the dance Couple were on the bed and their blood was not on the wall, the room would look exactly the way it did when Mr. Brooks said 'hello'.</context>
      <utterance>Too bright. What if it wasn't that light that was on, but this one?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's at the window now, feeling the curtains.</context>
      <utterance>That's better... What thrill do you get by killing people? Is it sexual, is it hate, is it power? Do you feel remorse? Probably that part of your brain doesn't exist. Do you have emotions of love or affection or joy? Or have you learned to fake them so you won't stand out in a crowd.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She separates the fabric and looks out the rain-streaked window at the four story building across the alley. There are lights on in almost all the apartment windows.</context>
      <utterance>What if these are stuck closed because you yanked them closed? Which means they were open when you came into the room.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She allows the fabric to drop back into place and turns to look at the bed.</context>
      <utterance>If Mr. and Miss Normal made love with the curtains open and the lights on, someone in that building noticed them and may have seen you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was that what you were angry about?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>A door is closed. We come to the corner and are looking down a HALLWAY at Atwood coming toward us. We move to her and arrive just as she raises her fist to knock. Before she can, the door opens and she and Mr. Smith who is on his way out of his Apartment are surprised that the other one is suddenly there. Each one takes a half step back. Phwap! The manila envelope that was wedged under Mr. Smith's left arm hits the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you for your time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh! You scared me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry...  ... I was about to knock. I'm Detective Atwood with the Chicago Police.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Through the open door, Atwood can see Mr. Smith's camera on a table and the collapsed tripod leaning against the wall.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you a photographer...  Mr. Baffert?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... eh, it's kind of a hobby, I just started.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know if you're aware but there was a murder...</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes in the house across the alley...</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Smith puts on his thinking expression and pauses a little bit before:</context>
      <utterance>Did you happen to see anything unusual or suspicious that night around that house? Anything at all?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves into the Hallway closing the door behind him.</context>
      <utterance>No... I wondered that when I heard what happened, but... no.  I'm sorry, I'm meeting someone and I don't want to be late.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He looks clean. He looks like he's alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm telling you he wants to do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess I should turn around and go pick him up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah. Just honk. Maybe he'll get killed crossing the street and save us the mess of doing it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Woof! It's really coming down out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Smith fumbles with the buttons and zipper on his raincoat.</context>
      <utterance>They say it'll be sunny tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He comes up with the manila envelope.</context>
      <utterance>I never trust those guys, when they say it's going to be clear it always rains and when they say it's going to rain, it's sunny.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks takes it and hefts it.</context>
      <utterance>Here's what you asked for.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The pictures and the memory card all here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You and I both know that not all the pictures are in here and you made a copy of the Memory Card, isn't that so?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks favors him with a wolfish smile.</context>
      <utterance>But you understand my position.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I do. But it's my hope that once you get to know me better you'll feel comfortable in giving me all that I've asked for.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His hand comes forward with a card.</context>
      <utterance>That sounds fair. Oh, I almost forgot. I thought you might be interested in this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marshall snaps forward from the back seat.</context>
      <utterance>It's the policewoman who's looking for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks pinches the rectangle of paper away from Mr. Smith for a closer view.</context>
      <utterance>Wow! We've never known anyone who's looking for us before.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've got to find out everything there is to know about this woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Smith interrupts Mr. Brooks's focus on Detective Atwood's card.</context>
      <utterance>This is too close, Marshall, too damn close.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks slips the envelope under the seat and starts the car.</context>
      <utterance>So, what do we do now? What's the plan for the evening?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We drive around until we see someone we think we might enjoy killing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? That's it? I thought you might already have someone in mind.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't enjoy this, Mr. Smith. I do it because I'm addicted to it. And before you entered my life I had vowed I would never kill again. So this is your party, you can chose anyone you want and we'll do it together.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can it be someone I know?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You never kill someone you know. That's the easiest way to get caught.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>STEWARDESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wasn't in town that night, my roommate was, maybe he saw something.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I speak to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEWARDESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's on his way to Tokyo now, he's also a Flight Attendant.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did the victims ever leave the curtains in the bedroom open?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEWARDESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All the time. I don't know if they thought we couldn't see them "fucking" or they didn't care.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's my card, could you ask your roommate to call me when he gets back, the people at that number will find me any hour of the day or night.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEWARDESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't be here, but I'll leave him a note.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... I buy one of those locks and I practice on it, same with the alarm... some I know how to bypass, some I have to study.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't mind me asking these questions?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A neutral-colored PICKUP swerves out of the next lane into Mr. Brooks' lane.</context>
      <utterance>No. This is your first time, you're interested. And you should be if you're...</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks is forced to slam on his brakes to avoid running up the PICKUP'S tailpipe. HOONKK!!! Mr. Brooks angrily lays on the horn. The brake lights of the PICKUP flash in response causing Mr. Brooks to brake again.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck him!! It was his fault!! What an asshole!!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe Mr. Smith would like to kill the driver of the pickup.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the driver of the pickup? What if we killed him?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The PICKUP makes a right onto a side street. Mr. Brooks follows.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, fuck, yes!! I've always wanted to kill someone who fucked with me in traffic.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want to kill the driver of the pickup or the owner, they may not be the same.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The driver.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay we'll follow until we get a look at him, or her; would it bother you to kill a woman?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks begins to slow down.</context>
      <utterance>No. An asshole's an asshole.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The asshole shouldn't know we've decided to follow him, or her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MALE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The phone is shut, the umbrella unfurled and the darkness swallows her up.</context>
      <utterance>It's Tracy. Can you carve out some time for me tonight?... I'll be home in an hour and a half. I'll see you there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you recognize him if you saw his driver's license picture?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've memorized the license number, you write it down. When you get home go on the Internet and find out everything you can about this guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We aren't going to kill him tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. We could, but then we wouldn't be in control. We could leave loose ends, and we both know the danger of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Smith does.</context>
      <utterance>Look at me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Close your eyes. What's the number?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Smith opens his eyes and grins sheepishly.</context>
      <utterance>VF... eh...</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't feel bad, I've been doing this a long time...  Pen, paper. Write it down.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was your first time?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really don't want to know that much about me, Mr. Smith.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. I brought a dress and a pair of shoes. I thought we could leave from here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lifts herself to him and they kiss.</context>
      <utterance>Great idea.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did something like that except I was the one who took the test. It wasn't math, a friend of mine was a theology major and needed a second language to get into the Master's program...</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She started her career in theology with a lie?!</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't that what all theology is based on?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you pass the test?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah...</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't tell me she ended up as Mother Teresa or the Pope.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, she realized very quickly there wasn't enough money in religion for her, the last I heard she'd written a diet book that was very successful.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Atwood smiles, her fingers find Larry's and they intertwine. The view floats over the balcony. As it slowly drops, the PEOPLE on the dance floor, Couple by Couple, disappear until there are only three Couples left, one of them is Atwood and Larry. Her head is on his shoulder. It's a slow dance. Larry is very good and wherever he leads, Atwood easily follows. The lights begin to dim and we move in. Larry touches his lips to Atwood's neck. She arches back and he kisses her neck again and again.</context>
      <utterance>She stayed in religion.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, this was wonderful.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For me too.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll see you then?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like that. The money is in the usual place.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not just the money, Tracy. I like you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like you too, Larry. Send me a bill for the dress and the shoes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will. Good-night.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good-night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think that was right. Go back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're in.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>We tip toe under the door.</context>
      <utterance>With the taxes we pay, you'd think they could make it more difficult to hack into the Police personnel files.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>.... Huh... her father's Gerald Atwood, why does that ring a bell?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone you did business with, someone we killed?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not someone we killed... MBA... College of William and Mary... she's been a cop for eleven years... Married Doctor Carlson, divorced Dr. Carlson, married Jesse Vialo... restaurateur... separated from Jesse Vialo, sued for support by Jesse Vialo, seeing a shrink because of Jesse Vialo...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excellent fitness report though.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She caught the Hangman, the guy that escaped the other day...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oooh... She's caught a lot of people... And look here, this isn't the first time she's been hunting for us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks taps a key that minimizes Atwood's file then drags it to the right hand corner. In the middle of a key stroke it hits him:</context>
      <utterance>I wonder what the deal was with her and Jesse Vialo?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tap, tap, tap. Jesse Vialo's Driver's license comes up.</context>
      <utterance>Ahhhh... now I remember. Her father, Gerald Atwood, never did business with him but Emma and I met him a couple times, big political fundraiser. He owns or owned one of the largest insurance groups in the country and a lot of other stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesse Vialo... Good looking, a little younger than she is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Younger, restaurateur...  She married him on the rebound from the doctor and I'll bet he married her for her money and her connections.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The old man being rich doesn't mean she's rich. Maybe he's one of those guys who would rather give it to the Opera than to his kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't she have to declare any outside income and holdings to the Police?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He restores Atwood's file. Tap, tap, tap, tap. Stop. The Men study the screen then look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Hmmm...</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Opera didn't get much.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would a woman with her education and worth 60 plus million dollars and probably more to come, want to be a cop?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like that about her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You like her because she's rich.</context>
      <utterance>You're such a fucking snob, Earl.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I like her because she found something that's hers. It's not the family business. And she's good at it. I'd like Jane to find something that's hers and that she could be good at.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's exactly why Atwood scares the shit out of me. She's a cop who doesn't need the money and she's looking for us. That's one fucking dangerous human being.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The fact that you're not wrong doesn't make me admire her any less.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches out, the Women shake hands.</context>
      <utterance>Hi...</utterance>
   <speaker>ASIAN ATTORNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. I got you a Latte.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks and thanks for meeting me here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASIAN ATTORNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got an injunction to quash the subpoena for your work records yesterday. They've already appealed.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That doesn't help me does it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ASIAN ATTORNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your father has a lot of political muscle.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father does nothing for nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASIAN ATTORNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand. If you're willing to play the game and ride a desk for a year; I think we can settle for one two five, one five.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No desk.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASIAN ATTORNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then the only other option is money. Tell me how high you are willing to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One five.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASIAN ATTORNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can try. If I were on the other side I'd hold out for more.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much more?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASIAN ATTORNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me a cap and that's how high we'll go.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try and get a number out of them first. I want to know what ballpark I'm playing in and if it's a lump sum, is it less than something that's paid in installments.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASIAN ATTORNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Atwood stands up with her coffee.</context>
      <utterance>I'll call them today.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to get this done as soon as possible.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ASIAN ATTORNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you working on the Thumbprint Killer this time?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASIAN ATTORNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Atwood nods and opens the front door then follows the Attorney out.</context>
      <utterance>That one's creepy to me. The doors are locked, the alarms are armed and the people are dead. It makes you feel like you're not safe anywhere.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you parked?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASIAN ATTORNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm right over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts to walk away.</context>
      <utterance>I'm down the street. Call me as soon as you have something.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASIAN ATTORNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Tracy... I almost forgot, your husband says there's a picture of him holding some trophy that you still have.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He took all those pictures. He took everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASIAN ATTORNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He claims it's his favorite picture and you put it up where you store your suitcases.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll look.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MEEKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her again and puts the gun to Atwood's head.</context>
      <utterance>I already know where I'm gonna hang you. But first I'm gonna watch her...  ... have some fun with you, then she's gonna watch me have some fun with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEEKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He raises up and straddles her.</context>
      <utterance>Now, don't move.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEEKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With his left hand he fishes a pair of handcuffs from a back pocket and snaps them on Atwood's right wrist.</context>
      <utterance>You know the drill, I'm gonna put the cuffs on.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEEKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rolls Atwood on her back and with the chain of the handcuff pulls her right arm toward her left. All Meeks' talk has allowed Atwood to catch her breath and suddenly she jerks her head up into the gun and screams at the top of her lungs.</context>
      <utterance>Now the left.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN LISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Detective Snyder comes in and hands a packet of photographs to Atwood.</context>
      <utterance>We found the van in an underground lot about two miles from where they left you. It was stolen last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are the women we have pictures of who know Meeks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN LISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Detective Atwood begins to go through the pictures.</context>
      <utterance>Meeks and the Woman, none of the Attendants remember seeing them.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That chiropractor, Alvin Griffin, who sold Meeks his steroids, he might know where he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN LISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His phone's been tapped since Meeks escaped. No contact that way so far and he's sure not going to talk to us.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about a warrant to search his house? Get me in the door and he'll talk to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN LISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's your divorce going?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stretching out her arm to return the photos:</context>
      <utterance>I took your advice and told my lawyer to settle.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>None of these is the woman in the van.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa... I'm sewing up your head here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN LISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And your ego can handle that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't like any of the other choices.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN LISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Until Meeks is caught, Snyder is with you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing personal, Snyder.  He's not part of our team.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN LISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's there to protect you. And listen to him, he's been alive longer than you have.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't volunteer for this, Atwood.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN LISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Parking Lot has a security camera. We're checking the tape. If Meeks and the Woman left in a car we'll have a license number. You have two days then I want a progress report on your divorce.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I have all the pieces on the Thumbprint Killer, I'm just not looking at them the right way.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN LISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, you have three days.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every babysitter I ever had loved me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe he went home with someone else.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Smith looks.</context>
      <utterance>Can you still see his pickup?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All three Men idly observe an old green Pontiac convertible with a frayed top and paint peeling, come into the Lot and park two spaces away facing them. We saw this car last watching Atwood from outside the Murder House. The headlights go off. The Driver's door opens. The Woman who was with Meeks in the Van steps out and hurries toward the Drug Store. She of course means nothing to Mr. Brooks but in the brief seconds the domelight is on, he catches sight of the Man in the passenger seat. A memory tickles his brain. He turns to Marshall.</context>
      <utterance>This is not the kind of guy who leaves his pickup in an unguarded Lot overnight. The silence returns.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do we know that guy from?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really should pay more attention to what you read, Earl.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I have you for, Marshall.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His picture was on the front page of the paper a couple days ago because he escaped from jail. He's the killer they call the Hangman.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahh...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks cocks his head at the vague outline of Meeks.</context>
      <utterance>Remember that cop you like, Atwood, who's chasing us, she's the one who put him away. I think his name is Thorton Meeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Smith who, remember, cannot hear or see Marshall, straightens up.</context>
      <utterance>Well, well, well... What would life be without surprises?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Man they are waiting for is coming down the steps of the store. On the way to his Pickup he takes off a Manager's smock.</context>
      <utterance>There he is!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks nods absently. The Drug Store Manager arrives at his truck.</context>
      <utterance>You know what's weird? I'll bet he has all these plans of what he's going to do tonight and tomorrow and he doesn't know he will already be dead and won't be able to do any of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think I want to kill this guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marshall smiles.</context>
      <utterance>What?! But you promised we would!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I love what you're thinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have no idea what I'm thinking.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yes I do, and it's wonderfully twisted.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks starts the car and puts it in reverse.</context>
      <utterance>I know I said we would, but I don't think it would be that much fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So just like that, you're saying 'no', it's not going to happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks casts his eyes on the license plate of the car Meeks is in.</context>
      <utterance>I see.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You get the number?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Smith wants you to notice he's pouting.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you're upset, Mr. Smith, and I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I am upset.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I was a little abrupt back there, but let me explain. Finding someone you think would be fun to kill is a bit like falling in love. You meet a lot of candidates, and you like some of them and they're nice, but they're not right; and then that special one shows up and your heart beats faster and you know that's the one. The man in the pickup did not make my heart beat faster.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, he did not make your heart beat faster. If not him, who?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, I think I have someone in mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you need me to do any work on it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, let's see how it plays out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see? That's my problem. That makes me feel like I'm being jerked around, Mr. Brooks. I thought it was happening last night, then it was happening tonight. And now it's "Let's see how it plays out".</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I promise you, it will happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When? That's what I want to know, Mr. Brooks. When?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow night, same time. When you come out of your building, turn right, go to the first street you can go west on, I'll pick you up on that street.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets out and with the door still open, turns back.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to do this. But if it drags on too long, I could change my mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you think I want to do this, Mr. Smith?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shuts the door. Marshall and Mr. Brooks watch him walk away.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe you don't anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even if that guy was charming and funny I still wouldn't like him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The shorter One holds up a badge.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, what can I do for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Detective Smolny with the Chicago Police and this is Detective Carfagno, from Palo Alto, California...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARFAGNO</speaker>
      <mode>DETECTIVE 2</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'd like to speak to Jane Brooks, if that's possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jane is my daughter, what's this about?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARFAGNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was a murder at Stanford not long before she left. She may be able to help us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is she a suspect?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARFAGNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not at this time. We simply would like to ask her some questions.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMOLNY</speaker>
      <mode>DETECTIVE 1</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is your daughter here?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... she is.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARFAGNO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The questions won't take long.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure you would have no objection if she had an attorney present.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMOLNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks looks at the card.</context>
      <utterance>That's fine.  Here's my card. We can schedule a time for later today or tomorrow for her to come in to see us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you gentlemen can wait, I will call my lawyer right now and see what we can work out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMOLNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, that's even better.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like some coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMOLNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We both knew she was hiding something bigger, I certainly didn't think it was this big.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks opens a door. The room that is revealed is a very well equipped home GYM.</context>
      <utterance>She's not a suspect, Marshall. She may not have anything to do with it at all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did Jane ever tell you that there was a murder at her school?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing? Not that a friend died or someone she knew died? Or someone in her dorm died?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are two Detectives downstairs, one is from Palo Alto, they want to ask her some questions about a murder that occurred shortly before she came home.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, my Gosh! I'm sure if she was close to someone who was murdered, she would have said something.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I called Roger, he suggested a criminal attorney, they'll be here within the hour.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll get dressed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Clifford, it was a pleasure. Thank you for coming on such short notice.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAVYSET LAWYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There won't be any more dropping by like they did today, they'll call us first.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks again, Roger. It was a good idea to hear what they wanted to know sooner rather than later.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. CLIFFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He waves and re-enters the house.</context>
      <utterance>Yup.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did good, Kid. Your answers were clear, concise and honest. And when they tried to trip you up, it didn't work.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope so. I'm not feeling so well.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should you lie down?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks kisses his daughter on the top of the head.</context>
      <utterance>I think I'd better.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jane bends her steps toward the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Try and get some sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry I didn't tell you about it, Daddy. It was horrible but I really didn't know the guy that well. It happened at about the same time I found out I was pregnant, and it just went out of my mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jane resumes her journey up the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>I understand.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sitting on the island behind him Marshall waits for Mr. Brooks to gulp the glass dry.</context>
      <utterance>God help me. What do I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She did it, didn't she?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. It'll take the Cops a week to ten days to put their case together and then they'll come back and arrest her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks puts his hands over his eyes and sobs, then wiping away the tears:</context>
      <utterance>What are you going to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been afraid of this since the day she was born. She has what I have.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, she does. But you've always been smart about it. She was stupid. She did it because she got off on it, she did it for fun. Why didn't she think it through? A hatchet! And she left it there!!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were pretty graphic, weren't they?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was to shock her into making a mistake.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does she think I think? Doesn't she remember what she told me? That the BMW was being driven across country by a friend and now right in front of me, she tells the Cops it was stolen.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've always cleaned up after her, whatever she did, all her life.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If the BMW has anything incriminating in it, I hope it was stolen or she dropped it at the bottom of a very deep lake.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think she knows what kind of trouble she's in?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think she thought she had gotten away with it until the Cops showed up. I should have listened to her, it was there. She was telling me. 'I didn't quit school because I was pregnant'. I should have dug deeper.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And where would you be but at the exact same place you are now. It is not your fault, Earl. Part of your problem with her is that you always think it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She has what I have, Marshall. So on a very basic level, it is my fault.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you going to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe the best thing for her would be to let her go to jail.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what about her child?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Emma and I would raise it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You might be right, Earl, you might be. Because you know if she's not stopped, she's going to do it again. And if she wants to take over the box business, the next victim could be you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think she'd go that far.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SIGY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The slide changes to an overhead schematic showing the interior of the house where the dance Couple was murdered. Detective Atwood and Detective Snyder are standing with Sigy watching the presentation. Atwood has a bandage covering the stitches over her eye.</context>
      <utterance>We found traces of this in two places.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The red dot indicates an area just outside the Kitchen and just outside the Bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>Here and here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We did an analysis and it's made up of feldspar, alumina and kaolin.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A high fire stoneware clay.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like you make ashtrays and vases from?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SIGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We're thinking it was the killer.</context>
      <utterance>This is more plates and teacups. It was slightly wet when whoever it was tracked it into the house and it stuck to the carpet fibers.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It could have been tracked in by a friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the thing, you see, the friend would have had to have been there almost at the same time the killer was. Otherwise the samples would have been dry and the killer would have vacuumed them up.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is the clay rare, is it difficult to get?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can buy it almost anywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not much help, Sigy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And this is the only incongruity you were able to find in the whole house.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've done everything we know how to do. It sure doesn't break the case wide open, does it?.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Sigy, it doesn't. It does give me an excuse to ask someone some new questions.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Before you open your mouth, be very sure this is the right thing to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Remember; Sunday can neither see nor hear Marshall.</context>
      <utterance>I will never be sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is your decision.</context>
      <utterance>You get pissed at me because I'm always the one arguing to go ahead and do murder. Not this time, Earl.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know it's wrong. In my heart I know it's wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then don't do it. Go with Mr. Smith tonight and end that, then let the Police put Jane in jail. Hopefully that will save her and we can happily go on with our tortured lives.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks raises his head and looks at Sunday.</context>
      <utterance>That's exactly what I want to do. That's exactly what I should do. The thing is, she's my daughter and I love her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going home. Cancel everything for the rest of the day. I might be in tomorrow afternoon. I'll let you know about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUNDAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take care of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you need me, need me, call my studio, that's where I'll be.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I probably won't pick up, just leave a message.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUNDAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door closes behind her.</context>
      <utterance>I'll try not to bother you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks chooses the first sleeve and the third sleeve. The other two go back into the Safe.</context>
      <utterance>The thing that bothers me about this, besides the fact we're not prepared, and a multitude of other things, is what does Mr. Smith do when he's walking west tonight and you don't show up. That little freak could flip out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take care of it on the way to the airport.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not - able - to - meet - Mr. Smith turns the page.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- tonight - Do - it - same - Turns the page.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- time - tomorrow - Turns the page.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Smith refolds the Newspaper and throws it at the passenger seat.</context>
      <utterance>- night - Don't - be - stupid -.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He inserts the key into the ignition. RAP-RAP!! There's a sudden sharp KNOCK!!, on the Driver's window.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All Mr. Smith can do is nod.</context>
      <utterance>You remember me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you step out of the car, please, I want to talk to you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So Mr. Baffert, what is that you have to tell me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean? I don't have anything to tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? Because I was driving around and I got this sudden feeling that you had something to tell me about the murders.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's disappointing. Because when I left you the last time we talked, I felt I had missed a clue that was right in front of me that would solve this whole case.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know why you would feel that.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't you tell me you were an amateur potter, that you made bowls and vases?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I said I was an amateur photographer.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you positive? Because we found potter's clay on the carpet of the murder house and I was sure you said to me that you worked with clay, that you made pots.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I said my hobby was photography, not pottery.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Smith can only stare at Detective Atwood. His Adam's apple moves up and down though he makes no sound. Should he or shouldn't he? Finally he throws his arms up in a shrug but in his half-turn of indecision he happens to spy the Newspaper he tossed at the passenger seat of his car. Part of it is draped over the console. The red circles around the words on that page jump out at him.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe that was it. The Stewardess upstairs said the victims kept their curtains open when they made love. Could I see some of the pictures you took of that Couple?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Mr. Smith returns his attention to Detective Atwood.</context>
      <utterance>Don't - be - stupid -.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are harassing me, Detective Atwood. You know very well I'm not a potter and I don't have any pictures! So my feeling is that your feeling is wrong and that you should move your car and let me go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is your job here? What do you do?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a mechanical engineer.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to be pretty smart for that, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives him a dazzling smile.</context>
      <utterance>Then be smart, Mr. Baffert. You lied to me right there at the end. I'll be watching you. And when you want to tell me the truth, you know how to get in touch with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Atwood walks back to her car and gets in.</context>
      <utterance>See you later, alligator.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Snyder accelerates away he points to the car's computer screen.</context>
      <utterance>Goddamit...</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain Lister got us the search warrant for Meeks' Chiropractor.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good.  Goddamit!, that guy knows something...  He almost told me and then something happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think he did it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think it's that simple.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STEWARDESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks who now looks like the Man in the picture on the third Driver's license, accepts the drink.</context>
      <utterance>Here you are, Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a sip and resumes his gaze out the window.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The earth that he is looking at below is a long way away.</context>
      <utterance>God grant me the Serenity to accept the things I cannot change, Courage to change the things I can, and Wisdom to know the difference...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A light and footsteps hurry toward her from the LIVING ROOM. Atwood swings her light at them.</context>
      <utterance>We have a dead woman in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He squints and turns away.</context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you were behind me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The living room is clean.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Uniformed Policeman comes up beside Atwood.</context>
      <utterance>Snyder, meet Mona.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNIFORMED POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The smell of blood and the sight of the carnage is too much for him. His gorge rises and he gags.</context>
      <utterance>I called it in.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Officer doesn't have to be told twice.</context>
      <utterance>Do that outside.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meeks did this.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Atwood retraces her steps in the Kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>I thought Meeks hung people.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She focuses her flashlight on an open padlock dangling from a steel band that runs around the Refrigerator. With the barrel of the Glock she opens the door. The only edibles inside are a tomato, half a loaf of bread, a package of hotdogs and some part of a chicken in a KFC box. The rest of the space is vacant.</context>
      <utterance>Meeks is a steroid freak. This Refrigerator was always full of steroids. Mona was Alvin Griffin's niece, receptionist, lover and keeper of the keys.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, the steroids are certainly gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think Meeks has Alvin with him?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shuts the Refrigerator.</context>
      <utterance>Meeks thinks Alvin turned him in.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go see what's in the rest of the house.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you feel?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dirty.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's understandable. You've never killed for this reason before. The feeling will go away.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so. It's the whole thing, Marshall. If I could find a way to just disappear, where there was absolutely no trace of me; because eventually I will get caught doing this. And it'll be very embarrassing for me and Emma and Jane. So I've been thinking... is there a way that Mr. Smith could kill me and make me disappear.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Number one, Mr. Smith is not smart enough to do that. Number two, there is no reason, if you're careful, to believe you will ever get caught.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know I will have to plan it for Mr. Smith, but I think that's what I want to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not particularly fond of that plan, Earl. Remember if you die, I go with you and I like being alive. I like eating, I like fucking, I like killing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to end it, Marshall. One way or the other. And I think this is the best way.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well fuck you then.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EMMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You worked all night.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had ideas for pots that took too long and the clay kept winning...  I'll be fine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASIAN ATTORNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi Tracy, this is Nancy Tang. We received a counter offer. Are you sitting down?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never. How long can you stall them?</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They know you want this done quickly, so they're going to expect a quick counter offer.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need two days. Wait two days before getting back to them. If they call, tell them it's a big number, I'm thinking about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NANCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slams the frame of Jesse's photo against the inside of a metal trash can. Nancy winces and then smiles at the sound of shattering glass. Atwood plucks the photo out of the frame and tears it so that the rip can be heard over the phone.</context>
      <utterance>And the picture he wanted...</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... tell him I couldn't find it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EMMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks opens his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Earl... Earl...</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Hi, Daddy, I thought you'd already be gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roger called. There was another murder last night near Stanford.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh...</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jane can't quite conceal the tremor of surprise that ripples through her and Mr. Brooks sees it.</context>
      <utterance>Done the same way as the one they talked to you about. Right down to the hatchet being left at the scene.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They think they have a serial killer. Obviously you were here last night, so you're in the clear.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's good news, isn't it? I mean even if you're innocent it's good news to know you're not a suspect.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah. How's the morning sickness? Do you want to ride in with me today?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks nods, turns to leave, then turns back.</context>
      <utterance>I feel fine, but I don't know how long that will last.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you love me, Jane?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course I love you, daddy, you're my father.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you decided whether or not to keep the baby?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are we doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We're playing a hunch.</context>
      <utterance>'Are we there yet?' , are we there yet?' , you sound like a child.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've been following this guy all day, he's boring, and everything we run on him comes up clean.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it didn't, it wouldn't be called a hunch.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meeks' finger-prints were all over the chiropractor, the note, refrigerator, he's the guy we should be looking for.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her and shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Look where? Please tell me. Everyone knows who Meeks is and is looking for him. The chiropractor was the last link to his old life that I know of. The only way we'll find him, now, is if someone turns him in or we trip over him at a bus stop. On the other hand, Detective Snyder, no one knows who the Thumbprint Killer is or where he is. However, I have a fucking hunch this guy Baffert does. I have two days to play that hunch. If you feel like you're wasting your time with me, I'd be happy to do it alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had a fight with my wife this morning; what's your problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My husband wants five million dollars.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lister is pulling you off this case.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She twists the screen around so she can read the message.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe they caught him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Snyder points across the street at Mr. Smith coming out of the Restaurant carrying a Take-Out bag.</context>
      <utterance>No. She would have said that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Atwood hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>You want to keep following him?</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lister only said you were off the case, not me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts the car. There's the muted 'tone' again. Atwood looks at the computer screen.</context>
      <utterance>Good thinking, Tonto.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit! She just 86'ed you too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is she in?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's with someone.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You promised if I settled my divorce I had three days on the Thumbprint Killer. I have the rest of today and tomorrow left.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN LISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Detective Atwood, meet FBI Agents Longnecker and Campbell, they're taking over your investigation.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You promised you would keep them out of it for three days.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN LISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Atwood glares at her then at the FBI Men.</context>
      <utterance>They won't allow me to keep that promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is my case, what you're doing is fucked. But since I can't stop you, and she won't, here's a tip. James Baffert, you should stake him out, he knows something.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE LONGNECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have some other ideas we are looking into.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what's the problem? You do that and I'll tail Baffert.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE LONGNECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Atwood looks from one Man to the Other.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you for all your good work, Detective. This is our case now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>INSIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The lamp at his elbow throws a yellow cone across his face. His head is in his hands, he's been crying. Marshall steps out of the shadows behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Brooks is at his desk.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's time to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches into a bottom drawer and as he takes out an envelope, Marshall reads the tear-stained hand written letter resting on the blotter.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks picks up the letter and folds it.</context>
      <utterance>Dear Emma and Jane, my loves, I have a terminal illness and instead of subjecting you to my deterioration, I have decided to disappear. Don't try to find me, I don't want to be found. Please believe that the time I spent with you brought me the greatest joy of my life. Love. Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks stuffs the letter in the envelope, seals it and picks up a pen.</context>
      <utterance>So you're going to go through with it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I smell gun oil, a gun oil that's different than yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He brought his gun. After he gets what he wants he plans to kill me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah... now I get it. You were counting on that, weren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It has a certain logic.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But if your plan is to have him kill you, why do you have to kill someone else first?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marshall roars with laughter.</context>
      <utterance>He'll need to see that to get up the courage to kill me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not even you believe that, Earl. It makes it more exciting, doesn't it, to think he's going to kill you after you kill someone else. You're getting your rocks off big time, that's why you're doing it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not true... and if it were, so what?  You're goddamn great, you know. To have the balls to do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm pretty nervous but that's normal right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perfectly normal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>FLIGHT ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INTERCUT with Detective Atwood.</context>
      <utterance>The weird thing is that they closed their curtains, at first they were open like they always were and they were making love, which they always did, and then when I looked again the curtains were closed, and there were what looked like camera flashes coming from behind the curtains.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Camera flashes?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLIGHT ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what it looked like.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why he poses them.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLIGHT ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLIGHT ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish I could be more helpful, I didn't see the killer or anything like that, but since it was weird I thought I should call.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's about to hang up when Struber speaks again.</context>
      <utterance>You've been very helpful. This answers a lot of questions for me. Thank you very much, Mr. Struber.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLIGHT ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The guy you should talk to is the guy on the floor below us...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FLIGHT ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>eh, I can't remember his name, but he told me once that he'd taken some great pictures of that Couple making love, he's the one you should speak to.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would that be, Mr. Baffert?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLIGHT ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I think Jim or James...</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Atwood disconnects then quickly dials.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Snyder, meet me at Baffert's apartment with a Search Warrant... Listen to me, this is what you tell the judge.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to take a crap so bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks and Mr. Smith come out of the Kitchen. The LIVING ROOM is quite well appointed. There's a fire going in the Fireplace. The sound of a T.V. is coming from a ROOM off a HALL up ahead. That is where Mr. Brooks and Mr. Smith are headed. They're more than half way across the LIVING ROOM when DING! DONG!, the doorbell rings. Mr. Smith gasps and looks beseechingly at Mr. Brooks. Without an ounce of hurry, Mr. Brooks maneuvers him back into the shadows of the KITCHEN. The doorbell rings again. A wet spot appears in Mr. Smith's crotch and runs down his pant leg. Pee drips onto the linoleum. A Man comes out of the Hallway. The Living Room light goes on. The Man is Jesse, Detective Atwood's estranged husband. He opens the Front Door. The Woman who comes in is Sheila, his divorce lawyer. They kiss, tongues. His hands brush over her breasts. He begins to unbutton her blouse. The kiss breaks. As he continues unbuttoning.</context>
      <utterance>This won't take long.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEILA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jesse opens the blouse and looks at the breasts under the bra.</context>
      <utterance>I called your wife's lawyer. They're thinking about the five million dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sheila gives him a quick kiss and moves on into the LIVING ROOM where she drops her briefcase on the couch.</context>
      <utterance>Realistically how much do you think we can get?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SHEILA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Backlit by the Fireplace, Jesse kisses her again. From the KITCHEN, Mr. Brooks and Mr. Smith watch Jesse unzip Sheila's slacks and dropping to his knees peel them off her legs. She steps out of them. He kisses the inside of her thighs, her crotch, then standing up:</context>
      <utterance>If we go to court, best case, two, if she wants to settle, best case, three, but I would be happy with two seven.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On his way out of the LIVING ROOM:</context>
      <utterance>I'll be right back.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shuts off the light. In the glow of the Fireplace, Sheila removes her jacket.</context>
      <utterance>I think we should hold firm for three.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEILA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The T.V. goes silent. Jesse returns with a partially full glass of Champagne. He hands Sheila a glass from a side table, takes a bottle out of an ice bucket and as he fills her glass:</context>
      <utterance>Let's not be piggish, two five, two seven, would be a good deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEILA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've already had half a bottle.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They clink glasses.</context>
      <utterance>You're late; if we want it, there's more.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEILA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To us.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To three million dollars.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SHEILA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to do this fast because remember, Marie is meeting us here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We could ask her to join us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEILA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She bops him playfully. He bends and slips a nipple into his mouth. Sheila bites her lip and moans. In the KITCHEN, Mr. Smith shifts around for a better view. The floor under him CRREEEKKS! In the LIVING ROOM, both Sheila and Jesse react to the sound.</context>
      <utterance>I wasn't trying to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEILA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we alone?</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks seems to appear magically out of the darkened Kitchen with his gun raised. He's followed by Mr. Smith. Sheila opens her mouth to scream.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't do that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door of the Apartment behind her opens and an OLDER WOMAN sticks her head out.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Baffert?... Mr. Baffert?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's gone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have any idea when he'll be back?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He skipped out. I heard him leave this evening and a few minutes later there were Movers here. Musta been behind on the rent. He didn't even say good-bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the Old Lady watches, Atwood tries the knob. It's unlocked. She pushes the door open. The HALLWAY and LIVING ROOM she can see are completely empty. Furniture, T.V., camera equipment, art, gone.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Atwood whirls, gun up. She sees that it's Snyder.</context>
      <utterance>Obviously Baffert's gone...</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamit, Snyder. Knock.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wasn't able to get the search warrant.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where were you when you called me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At home in bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you prove that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was home in bed, why should I have to prove that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Atwood slowly lowers her head and fixes her eyes on the floor in stunned silence.</context>
      <utterance>Your husband Jesse and his lawyer were killed tonight...</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It looks like the Thumbprint Killer, I've been ordered to bring you in for questioning.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, I didn't want Jesse dead, I loved him, I hated what he was doing to me...</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's on record you said you'd like him dead and who better to fake a Thumbprint killing than you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't actually believe I would do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If our jobs have taught us anything, Tracy, is that people do strange things. They just want to ask you some questions.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Atwood goes to leave the room. Snyder blocks her way.</context>
      <utterance>I will be happy to answer any questions after we check out this address.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to take you in, Tracy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the answer to the Thumbprint Killer, Snyder, and this is where I'm going and you're not going to stop me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Atwood smiles winningly.</context>
      <utterance>Don't make me cuff you, Tracy, because I will if I have to.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I believe you would.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can count on it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was great! It was fantastic! It was everything I hoped it would be. Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the back seat:</context>
      <utterance>You're welcome.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without taking his eyes off the road.</context>
      <utterance>Here comes the gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Smith slides a pistol from under his jacket and points it at Mr. Brooks.</context>
      <utterance>Yup.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're smart enough to figure that out, Mr. Brooks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well we're going sixty five miles an hour, Mr. Smith, if you shoot me now, there's a good chance we'll both die.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not now. Take the next off ramp.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He accelerates around a truck into the Fastlane. Mr. Smith can see the Exit coming up, it's quickly left behind.</context>
      <utterance>That wouldn't be very smart of me would it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think about this. You pissed yourself back there, you left your DNA at the scene of a double homicide, and there's nothing to indicate that I was ever there. If the Cops do an analysis of that urine, and they will, you're the Thumbprint Killer.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Smith doesn't have an answer for that.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. But what were you doing at the second murder?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me help you with a thought. You say I forced you to come along and if I'm not here or more specifically my body is not here to say different, you might have a chance to beat the rap. Now you're probably asking yourself why I would help you. I'm tired, Mr. Smith, I'm tired of killing. But I'm an addict, I can't quit. I've tried. I can't do it on my own. So I'll let you kill me but I want you to do it smart, in a way that I disappear and my family never knows what I was.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do I do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a cemetery I know about. We find an open grave, you shoot me, I fall in the grave, you shovel in just enough earth to cover me, tomorrow a casket is lowered onto me and I've disappeared. It's a good plan. What do you say?...</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why should I trust you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to trust me. You're the man holding the gun, you saw me put mine in the trunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. You really want me to kill you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay... But any sudden moves and you're dead on the spot and I'll make sure your family knows what you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks does as he's told. A key dangles from his fingers.</context>
      <utterance>Uh uh, take your hand out real slow.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's locked. You don't want to climb over, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing with a key to a cemetery?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I own it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks unlocks the gate and preceding Mr. Smith, goes inside.</context>
      <utterance>Why do you own a cemetery?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He locks the gate and handing the key to Mr. Smith:</context>
      <utterance>You always want to invest in things people can't do without. Water and cemeteries are pretty safe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MEEKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Atwood?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEEKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on down, there's something I want to show you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There we are. Now if I stand here... He positions himself at one end of the Grave.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... and you stand there, not too far away and you shoot me, I should fall straight back into the hole.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't think I have the guts to do this do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Brooks shuts off his light and straightens up.</context>
      <utterance>I'm hoping you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Smith raises his gun and points it at Mr. Brooks's head. He hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, let's get this over with.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He does. Mr. Smith pulls the trigger. Click! Mr. Smith looks in horror at the malfunctioning gun. Mr. Brooks opens his eyes. Mr. Smith aims the gun again. Click!... Click!</context>
      <utterance>I'll close my eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he talks he counters around until Mr. Smith is the one with his back to the open Grave.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He wrenches the shovel out of a mound of waiting earth. Mr. Smith tries to fire the gun at Mr. Brooks again.</context>
      <utterance>I really did want you to kill me. But in case at the last minute I changed my mind, I returned to your apartment and bent the firing pin on your gun.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unfortunately for you, my daughter is pregnant and just before you pulled the trigger, I realized how much I want to see the end to that story.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you do anything to me, if you touch one hair on my head, the Police will find the pictures of you killing that Couple.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without warning, Mr. Brooks swings the shovel. The force of the blow breaks Mr. Smith's left arm. He howls. The next blow comes almost immediately. It smashes into the left side of Mr. Smith's head. The screams stop and a misfiring set of neurons causes Mr. Smith to stand up straight and wobbling, look directly at Mr. Brooks. The blood streaming down his face is black in the moonlight. Mr. Brooks takes a step to the side, cocks his wrists and swings again. His full weight is behind this one. The blade of the shovel strikes Mr. Smith in the throat very nearly taking off his head. The flesh that was once Mr. Smith falls to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>The contents of your safety deposit box, Mr. Smith, have vanished.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Before I was the Thumbprint Killer, Mr. Smith, I killed a lot of people in a lot of different ways.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It says here the Thumbprint Killer is a monster... annoys you a little bit that you can't take credit, doesn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyone who is good at what they do, wants recognition. But since I'm not going to do it anymore, I'll let Mr. Smith take the credit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't kid yourself, Earl, you're going to kill again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the other stool next to Mr. Brooks is a WOMAN. Her large purse hangs open from the back of the stool; the cel phone clearly visible inside. Mr. Brooks looks at the phone.</context>
      <utterance>No, I'm not. I'll continue the AA meetings and I'll control it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But there is an answer I would like to have.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good work, Atwood.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves on. From off screen:</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Tom.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should ask the FBI to kiss your ass and buy you a Cadillac.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Snyder comes in and holds up the Work Order from the Moving Company.</context>
      <utterance>I like my ass too much for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is bogus. The company doesn't exist in the city, the state, the United States or Canada.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So the whole point of this piece of paper was to give me Meeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what it looks like.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? Who moved him, where did they move him to, and why did he give me Meeks?</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Atwood picks up the Newspaper.</context>
      <utterance>That's what we get paid to find out.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stands. The phone rings. She answers it.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to go to the bathroom and think about this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="143" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INTERCUT with Atwood.</context>
      <utterance>Why are you a cop?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're rich, you have a good education, you could have gone into your father's business, instead you went outside all of that and became successful on your own. Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want something from me if you don't tell me who you are I'm going to hang up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you think your husband's killing was random and I certainly didn't have to give you Meeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Snyder perks up. She points for him to get on the other line.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Baffert?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the answer?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't sound like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a little cold. Are you going to give me the answer?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="144" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Detective Atwood weighs her options and decides to go for it.</context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you if you can give me the true answer to my question.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father was very disappointed I was born a girl and he let me know that. I've spent my whole life trying to prove him wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait. You promised to tell me where you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Atwood and Snyder hear the click as Mr. Brooks hangs up.</context>
      <utterance>Me? I'm on top of a building.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE ATWOOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the Parking structure, Mr. Brooks holds the phone over the edge and drops it. We follow the phone down, down, down, until it hits the pavement and disintegrates.</context>
      <utterance>Why would he be interested in that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="145" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs at the handle of the scissors, but his blood makes them too slippery. He can't pull them out.</context>
      <utterance>Agghhh!!! Agghhh!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey, Earl, Earl...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="146" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>EMMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the pillow Mr. Brooks' eyes fly open.</context>
      <utterance>Wake up, wake up...</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were having a nightmare.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BROOKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh... I woke you up.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses him on the forehead.</context>
      <utterance>It's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMMA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Taking his hand, she lies back down. After a moment Mr. Brooks turns over on his side and looks directly at us. His lips begin to move but we can't hear what he's saying, so we move in on his face. It's not until it fills our view that we can hear the words.</context>
      <utterance>I'm here, go back to sleep, I'm here.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
