<movie id="400" title="Mumford">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>He squints through the dirty screen door but sees nothing, then knocks and turns away to survey the neighborhood.</context>
      <utterance>...Oh yeah, one other thing I need -- an angle.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was thinking -- if it weren't for bad luck, I wouldn't have any luck at all...</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDLADY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The Newcomer turns toward the door. Standing there, holding the screen open, is the LANDLADY. She's a knockout in a cheap, small-town way: a cotton dress that buttons down the front and clings with sweat to her generous curves.</context>
      <utterance>Can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Either my luck had just changed, or Fate just bought me another round of trouble.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>LANDLADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...not very fancy... house needs repairs... We haven't had a man around here for so long...</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The Landlady reaches the tiny landing at the top of the stairs and opens a door to a squalid room with a bed, bureau and tiny window. The Newcomer has to squeeze by her voluptuous body to get inside and look around. It doesn't take long. His gaze returns to the Landlady who is leaning against the door, chest thrust forward. He focusses on her fingers, toying with the button at her sweat-shiny cleavage.</context>
      <utterance>She kept yammerin' the whole time, but her hips were doing all the talking...</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The Newcomer takes a step in the Landlady's direction --</context>
      <utterance>It couldn't 'a been any clearer what the set-up was. The next move was up to me...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't tell me!</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have eighteen more minutes!</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to hear any more today.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Follett, do you trust me or don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't know... I only been seeing you --</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Without trust, there's no point to any of this. You might as well not come.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now hold on, I didn't say I didn't want to come --</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good, then go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're early... it's not ready. What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My patient had to leave early.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She comes over to the register with an order. Mumford is am[...] her, likes her a lot.</context>
      <utterance>Who was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does the phrase "nosy" have any meaning to you, Lily?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it's like... inquisitive.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was Henry Follett.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, you see him a lot. And it's very wrong to reveal it. Next you'll be saying what his problem is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want to know?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A Patron passes on the way out.</context>
      <utterance>You're terrible. I'm never telling you anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Doc... how's it going?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine, Vincent... how's yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long you been in this town?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I don't know...</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four months, two and a half weeks -- that's how long.  And you've already got more patients than those other two shrinks combined.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lily, I don't think even you could know that -- Lily sees something out the window.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford turns to look out the window. A young man of about 30, in jeans and a Hawaiian shirt, is skateboarding down the street at high speed, weaving in and out amongst the cars. He zips past the front of the restaurant.</context>
      <utterance>Look at that guy...</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know who that is, don't you?  You really don't? That's Skip Skipperton, man. He gets himself hit by a truck, this whole town shuts down.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LILY hands over Mumford's bagged order, rings it up. Back on track:</context>
      <utterance>Oh, so that's him? The Panda Man.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, what makes you so popular? What's your secret?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like me. How come?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford is smiling as he goes out. Another Patron, LIONEL DILLARD, a lawyer, brings his check to Lily, watching Mumford cross the street. Lily can't stand this guy.</context>
      <utterance>Not sure. Let me think about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the new psychiatrist?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Psychologist. He's not medical.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably thinks he's pretty smart. Lily gives him a look as she takes his money.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>NESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...so he already had the tattoo that said, "Naomi Forever"... and now they're broken up, see, and he has to have it removed. But while the scar is still healing, or whatever you call it when you have a tattoo removed, he meets Chandra. And it's serious, immediate love. So in no time, he's gone from the most gorgeous model in the world to the most gorgeous actress in North America.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, "in no time"?</utterance>
   <speaker>NESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In maybe three or four issues.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Weekly or monthly?</utterance>
   <speaker>NESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monthly! God, how shallow do you think Brad is? Why do I waste my time telling you this stuff?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you think you tell me, Nessa?</utterance>
   <speaker>NESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't do that thing...  ...that shrink thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She jams the cigarette in her mouth and flames the lighter, but is afraid to actually break his rules.</context>
      <utterance>It's a big part of the show.</utterance>
   <speaker>NESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford indicates "nothing".</context>
      <utterance>You really need to let people smoke in here, you know. It's perverse. What are they paying you to see me?</utterance>
   <speaker>NESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The school board doesn't pay you? What kind of deal is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's called pro bono.</utterance>
   <speaker>NESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pro boner?  Pro bono, huh? For whose good, supposedly?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's my bit for the community.</utterance>
   <speaker>NESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck the community.  There was this article my friends and I read. It was "25 Signs He's Great in Bed". It was very fascinating.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where was this?</utterance>
   <speaker>NESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?... The New York Times. The first one was -- "he handles produce well." Which we already knew!  The point is, you have a lot of the signs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You been spying on me in the supermarket, Nessa?</utterance>
   <speaker>NESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Have women found you attractive?</utterance>
   <speaker>NESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew you wouldn't answer. I've been thinking about what you said last time. How me trying to lose weight -- and constantly not -- is like a lot of people with addictions. How maybe I can't lose the weight, ever...  Which we already knew...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not quite what I said --</utterance>
   <speaker>NESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford waits.</context>
      <utterance>It's a really weird thing for a shrink to say... and then you said maybe people'd be happier if they'd accept that some things don't change -- that it'd be some kind of a relief or something...</utterance>
   <speaker>NESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I guess I'm just a dumb bitch, but how depressing is that moment -- the moment when you give up?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford looks up, smiles. Skip offers his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're Doc Mumford.  Skip Skipperton.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford waits, friendly. Skip runs out of gas, gets uneasy, glances around.</context>
      <utterance>Fine. Okay. Pretty good. I've been hoping we'd meet. I've heard a lot about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think we could...? Can I buy you a drink?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>..."Find the need and fill it" my dad used to say -- I guess a lot of dads say that -- but I did and it just took off.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No kidding... Panda. Where'd that come from?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Skip stares into his beer for a moment, as though the thought depresses him. He catches himself and snaps back --</context>
      <utterance>Panda? I've always liked giant pandas... I've been to China and seen them in the wild. That's the kind of thing I can do if I want... now. I can do pretty much anything I want to do these days.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Skip glances around, leans in, confidential.</context>
      <utterance>So now we make 23% of the modems in the market, which is pretty good.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford waits, watches. Skip gets uncomfortable.</context>
      <utterance>When I was growing up here, the town was about dead. The timber business was played out... Panda changed all that. Now, just about everybody in town either works for the company or depends on it somehow. Which is kinda the problem...</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like another beer?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah... scotch.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Skip heads off to the bar. Mumford looks around. Everybody is watching.</context>
      <utterance>Far out. Single malt?  Can I pick it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Skip beams. Mumford leans forward in the same confidential way Skip did before; he indicates that Skip should lean in too. Mumford is almost whispering --</context>
      <utterance>You want me... to be... your friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Skip confirms that's it.</context>
      <utterance>But that's not what's really going on...  ...What's really going on is... you have some problems and you want some therapy, but you feel it could be very bad for Panda Modem stock if word got out that you were having head problems.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I ask you a personal question?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course! That's exactly what I want.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Skip makes a face and gesture to indicate a large "YES!", but also total frustration and failure.</context>
      <utterance>Have you thought about getting a wife?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford considers that.</context>
      <utterance>When Panda started to happen, I was dating women from New York, San Francisco, L.A. They came out of the woodwork. Models, actresses, venture capitalists... These were not the kind of girls who were interested in me before I hit it... And you know what I discovered? I discovered these girls did not love me for myself. The majority of them didn't even like me. But a lot of them would've gladly become Mrs. Skipperton for a while. Can you imagine that -- marrying someone just because they've got money?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta pee.  Can I ask you something? This town is called Mumford... Been that way since... 18... 18-0... 18-0...  ...thirteen! Right?  Now here's the question -- Your name is Mumford, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that the question?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Skip takes a few steps toward the men's room, then comes back and leans down toward Mumford.</context>
      <utterance>You moved here from back East and your name is the same as this town. Is that right?  Far out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope you don't think I want you to do this for free. Just because we're gonna play it like we're friends, doesn't mean I won't pay you like a doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a lot of money. Do you know how much money I've got?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't tell me, 'cause I'm not going to tell you what I've got.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got three big ones.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm impressed. I couldn't make three million dollars if I lived three lifetimes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Skip stumbles off to take a leak. Mumford takes a moment to digest that. It's difficult.</context>
      <utterance>No, no... I have three billion dollars.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LIONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...so I'm watching Brokaw and they've got some astronomer, this little limey know-it-all, and he's telling how, with this Himball telescope, they've discovered there are maybe 400 million more galaxies than they thought there were. And I guess that's supposed to make me feel small? I'm supposed to feel insignificant? Is that the point? Because I can tell you it didn't. Mumfords eyes dart to look at -- THE CLOCK on the bookshelf: 2:23</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lionel is twisting his neck around painfully to look back at Mumford.</context>
      <utterance>Lionel, since this is our first session together, maybe --</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- you can sit up and look at me if you'd like --  -- maybe it would be helpful if you told me a little about what brought you here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Lionel goes on, Mumford's eyes again dart toward -- THE CLOCK: still 2:23! Hold on it. Finally, it moves. Mumford's eyes dart toward his desk -- A deadly-looking letter opener in the shape of Excalibur stands GLINTING LIGHT in a marble rendition of Arthur's stone.</context>
      <utterance>Kind of impatient for a big-time headshrinker, aren't you? How 'bout you let me explain it my own way...</utterance>
   <speaker>LIONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford's head rocks slowly back for a moment as if he's going to drift off. He snaps back to life and stares hard at the top of Lionel's head, where there is a bald spot starting to take hold. The sound of LIONEL'S VOICE begins to echo --</context>
      <utterance>...and in the dream, it's always the same, I wake up in my room from when I was I kid in Ohio, and I realize this is the day of the big exam at school...</utterance>
   <speaker>LIONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MUMFORD'S GLANCE FLASHPANS from Lionel's bald spot to the gleaming letter opener. Mumford closes his eyes. We CUT TO:</context>
      <utterance>...which is no problem for me, because I remembered it was coming and I've attended every class, so I'm totally prepared. Then I see myself running down the hall at school...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LIONEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...but it's not really my school -- and this is very interesting -- it's the school from the next district --</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Go on!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LIONEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>WHAT YOUNG LIONEL SEES: Everyone in the class, including the Teacher in the front, is naked. The Teacher holds out an exam toward Young Lionel.</context>
      <utterance>And even though I arrive a little bit early, everybody's already there. But the surprising part is --</utterance>
   <speaker>LIONEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- I'm the only one who's prepared!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LIONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- you crazy? You can't do this!</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure I can, Lionel.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a criminal lawyer -- you think I like my clients? I can't stand most of them! But I don't kick them out...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lionel looks around, but there is no such sign. He does spot Althea watching the show from the couch.</context>
      <utterance>See that sign -- We retain the right to refuse service to anyone. I'm not going to charge you for this session, but I don't want to see you back here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you at least have a back door I can use?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Althea stands up, smiling. She thinks Mumford is the bee's knees.</context>
      <utterance>Come out this way. There's no shame in getting a little therapy... is there, Althea?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lionel steams by them in a black mood.</context>
      <utterance>Not at all. It takes guts, Lionel.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe some of us don't need this crap!</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lionel bangs out the front door. Mumford motions Althea inside --</context>
      <utterance>And it's the Hubble Telescope, not the Himball Telescope.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Althea heads inside, giggling wildly. She can't get enough of this guy.</context>
      <utterance>Jeez... what an asshole.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ALTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do they want from me?  What have I done that's so wrong?  They act as though they don't have their own peculiar things... They do! Believe me. Everybody's got something...  Even you probably have things.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me more than most.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are they ganging up against me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure. But I think they're worried about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the kids, you know, not Jeremy. He had nothing to do with this -- except pay, of course. He's always willing to pay. He's extremely generous.  I'm so humiliated that my own children would threaten me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did they threaten you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They said if I didn't get help, they wouldn't deal with me any more.  What do you think about that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Althea stares at him a long moment. She knows he's right. Tears well up in her eyes and roll down her cheeks. She grabs another Kleenex. In the midst of the torrent she tries to talk, but it's undecipherable:</context>
      <utterance>Good kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmmmfffstttubll abbittmm.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Althea uses three new tissues to dry up her face.</context>
      <utterance>Hmm?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said... you must come out to the house for dinner on Thursday.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? You think so?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford considers, then nods his assent.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Jeremy will be home for the weekend. And you can meet the kids.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How ya doin', Ainge? Evenin', Lily.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dog leaps gracefully back into the yard. Mumford hurries up the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Doc.  Ainge...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Mumford.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Cook.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mystified, Mumford follows Cook through the door into the back. BACK OF THE STORE. Cook motions for Mumford to take the seat of honor in the work area, but Mumford prefers to stand. Cook has a little trouble figuring how to start. Finally --</context>
      <utterance>Could you come with me please?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know I shoulda come to your office. I was gonna, actually, but then when you walked in here today...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's my daughter Sofie... she's gotta problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not sure. She's been to all kinds of doctors in the city and they've said different things. Some of 'em are callin' it --  -- Epstein-Barr virus, and the rest are callin' it... Chronic Fatigue Symptom...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Syndrome... Chronic Fatigue Syndrome.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it -- syndrome. So you know all about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... a little. There's a lot of debate about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I got that. Some people think it's all in their heads.  It's been so bad she's had to move back here to Mumford and live with us. And I'm not sure that's the best thing, either...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh... a lot of things. Several different factors. Will you see her, Doctor Mumford?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cook nods, but looks worried.</context>
      <utterance>Sure. Why don't you bring her up to my office at 3 tomorrow afternoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure she'll come. She's in a mood. Do you ever go to somebody's house?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cook is quick to agree; he doesn't want to make waves. But he's worried.</context>
      <utterance>Generally that doesn't work out so well. It sends the wrong message to people who need to make a change.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Lionel.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got to have the right ladder for the job. You don't know what you're doing, you can get yourself in trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford continues up the street. We STAY WITH Lionel, who watches Mumford with a sour look, then turns to enter a small medical building.</context>
      <utterance>You're right, as usual. See you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LIONEL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...completely inappropriate and highly unprofessional. Now I don't want to presume to tell you how to run your businesses --</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lionel is sitting across the room, making an ardent case --</context>
      <utterance>-- practices.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Whatever. Six months ago, you two were the only games in town. The value of your...  ..."practices" could be seriously undermined by this bozo. A town this size has only so many headcases to go around.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELBANCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What exactly would you have us do, Lionel?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Delbanco and Sheeler exchange a look; they find Lionel distasteful.</context>
      <utterance>Protect your turf! Check this guy out. I smell a rat, I tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Dillard, I'm sure Dr. Delbanco shares my gratitude for your concern. But I also know he'd agree that you misunderstand the nature of our calling to mental health. We're not in some... widget business, trying to crush our competition.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell's a widget?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DELBANCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What an asshole!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ernest, what do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELBANCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>So does she.</context>
      <utterance>I think he's got a point.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Skip, you must have lots of people you can throw a ball with.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd be surprised. Most guys have kids or wives or girlfriends. They're busy. It's not as easy as you think.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Skip, you're the head of the whole deal here. Are they busier than you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford considers. SLAP... SLAP... SLAP.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you know... that's the thing. Like I said, just about everybody in town works for me. And it's just not the same asking someone to throw a ball when they work for you. It's like an order or something... And no one -- no one -- asks me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, would you say we're out here... let me think how to put this... Is your problem really that you're... lonely?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell yes, I like it. What's better than this? Most guys would kill just to have someone do this with them whenever they like.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay then.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode>SLAP... SLAP</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you got a lot of friends?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lily and I talk a bit. You know Lily, runs the coffee shop?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... I've seen her. Good-looking woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's probably ten years older than you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode>SLAP... SLAP</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good-looking woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lives downstairs from me. She's got a great dog named for Danny Ainge.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? I'm the only person I know that likes Danny Ainge, outside of Celtic fans. Maybe Phoenix.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, there's Lily.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you know that Danny Ainge was drafted by the Blue Jays? Do you know what kind of athlete you have to be to play in the NBA and in the bigs?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amazing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unbelievable...</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode>SLAP... SLAP</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...And Lily named her dog after him? Far out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford gestures off in the one direction we have not yet seen.</context>
      <utterance>What kind of person do you have to be to do this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford takes that in. SLAP... SLAP.</context>
      <utterance>I would've traded any of it to have made the Mumford High varsity.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I guess Henry Follett is a patient of yours. He's my pharmacist.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>SLAP... SLAP</mode>
      <context>Skip is a little surprised to hear this from Mumford, but he just throws the ball.</context>
      <utterance>Guy's got some serious sex fantasies.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretty good, too. Lots of detail. Nothing hard core. Old-fashioned ones, from back when people cared about atmosphere and character.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Problem is, his fantasy life's a lot better than his real one. Nothing can live up to it. His wife got sick of it and left him. Took his kids with her.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Skip is fascinated, but a little uncomfortable. Mumford seems oblivious, unusually talkative --</context>
      <utterance>I wondered what happened to her...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For the first time, Mumford throws the ball way high, like a long fly ball. Skip, delighted as a dog, takes off running and just barely catches it on the run. He pegs it back to Mumford.</context>
      <utterance>Of course, it's not that simple. There's something powerful going on there. We've got a lot of work to do.  It's hit to the warning track!</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In these fantasies, Henry Follett is played by a handsome guy with biceps. Can you imagine that? Where your self-esteem has to be?  Man, I'd just like to move the guy to the point where he gets to appear in his own fantasies.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="30">
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Feel free to lie down. Most people do.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A joke. Mumford smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I'd better not, I'll fall right to sleep. I think it's too soon for me to be sleeping with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can you tell me about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's taken all her energy to say this and she sinks down a bit into the couch.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, lord. It's almost too exhausting to tell you...  ...about my exhaustion. I didn't really want to come. I'm not hopeful right now. But I couldn't take the look on my dad's face. He's a truly kind person, which is pretty extraordinary if you knew the story. He's the opposite of me, I guess -- all stamina and resolve.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When did you start to feel this way?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sees something in his face and suddenly laughs -- it's a weak but magical sound.</context>
      <utterance>About six months ago, I guess it is now. God, it seems like years. What a bore! I'm embarrassed by it. Before this happened -- when I'd hear people talk about this kind of thing -- I thought it was a bunch of bullshit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think that now! You think it's a bunch of hooey, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford is knocked off balance -- she's right. She saw him clearly.</context>
      <utterance>I saw it. I saw it in your eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's okay. Maybe it is. My mother always says -- "Everything that's wrong with you is in your head." I suppose that's true.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Back when this started, was there anything unusual happening in your life? A change of job, of living situation... a loss of some kind?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... but it started one year to the day after my divorce became final. That's not too suspicious, is it?... But it wasn't like I was feeling bad about the divorce. Just the opposite.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmm.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmm? Is that a professional opinion?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmm, as in -- that's interesting. Sometimes, with enough clues, it's possible to figure these things out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even if you don't think it's real?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what's real and what isn't. That's never been my strong suit. But if you're tired all the time and you've had to give up the life you were having and come back home when you didn't want to... that's worth trying to fix. Maybe I can help you do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What would you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We... we would try several things. But I need to see you a lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I barely made it today.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sofie suddenly looks defeated.</context>
      <utterance>I'll come to you. We'll try a little walking.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll take it slow. You'll never feel you can't handle it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think I can afford it. I don't want my dad paying.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sofie gives him a long look.</context>
      <utterance>We'll work it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have the best answer for everything.  You seem so... hopeful. Are you always this sunny?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one ever thought so. You must bring it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it contagious? 'Cause everyone agrees my immune system's way down.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you'll catch it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford just smiles. He doesn't want to tell her the truth -- everything.</context>
      <utterance>Can I ask you something?  Didn't you tell my dad you didn't think it was a good idea to come to the patient?  So what changed?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ALTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She disappears inside with a bang of the screen door. Mumford gets a drink for himself, taking in the view. He sees something out there. MUMFORD'S POV: Way in the distance, coming out of the woods and down toward the house is a teenage boy.</context>
      <utterance>I'm awful I know, but will you please help yourself. I just got a new copper sauciere from Williams-Sonoma and I'm afraid it'll be the death of us all if I don't get back in there...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATIE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Mumford turns to see that Althea's thirteen year old daughter KATIE has silently appeared. Her jeans and little tee-shirt are meant to be sexy; it seems sad on her. Mumford nods.</context>
      <utterance>You're the doctor, aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must be Katie. People call me Doc.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford follows as she disappears around the corner of the porch.</context>
      <utterance>C'mere. Quick... c'mon!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this him?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I showed him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEREMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seeing Mumford, Jeremy steps out onto the porch to shake his hand. Jeremy is quite handsome and a fantastic dresser; his Armani outfit cost $4200 all in. His tone: hearty and strained --</context>
      <utterance>Hey, kids. Oh, hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEREMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must be Dr. Mumford of Mumford. Jeremy Brockett.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doc. Nice to meet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEREMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeremy goes inside. Martin and Katie exchange a look with each other, then to Mumford. Martin goes inside.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry I'm late... traffic was a motherfucker. Have another drink, I'll be back in five.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>ALTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes inside. The men each have a snifter of cognac. Jeremy makes a ceremony of cutting the cigars --</context>
      <utterance>I'll be back.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEREMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you'll like this. Know much about Cuban cigars?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeremy puts the cigars down, pulls a joint out of his cashmere pullover and fires it up. After exhaling a huge cloud of smoke, he offers the joint to Mumford, who declines.</context>
      <utterance>Nope.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEREMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeremy takes another hit on the joint and puts it down. He gives a cigar and his gold lighter to Mumford, who begins to light up --</context>
      <utterance>Makes the whole thing that much better.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEREMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford does as he's told. Jeremy lights his own cigar.</context>
      <utterance>Just hold the flame a little bit below the end... that's it... now just turn it slowly as you draw...</utterance>
   <speaker>JEREMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you a man who likes to treat himself right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've had my moments.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEREMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am. And I'm not ashamed of it. Nobody ever said on their death bed -- "I treated myself too well."</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought it was -- Nobody ever said, "I should have spent more time at the office."</utterance>
   <speaker>JEREMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fill in the blank. I don't mind the office. The point is, you only go 'round once. Like the Zens say -- Be here now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEREMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Althea hasn't told you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've been talking about her, mostly.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEREMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, in '85 four of us left our firms and formed an investment banking venture. We've got twenty-three people working there now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The marijuana is kicking in now -- Jeremy gets a self- satisfied, condescending look on his face that no straight mind would dare. His response includes their lavish immediate surroundings--</context>
      <utterance>You've done well.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEREMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've done... very well. You know anything about addiction, Doc?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEREMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm addicted to winning. I say when you're in the red zone, you gotta score.  So what do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tastes good.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEREMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... I mean about Althea. About her...  ...behavior. Do you think you can fix her up?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think's wrong with her?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEREMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeremy blows cigar smoke into his snifter, then takes a mouthful of cognac, savoring the sensations. Mumford watches, fascinated by this guy.</context>
      <utterance>She's gone weird is what's wrong with her. Out of control. Probably from living out here in Mayberry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEREMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the doctor, what do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeremy gives him a look, as if to say "duh."</context>
      <utterance>She seems very unhappy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEREMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford looks at him a long time.</context>
      <utterance>I think we all knew that, professor. The question... the real --  -- quest-tio-nee... is... why?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you know how to drive?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got a license?  But no car?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't need it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just got my license two weeks ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I been drivin' since I was twelve.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That would explain it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you help Mom?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm trying.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They drive in silence for a bit. Then --</context>
      <utterance>Got to.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford gives him a surprised look, then acknowledges it.</context>
      <utterance>Nessa Watkins... She comes to you, doesn't she? You're treating her, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with her?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is she a friend of yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford knew that.</context>
      <utterance>No... sort of. Man, she could be cool, but all she does is get wrecked and do all the guys. She's blowin' them in the parking lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford regards Martin with respect, then turns to look out front. After a few moments --</context>
      <utterance>A person's got to hate themselves to act like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you ever met a bigger shithead than my stepfather?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ainge!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's okay. Jeremy won't mind. Good dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dog obediently leaves Martin and runs back to Lily. Mumford waves as Martin pulls away.</context>
      <utterance>Ainge!</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do we run into the street? No, I didn't think so.  Nice car. How's that place?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk up the block with the dog.</context>
      <utterance>It's a pretty piece of land.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the Brocketts?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Horror show. What'd you do tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was insane here, man. 'Hadda call in the National Guard.  Then I did my laundry... watched</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...And?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shocking. Did you know the government is wasteful?  You heard it here first. Oh, and being a supermodel... it's no walk in the park.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you watch?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford laughs.</context>
      <utterance>No gentleman caller, Doc.  Not that I care. I've had it with men. They're so fascinated by their own crap. Took me four years to get the last one out. Almost turned me into a dyke... These days my idea of a hot date is a long shower by myself before bed. Now that feels good. And you don't have to do all that... listening.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oops... sorry. I guess that's the story of your life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not making any promises.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll turn back anytime you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Mother. I want you to meet Dr. Mumford.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mumford... like the town?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She finally takes his hand, but it's not friendly.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. It's nice to meet you, Mrs. Cook.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's happening here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going for a walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think that's a good idea?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Mumford does, yes. I've put myself completely in his hands. For today, anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of doctor are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ph.D., psychologist.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh... not a real doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Cook is not amused. Sofie pulls on Mumford.</context>
      <utterance>That's right, the fake kind.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Cook steps aside as they move up the walk.</context>
      <utterance>We'd better go or I'm liable to bail on the whole thing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom's such a cutie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People usually have to get to know me before they hate me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's not in a bad mood. She's like that all the time.  It doesn't bother me anymore. It's my dad and my brother I worry about.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe... but you're the one whose ass is dragging.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that the technical description of what I've got?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is she against you getting help?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't discuss it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something's bothering her.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sofie suddenly seems to be fading.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, we've all disappointed her. Me, especially, but Dad, of course. She thinks my brother's all right, but she didn't expect much. It's what happens when you "marry beneath yourself"...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please... forgive me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him, unsure if he's serious. It seems so corny. But she agrees.</context>
      <utterance>Negative thinking makes everything more difficult. If you're going to have enough strength to do this, we have to talk only about positive things. All right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay then... Are you positive your mother's a bitch?  Just kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got a funny idea of funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've offended you!</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She laughs again; surprised again. He's got her off balance makes a "rim shot" sound.</context>
      <utterance>Really? What would it take?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this the treatment?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry... I'm done.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They've come to the corner. He gestures to ask -- "shall we cross?" She considers for quite a while, gauging her strength, then, still on his arm, steps off the curb --</context>
      <utterance>'Cause I'll tell you, none of the others have tried this approach.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, 'Just do it!' THEY CROSS OUT OF FRAME as we HEAR:</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to tell me all your symptoms.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm embarrassed. The list is so long.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be specific.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... I'm tired all the time, obviously. I always feel like taking a nap. But when I try to sleep, I have trouble.  My muscles ache. And my joints. I feel like an old person, or like I did back when I used to work out too hard... What else?...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sore throat?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>ON THE SCREEN: "Low grade fever... Painful lymph glands... Irritability..."</context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Low grade fever?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Painful lymph glands?  Forget fulness... irritability... depression?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, yes, and definitely yes. Also... I get confused.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, most people have that. It's confusing here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know if I mentioned the headaches.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you get headaches before this?  But you get more now? Or more severe?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not really. They're about the same. My marriage was one long headache.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She considers that, reluctantly agrees.</context>
      <utterance>So the headaches may not even be a part of this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can give myself a headache instantly.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that like a party trick?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sofie's not sure how to take that. She looks away.</context>
      <utterance>All I have to do is have two conflicting thoughts at the same time... Like I'll think -- 'Taking these walks is going to help Sofie get better.' But then I'll also think -- 'Mumford, you just enjoy taking these walks and you're kidding yourself about the benefits.'</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There... I've given myself a real whopper.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You actually address yourself by name in your thoughts?  So you really think having two opposing ideas in your head does some kind of damage?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes, yeah... pulling in two different directions at once. It makes tiny little tears in our fabric.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well then, my life has been some kind of huge rip.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>IN THE BATHROOM MIRROR, the Newcomer's POV: a nubile teenager, 17 going on 35, in a tight cheerleader's outfit, comes up the stairs and stops at the top to turn and yell back down at her mother. Her dialogue distant and echoey:</context>
      <utterance>The town was a rube's heaven, but I found work my first day out down at Old Man Sutter's gas station and diner. I knew his stacked young wife was going to be a problem, but, hey, life is full of problems. Back at the boarding house, I was washing up when I heard a load of yellin' and --</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDLADY'S DAUGHTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...get off my case! You don't like any of my friends...</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The LANDLADY'S DAUGHTER looks up and sees the Newcomer watching her through the half-open bathroom door. She gives him a petulant, white-hot look, then turns on her heel and goes into her room at that end of the hall. She bangs her door behind her, but it bounces open again about a foot. The Newcomer, still watching in the bathroom mirror, now has a view of the bureau mirror in the Landlady's Daughter's room. In there, seemingly oblivious, the girl quickly strips off the top of her outfit, revealing a '50's-era white bra.</context>
      <utterance>...I got my first look at the landlady's daughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Suddenly, in mirror reflection of mirror, the Landlady's Daughter meets the Newcomer's smoldering stare and her lip begins to curl.</context>
      <utterance>Lucky for me, she was plenty upset but not too careful.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or maybe it wasn't an accident at all --</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Follett.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- 'cause in that instant I saw the beginning of a vixen's smile and I knew --</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Mysteriously, the door to the girl's bedroom slams shut, cutting off the Newcomer's view. He looks with surprise into his mirror -- it suddenly shatters.</context>
      <utterance>Henry!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop now.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? I'm paying for this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not for this. Not me, you're not.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You find it distasteful, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't matter how I feel about it. It's how you feel about it that matters.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I enjoy it. Does that make me some kind of pervert? Just because a man has a rich imaginative life --</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't come to me because you have a rich imagination.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You came because it's taking over. You're in its grip.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford's tone suddenly picks up a touch of steel.</context>
      <utterance>I never said that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Follett flinches, settles back down onto the couch, sulking.</context>
      <utterance>Where's your wife, Henry?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's your wife, Henry?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go to hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Follett mutters something to himself, then is silent until --</context>
      <utterance>I didn't hear you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got divorced.  I had to get rid of her. She couldn't satisfy me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Follett seems to shrink in size. They've been here before and he doesn't like it.</context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was... never satisfied.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again, Follett says something under his breath.</context>
      <utterance>Now we're back on track.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are so mean.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Skip.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doc. I know we're not supposed to get together till Wednesday...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford indicates that Skip should walk with him up the trail.</context>
      <utterance>That's all right. What's on your mind?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many sessions have we had now, Doc?  Six. And it's been good... like we were two buddies hanging out. Just shootin' the shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk in silence for a while.</context>
      <utterance>Yep.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is really hard. Everything I want to say is hard...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="39">
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He checks Mumford's reaction. Mumford nods, offers Skip water, who turns it down. Mumford takes a swig.</context>
      <utterance>...We're like friends, almost... who trust each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to tell you something, Doc, but before I do, I need to ask you a question... Because, for me to tell you this thing -- well, I haven't told anybody about this. It's the biggest secret I've got.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes it's best to keep a few things just for ourselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a shrink, Doc. Aren't I supposed to be able to tell you everything?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Skip, even more unsure now, looks away, at the town below.</context>
      <utterance>It's just a thought.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford lets that hang a few moments, then acknowledges it silently. Now Skip is even more nervous.</context>
      <utterance>That really relates to the thing I want to ask you... I've noticed that sometimes, not a lot, but sometimes, when we're hanging out, throwin' the ball... or that time we went bowling... sometimes you'll like --  -- tell me things about your other patients.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, maybe that's all right! I don't know all that much about psychology or therapy or... ethics, so maybe there's something I missed... or something...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're concerned that maybe I can't be trusted with a secret.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford looks at Skip for a long moment.</context>
      <utterance>I trust you. Definitely. No question. But, yeah, I'm a little concerned. I mean, you're not supposed to tell anyone about your patients' problems... are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The conversation seems to end there. Skip's not sure where to go next. Finally --</context>
      <utterance>That is correct, Skip. I'm going to have to take a long look at that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well... what I was gonna tell you --</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Skip. Knowing what you do about me --</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Skip looks around at the darkening woods, though clearly there's no one around.</context>
      <utterance>Doc, I trust you! You've listened to me better than anybody... maybe ever.  And this secret I've got, I can't stand it anymore. I don't know if I'm some kind of --</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Skip closes his eyes for a second and gathers himself.</context>
      <utterance>-- I don't know if I'm a pervert or what. It's taken me this long to get where I can come out and say it... I can't back away now. I can't spend another day not knowing if I'm nuts.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, I'm just gonna tell you, as simple and direct as I can.  And you understand that this is a big secret? Just between us?  Okay. You know I've got this gift for certain kinds of... machines.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are Panda, monarch of modems.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. And you also know that even though I make 23% of the modems in the world... I cannot make one simple connection with any woman who could truly love me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay... let's say that, for now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford shakes his head, "no."</context>
      <utterance>It's true, believe me. So... do you know what I've been doing, all alone, in my workshop, for almost two years?... Mr. Find-the-Need-and-Fill- It. How I spend my every solitary hour?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guess.  Go ahead, guess!</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jerking off?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford tries to put that all together. Finally --</context>
      <utterance>No!... Although that's a good guess. No, what I've been working on, what the world really needs and no one has been able to create --  -- a virtually life-like, humanoid, gender-specific, anatomically functional... sexual surrogate slash companion.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Slash what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sexual surrogate... slash... companion.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A doll?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford considers that a long time, watching as the sun finally sinks below the horizon. He looks back at Skip.</context>
      <utterance>No, Doc, not a doll. I am Panda. I'm talking about much, much more than a doll. The world has never seen what I'm talking about... except maybe in the movies.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's it coming?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't think I'm insane?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that's your secret?  You meant -- like a trade secret?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Doc, a private secret! It's perverted, it's pitiful. What am I -- Dr. Frankenstein? Aren't you repulsed?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds like kind of a good idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's getting dark fast now. Mumford reaches into his bag and takes out the headlamp we saw earlier. He fits the straps carefully over his head.</context>
      <utterance>Definitely.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Skip, that's not much of a secret.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford twists the headlamp and the light shines out in the dusk. Mumford turns the beam directly at Skip.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, it's okay. It's just not something to be ashamed of. Maybe you don't want people knowing -- and believe me, it's safe with me -- but on the scale of dirty little secrets, I'd give it, say... a two.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Skip, hanging on every word now, agrees emphatically.</context>
      <utterance>You want to know a secret? I'll tell you a secret. Since it's just between us and all...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At first, Skip thinks he's misunderstood Mumford. But in the huge silence that ensues, he replays it and knows he's heard right. Mumford looks around, adjusts his headlamp, and gets up.</context>
      <utterance>The secret, Skip, is this -- I am not now, nor have I ever been... a psychologist.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'd better get going. Just follow my light. And, Skip, watch your step.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who else knows?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford takes a drink of beer.</context>
      <utterance>It's time you did some talkin', Dr. Mum -- Wait a minute. That is your name, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn! What is your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't matter. You can call me Doc.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford gestures: "sorry, no can do."</context>
      <utterance>It matters to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've told you a lot of private stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can tell you anything else.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford looks at Skip, considering. He takes a long pull from his beer, then looks at the frosty bottle.</context>
      <utterance>What about everything? How did this happen?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AS MUMFORD TALKS we SEE IMAGES FROM HIS PAST, all FROM MUMFORD'S POV. We do not see him in the scenes. Instead, everyone else in the scene RELATES TO THE CAMERA AS MUMFORD, even if they're just ignoring him.</context>
      <utterance>Did you know that every species of mammal has found some way to drug, inebriate, or anestnetize itself? Even if it's just banging its head against a rock. Seems to be some natural urge... to get away for a while.  I've had it for as long as I can remember. The first place I wanted out of was home...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>AT THE DINNER TABLE. Across the table, MUMFORD'S OLDER SISTER eats with her head down. On the right, Mumford's Mother is picking at her food. Mumford's POV shifts to his Father, who is yelling something at his wife.</context>
      <utterance>I thought I had the best parents in Bald Knob, West Virginia... till I was seven years old and got a look at some others. They weren't bad folks...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Now, his Father looks suddenly at Mumford; his hand shoots out to slap Mumford's face, and the IMAGE GOES BLACK, then immediately FADES UP AGAIN on --</context>
      <utterance>...but they were real unhappy about being who they were...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>MUMFORD'S POV lifts from the fountain and turns to the endless, deserted corridor of the huge building. We begin TRACKING DOWN the hall, checking out the various doorways. A Cleaning Crew appears far up ahead.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't want to jump into my career right out of college. And since I had no career, that turned out to be not much of a problem...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had a series of challenging jobs over the next few years...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford stands up and stretches, then sits on the railing facing Skip.</context>
      <utterance>...pizza delivery, pipe fitting, pest control... lots of jobs that started with the letter "p". For some reason, I kept losing these jobs.  The only mind-altering substance I never had a problem with was alcohol. I never got drunk. I didn't like the feeling. But really, when you're as fucked up as I was... big deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eventually, doing all these different jobs, I noticed something. For some reason, probably because I was too stoned to talk, everywhere I went --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The cinderblock tips over and a swarm of scary-looking spiders comes rushing out toward camera.</context>
      <utterance>Anyway, one day I was spraying for termites when I had a vision --</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- it was time to put my college degree to work and get a job with a desk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>SERIES OF SHOTS: computer records scrolling rapidly, paper files being pulled, documents being routed.</context>
      <utterance>I took the civil service exam and found myself working at the Internal Revenue Service, District 14, Central Administrative Office. I started off as a general records clerk...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess the standards weren't too high there, because my superiors got excited and pushed me to take the advancement tests...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>His POV PANS with a couple of intense COLLECTION AGENTS who pass behind the first scene on their way out of the offices.</context>
      <utterance>But I sure didn't want to be a Revenue Officer, where you were face to face abusing -- and getting abused -- all day long...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>His POV STOPS, letting the Collection Agents go, on another fellow, with the disreputable, cocksure demeanor of a private dick, who is lolling near the water cooler, watching the altercation with amusement. He is GREGORY, an IRS</context>
      <utterance>...And being a Collection Agent was definitely not in my genetic make- up...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But there was one job that looked like it might be fun -- Investigator.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you telling me your last job before becoming a psychologist was --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- an investigator for the Internal Revenue Service?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody has a story, Skip.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds like you have several.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What it felt like was... a series of separate, unconnected lives -- hillbilly kid, wrecked college boy, garbage man, civil service guy...  ...et cetera... et cetera. Every time I'd leave a life, it felt good. Whatever problems I was having were suddenly gone. I had no friends and I didn't talk to my family. The only constant, stabilizing force in my life was... drugs.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An IRS investigator with a drug problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wasn't the best situation.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you carry a gun?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't need one. We didn't even need a warrant for most of the shit we did. Man, the IRS... we could go in your bank account, your credit cards... hell, we used to go into doctors' files and get all the juicy details. Nobody wants to argue with the IRS.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>WHAT THEY SEE: The DRY CLEANING BOSS, a Middle-Eastern fellow, is standing at the back door of his place paying his Asian employees in cash as they leave.</context>
      <utterance>I got teamed with one of the top guys, a fanatic named Gregory. He always got his man, whether they deserved it or not. He was a "closer" and everybody admired that...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Gregory turns to look at camera (Mumford) with a devilish grin.</context>
      <utterance>He'd make the case and the Collection guys would come in and clean up. Our specialty was... sleazy skulking...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were a good team. I was a dope addict and Gregory was insane.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course, him being insane didn't make it all right that I fell in love with his wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy shit!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Get to know your therapist."</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were messed up, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But look at me now...</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Skip stops, remembers the truth, realizes. Mumford smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, you've done good. Look at yourself... you've cleaned up, you've got a career --</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least you pulled yourself out...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Things got a lot worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You and Candy...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Mumford follows Gregory, crawling, to the edge of the roof and looks down on a building one block over. It is a small furniture factory. Employees are eating their lunches on the loading dock.</context>
      <utterance>The way the District Managers got ahead and won their bonuses was by generating maximum payments. That meant the revenue officers had to use all their "collection tools" -- seizures, liens, levies -- even if a more reasonable compromise could have been worked out. The best way to reduce resistance from the taxpayers was to build a convincing case -- whether there'd actually been a violation or not...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's where we came in. Our DM was a particular sonuvabitch, and he knew just how to get Gregory crazy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Giving up, Mumford slams the medicine cabinet shut and FOR THE FIRST TIME SINCE HIS STORY BEGAN, WE SEE MUMFORD in his previous incarnation. And this is probably as bad as he ever looked. He stares at his image in the mirror.</context>
      <utterance>...In fact, I was jealous of Candy. I wanted to leave too, just like her... get as far away from --</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- me... as possible.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford nods.</context>
      <utterance>And so you did...</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the drugs?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harder than I thought. Took me three tries. But I was highly motivated -- figured there was no point in leaving me and taking that along. After two bomb-outs, I found a place in the desert...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford goes inside. Skip sits listening to the night. From downstairs, in Lily's apartment, he HEARS A SHOWER GO ON. Mumford comes back out.</context>
      <utterance>...which seemed perfect for starting something new. Be back.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody's taking a shower down there.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That'd be Lily.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish I could live in the shower. I'd take five a day if I had the time. I went to this spa in Germany, a sanitarium practically, up on this mountain. And the great thing -- they just kept you wet all day.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who'd you go with?  That's not good.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd you do it?  The new you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know how easy it is. A kid can manage it if he wants a fake I.D. You can do practically the whole deal at your local Kinko's. The only variable is how much pride you take in the product.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know it starts with a birth certificate...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All new people start with that...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that like a mimeograph?... What about the name?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Mumford"... I mean, why pick the name of the town you were going to?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. You got it backwards. I already had the name when I started looking for somewhere to settle. When I saw this town on a map, I thought maybe it was a sign. See...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>ON A KITCHEN TABLE, the new birth certificate, now filled out for Michael Mumford, is carefully lifted from a shallow bowl of light tea (the tea bags are nearby). The paper has taken on an aged, sepia look. CUT TO: A STACK OF BOOKS. The ones on top are lifted away. The bottom book is opened to reveal the birth certificate. It has been folded in an official way. Now Mumford unfolds it, then refolds it differently -- with its smudges and creases, it's starting to look old.</context>
      <utterance>...Mickey Mumford was in Miss Rice's kindergarten class with me. He was killed with his parents in a wreck on their way back from a Steelers game. He was only six years old, which is a real plus, so there's a birth certificate if anyone checks -- but not much else. They died in Pennsylvania, so there's no death certificate in West Virginia... that's also good.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And a birth certificate is enough?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>SERIES OF SHOTS of Mumford's DOCUMENTATION PILING UP. A post office box is emptied, official-looking correspondence is opened, the bounty is laid out for perusal: Social Security card, driver's license, college and graduate school diplomas, license and accreditation to operate as a therapist.</context>
      <utterance>Everything flows from that, and what doesn't... can be easily purchased.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course, my IRS training made it easier. Once you've done that, there's not much data you can't access and use any way you want.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Skip looks upset.</context>
      <utterance>In a free society, you are who you say you are.  People should remember that before they go around knocking this country.  Skip, all this beer's got me sleepy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you studied psychology, right? You did the training and just never got the degree?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... no training.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Psych major?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>English Lit.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeez, man. But you're good at it!</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He heads inside.</context>
      <utterance>I understand what it's like to want to leave a problem behind. That's all most people are looking to do.  Mainly, I listen.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where ya going? I've got a million questions.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford goes inside. Skip nods, head spinning.</context>
      <utterance>See you Thursday... regular time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford hands her another paper, which she heaves with all her limited strength, missing the front porch badly. Mumford, who can't get enough of watching her, doesn't notice at first.</context>
      <utterance>...so we get on this incredible steam engine train that runs up into the mountains...  ...and this trip is everything it's cracked up to be... an open car, great views, the mountain air blowing through. We're sitting there, married for six years, and he says how he likes it better when I put my hair back...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford snaps out of it. He goes up on the lawn and flips the paper deftly onto the porch. As they continue --</context>
      <utterance>That wasn't so good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're doing great.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know if I'm going to make it the whole way.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't matter. Go on.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leans against the iron handrail on some front steps, breathing hard.</context>
      <utterance>Oh... this makes me sound irrational, which is probably right, but there was something about him saying this -- it was maybe the millionth time he'd told me about some preference of his. Well, I was so... tired of it.  Seems like my whole life someone's been telling me... I'm just not getting it right. Can we rest for a second?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're purposely making me talk while we do this...  ...because you think this is good for me...  ...and you're a sadistic bastard...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...who thinks there's nothing really wrong with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She laughs. They're playing with each other.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, there's something wrong with you, all right. Especially after hearing that dream of yours, about the Roto-Rooter.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was really bad, wasn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Disgusting.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I'll bet you can interpret the whole thing</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sofie starts walking again, taking another newspaper from his sack. He points to the next house.</context>
      <utterance>It's pretty obvious to a trained professional.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sofie heaves the paper squarely onto the porch. She turns to him with pride, but when she sees the way he looks at her, she glances away, uncomfortable.</context>
      <utterance>I hate those dreams where everything means something.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that when you split up?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford hands her another paper and indicates the next house.</context>
      <utterance>No, that'd be a good story, but that was just the beginning of the end. We went on for another year or so.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So whose route is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brady Peck's. Fourteen years old. Lives next door.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And he's where?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the capitol for Boy's Nation. Five days. Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm thinking a gal could make a good living doing this. How hard could it be squeezing out some fourteen year old?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you can expect me at 5:30 tomorrow morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And this is legitimate therapy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Therapy? Hell no, I just don't want to do it alone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The IMAGES CONTINUE.</context>
      <utterance>What is it, Nessa?</utterance>
   <speaker>NESSA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't she amazing? That is such a wicked look.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want me to see?</utterance>
   <speaker>NESSA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Mumford is sitting next to Nessa on the couch. At their feet is a mess of magazines. Nessa discards one and immediately starts flipping through a new one beneath it. She is very agitated. Mumford stands up, walks over and sits in his chair.</context>
      <utterance>Just chill for a second. Look at this guy, it appears he's actually dead... but gorgeous.</utterance>
   <speaker>NESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing? We're not done. I just need to find the thing...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you don't want to have a session today, it's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>NESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to have the session. I thought it would be cool if I could show you some of the things that interest me. But I guess you're not into it... which we already knew.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened today?</utterance>
   <speaker>NESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was it something that happened at school?</utterance>
   <speaker>NESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These appointments were not my idea, remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A look of panic crosses Nessa's face, but she instantly hides it, busily taking out cigarette and lighter, which she doesn't use. Instead, she lies down on the couch, balancing the closed magazine on her chest.</context>
      <utterance>True. Should we stop them?</utterance>
   <speaker>NESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think you know what you're talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>NESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford waits. Nessa refers to the magazine beneath her chin.</context>
      <utterance>This shrink school you went to... did you hear about it on an infomercial?</utterance>
   <speaker>NESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nessa suddenly seems on the edge of tears, but beats it back.</context>
      <utterance>I want to live in the world these people are in. No one ever says anything in there, have you noticed? So they're very cool. Like they're all really deep. It's when people start talking that everything goes to shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>NESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's this kid at school... Martin Brockett. He has some gigantic idea of himself that no one else shares. You wouldn't believe the crap he lays on me... Who appointed him my spiritual leader? If he has everything so figured out how come his best friend is a .22 rifle? And why's he spend all his time chasing after me? Probably thinks I'm gonna give him a hummer...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think that's what he wants?</utterance>
   <speaker>NESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I don't know what he wants. But I know I don't like being watched. Nobody's ever paid any attention to what I did, and I liked it just fine. Where does he get off telling me I disrespect myself?  Fuck him. Look in a mirror, bozo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="37">
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lily continues her welcomes, but points out a hand-lettered sign in her front window -- "Closed for Lunch. See you tomorrow."</context>
      <utterance>What's the deal?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They come through a few times each year.  Hello, Mrs. Saito, good to see you again!  It's a tour.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where am I supposed to eat?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford's attention is suddenly drawn to something across the street. He glances thoughtfully at Lily for a moment, then back out there. WHAT HE SEES: Skip is once again zipping down the street on his skateboard in the midst of traffic. He has not noticed Mumford.</context>
      <utterance>You're on your own today, honey.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Skip looks over, then immediately changes course toward them, barely checking the surrounding traffic. He is extraordinarily skillful. When he gets to the curb, he pulls a snazzy board- flipping maneuver to dismount and come up on the sidewalk. Some of the Japanese matrons react with delight.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Skip!</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Skip notices the tour members filing by, but is immediately distracted by the presence of Lily, who's a little excited to meet the local celebrity.</context>
      <utterance>Doc.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lily, I want you to meet Skip. Skip, Lily.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a pleasure to meet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... me you, too... I was at your house...</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Skip can't believe what he just said. Neither can the other two, actually. Mumford can't stop himself from laughing, but he cuts it off fast. Lily blushes, but Skip's agitation has charmed her. Something's happening here.</context>
      <utterance>Upstairs, with Doc... Yeah, it's very nice... I heard your shower.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've seen you going by on your board, but I didn't realize -- you're so young... to be so...</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...so rich?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...so accomplished.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's making a joke and it represents quite a recovery. They're all relieved. Then there's an awkward silence. Skip watches the last of the tour enter the restaurant.</context>
      <utterance>I may be young, but Doc can tell you, I'm very immature.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, is this like a Japanese restaurant?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd better get in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a lot of people all at once.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay. They pre-order. There's a choice of three entrees.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lily gives him a careful look: Is he really interested? There's something about him...</context>
      <utterance>What are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meat loaf, turkey quesadillas, or salad nicoise.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Salad nicoise? I love salad nicoise.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She motions him in and starts to follow. Mumford makes a "what about me?" sound. Lily, grinning, just points to the sign and leaves Mumford standing on the sidewalk.</context>
      <utterance>Well, come on in.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELBANCO</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Mumford turns to find Dr. Delbanco and Phyllis Sheeler, the shrinks Lionel had conferred with, standing nearby. It takes a moment for Mumford to remember Delbanco. Finally, shaking hands --</context>
      <utterance>Dr. Mumford.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Delbanco. It's nice to see you again.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELBANCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think you know Dr. Sheeler. She's the other therapist here in town.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course... I've heard great things about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELBANCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford makes a show of remembering.</context>
      <utterance>You never got back to me.  ...I called to say we'd like to take you out for a meal?... Kind of a professional welcome.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forgive me, please. What a gracious thought. We must do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't I call you when I've got my calendar in front of me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELBANCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing for lunch?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other two nod in unison. Mumford considers, trapped.</context>
      <utterance>Right now?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="47">
   <speaker>DELBANCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford nods appreciatively. (He really is an extraordinary listener.) Delbanco catches his own vanity in Sheeler's adoring gaze and becomes self-conscious --</context>
      <utterance>...annihilation anxieties engendered by bad experiences with a depriving mother... but no one can escape the fear of death. It is, as Henry James put it, "the worm at the core." Try as we may to forget or ignore our mortality, James said --  -- "the skull will grin in at the banquet."</utterance>
   <speaker>DELBANCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've run on. Forgive me. We're here to talk about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What Ernest means, I think, is we're very interested in other methodology... different kinds of training. We're great believers in learning from each other. I've learned so much from Ern -- Dr. Delbanco...</utterance>
   <speaker>DELBANCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...And I from Phyllis.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So... the University of Kentucky. Who runs the program down there?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My mentor was an amazing teacher named Benton Mandlebaum. Died quite tragically in the collapse of a gazebo.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELBANCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford's response, and all that follow, is calm and pleasant.</context>
      <utterance>I think I've heard of him... a disciple of Rothberg, wasn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's possible. I don't know about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose your extended training was at an institution in that area?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lots of institutions. My graduate advisor believed we should experience as many environments as possible -- prisons, clinics, half-way houses. For a while I was chief therapist in a shopping mall. Had a little spot next to the yogurt place.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELBANCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Interesting approach. What was his name?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Delbanco and Sheeler exchange a look. Sheeler adopts a "casual" tone --</context>
      <utterance>Dorothy Fowler. Fantastic woman. She passed last year in a train wreck. Damned Amtrak.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I trained in the east, myself -- Cornell -- and I don't care what anyone says, there really are regional differences. I found the state certification exams out here quite harrowing... Did you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah, very tough. But I guess that's good... to keep out the quacks.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which examiner did you have? I probably know him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A dark look comes over Sheeler's face for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Wallace Franklin... from Greensburg.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was a terrible thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't even know why hang-gliding is considered a legitimate sport.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELBANCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're interested in any new therapies. How would you characterize your approach?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My approach?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... your particular approach.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford sits back, considering the couple across the table. His gaze is so crystalline that, after a moment, they become uncomfortable and steal a glance at each other. Finally --</context>
      <utterance>I don't have one really. Most of the time I'm faking it. See, I think there's not much that can be done about most problems... they're too complicated, too deep-rooted by the time I hear about them. The most I can do, usually, is look and listen real closely, try to catch some glimpse of the secret life everybody's got. If I can get a sense of that, well then, maybe... just maybe, I can help them out a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELBANCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- The argument had nothing to do with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand. I just want to know what the argument was about.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had ordered some books. "The 100 Greatest Books Ever Written."</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh. What are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, all the great writers -- Shakespeare, Charles Dickens, Moby Dick... those people. Each is bound in genuine premium leather with 22 carat gold accents. It's a magnificent set -- and only $33.50 per volume. Right away you get Great Expectations for just $6.99.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One hundred books?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's irrelevant. It had nothing to do with what happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Althea is sitting on the couch facing Mumford. She has a bulky knit cardigan sweater hugged tightly around her -- the only sign that she's not completely calm.</context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We argued on Sunday. He went to work on Monday and stayed in the city during the week, like always. But on Thursday, when he normally comes home, he didn't. Didn't call either. Not till Saturday afternoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must have been concerned.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's happened before.  I'm shocked by how little I'm feeling. I can't understand it.  I'll probably have a complete depressoid collapse soon, won't I?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doubtful. What did he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford looks away. Althea realizes what he's thinking.</context>
      <utterance>He said he wasn't coming back. He said it wasn't working for him any more. That it hadn't "worked for him" for quite a while... You know what I regret the most? I'm sorry I let him make the kids take his name. He was an acquirer.  He liked to acquire things.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It hadn't occurred to Mumford, but it's an interesting thought.</context>
      <utterance>You think that has something to do with my problem? Ordering all those things?...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Like I was on some kind of campaign to out-acquire him...  ...If I was just an acquisition to him, and he lost interest once he had me -- She stops, shakes her head.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford nods.</context>
      <utterance>That can't be it. It's too simple. And besides, I still like it. This morning I ordered a marble turtle cheese board from The Horchow Collection.  Can I tell you something just awful? You know how people who are just assholes will sometimes look at a woman who's got problems and say, "What she needs is a good shtupping!"?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances at her watch, then starts talking fast --</context>
      <utterance>Well, there may be something to that. Jeremy didn't keep up his end -- Oh, what difference does it make?  Why do I feel elated? Am I in denial? You know what it feels like?...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know my time's up, but I've got to get this out while I've got hold of it --</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take your time.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- When I was in high school, the thing I wanted most, when I was stuck in class, the thing I was always desperately in pursuit of -- was a hall pass. That's all I wanted. I loved moving freely around the school while everybody else was trapped in there... And that's how I feel right now... Like I have some giant, all- day hall pass. She is beaming, but suddenly becomes self-conscious. She stands up abruptly, flushed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes off the bulky sweater and bends to pick up her purse. She is wearing a simple cotton dress that buttons up the front and hugs her body. WE SEE for the first time what all her other outfits have hidden: Althea has a terrific, voluptuous figure.</context>
      <utterance>My god, did it just get hot in here or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She heads toward the door to the waiting room. Mumford indicates the back door.</context>
      <utterance>See you next time. I'll probably be a basket case by then.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can go out there if you like...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes out.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Mr. Follett. Have a good session. Bye, Doc.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Follett continues to stare in the direction Althea has gone.</context>
      <utterance>Henry...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Mumford looks that way. In the distance, Skip is descending from an upper level on his skateboard via a unique system of ramps designed for that purpose alone. None of the hustling Panda Employees in the area take any particular notice of the sight. Skip meets Mumford and his escort at the bottom of the ramp with a spectacular stop.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Doc!</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Security Aide retreats as Skip (riding slowly alongside) leads Mumford into a side corridor.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Jennifer, I'll take him from here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never brought anyone down here before.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm honored.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doc, there's something about what you told me the other night I can't get out of my head. It's driving me batty --  Why me? How did you know you could trust me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Skip is pleased. They approach a heavy steel door, the entrance to Skip's Workshop. A VERY OLD SECURITY AIDE sits at the end of the intersecting hallway, watching this area. Skip shouts down there --</context>
      <utterance>You're completely reliable.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The old man nods, barely awake.</context>
      <utterance>It's just me, Dino!</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Skip, I've got a problem and I need some advice.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Skip puts his hand in a scanning device in the wall. Some lights blink and the heavy metal door pops open a few inches. Skip has to put all his weight into opening the door. He hesitates, suddenly concerned --</context>
      <utterance>You want my advice? Far out!</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford reassures him with a look. Skip pushes the door open far enough for them to enter, then pulls it closed behind them.</context>
      <utterance>I hope nothing you're about to see will shake your faith in me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretty creepy, huh? Are you totally disgusted?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Skip, you're a visionary. That can be a burden.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This doesn't seem a little... perverse?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are a lot of lonely people in the world. Somebody's gonna figure this out someday.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not going to be me. I'm giving it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all your fault. In the last 48 hours, I've completely lost interest.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Skip looks at Mumford, a wide grin on his face.</context>
      <utterance>What'd I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lily.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lily...  ...Skip, that's great! You and Lily.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Skip settles in front of the Body Parts section, framed by an array of limbs and sex toys. There's an assembled pelvic section with upper legs lying in the clutter behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, she doesn't know about it yet. Right now, of the two of us, I'm the only one in love. But I'm very stoked.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Skip leans back against the table and accidentally hits a button. The pelvic section begins to hump, slowly and sensually, in place. It's amazingly life-like, but it makes a mechanical WHIRRING SOUND. Skip fumbles to turn it off.</context>
      <utterance>Doc, how I can be of help to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Skip gets the pelvis switched off and turns back to Mumford.</context>
      <utterance>Wow.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm here for you, Doc.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Skip, you know that it's improper -- completely unethical -- for a licensed psychologist to carry on a romantic relationship with one of his patients?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess that makes sense.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford sinks into silence. He begins to wander the room.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, yes it does...</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford nods. Skip is desperate to say something useful. Suddenly, he has an alarming thought.</context>
      <utterance>You've fallen in love with one of your patients?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doc!... It's not me, is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford understands and can't stop a laugh.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Skip is relieved. He has another thought and brightens.</context>
      <utterance>No, Skip, it's not you. But I like you a lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford turns to meet Skip's gaze. Skip realizes the ramifications of what he's just said.</context>
      <utterance>Doc, what about this? You're not really a licensed psychologist!</utterance>
   <speaker>SKIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmm. I guess that doesn't help... I see where you're going here. It's a mess.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>LIONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you find it incredibly convenient that everyone who could possibly corroborate his story has recently died some exotic death?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELBANCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're neither all recent nor exotic.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But they're certainly dead. And yes, personally, I find it a bit odd.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELBANCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lionel's derisive snort is so obnoxious, it's hard to bear.</context>
      <utterance>It could happen. What about his state certification exams? The records seem to be in order.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's easier than hacking your way into a state computer and inserting some numbers? For all you know he never even took the exams!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's true.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELBANCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know that it's all that easy...</utterance>
   <speaker>LIONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doctor, correct me if I'm wrong, but it sounds to me like you've gone for this guy's story hook, line and bull- twaddle.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do seem much more disposed toward him than I understand, Ernest. Did I miss something?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELBANCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Phyllis, I'm sorry. I didn't mean to shout...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She breaks into tears and rushes out of the office. Delbanco is left facing Lionel, who gives him exactly the look the doctor least wants to see.</context>
      <utterance>No, Dr. Delbanco, it is I who am sorry. Sorry to have wasted your time with such...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford smiles, eats.</context>
      <utterance>Stop it! He's a kid. I'm old enough to be his... older sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford comes in, reluctantly.</context>
      <utterance>Dr. Mumford. Please, come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Mr. Cook. I was wondering if Sofie was around?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were you supposed to have a session?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. It's sort of spur of the moment.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="38">
   <speaker>COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look who's here. Have you met Sofie's moth--</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- We've met.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And our son, Ben...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford continues to stand.</context>
      <utterance>This is a real honor, Doctor. Have a seat, will ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, actually, I can't really... Do you think I could see Sofie?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford sits.</context>
      <utterance>I insist! I've been wanting to meet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford's surprised. Mr. Cook speaks with some pleasure.</context>
      <utterance>Sofie's not here.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her friend from the city came and took her out to dinner. First time in a long time she's been willing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Cook gives Ben a condescending look and keeps knitting.</context>
      <utterance>We owe that to you. She's perked up a lot since you started treating her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's something I think we need to talk about.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we have a right.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We certainly do not.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben gives Mumford an exasperated look, but doesn't argue.</context>
      <utterance>Keep it zipped, Ben.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford is conflicted, not sure what to share with them.</context>
      <utterance>Is there something we need to know, Dr. Mumford?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Cook and Ben exchange an alarmed glance. Mrs. Cook actually cheers up.</context>
      <utterance>Well... yes, I guess I should tell you. I don't think I'm going to be able to treat Sofie anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finally, some common sense...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you know what I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I really don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you tell me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you go to hell? It's all a bunch of nonsense and you know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth, I'm tellin' you, stop this...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're telling me? That's rich...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd better go.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford looks from Ben to Mr. Cook, who nods his agreement.</context>
      <utterance>Why can't you see Sofie? I know the treatment's working.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... you see, the problem is --</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford looks at Mrs. Cook and can't stifle a laugh.</context>
      <utterance>-- the problem is you're a big fake. You haven't got a clue what's wrong with that girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. You're something.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take a hike, Dr. Quack!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford can't take his eyes off Mrs. Cook, even as he speaks to Mr. Cook.</context>
      <utterance>What is the problem, Doctor?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Problem? I guess there is no problem... Uh, this friend of Sofie's, where'd he take her?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's she -- Roxy. Used to work with her. I think they went over to The Lantern.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Cook looks at him sharply. She's heard what the other two have not.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Roxy! Excellent. Roxy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a thought I had.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford seems hesitant, but nods. Follett takes out an Exacto knife and makes the first incision, but as he's about to go on, Mumford suddenly reaches out and stops him.</context>
      <utterance>Should I open it now?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me just say something here... I have no idea if this is going to help.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What exactly is it supposed to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You remember when I asked you about pornography --</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- I find it degrading. Maximum gynecology and minimum turn-on --</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- and you told me that. Still, there's some kind of imagery that's haunting you and, I think, getting in your way --</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Which I don't necessarily agree.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Follett reacts. It's true, even if he keeps forgetting.</context>
      <utterance>But you did come to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My guess is these images were burned into your brain when you were young. Maybe if we could nail down the exact fantasies that are haunting you -- maybe you could get past them... Anyway, I thought we could try an experiment.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford nods, but suddenly looks depressed, distracted.</context>
      <utterance>And the experiment is in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to take hold of the box.</context>
      <utterance>You know what? I think this was a dumb idea...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Follett grabs the box back.</context>
      <utterance>...I just heard myself talking and I realize I'm completely unqualified to be doing this. Let's forget the whole thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa, whoa, what are you doing? I want to know what's in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford gives up. Follett gestures to ask whether it's safe to put the box on the desk; Mumford reassures him. Now, with much more anticipation and ceremony than before, Follett carefully cuts open the package. THE CONTENTS OF THE BOX is revealed as Follett opens the flaps. There is an inner, brown paper wrapping upon which has been set a low-rent catalogue: "METROPOLITAN COLLECTIBLES -- Periodicals, Erotica, Adult Nostalgia." Follett lifts away the wrapping -- There are perhaps a dozen men's magazines of the late fifties and early sixties: Nugget, Adam, The Adam Reader, Swank, Dude. Plus several cartoon collections: Sex to Sexty, Stag Humor. Plus trashy adult novels of the era, with provocative illustrations on the covers: Night Call Nurse, The Neighbors Have No Curtains, Secretarial Sluts, etc. Finally, two video tapes, both of Russ Meyer films: MUDHONEY and COMMON-LAW</context>
      <utterance>Hey! I agree with you that you don't know what you're talking about. That's what I've been saying all along. And I can guarantee you that looking at the Lost Ark or whatever you got in here is not going to mean diddly to me...  ...but if you think I'm going to let you walk out of here without seeing what's in this box, you don't know much about Henry A. Follett.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>YOUNG PHARMACIST</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Follett jumps, startled from his revery. As the Young Pharmacist steps tentatively into the office, Follett jams everything back into the box as best he can and tries to cover it.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Follett --</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Young Pharmacist is cowed and doesn't advance into the room.</context>
      <utterance>What?! What the hell is so important I can't have five minutes --?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG PHARMACIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It takes Follett a moment to understand, but when he does, his whole manner changes. He dismisses the Young Pharmacist with a nod, then gives a quick, self-conscious glance to Mumford.</context>
      <utterance>It's her, sir. You told me to get you when she came to pick up her prescription.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, sorry, I'm going to have to...  ...I really appreciate what you're trying to... uh, I can't thank you enough for...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Follett heads for the door, pausing briefly at a mirror to check his appearance, pushing at his hair with his palm.</context>
      <utterance>My pleasure.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hurries out. Mumford stands up to leave, but first looks down through the one-way mirror. WHAT HE SEES: Follett hurries up behind the prescription counter, where Althea Brockett is waiting; once again she looks quite sexy. Follett brings her prescription up and begins playfully flirting. Althea is responsive. Follett motions Althea down the aisle, where it's more private. He comes out from behind the counter, ostensibly to show Althea something on the prescription bottle. Althea leans back against some shelves in the same posture as the Landlady in Follett's first fantasy. Mumford reacts, bemused.</context>
      <utterance>I'll see you on... whatever...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I was in high school we used to come up here and make out. I liked to sit on the rock and watch the sun go down.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I like.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Either one.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why'd you come to the house the other night?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought I had something to tell you. But it turned out I didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My brother said you were about to fire me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's one way to put it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bet I know what changed your mind...  ...My mother. She was so horrible, you decided you couldn't desert me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sofie gestures ahead.</context>
      <utterance>I thought only action movies had villains like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford slows at this. Sofie heads off the trail into the woods.</context>
      <utterance>That's the cut-off, isn't it?  I know why you were going to quit seeing me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford looks up, sharply.</context>
      <utterance>You feel like a fake, an imposter...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts a hand on his arm.</context>
      <utterance>...as if maybe you don't know what you're doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody feels that way sometimes... like we're not who we're supposed to be. But I have to tell you, Dr. Mumford -- He winces at her formality.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- you've been a tremendous help to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't tell you how much I admire you. You have a wonderful way with people. And you're very insightful. I feel like you've seen me clearly... I never used to admit what a horrible person my mother was. You've made that possible for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's... good?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes! And my ex-husband -- he never accepted me for who I was, just like Mother. The things you've said have helped me understand what a dick he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know if --</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're shockingly honest, that's what makes you great. I've never had a man treat me this way. With you, I feel really... listened to.  Can I tell you something? It's a little embarrassing, but I feel very unguarded with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford is in agony.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks to this therapy, I now know what I'm looking for. I need to find a man like you.  Not one who's treating me, of course.  And I'm going to do it, dammit! You've given me the confidence.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sofie... that makes me very happy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>NESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I mean, Doc, the dude is seriously deluded. I said that to him, I said, "If you think I'm gonna do all that shit for you, man, you are seriously deluded."</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>NESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said -- "Which we already knew!" Mumford laughs, delighted.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did he want you to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>NESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds up the cigarette as though it were her middle finger, flipping the bird.</context>
      <utterance>First off, he tells me to stop smoking cigarettes. I told him abso-fuckin'- lutely no. As you can see --</utterance>
   <speaker>NESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford doesn't have to see her face to know how much pleasure this gives her, despite her hard-ass cover.</context>
      <utterance>Then he says stop smoking dope. No again. So then he says he doesn't want me getting together with any other guys...</utterance>
   <speaker>NESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...What balls on this guy? What're we...  ...going steady? Jesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No again?</utterance>
   <speaker>NESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said I'd consider it. Nobody owns me. And the last thing was insane. I don't know what's wrong with him... No magazines.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>NESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know if I can quit. We're gonna try it together, like, you know, AA or something. And I made him give up his .22. No more sneaking around the hills with his fucking nut gun like some loony tune.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He agreed?</utterance>
   <speaker>NESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's pitiful, Doc, a goddam puppy. I don't know how much longer I can put up with it. I already got two arms and legs, I don't need another appendage. She takes a look at her watch and immediately lights her cigarette as she stands up --</utterance>
   <speaker>NESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She heads toward the waiting room. Mumford gestures to indicate the back door. She waves him off. He shakes his head -- no one wants to use the back anymore. Nessa opens the door to the waiting room. Martin Brockett is sitting there. He makes a gesture to Nessa to underline the fact that he is not reading any of the many magazines lying around, then stands up. She goes into his arms like maybe she's the puppy. He beams and looks at Mumford.</context>
      <utterance>Oops... gotta go!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hiya, Doc.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Martin.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nessa give him an affectionate punch in the side, then blows smoke in his face.</context>
      <utterance>Did you straighten her out?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nessa gives Mumford an embarrassed, "ain't he corny?" look, but as they go out the door, she's never looked happier.</context>
      <utterance>Insane! Didn't ja hear? My family got five hundred times better.  Let's go, Vanessa.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILROY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Mumford is startled to find a man in a suit, GILROY, rising from the chair behind the door. He's got a briefcase and a document in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Doctor Mumford?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't see you there. Can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He proffers the document in his hand, but Mumford doesn't take it.</context>
      <utterance>My name's Gilroy. I'm from the State Certification Board.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all right, it won't bite you. Under civil code 1294.67b you are entitled to be notified that your status and certification are being reviewed. This is the notice.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want to come in?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No thanks. Plenty of time for that when we're a little further along.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Gilroy -- Gilroy stops, outside door already open.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What brought this on?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes out. Mumford considers the paper in his hands, thoughts elsewhere.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not at liberty to say. Sometimes it's just routine, sometimes there's been a complaint. We'll be in touch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>DELBANCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Across the room, Mumford sits, chin in hand, displaying no reaction.</context>
      <utterance>...and when you said at lunch about everybody having "a secret life", something just snapped inside me. I knew I could no longer continue my relationship with Dr. Sheeler. It was tearing me up inside. And I know Phyllis wasn't getting what she needed from it. What had started as a genuine respect, I think, for each other's professional abilities, and became, over time, a personal attraction had somehow... migrated into a rather torrid sexual relationship...</utterance>
   <speaker>DELBANCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I won't go into that today. Though, if we should continue these sessions, as I certainly hope we will, there are some aspects of that I would like to look at. God knows, I've listened to enough people giving me the juicy --  ...At any rate, I just wanted to acknowledge the catalyzing effect your comment had on me. I just hope that it doesn't come roiling back upon you like some dreadful undertow.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This next is painful for Delbanco.</context>
      <utterance>How do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELBANCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... you see, when I broke it off with Phyllis, she was naturally upset and she became more determined than ever to pursue certain -- how to put it -- doubts she's been harboring...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of doubts?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELBANCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford digests this.</context>
      <utterance>About you... your background and your qualifications. I'm afraid Phyllis somehow got you mixed up in her fury with me, and actually took the whole issue to the state board.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELBANCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And please, for whatever small way I may have encouraged this, accept my apologies.  There is good news, though.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELBANCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Phyllis has decided to leave town and pursue her practice in the city. Which leaves you the only psychologist in town.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Sheeler is leaving Mumford? I'm sorry to hear that.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELBANCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford's head snaps up. He had no idea Delbanco was married.</context>
      <utterance>As you can imagine, my own feelings about this are mixed... Unlike, I must say, those of my wife.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>CUT TO REVERSE and see the hero, who this time is actually played by Henry Follett, appearing in his own fantasy for the first time. He's lying in bed, his face bruised in the manner of a fifties movie.</context>
      <utterance>The Landlady was good at quite a few things, but doctoring wasn't one of them...</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>BACK AT THE DOOR, the Cheerleader hears someone coming and steps aside to make way for -- Althea Brockett, dressed now in a nurse's uniform so tight the buttons are straining.</context>
      <utterance>...Lucky for me, one of the other boarders, the broad who lived downstairs in the front room...</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>As the Landlady and the Cheerleader retreat out the door, Althea the Nurse sways forward toward the bed bearing bandages and a bowl of steaming water, a lascivious look of concern on her face.</context>
      <utterance>...was a nurse...</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Althea the Nurse places a bandage over Follett's eyes,</context>
      <utterance>...and she had ways to make you feel better they didn't teach in nursing school.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="36">
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford, surprisingly, takes Follett's hand and shakes it vigorously.</context>
      <utterance>I'm very happy for you, Henry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel like we're making real progress here.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLLETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford stops him with a "don't mention it" gesture. Follett accepts and goes out the back door. Mumford is pleased someone still wants to use that door. Mumford returns to his desk and begins reading some papers when he HEARS the entry door to the waiting room. Not expecting anyone, he checks the clock, then goes to his office door and opens it. Sofie is standing there, very agitated, just about to knock. She peers past him to see if he's alone.</context>
      <utterance>Me too, Doc. And I can't tell you what that package meant to me --</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to talk to you... Doctor. Can I come in?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sofie sits on the couch. Mumford sits in his chair, facing her. Her voice is as strained as her manner.</context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford waits.</context>
      <utterance>We haven't met in this office since that first time. This is how a real professional and his client are supposed to see each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It might've been more appropriate if we had followed a traditional approach to the doctor-patient relationship.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is something wrong, Sofie?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, something's very wrong, Dr. Mumford.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're upset.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford considers a long moment, several scenarios racing through his mind. Finally, carefully --</context>
      <utterance>How intuitive! That must take years of training right there. Maybe you can guess what has upset me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it something you've heard about me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it is not something I've heard about you! It is someth--  Why? Is there something I should have heard about you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sofie suddenly finds it difficult to look into his eyes, she looks around frenetically for a moment. Then, indicating the couch --</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you tell me what's on your mind?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford gestures "of course." Sofie swings her legs up and lies on the couch so they can no longer see each other's face. (It's the most vigorous movement she's yet shown us.) This seems to help Sofie a bit.</context>
      <utterance>May I?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right... I'm going to come right out and say this, because that's what your shrink is for, right, so you can tell him what's bothering you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First of all, I have been feeling much better lately. I don't know if the syndrome is over -- if it's just run its course or something -- but I feel a hundred per cent better than when I first came to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm glad.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Given that, I'm obviously not going to be judging things in the most realistic way.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't follow you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm saying that since I'm doing so much better -- which I attribute to you -- I'm liable to misinterpret some of my feelings.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The point is this -- I am not a blank page. I did not just fall off the turnip truck. Do you know what I mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know a little about psychology. I took three different courses in college. It's true, none of them were above the two hundred level, but I took them... And there was one concept I remember very well.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Transference!</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Transference.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford appears frozen in his chair. There is a heavy silence in the room. Sofie does not look back there.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, and that is what I have got right now. I have taken my feelings of gratitude... and relief... and transferred them onto... you. I have taken all those warm, grateful emotions and confused them with feelings for you... So that now I am under the delusion...  ...that I am in love with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, Sofie's voice cracks. She is starting to cry, but refuses to acknowledge it.</context>
      <utterance>I think you can understand why I have some serious questions about your methods. I mean, obviously it becomes much more likely that I'm going to have confusion about this when your idea of treatment is to go walking in the woods and up to make- outs-ville and do all these highly romantic activities --</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford doesn't know what to say. He's on the rack. Finally --</context>
      <utterance>-- We had a paper route together, for godssake! Do you understand how I might be a little resentful? Knowing that this so-called "love" I'm feeling is totally bogus, and just a pathetic case of... transference?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. Then Sofie gets up, wiping at tears with the back of her bare hand. Mumford jumps up to offer her a tissue, but she ignores it. She will not meet his gaze.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sofie turns to go out through the waiting room, but after a step, she stops, pirouettes and goes out the back.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe you ought to think about how you're going to fix this. And when you do...  ...please get back to me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lily rises up suddenly from where she's been working in the garden.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Ainge.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doc...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lily.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford reluctantly stops. Lily comes up to the fence.</context>
      <utterance>Doc.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want you to be mad at Skip...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He told you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Skip and I wouldn't have got together if it weren't for you. That's a big deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You would have met in some shower eventually...</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to give you something. Will you let me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Lily, I don't need anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, you do, you damn well do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here it is, some advice -- do the hard thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it? That's what you're giving me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford leans down to pet Ainge.</context>
      <utterance>Clean up the mess. No matter what it takes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What it might take is... doing time.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford straightens, looks at Lily and acknowledges it.</context>
      <utterance>Too bad. That's tough, I mean it. I'm not unsympathetic. But Skip says you're in love.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford looks at Lily a long moment, then leans over the fence and kisses her on the forehead. Ainge jumps back over to her side.</context>
      <utterance>Then it's worth it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford turns and continues toward his stairs.</context>
      <utterance>I'll tell her tonight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ROBERT STACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A CLOSE-UP of an IRS identification card featuring a picture of a younger Mumford, badly photographed in suit and tie. His name is not visible.</context>
      <utterance>...A drug rehabilitation center in the lonely southwestern desert... run by reclusive monks... becomes the point of departure in a mysterious vanishing...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT STACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>investigator disappears -- without a trace. In the kitchen, Mumford spins to look. DISSOLVE TO: LATER IN THE PROGRAM. Documentary shots of IRS Headquarters, etc., are INTERCUT with hokey-looking re-enactments from Mumford's life -- with a YOUNG ACTOR who looks vaguely like Mumford playing him. IN MUMFORD'S APARTMENT the telephone is RINGING. Clearly, it's not the first time. Mumford, watching the show intently, lifts the headset an inch from the cradle and then hangs up. When it immediately RINGS AGAIN, Mumford takes it off the hook, cuts off the call, and buries the headset under a sofa cushion. ON THE SHOW: scenes of tax investigation -- in the show's version the IRS guys have drawn guns and are storming houses -- are interspersed with scenes of sordid drug-taking.</context>
      <utterance>...as an intrepid government</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT STACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MUMFORD'S SISTER, the real thing, a plain, middle-aged West Virginia woman, appears in a "dramatic", badly-lit interview. (As with all the interviewees, she is identified by a supered title.)</context>
      <utterance>...despite brilliant promise as a fearless investigator... found himself on a downward spiral of drug abuse and dissolution...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD'S SISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A snapshot of some IRS-era party, happy revelers posing for a flash. Camera PUSHES IN on Mumford, smiling and high, his neck encircled by Gregory's arm. Candy is on the other side of Gregory. A shot of the Pennsylvania Turnpike as a State Police Cruiser zips by.</context>
      <utterance>...we didn't talk much after our folks died, but I know he felt his life had taken a wrong turn...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT STACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>GREGORY, in State Police uniform, with a sadistic glint in his eye, is interviewed by the roadside, cars whipping by.</context>
      <utterance>His former undercover partner at the IRS... is now a trooper with the Pennsylvania State Police...</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ragged telephoto shots of the Drug Rehab Center in the desert, low, innocuous adobe buildings.</context>
      <utterance>The guy was obsessed... didn't always know where to draw the line... but I would have trusted him with my wife -- er, my life --  -- What'd I say? Both, actually...  ...I can't say I was surprised, though, when he disappeared.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT STACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>IN AN ARIZONA TOWN, a monk with a clerical collar, BROTHER TIMOTHY, is loading groceries into the back of a pick-up. He's being ambush interviewed. He's polite, but not cooperative.</context>
      <utterance>Who was this enigma... a courageous public servant or a debauched addict?... Either way, his last known stop was here... isolated in the Arizona desert... taken in by an order of devoted monks...</utterance>
   <speaker>BROTHER TIMOTHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shots of wind-swept desert, cactus, and dust-blown highway.</context>
      <utterance>We don't talk about the people who've been our guests... but I can tell you this about our order -- we believe everybody has the right to start over... everybody deserves a second chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT STACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And perhaps... that is exactly the chance the now-sober pilgrim took... on a blustery November day... walking away from the rehab center... never to be heard from again...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MUMFORD'S SISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford, in his apartment, watches with real emotion. His sister's face DISSOLVES into a new snapshot of Mumford, dressed in an Orkin Exterminator uniform, as the MUSIC on the show comes up. A 1-800 telephone number appears across the bottom of the frame.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like to know if he's alive. If he is, I just hope he's happy and his new life is...  ...well, I hope he's found what he was looking for...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERT STACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you have any information about this man or know anything about his whereabouts, contact the Sheriff's Department in Cochise County, Arizona, or call this number...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="40">
   <speaker>MRS. COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, look who's here...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good evening, Mrs. Cook.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just who is here, can you tell me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could I see Sofie, please?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you can not. I wouldn't know who to say is calling.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Mrs. Cook glances inside at the as-yet-unseen Sofie, then hisses at Mumford --</context>
      <utterance>Mother...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sofie appears behind her mother.</context>
      <utterance>I could see right through you from the start, you imposter. I know what you're after. I knew it then and I know it now!</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mother...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think I'm after, Mrs. Cook?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sofie. It's so obvious... you're after my daughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both Sofie and Mrs. Cook are set back for a moment. Mrs. Cook recovers fastest --</context>
      <utterance>Well, I gotta say, Mrs. Cook, you're right about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll never happen! You're in big trouble, mister.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Cook suddenly appears, takes Mrs. Cook by the arm and makes her vanish. Sofie and Mumford are left alone. She looks at him through the screen.</context>
      <utterance>Mother... go away!</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess you saw the show...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which show was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sofie...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Part of it. We were watching "ER" until someone called.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sofie comes outside. She doesn't get too close or look at him as she walks to the other end of the porch.</context>
      <utterance>You probably got the idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford knows.</context>
      <utterance>Do you know what a betrayal this is?...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...How violated I feel?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sofie turns sharply to look at him, ready to blow up.</context>
      <utterance>You're not the only one...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You feel violated?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not me... all my other my patients. I smelled tar and feathers on the way over here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford agrees. He watches her closely.</context>
      <utterance>You deserve it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford immediately perks up. Sofie tries to correct --</context>
      <utterance>I should be irate.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am irate!</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But nothing... I'm mad as hell. This is a terrible thing you've done.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford steps closer to her.</context>
      <utterance>I know it! Please believe me, I know that...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, there is one... mitigating factor I want you to consider before you write me off.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you think about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Depends. I'm in a bad mood.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks into his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I love you. More than I've ever loved anyone or anything in my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She regards him for several moments, her mind racing.</context>
      <utterance>I want to spend the rest of my life with you... but I'm not sure you feel the same way.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford feels joy. Now, finally, he takes her in his arms.</context>
      <utterance>I sort of do...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...but first, you have to tell me something...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything... just ask.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Mumford breaks into a huge grin, CUT TO:</context>
      <utterance>What is your name?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>JUDGE OTTO</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Mumford and Lionel stand up.</context>
      <utterance>The defendant will rise.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE OTTO</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Lionel sits down, squelched again. We see JUDGE OTTO for the first time, a tough guy in his sixties.</context>
      <utterance>Sit down, Lionel.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE OTTO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clarence Norman White, do you understand how serious are the crimes with which you have been charged?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE OTTO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WE SEE there's a pretty big turnout for this hearing. Prominent among the onlookers: Lily and Skip, sitting together; Nessa and Martin, holding hands; Dr. Delbanco and MRS. DELBANCO. Gilroy, from the State Certification Board, sits with the PROSECUTOR.</context>
      <utterance>Do you realize how insidious it is to invade the most private thoughts and secret lives of unsuspecting people?...</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE OTTO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...People who have come to you with the faith that you know what you're doing... and that you are who you say you are?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, your honor.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE OTTO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It means absolutely nothing to me that so many of your patients have come forward with praise for you and your therapeutic skills. You understand that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Follett is sitting in one of the back rows, apparently alone. But now he looks down the row. Althea is sitting down at the end in a stylish suit, completely appropriate, but a size too small. She gives Follett a sidelong glance, then crosses her legs provocatively. Whatever fantasy they're currently enacting is working really well for both of them.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE OTTO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. White, I am frustrated that the criminal code in this state allows a maximum sentence of only six months and a maximum fine of only $2000.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, your honor.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE OTTO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry you're frustrated.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE OTTO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you disrespecting this court, Mr. White?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir. I was empathizing. Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE OTTO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The judge slams down his gavel, stands up and stalks out. A DEPUTY moves in to take custody of Mumford. Lionel stands up and leans in --</context>
      <utterance>Maybe you can empathize with this -- Maximum fine. Three months in jail, three months house arrest. Sentence to begin immediately at the Orchard Valley Correctional Facility. Case closed. This court is adjourned.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a country club. Don't worry about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumford turns to face the Cooks. Mr. Cook and Ben shake his hand like he's just won something. Lionel addresses them all with his usual self-satisfaction --</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for your help, Lionel.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll have him out in half the time. WE PUSH IN on Mumford and Sofie, who embrace.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got off easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you wait for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're only talking about six weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you be here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOFIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They kiss. The Deputy takes Mumford's arm, and we --</context>
      <utterance>Of course... I haven't got the energy to get out of town that fast.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CORRECTIONAL OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better make yourself comfortable. We got a three hour drive here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORRECTIONAL OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the shrink, aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not really.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORRECTIONAL OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you do therapy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They ride along in silence. At peace, Mumford watches the town go by. Finally --</context>
      <utterance>Not any more.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORRECTIONAL OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Correctional Officer watches Mumford in the rear view mirror, waiting hopefully. Mumford ponders the question a long time, then gives a "what the hell" shrug.</context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you, Doc, the wife and I, we got a little bit of a problem. Would you mind if I just ran it by you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUMFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
