<movie id="402" title="Music of the Heart">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WOMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>We hear the sound of KNOCKING as the CAMERA PANS a small, darkened guest room. A few streaks of daylight filter through Venetian blinds.</context>
      <utterance>Wake up, Roberta!</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The CAMERA finds a WOMAN lying face down on a twin bed, thick wavy hair sprawled across her shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Bert -- get out of bed!</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The KNOCKING continues, and she puts the pillow over the top of her head.</context>
      <utterance>Please, Bert -- you need to get out of that bed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BOY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She puts the half with her and her husband on the dresser, then tears the woman off the other half and rips her into pieces.</context>
      <utterance>Can you come out now, Mommy? Please?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mommy, Nick broke my crayon!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>O.S. arguing "I DID NOT!" "YES YOU DID!" "LIAR!" etc. As if that one action siphoned all her energy, Roberta returns to bed, gets into fetal position, and stares at a point beyond the wall, ignoring the O.S. voices.</context>
      <utterance>Well, Lexi hit me and he almost broke... he almost broke my ear!</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hear that? Your boys need you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ASSUNTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I have no room for this!</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Assunta looks beyond the man, dismayed.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, M'am. We have orders to deliver these.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men scramble to pick them up. Assunta looks at all the violins, then up at Roberta.</context>
      <utterance>Watch it, you idiots! Be careful with those!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSUNTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta disappears inside and slams the window shut.</context>
      <utterance>Why so many?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ASSUNTA grabs the phone from her hand and hangs it up.</context>
      <utterance>Look, I know he's there, so quit lying to me!... Then check under Lana Holden -- Mrs. Lana Holden... Fine. Just tell Lieutenant Demetras that his wife called and --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ma!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSUNTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I want you to listen to me. You can't keep doing this to yourself -- or to the boys. They need their mother now. You're a beautiful, talented woman and you have your whole life ahead of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I'm so beautiful and talented, why did Charles leave me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSUNTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She exits, leaving Roberta to mull over her words.</context>
      <utterance>Because Charles is a big jerk.  Now get dressed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really think Charles is a jerk?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSUNTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From the day you married him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you say something?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSUNTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta half-smiles, pours herself some coffee, then sits down at the table.</context>
      <utterance>Since when do you listen to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What am I gonna do?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSUNTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First, you eat breakfast. Second, you go out and get a job -- any job. Your boys, god-bless-em, are good eaters -- but I can't afford it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Assunta's face shows she's doubtful about this.</context>
      <utterance>Mama, he's gonna get tired of her -- you'll see.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSUNTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well in the meantime, get a job.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SUPERVISOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He exits, and Roberta quickly tries to finish her task.</context>
      <utterance>Just wrap. You're not Picasso.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Roberta looks up to find BRIAN TURNER (40), a handsome, sexy guy with longish hair and a beat-up leather jacket.</context>
      <utterance>Picasso would probably put the bows on the back of the box.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brian Turner?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Roberta.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you moved away.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds out his hand. Roberta misunderstands the gesture and tries to shake his hand.</context>
      <utterance>I did. I'm in town for my Mom's birthday.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- that's her gift.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta hands him the gift she's been wrapping.</context>
      <utterance>Oh! Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It looks very pretty.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.  I heard you had a book published. I didn't read it but...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta smiles.</context>
      <utterance>That's O.K. My parents didn't read it either. It looks good on their coffee table, though.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HOLD ON ROBERTA as she takes this in.</context>
      <utterance>So what are you doing here? I thought you'd be in Carnegie Hall by now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My college professors said it was too late -- I hadn't had enough training to be a concert violinist. So I got a teaching degree instead.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll bet you're a great teacher.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I am. It's just that...  See, every time I'd get started somewhere, Charles would be transferred... then I had my kids and took time off to raise them... and then when I decided to teach again, no one would hire me 'cause you can't count on a navy wife to stick around. I finally decided I'd start my own program -- Charles gave me the money and I bought fifty violins from this little Greek shop -- got started at a private school and then...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>Your husband ran off with your best friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat as she gets lost in the memory. She takes a bite of a french fry.</context>
      <utterance>She wasn't my "best" friend. She was a friend.  Charles is the last person you'd think would cheat on me -- he never broke a rule...  I wake up one night -- it's like one in the morning -- and he's not in bed. I go outside and our neighbor -- this old Greek guy -- is sitting out there, smoking a cigar, so I ask if he's seen my husband. "He's taking a walk with the other officer's wife," he says. "He takes a walk every night with the other officer's wife."</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, these are cold.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're just gonna wrap presents and wait for him to come back?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sound like my mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not very sexy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you trying to be sexy or be my friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta smiles, blushing a bit. Brian looks at her, getting an idea.</context>
      <utterance>A little of both.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I know this really cool lady who runs this elementary school -- I wrote a piece on her. It's a public school, but it's alternative -- she might be able to create some kind of gig for you. Let me give her a call.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If she hires you, though, you have to be willing to relocate.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aside from half a term in a private school -- in Greece -- and a year teaching chorus in Hawaii -- ten years ago -- it doesn't look like you've had any other teaching experience.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Janet looks for this on the resume.</context>
      <utterance>Well, not traditional teaching experience. I've been doing private lessons...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Janet smiles politely.</context>
      <utterance>It's not on there... I taught my sons.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta nods, defeated.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like to help you, Mrs. Demetras. Brian spoke highly of you and I told him I'd consider starting a violin class... But without the proper qualifications, and without any experience in an inner city school...</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm very sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>As Roberta opens the door, we see that Nick and Lexi are with her. All three have violins. INSIDE, Janet's in conversation with DENNIS RAUSCH (38), an uptight man with a tie that doesn't match his suit jacket. He's showing Janet a large scheduling chart.</context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They enter.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry to interrupt, but I wanted you to meet my sons -- Nick, Lexi...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roberta Guaspari-Demetras. Dennis shakes her hand, regarding her warily.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Dennis Rausch, our music teacher and program coordinator.  Mrs. Demetras, didn't I make things clear yesterday?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Janet can answer, Roberta and the kids quickly take out their violins and get into position. Janet and Dennis exchange a look.</context>
      <utterance>If I could just show you something -- it'll only take a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta ignores the jab, then nods to the boys. The three of them begin an incredibly impressive violin trio, playing an ETUDE in three-part harmony. For the first measures, Janet's still annoyed by the intrusion, but she's quickly won over. Dennis watches impassively. Roberta and the boys finish their piece; Janet applauds and Dennis joins in to be polite. The three take bows. A beat.</context>
      <utterance>Are we having a talent show? I should have brought my tap shoes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Janet laughs, then gestures for them to sit.</context>
      <utterance>Will you hire her now?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long have you boys been playing?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since I was three.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe since I was three and a half.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your mom must be a good teacher.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta gives Nick a look, but Janet smiles.</context>
      <utterance>She's O.K.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you could teach our students to play like that, I'd be thrilled, but --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can. Any child can learn the violin.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Assuming they had the discipline.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll teach them to have discipline.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A lot of our parents are struggling to feed their kids and pay the rent -- they don't have time to help them learn violin.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dennis laughs. Roberta looks at him, a bit miffed.</context>
      <utterance>They don't have to. If they can help, great -- but these kids will be committed. They'll practice on their own, they'll help each other in the classroom --</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I know these students, Miss Demetras. Their attention span doesn't go past do-re-mi. Maybe on a good day, I can get them to "fa."</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're underestimating them. They can play as well as any other kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That I'd like to see.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Janet observes the tension, then turns to Roberta.</context>
      <utterance>You will.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For now I'll put you down as a sub, but I have to warn you -- even if it works out, the Board may not let me create a permanent position for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see relief -- and fear -- in Roberta's face.</context>
      <utterance>That's O.K. I'll worry about that later.  Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I've already planned out the whole term, and I can tell you right now, there's no room for this! Besides, where you gonna find money for violins?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need violins?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They ignore her.</context>
      <utterance>Please do not open the cases, O.K.?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE - Three girls open their cases.</context>
      <utterance>Look, can everyone just settle down and listen to me -- please?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE - Two boys open their cases.</context>
      <utterance>Keep them closed! Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE - A boy and a girl are having a "sword fight" with their bows.</context>
      <utterance>Put those down, please!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's the SOUND of violin strings being plucked.</context>
      <utterance>Don't do that! Put the bows back in the cases -- right now!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta wheels around to find a girl plucking her violin like a banjo, and doing a little dance. This is LUCY, a skinny Puerto Rican girl in perpetual motion.</context>
      <utterance>Who's plucking?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta takes a breath. The kids settle down a bit.</context>
      <utterance>What have I been saying? Put that away! Back in the case!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE - A boy plays "bongos" on his violin case.</context>
      <utterance>O.K. Thank you. That's much better.  I'll be dividing you into five classes, but for today --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The bongo player stands.</context>
      <utterance>O.K. -- that's it! You! Stand up!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The child looks stunned.</context>
      <utterance>You will be the first student who will NOT be in my violin class. Out!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a sheepish expression, he exits. The room is finally quiet -- and Roberta's amazed that something worked. She puffs up a little bit, enjoying the feeling of control.</context>
      <utterance>I said OUT!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The students stare at her, afraid of her now. DE SEAN, a small but tough Black boy, raises his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Who else would like to be kicked out of my class?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you raising your hand because you want to be kicked out?</utterance>
   <speaker>DE SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>DE SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't wanna learn no stupid violin. It's for wimps.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who told you that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DE SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>De Sean.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks around the room.</context>
      <utterance>Well, De Sean -- you haven't given me a good enough reason, so you're staying.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>Anyone else?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NAEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, I play pretty good.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See how easy it is?  Maybe in the spring, we could have a big concert for your families and for the whole school.  What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta writes in a notebook and we see that she's measuring for violin sizes.</context>
      <utterance>Naeem.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON THE KIDS, not used to a teacher speaking like that.</context>
      <utterance>If you listen to me and do exactly what I say, you're gonna sound beautiful at the concert and you're gonna be so proud of yourselves.  Good, Naeem. Your hand's staying soft.  But if you don't listen to me, you'll sound so bad that your own parents will feel sick when they hear you. They might even throw up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They clink glasses and drink.</context>
      <utterance>It's a toast.  To Roberta, who's made it through her first week.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, Brian. I'm hanging on by a thread there. Out of fifty kids, maybe six are listening to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Look at the progress. Didn't you say no one was listening to you on Monday?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I really appreciate all you've done for us. And I promise -- this weekend I'll start looking for a place.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no rush.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, we've put you out enough. You're supposed to be writing, not babysitting for us.  I've started your book. It's very powerful.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian comes up behind her and starts to kiss her neck. Roberta's scared -- so she keeps talking, as if it's not really happening.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what made you choose migrant workers for your next book? I mean, how do you know what to write about?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta's aroused, in spite of herself. She turns around and faces him.</context>
      <utterance>I follow my gut, pay attention to what I'm being drawn to...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been waiting to do that since Mr. Baines' orchestra class.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't even notice me!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure I did. You used to ignore me and it drove me wild.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You had at least five different girlfriends.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives her a flirtatious smile, then takes out one of her rollers.</context>
      <utterance>It didn't mean I had the one I wanted.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves to takes out another roller and Roberta stops him.</context>
      <utterance>You're not a navy wife anymore...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes I am... legally.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And is it a navy requirement that you dress like it's the 1950's?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do not!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who did you vote for in the last election?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does that have to do with anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Charles filled out my absentee ballot.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She laughs wistfully, then looks a little sad.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God -- it's even worse than I thought!  Is this the same Roberta who got the orchestra to strike until they gave us new uniforms?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls her towards him by the belt to her robe.</context>
      <utterance>That Roberta's not around anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They kiss and it heats up quickly. Roberta pulls back.</context>
      <utterance>I don't believe that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I shouldn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The boys --</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're sleeping.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, but... I'm still married.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A few beats, and she moves towards him.</context>
      <utterance>And what's your husband doing right now?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh shit -- the boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She turns, relieved, until she sees that Brian's packing a suitcase.</context>
      <utterance>They're still sleeping.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He dashes out. Roberta sits up, rattled by this news.</context>
      <utterance>Texas.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>He turns to see Roberta in the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>What's in Texas?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Farm workers. I just got the call -- it came through -- my research grant! It came through! Isn't that great?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He places items into a carry-on bag, packing at a rapid clip. In contrast, Roberta seems to be moving in slow motion.</context>
      <utterance>Today?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got a few families lined up there, some in California --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long will you be gone?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two, three months.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought... I just thought you were gonna be around. And then last night -- He stops what he's doing and looks at her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa. Roberta -- last night was great but did you think I was gonna marry you in the morning?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see in her face that part of her did think that.</context>
      <utterance>No! Of course not.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian softens as he sees how vulnerable she is. He takes her in his arms.</context>
      <utterance>It's just that... we just got here and we're barely... I don't even know where to buy groceries.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She attempts a smile.</context>
      <utterance>You're gonna be fine. You have a job, a place to stay, your kids have a school to go to -- and there's a D'Agostino's around the corner.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her forehead, then exits. HOLD ON ROBERTA, looking hurt and frightened.</context>
      <utterance>Congratulations.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what am I doing now?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAEEM/GUADALUPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rosining the bow.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kids quiet down. Only Naeem raises his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Good. And what am I doing when I turn this little screw?  Everyone stop talking. Right now!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naeem?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tightening the horse hair.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again, only Naeem raises his hand. Roberta sees him but turns to DE SEAN, who's talking to his neighbor.</context>
      <utterance>And what do we call this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>De Sean?</utterance>
   <speaker>DE SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do we call this?</utterance>
   <speaker>DE SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>DE SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wasn't here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This makes De Sean blush -- and it pisses him off.</context>
      <utterance>Yes you were but you weren't paying attention! Do you want people to think you're stupid?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, Naeem -- tell them.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some kids giggle and joke about this. Roberta points to the scroll of the violin.</context>
      <utterance>It's called the frog.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LUCY, the fidgety girl, snaps her fingers.</context>
      <utterance>Anyone remember what this is?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lucy! Do you like people snapping their fingers when you're talking?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kids laugh. Roberta doesn't. She points to the scroll.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this called?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta laughs, even though she's trying to be tough.</context>
      <utterance>The jeri curl?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me -- sorry to interrupt -- The students immediately start to chatter.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks back at Roberta, annoyed by her intrusion.</context>
      <utterance>No talking!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm supposed to take kids out of Miss Cooper's classroom for my ten o'clock class -- there's nobody there.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miss Cooper's students have phys ed on Tuesdays.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you scheduled them for violin.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must have read the schedule wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I can't solve this problem for you right now.  I'm trying to teach.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She exits.</context>
      <utterance>So am I.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I bring a puppy for show and tell tomorrow?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey, we don't have a puppy.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta looks at Nick, then turns back to Lexi.</context>
      <utterance>Daddy said we could get one when we moved back to America.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about your truck? I'll bet you're the only one in school with a truck from Greece.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta turns to Nick and tucks him in.</context>
      <utterance>When's Daddy coming back?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, he's still on his tour, so we'll just have to see but... It shouldn't be too much longer.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he gonna live with us and Brian?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns back to Nick who looks worried. She kisses him.</context>
      <utterance>No, honey. We're just staying at Brian's house for a little while.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses Lexi, then reaches to turn off the lamp.</context>
      <utterance>Good night, sweetie.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta nods, smiles at her sons, and exits.</context>
      <utterance>No! Leave it on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks over to BENJAMIN, a white boy with glasses, and corrects his feet. She sees Lucy dancing in place.</context>
      <utterance>Now take the right foot and put it on a tile. Good. Now with the other foot take a tiny step forward and put it on a line. Try to make a box with your feet --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lucy nods, giggling. Roberta walks down the row of students.</context>
      <utterance>Lucy! Would you like to leave the class right now?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She crosses to TANISHA, a sweet-natured Black girl with her hair in tiny braids, and gently pushes her belly.</context>
      <utterance>You should feel very strong -- so strong and balanced that if I wanted to knock you over I couldn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta turns to De Sean, who's talking to JAMES, a pudgy Black/Puerto Rican boy.</context>
      <utterance>You see? If you're standing strong, I can't even push you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>De Sean! James! Quiet!  Does anyone know where Naeem is?</utterance>
   <speaker>TANISHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw him this morning but he's not here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gently pushes Guadalupe's belly. The girl stumbles back.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I know he's not here -- that's why I'm asking.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Guadalupe tries to correct her feet. Roberta bends down to help and sees that the little girl wears LEG BRACES under her pants. Roberta stands and gestures to one of the boys.</context>
      <utterance>See how I pushed you? It means your feet aren't centered.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy brings the chair. Guadalupe sits, embarrassed.</context>
      <utterance>Can you bring over a chair?  It's probably better for you to sit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where were you today, Naeem?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't be in violin class anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My mother won't let me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>NAEEM'S MOTHER, MRS. ADISA, steps INTO FRAME. She's an attractive Black woman in a dress and head scarf made of African fabric.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. ADISA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My son's got more important things to do than learn dead white men's music.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're gonna learn "Twinkle Twinkle Little Star"!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. ADISA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many Black classical composers can you name? How many Black classical violinists do you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That doesn't mean it's the way it should be. Naeem's learning to play music -- and that makes him feel good about himself. Why should it matter who wrote it?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Adisa puts a protective arm around her son, then addresses Roberta.</context>
      <utterance>Please, Mom? Can't I be in the class?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. ADISA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks off with Naeem. He glances back at Roberta, then turns away quickly. Roberta watches after them.</context>
      <utterance>Look. I've seen this before. You white women come up here and think you can rescue our poor inner city children who never asked to be rescued in the first place. No thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kids simultaneously yell out "ATLANTIC" and "PACIFIC."</context>
      <utterance>And which ocean is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me... I'm here for the violin students.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're late.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a couple of minutes -- I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're having a lesson now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But this is when they have violin class!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta's reluctant to argue in front of the kids; she exits.</context>
      <utterance>That's not my problem.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought all the teachers agreed to this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In theory.  Adam! I want you in my office right after lunch, you understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think about it!  Whenever you pull kids out, it's a disruption, plus it's extra work for the teacher 'cause they have to fill the kids in on what they missed. Some teachers resent it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Janet stops walking and pulls a box cutter out of her pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Well, can't you talk to them?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Janet starts to walk away, then turns.</context>
      <utterance>I took this off a second-grader this morning. I'll help you Roberta -- but I can't hold your hand here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A word of advice? When you're picking up your students, go to Alice's classroom first. Roberta stands there as Janet walks on ahead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON THE CHILDREN, attempting this. She walks around and helps.</context>
      <utterance>So pretend you're driving a car and I'm the policeman and I say STOP! Thumb up, fingers straight up, flat palm. Now you be policemen, but turn your hand and make it say stop to yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>DE SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some kids crack up and start joking and chatting.</context>
      <utterance>You're under arrest.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some of the children think about what she's saying. A couple, uncomfortable with the intensity, hold back giggles.</context>
      <utterance>Knock it off, De Sean!  If you kids can't take this seriously, I don't want you here. I'm teaching you a difficult instrument because I respect you and have faith that you can learn it. But none of that matters if you don't have respect for yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta sees Guadalupe struggling.</context>
      <utterance>Now turn your wrist so it's flat against the fingerboard, and that's how you'll set up your hand...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guadalupe! You've got the violin in the wrong hand! How did that happen? Embarrassed, Guadalupe corrects her position.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Her face falls as she hears the voice. She holds onto the counter to steady herself.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Bobbi.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Roberta closes the oven and gathers her courage.</context>
      <utterance>I'm back in the States. I'm at my parents.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>Are you still with her?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>We watch Roberta's body collapse into a sense of overwhelming relief. FOLLOW HER as she steps into THE HALLWAY, then stretches the phone into:</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've missed you so much, Charles. The boys... they can't wait for you to come home... I know we'll have a lot to work out and it won't be easy right away, but we're gonna get through this, you know? We're a family and we belong together and --</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Roberta looks as if she's been slapped. A beat.</context>
      <utterance>Bobbi -- stop, O.K.? Just stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want a divorce.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you said... you and Lana... you said it was over.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLES</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>It's over between us too, Bobbi. HOLD ON ROBERTA, devastated. ANGLE on NICK, watching her through the door.</context>
      <utterance>It is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe you were still holding out hope. The guy hasn't called you or the kids in three months -- I thought you'd moved on.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never said that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This embarrasses her, then pisses her off.</context>
      <utterance>No? Maybe not with words.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what? I shouldn't have called you. This was a mistake.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no -- I'm sorry. Look, I know it hurts, but you're gonna get through this, Roberta -- you will.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm moving back to my Mom's.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? You're gonna quit teaching in the middle of the term?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't fit in there -- I'm not making any progress with the kids...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you gonna tell Janet -- your husband left you and nothing else matters?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know yet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My mother gave it to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would she give you fifty dollars?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Janet gives him a stern look.</context>
      <utterance>To buy breakfast.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know how hard your mother works? Do you think it's right for you steal from her?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't!</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Janet turns to walk off, Roberta crosses to her.</context>
      <utterance>Well let's go call her right now and ask her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to speak to you. It's important.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta watches as Janet dashes off with the boy in tow.</context>
      <utterance>It'll have to wait.  Come on. In my office.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guadalupe? What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUADALUPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't get the stop sign.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Guadalupe sighs, then hands Roberta the violin.</context>
      <utterance>Honey, your teacher's probably looking for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUADALUPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't come anymore. It's too hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The violin is hard for everyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUADALUPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta looks at her sadly and puts the violin in its case.</context>
      <utterance>But everyone else is better than me. I'll always be slow.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you ever hear of Itzhak Perlman?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUADALUPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's one of the greatest violinists in the world, and he has problems with his legs too. He walks with two canes -- but he still makes the most beautiful music.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUADALUPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And he sits down when he plays?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Guadalupe takes this in.</context>
      <utterance>He has to.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUADALUPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta laughs.</context>
      <utterance>He was your student?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. But if he was, I'd tell him the same thing I'm telling you. You shouldn't quit something just because it's hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUADALUPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I can't stand strong.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Guadalupe nods. Roberta holds out the violin case. Guadalupe lunges forward and hugs her around the waist. Roberta awkwardly accepts the hug, startled and touched by it, and strokes the girl's hair. Guadalupe lets go, takes the violin and exits. HOLD ON ROBERTA as she absorbs what just happened. JANET pokes her head into the room.</context>
      <utterance>Standing strong doesn't only mean using your legs. You can stand strong on the inside too.  Know what I mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanted to speak to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Janet looks at her curiously, then exits.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Umm -- that's O.K. It's taken care of.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LANDLADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is just for you and your boys?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDLADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>No husband? No boyfriend?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives her a tempera PAINTING of a man's face, the background decorated with glued-on macaroni. It says DADDY.</context>
      <utterance>Look what I made you, Mommy!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs off. Roberta exhales, sits down alone on a bench and takes out her lunch. She smiles at ALICE CROWLEY and another TEACHER but they cross to another bench. ISABEL VASQUEZ (25) approaches, a lively Puerto Rican woman with a strong New York accent.</context>
      <utterance>That is so beautiful!</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatsa matter -- you got cooties?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Apparently.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take my chances.  Isabel Vasquez. Second grade.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roberta Demetras. I'm the --</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sits down beside Roberta, takes out her lunch.</context>
      <utterance>Violin teacher. I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it my imagination, or does everyone hate me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's hard to fit in when you're doing a special program. People figure you're not gonna be here very long, so why make the effort?  It may take a while for folks to warm up, but nobody hates you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Alice Crowley?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then there's Dennis.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Music Man. You've had the bodacity to threaten his private little empire -- not to mention the fact that you messed up his sacred scheduling chart.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come you're being nice to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Ulterior motives. I want my daughter in your class next year.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I'm here next year.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will be.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In Greece, we could see the ocean. Remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I remember. And the fishing boats...</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta smiles and puts her arm around him.</context>
      <utterance>And the octopuses.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta tenses up.</context>
      <utterance>Is Daddy coming here soon?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>Well, that's something I've been wanting to talk to you about. Daddy's not gonna live with us anymore. You and Lexi will have special times when you stay with him, like at Christmas.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta looks at him, concerned that he's not responding to her news.</context>
      <utterance>Can you tell the birthday story?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you want to talk about what I told you?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat as she contemplates whether to push or not, then:</context>
      <utterance>I want to hear the birthday story.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was the day of Grandpa's birthday, and I was sad because he had died a few months back.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you knew I'd be born that day.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I packed a bag and got all ready --</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Daddy laughed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said, "It's my father's birthday, and the baby's gonna be born today."</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He didn't believe you. But I was born. The same day as Grandpa.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was a happy day.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him, taken aback by the question.</context>
      <utterance>Was Daddy happy too?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course he was.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta, overcome with emotion, can barely answer.</context>
      <utterance>Then why is he leaving me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not leaving you, Nick. He loves you and Lexi very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why can't he live here?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Slow bows! Slow bows! Don't squeeze! Stop! Everybody stop!  How much did you practice this week?</utterance>
   <speaker>DE SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My asthma -- it was very bad and I had to go to the hospital.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Again? You told me you went to the hospital last week.</utterance>
   <speaker>DE SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta rolls her eyes, then turns to Lucy.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah. Maybe it was last week.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lucy -- you sounded the worst of all. Have you practiced?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not? You can't be in this class if you don't practice!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>My grandma got mugged.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. I'm sorry. Is she O.K.?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta stands there, sobered.</context>
      <utterance>She died.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm really sorry, Lucy.  Just do the best you can.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NAEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Roberta.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Naeem nods and moves off.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Naeem. Can I talk to your mom for a minute?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Adisa takes this in. Roberta exits. Mrs. Adisa looks for Naeem and sees him watching the violin students, longing to be among them. She watches her son with compassion.</context>
      <utterance>Look, I didn't come up here to rescue anybody. I'm a single mother and I needed a job. And I know you think you're protecting your son, but you're not. I mean, what if Arthur Ashe's mother had stopped him from playing tennis because it's a "white man's game"?  The important thing is that when Naeem plays music, his whole face lights up. You should see him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys are oblivious to her -- they're in heaven.</context>
      <utterance>We all have to take turns cleaning up, O.K.?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stop playing. Tanisha raises her hand.</context>
      <utterance>First finger on the E! Three -- two -- one -- open!  Wrong string, Becky! We've done this fourteen times! And look at your nails! You're supposed to cut them for violin class! O.K, everybody stop! It sounds horrible! I can't believe how bad it sounds!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tanisha nods.</context>
      <utterance>Is this an important question, Tanisha?</utterance>
   <speaker>TANISHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have two of those skirts?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>TANISHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some of the kids crack up.</context>
      <utterance>You wore a skirt just like it on Monday.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door opens and Naeem enters with Mrs. Adisa. Roberta crosses to them.</context>
      <utterance>You know, Tanisha -- I don't think that's such an important question.  O.K. Let's try --</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. ADISA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>Naeem and I were wondering if he could still be in the class.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd love that.  You'll have a lot of catching up to do. You think you can work that hard?</utterance>
   <speaker>NAEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I can.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe we can also arrange some private lessons at my house.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. ADISA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't have the money for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Why don't you go grab one of my spare violins? Naeem happily runs to the extra violins at the front of the room; Mrs. Adisa nods to Roberta with a look of gratitude, then exits. Roberta crosses back to the front of the room.</context>
      <utterance>That's O.K.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They begin again, and we see Naeem take out a violin and join in. As they play, Roberta's ears perk up at something she's hearing. She crosses to Lucy.</context>
      <utterance>Let's try it again.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you playing?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twinkle.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lucy hesitates, thinking she's in trouble. She plays a jazz variation of the song. Roberta smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Everyone stop!  Let me hear.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did someone teach you that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I made it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lucy beams.</context>
      <utterance>That's really great, Lucy. I'm proud of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The class plays Lucy's jazz variation and Naeem happily joins in.</context>
      <utterance>All of you -- try it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MRS. LAMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're shouting at them. All the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not all the time. But if they don't listen --</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. LAMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Janet raises her eyebrows at this.</context>
      <utterance>Didn't you tell them that they were making their parents sick?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That wasn't exactly what I said --</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. LAMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm raising Becky in a supportive atmosphere. I don't send her to school to be abused.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just trying to discipline them. If they're gonna learn an instrument, they need to take it seriously --</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives Roberta a long hard look. Roberta nods.</context>
      <utterance>I think what Mrs. Lamb is trying to say, Roberta, is that you're a little too harsh. I'm sure you might be able to soften some of your comments to the children?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at her in disbelief, then look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Well, that was... that was pretty good... that wasn't too bad...</utterance>
   <speaker>DE SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wasn't? I thought we stunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy nervously shakes his head no.</context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't put it that way... You all just need to practice a bit more.  James, have you practiced this week?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>James nods. The kids are baffled by her politeness.</context>
      <utterance>Can you please try a little harder for next week?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. Just do the best you can.</utterance>
   <speaker>DE SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why you acting like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>DE SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you want a nice teacher?</utterance>
   <speaker>DE SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I already got nice teachers. You added some variety.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. We like you better the way you used to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.  What about you, Becky?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. This is even worse. You're acting weird now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kids laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Well, then -- I take it back. You all stunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kids laugh again.</context>
      <utterance>But don't tell your parents I said so!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't you come with us? Please?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lexi looks upset; Nick is stoic. Roberta hugs them one last time. The FLIGHT ATTENDANT steps forward.</context>
      <utterance>Honey, I told you. This is Daddy's special time with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLIGHT ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The FLIGHT ATTENDANT escorts them into the jet way. Roberta holds back tears as they get further away from her. At the last moment, Lexi turns and waves; Nick does not. Roberta waves, tears starting to fall, and the boys disappear from sight. She observes all the families travelling together, and feels like the loneliest person in the airport.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take good care of them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She looks through the peephole, then quickly unlocks the door and opens it, revealing BRIAN, giving her a big smile. He looks sexy as hell (even with a silly lit-up Santa Claus pin on his leather jacket), and he holds a long-stemmed red rose in one hand, and a Christmas present in the other.</context>
      <utterance>Santa Claus.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta's thrilled and relieved to see him. She embraces him, and they kiss passionately.</context>
      <utterance>I'm back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>O.K., enough goofing off -- back to work.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ASSUNTA comes up the street with a bag of take-out food. She casts a dubious glance at the lovers.</context>
      <utterance>You trying to kill me? She laughs and they kiss.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSUNTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was the only person in the whole coffee shop not speaking Spanish. Roberta rolls her eyes. O.S. a car BACKFIRES.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSUNTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You hear that? Gunshots! How you gonna live here by yourself?  Boys, come eat!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys approach and Assunta hands them sandwiches. Lawrence hangs back. Assunta calls to him.</context>
      <utterance>I work in this neighborhood, Mama. I want to live here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSUNTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWRENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lawrence.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSUNTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lawrence nods and she hands him a sandwich. Roberta smiles at her mother's gesture. The kids move off to Lawrence's front steps and Assunta gives Roberta and Brian sandwiches.</context>
      <utterance>You hungry, Lawrence?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSUNTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did you let her buy this house?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, your daughter does what she wants -- or haven't you noticed?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSUNTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've noticed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>ASSUNTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still don't understand the rush.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Having my own place will make me feel like I'm really starting my life again.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSUNTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But if you invested your divorce settlement, you could buy something nice someday. It's bad enough that you've been renting in this neighborhood, but to lock yourself into a mortgage --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Assunta backs off. Roberta feels guilty and moves to her.</context>
      <utterance>Mama, please. Just stop!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A few beats.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, O.K.? Besides, if things keep going well, I'm sure eventually Brian will move in with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSUNTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much do you know about this man?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brian's a good person, he's helped me a lot, he's great with the boys -- since he got back to town, it's been really sweet.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSUNTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And how long has he been back?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two months.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSUNTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not very long. Don't make the same mistake twice, Bert. You barely knew Charles when you married him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't get it -- you're ragging on me about buying the house -- I would think you'd want Brian to live with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSUNTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta locks her jaw, not wanting to believe that she's right.</context>
      <utterance>Not if he's the wrong person.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They reach a certain note, then pause.</context>
      <utterance>Get ready, now -- we're coming up to the fermata...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts for the door and the kids moan and groan: "Come on, Roberta!" "Roberta, get back here!" She smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Hold... Hold... Don't anybody move. Now at the Spring Concert, the audience is gonna be dying for that next note -- but we'll make them wait. As a matter of fact, I think I'll go grab a cup of coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods. They begin again -- all at different times.</context>
      <utterance>Well, O.K. But you have to promise you'll all start together.</utterance>
   <speaker>DE SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man. We'll never get that right.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All the kids raise their hands. De Sean looks around, embarrassed, then raises his too. Roberta smiles.</context>
      <utterance>That's not a very nice thing to say about your classmates.  How many people think they can get it right by the concert?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian makes a sound that's either panting or laughing.</context>
      <utterance>I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you just laugh?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta looks at him, offended.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. It's just...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She disentangles from him.</context>
      <utterance>Why do people feel like the minute something's going great, they gotta name it?  Once you name something, you snuff the life out of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Brian. Do you still get away with that crap? It's not the Sixties anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, maybe if you'd actually gone through the Sixties, you'd know what I'm talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She angrily turns on her side with her back to him. Brian regrets hurting her and moves to her, kissing her shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Fine! We won't name it, we won't talk about it, we'll act like we have no feelings for each other whatsoever!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I'm being an asshole.  You can say you love me if you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs and coaxes her to kiss him -- a temporary truce.</context>
      <utterance>Forget it. I changed my mind.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's it coming, Ernie?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian overhears, rolls his eyes and pulls her aside.</context>
      <utterance>Well, if I could just remember what I did here yesterday, I'd be moving a whole lot faster.  You look real pretty today, honey.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're crazy. Why did you hire him?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He needed a job. Besides, he's wired all of East Harlem.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian sighs and walks off into another room. Two MEN carry in large panels of sheetrock with old WALLPAPER on it.</context>
      <utterance>When? Fifty years ago?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why is there wallpaper on it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They lean the panels against a wall. Roberta turns to Ernie.</context>
      <utterance>That's how it comes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guys quickly exit. Brian re-enters and sees the panels.</context>
      <utterance>Yep, that's how it comes now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sheetrock.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta feels stupid but doesn't want to show it.</context>
      <utterance>You've gotta be kidding. Those ex- cons you hired ripped this off -- and you too!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look -- this house is taking every penny of my settlement. I can't afford fancy union workers!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stomps off. ANOTHER ANGLE - Nick watches them fight and looks distressed.</context>
      <utterance>Fine. Do it your way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm giving him a two-day suspension -- but next time he'll be expelled.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There won't be a next time -- I promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you noticed your son lately? He's tied up in knots and he needs help.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Janet, kids fight. You're making too much of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta takes this in, upset.</context>
      <utterance>He was choking the kid.  Nick's in trouble, Roberta. You need to deal with it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta crosses to Nick and shuts off the T.V.</context>
      <utterance>Keep playing, guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can watch when we're done.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's my house! They don't live here -- I do!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick honey -- the kids are real nervous about the Spring concert. You could probably give them some pointers.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches for the T.V. dial and she stops him.</context>
      <utterance>I don't feel like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She crosses back to her students; Nick turns on the T.V.</context>
      <utterance>I said no.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick throws it back to Brian and it lands in the WATER.</context>
      <utterance>Good catch Nick!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't! Don't throw me in!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatsa matter? Afraid of a little water? The ducks aren't afraid! Are you a chicken or a duck?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't! Don't throw me!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like you got yourself a chicken, Roberta!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not a chicken!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pretends again to throw Nick in, then puts him down. Lexi holds out his arms to Brian.</context>
      <utterance>Well then you must be a duck!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian swoops him up and Lexi starts laughing. Roberta laughs along, happy to see the affection between Brian and her sons.</context>
      <utterance>Throw me in the water, Brian! Do it to me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You seem to be the only one who can get Nick to laugh these days.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He misses his dad. I'm just a surrogate.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- I think Nick really likes you.  You know... we're all hoping you'll move into the new house with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa. Can we just slow down here a minute? It's too much like getting married.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's so bad about that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That kind of commitment just isn't realistic. I mean, how can we know that you and I will even be able to stand each other in five years?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we don't. But if two people care about each other, they take a chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And look what happened to you and Charles.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not talking about Charles. I'm talking about us.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is making her nervous. She looks at him, afraid of what he might be saying.</context>
      <utterance>Look, Roberta. Marriage is based on a belief that one person can completely meet another person's needs. I just don't buy that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you saying? If there's some need you have that I don't meet, you'd go and get it "met" by someone else? He heaves a sigh of frustration, not wanting to answer the question.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm saying that it's the 80's and it's a fantasy to think of marriage lasting these days. One out of two marriages ends in divorce!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>You didn't answer my question.  If I don't meet all your needs, and we're in a committed relationship -- forget marriage for a minute; I'm just talking about a relationship -- would you go to someone else?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In theory, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta looks very disheartened. Brian feels badly.</context>
      <utterance>In theory.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roberta, we've got something good right now -- that's the important thing. Let's just keep it that way,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Roberta looks distressed by her talk with Brian as she and the boys enter, back from the park.</context>
      <utterance>Why can't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He just can't, O.K.? Brian's at his house tonight, and we're at ours.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well then I wanna go to his house.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enough, Nick. Now why don't you and your brother practice while I make dinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't feel like practicing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well do it anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanna go to Brian's!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick stomps off to get his violin. Lexi follows. Roberta puts down her bag and takes off her coat. While Lexi sets up his violin, Nick opens his violin case, takes out the violin and angrily starts playing, loudly and roughly.</context>
      <utterance>Stop whining, and get your violin.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The problem with you is you're mean to everybody and then they don't want to be with you!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick THROWS the violin against the floor. Roberta's speechless.</context>
      <utterance>I've heard just about enough from you, young man. Now set your violin up properly and start practicing.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate the violin!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick picks up the violin and THROWS the violin down even harder, then YELLS at Roberta before she can even respond.</context>
      <utterance>You pick that violin up right now and don't you ever ever --</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta is stunned. The anger drains out of her as she suddenly sees what this is all about.</context>
      <utterance>It's all your fault! You made Daddy leave and you're gonna make Brian leave too! You're gonna be all alone and I'll have to take care of you!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick -- you don't have to take care of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then who's going to?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take care of myself -- and I'll take care of you and Lexi. I promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This hits her in the solar plexus. Her hurt and vulnerability start to pour out.</context>
      <utterance>You didn't try hard enough. You made Daddy leave us.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not true. I begged him not to leave, but he didn't listen.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta hesitates, but knows she has to tell them the truth. She addresses both boys.</context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your father met someone he liked more than Mommy, and then --</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta swallows, shocked to hear him ask this. She can hardly answer him.</context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lana. Remember our friends Lana and Tom?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he gonna marry her now?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick and Lexi look very upset, not only from hearing the finality in her words, but from seeing their mother's pain. Roberta moves closer to them.</context>
      <utterance>No, but he's not coming back... to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick starts crying. Roberta takes him in her arms. Lexi starts to cry and Roberta holds him too.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take care of you, Nick. You too, Lexi. I promise. I'm not going anywhere. We're still a family.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I promise.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What color is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>White.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you Eggshell.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian watches this interaction as he sands a door.</context>
      <utterance>Eggshells are white.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're an idiot! I told you -- you can't be your own contractor.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She crosses to Ernie and shakes him.</context>
      <utterance>You're right. I'm an idiot.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her groggily.</context>
      <utterance>Wake up, Ernie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She crosses to the brick workers.</context>
      <utterance>You're fired.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She crosses to the painters.</context>
      <utterance>You're fired.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian smiles at her, impressed.</context>
      <utterance>You're fired.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's more like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian laughs.</context>
      <utterance>You're fired too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Brian. I mean it. I need to be with a man who can make a commitment to me. I need that, and my sons need that.  So can you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His tone and expression tell her the words are not forthcoming.</context>
      <utterance>Roberta --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her, shocked by her toughness, but knows he can't give her what she wants. He exits. Roberta stands in the middle of the room, a determined look on her face.</context>
      <utterance>Get out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon everybody, settle down -- Janet wants to talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Today's a very special day because we're starting the tenth year of the East Harlem Violin Program. This is a wonderful opportunity for you, so I want you to talk to your parents about whether you'd like to try this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My daughter took violin with Roberta when she was your age, and now she's in high school and she still talks about how much she loved it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CUTAWAY to Roberta and Janet exchanging glances over Dennis taking credit for the program.</context>
      <utterance>Janet and I started this program because we knew how much you kids could benefit from it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JUSTIN, a Black boy with attitude, raises his hand. He always wears a puffy red, yellow and green crocheted beret. Isabel nods to him.</context>
      <utterance>You should know, however, that the violin is a difficult instrument.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE - DOROTHEA (Doro-taya) VAN HAUFTEN (40's), an elegant, beautiful woman, smartly dressed, takes photographs from the back of the room.</context>
      <utterance>Who's that lady in the back?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Dorothea Van Hauften --</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say what? What kinda name is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Justin -- sshh!</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- and she's taking pictures of Roberta's classes for a magazine article about music education.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanna be in the magazine!</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta steps forward. RAMON OLIVAS (7), a small, adorable Puerto Rican boy with a crew cut, watches her with adoration.</context>
      <utterance>First things first, Justin. Roberta's gonna explain to you about the "lottery."</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VANESSA raises her hand, a white girl whose clothes and accessories are always adorned with cats.</context>
      <utterance>I used to just teach fifty kids at this school. But now I teach a hundred and fifty kids at three East Harlem schools and there's so many children who want to take violin classes that we have to have a lottery.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I be in the class?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roberta's explaining that. Just listen.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE - Ramon listens intently with his fingers crossed.</context>
      <utterance>After your parents sign your permission slips, I'm gonna put them in a sack, and I'll pick fifty names from each school.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So everyone bring in your slips by Friday, and I'll come back and tell you who's in violin class.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RAMON raises his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Remember, she's just picking names from a hat. It doesn't mean that anyone's better than anyone else.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta looks at him, struck by his sweetness.</context>
      <utterance>I really really hope that I get in the class.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope so too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come you guys don't play the violin?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel cracks up but stifles her laughter as Roberta enters from outside with Allegra.</context>
      <utterance>Well, picture her being your teacher and your mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Roberta removes Allegra's leash, Rachel and Lexi share a conspiratorial look. In the b.g., Nick packs up his cello.</context>
      <utterance>Hi Rachel. Be right with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gonna practice upstairs?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I'm done.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Already? You've barely practiced.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What -- are you timing me with a stop watch? Why don't you pick on Lexi for a change?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick jostles him and heads upstairs. Lexi gets up from the piano.</context>
      <utterance>'Cause I'm perfect.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He crosses to a sharp-looking bike parked behind the front door and addresses Roberta.</context>
      <utterance>Have a good lesson.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be back in a couple of hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lexi mouths "be careful" along with her.</context>
      <utterance>Be careful.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MALE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Lexi wipes his mouth and looks up at HENRY (18), a tall, intimidating Black teenager who towers over him. Lawrence watches tensely.</context>
      <utterance>Can I try your bike?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna be leaving pretty soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just wanna take it for a spin.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWRENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Henry -- he don't want to loan you his bike.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lexi looks at him, knowing there's only one right answer.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't hear him say that.  Is that true? Did you say that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel stops, frustrated.</context>
      <utterance>Vibrato... don't wiggle your wrist.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dang! I can't get that right.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You almost have it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Almost isn't good enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did I turn you into such a perfectionist?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I came that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just as long as you get it right for your Julliard audition.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE - Lexi enters the front door, a glum look on his face.</context>
      <utterance>I've recommended you for a gifted kids scholarship. Rachel looks at her in wide-eyed gratitude.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's the bike?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom, please. Don't do this to me!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Mom -- why don't you let me handle this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we getting closer, Lawrence?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWRENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the next block up.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to do this. I'll pay you back.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How? It took me six months to save up for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll help him, O.K.? We'll both pay you back.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or we'll ask Dad -- he'll help us out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, right.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWRENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta slows the car down next to a HOUSING PROJECT.</context>
      <utterance>O.K., slow down. It's the second one on the right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon Mom, let's get out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she exits. The boys watch as she heads for the building, then Lexi shakes his head and covers his face.</context>
      <utterance>Lock the doors.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick jumps out of the car and heads after her.</context>
      <utterance>I'm dead. She's gonna get me killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm coming with you!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick hesitates and heads back. Roberta presses on. Lawrence opens the window and calls to her.</context>
      <utterance>No. Get back in the car and stay with the boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWRENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't take the stairs!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat, then the door cracks open, an OLD WOMAN visible through the chain lock.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a school teacher. Henry has taken my son's bicycle and I want it back.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Henry's not here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A couple of beats.</context>
      <utterance>Well you tell Henry that if he returns the bike, I won't have to notify the police -- or his school principal. Although since I am a teacher, it would be very easy for me to do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not home. He doesn't get home till late.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How late?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not till after ten.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door closes. Roberta exhales. Did she just do that?</context>
      <utterance>I'll be on the steps of CPE 1 at 11 P.M. I'll be waiting for him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta sits confidently.</context>
      <utterance>You're crazy. He's not gonna show.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think he actually cares that you're a teacher? You think he even goes to school?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Mom -- let's just go.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick and Lexi roll their eyes and exchange a look: she's nuts. Suddenly, there's the SOUND of a bicycle. Nick, Lexi and Lawrence look towards the sound, incredulous. Lexi stands. Henry rides up on the bike and dismounts. Lexi looks directly at him as he takes the bike from him.</context>
      <utterance>It's only five after eleven.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances at Roberta, then walks off.</context>
      <utterance>I was just borrowing it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pretty Black girl with braids and tons of barrettes jumps up and down, then runs up for her letter. The kids SQUEAL and CHEER for each student called. Shandra hugs her best friend MYESHA, a chubby Black girl who also holds a letter.</context>
      <utterance>Shandra Wilson.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JUSTIN raises his fists in triumph. ANGLE - RAMON anxiously waits to see if his name will be called. JUSTIN sits down next to him, waves his letter in Ramon's face, taunting him.</context>
      <utterance>Justin Brady.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vanessa takes her letter and smiles. She puts it into her cat-shaped backpack.</context>
      <utterance>Vanessa Klein.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ramon crosses his fingers and holds his breath.</context>
      <utterance>O.K. One more name...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RAMON looks crushed. JUSTIN taunts him some more. LEONARD, a scrawny white boy takes his letter, scared by it. He starts to cry.</context>
      <utterance>Leonard Hood.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEONARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's too hard! I don't wanna do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you even wanna try, Leonard?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEONARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Isabel looks at Roberta.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ramon's face lights up.</context>
      <utterance>Well, O.K. then. I'll pick someone else.  Ramon Olivas.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RAMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is to inform you that your child, Ramon Olivas, has been chosen by lottery to be in the violin program.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONCEPCION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ramon spins round and round with the letter in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>You happy?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONCEPCION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you're happy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WOMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Roberta turns. It's DOROTHEA, the PHOTOGRAPHER we saw in the classroom.</context>
      <utterance>Does that really work?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rushes towards the school and Dorothea follows her.</context>
      <utterance>No. But I keep trying. And maybe someday the school will give me a parking space!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands Roberta a thin box. Roberta puts down her violins, glances inside it and forgets about being late.</context>
      <utterance>Wait --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DOROTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those copies are for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Can I... pay for you them?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They smile at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be silly. Besides -- you'll need your money for parking tickets.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you're doing for these children is wonderful. My husband's a violinist -- he was quite impressed when I told him about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's his name?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arnold Steinhardt.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dorothea nods, and hands Roberta a card.</context>
      <utterance>Of the Guarneri String Quartet?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RACHEL, heading for school, calls out to Roberta.</context>
      <utterance>Stay in touch. Let us know when the kids have a concert.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta smiles, slips the card in her pocket, nods to Dorothea and follows Rachel.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be late for violin class! I hear the teacher's really mean.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She crosses to a pudgy Black/Puerto Rican boy with glasses.</context>
      <utterance>Amanda, what did I tell you about wearing cowboy boots to violin class? They're too slippery!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances at STEPHANIE, a white girl with red hair, next to KENNY, a Black boy with an earnest expression.</context>
      <utterance>Relax your two, Simon...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CARLOS (13) hurries in, a handsome Black boy in a baseball jacket that says "LOS LEONES." He looks 15.</context>
      <utterance>Your stop sign has to be up, Kenny! Stephanie, it doesn't look like you ever had a lesson with me!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's your violin, Carlos?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nervously looks down the hall.</context>
      <utterance>It's coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A Black third-grade girl rushes into the room and hands Carlos his violin, then runs off. Roberta crosses to Carlos as he quickly readies the violin.</context>
      <utterance>What, is it walking here by itself?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your buddies giving you a hard time?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, it's just not cool. You wouldn't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, you want your sister to carry your violin, that's fine. But is she practicing for you too? Because lately, that's how it sounds.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been busy! I've been --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods sullenly.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not interested! Just get here on time, and commit to this class or I don't want you in here, you understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carlos takes this in as Roberta crosses to another student.</context>
      <utterance>You're a good violinist, Carlos -- and it's definitely not "cool" to waste your own talent.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MANUELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you show it to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONCEPCION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It just needed one parent's signature.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANUELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm his parent and I don't give permission! He should be playing baseball, not the violin!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONCEPCION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON RAMON, looking far from happy at the moment.</context>
      <utterance>It makes him happy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BOY #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ooh, check out little Miss Violinhead.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel turns to them.</context>
      <utterance>She carry that violin with her all the time 'cause she think she special.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She proudly continues on, then sees Roberta walking towards the school and catches up to her.</context>
      <utterance>I am special.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta stops and looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>So I heard from Julliard.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta gives her a big hug.</context>
      <utterance>They said yes!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vanessa enters the front door without her violin.</context>
      <utterance>More bow! To the frog! Myesha, your stop sign line should be touching. Don't let it wiggle! You're on the wrong string, Justin! And look at your feet!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's your violin?</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I forgot.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vanessa pouts and exits. Roberta moves to ROSARIO, a Puerto Rican girl.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye! And you may be dropped.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls a clipper from her pocket and swiftly clips them. MYESHA nervously glances at her own nails.</context>
      <utterance>Look at those nails, Rosario!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves to Ramon and corrects his bowing position.</context>
      <utterance>I see you over there, Myesha.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Roberta walks on to the next student, Justin purposely knocks over Ramon's music stand.</context>
      <utterance>You're doing much better.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drop dead, Justin!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUSTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was a accident!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was not!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ramon, I don't like that kind of talk. Justin, pick up his stand, now! Our spring concert is in three weeks and you might not be in it. Is that what you want?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Klein? I'm gonna have to drop Vanessa from the class if she keeps forgetting her violin.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. KLEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's going back and forth between houses. My wife and I split up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta leans into the car window.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vanessa, maybe you could write down for your Mom and Dad which days are violin days.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The tape doesn't stick.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Klein's eyes tear up and he quickly wipes them.</context>
      <utterance>I taped the music to the wall at my Mom's house and then I took it to my Dad's house and it doesn't stick anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks through her book bag, takes out a piece of music and gives it to her.</context>
      <utterance>Well you know what? That's an easy problem to solve.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vanessa nods, clutching the piece of music. Roberta and Mr. Klein exchange a look. She touches his arm, then walks off.</context>
      <utterance>Now you have two, O.K.? One for each house.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RAMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna hear my new song, Papa?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANUELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ramon exits, hurt. Concepcion watches from the side, and crosses to her husband.</context>
      <utterance>Not right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONCEPCION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shows no response, and she exits. Manuelo ponders what she said.</context>
      <utterance>We made mistakes with Pedro and Ernesto and we can't fix them now, but Ramon -- he works so hard. The violin makes him want to be good at everything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>RAMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta enters slowly. She looks very shaken up. She takes note of what Ramon is doing, and overhears Toussaint and Shandra in mid-conversation.</context>
      <utterance>You go to heaven... You go to hell... You go to hell... heaven...</utterance>
   <speaker>TOUSSAINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My grandpa died and my uncle, so that makes six.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta gently tells Ramon to sit, and then she sits down on a child-sized chair in front of them.</context>
      <utterance>I know more than that. At least seven people... maybe even nine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know that you've all heard the bad news about Justin.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYESHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't hear.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOUSSAINT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Myesha takes this in, looking sad.</context>
      <utterance>There was a drive-by shooting by his house and he got shot on accident and he died.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does anyone want to talk about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta watches him.</context>
      <utterance>I think we should just play violin.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CONCEPCION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta enters.</context>
      <utterance>Roberta! Come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I came by to check on Ramon.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONCEPCION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Concepcion shakes her head no.</context>
      <utterance>Didn't he tell you what happened at school?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>CONCEPCION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods. Concepcion touches his head, then exits.</context>
      <utterance>Roberta wants to talk to you, O.K.?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did that sound O.K.?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ramon smiles, pleased with himself.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it did.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been thinking about Justin. Remember how mad I got the last time I saw him?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. You got very strict with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ramon looks away from her, upset.</context>
      <utterance>It wasn't always so easy to be nice to him, you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think Justin's in heaven or hell?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ramon runs his fingers along his bow.</context>
      <utterance>Heaven.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta touches Ramon's back.</context>
      <utterance>I told him to drop dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Justin didn't die because of what you said. I promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think you're that powerful, do you? I mean, if you had such powers, just imagine what kind of violin player you'd be by now!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They laugh together, then Ramon looks sad again.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I'd be better than you!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's O.K. to cry, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not for a man.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ramon's eyes get teary. Roberta quietly leaves the room.</context>
      <utterance>My boys still cry and they're big, strong young men now.  I bet Justin's daddy cried.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick and Lexi stand by the table, opposite Roberta -- with the incriminating pile of letters between them.</context>
      <utterance>We were just trying to help!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is humiliating!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom, no one knows it's you! I mean, you don't even have to read them if you don't want to.  Although obviously, a lot of guys are interested in dating you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They thought she'd never ask.</context>
      <utterance>No. A lot of guys are interested in dating you and Lexi.  What did you say about me, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Beautiful musician, late 40's, tired of playing solo --</utterance>
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- seeks a healthy, stable, attractive man who's not afraid of a duet with a strong, independent woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My violin playing will feed your soul...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They beam with pride. Roberta looks at them, mortified.</context>
      <utterance>...And my lasagna will be music to your palate."</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, my God.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you catch all the music metaphors?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you think it's a little weird that you're trying to get your mother a date?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you think it's a little weird that you're not even interested in dating?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys nod, disappointed, and she exits. They look at each other with glum expressions.</context>
      <utterance>Boys, look. Number one -- even if I wanted to date, I don't have time. And number two -- I've got my teaching, I've got you guys -- that's all I need.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I really thought she'd like the music metaphors.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you're flat, Nick.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not flat.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The B sounded flat.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They play for a few beats.</context>
      <utterance>Just play the violin, Mom. I'll take care of the cello.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You nervous, Mom?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The DOORBELL rings and Roberta jumps up, bolting into the bathroom down the hall. Lexi and Nick exchange a smile, then Lexi crosses to the door and opens it.</context>
      <utterance>No. I'm fine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. An honest woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honest?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles, blushing, and avoids eye contact with her sons who are trying really hard not to laugh. As she and Dan start to exit:</context>
      <utterance>Your ad. When you said you were beautiful, you were telling the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make sure you're home by midnight, young lady.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CLOSE ON CLOCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WIDER - Nick and Lexi play a video game on the TV screen. O.S., there's the SOUND OF A CAR. They race to the window.</context>
      <utterance>It reads 12:30.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten bucks he tries to kiss her.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a no-brainer. Of course he'll try. The real question is whether she'll let him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>O.K. -- ten bucks she lets him.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stare out the window intently.</context>
      <utterance>You're on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had a lot of fun tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I did too.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a confession -- I've never answered an ad before. I did it on a dare.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both laugh, then smile at each other. An awkward beat: will he or won't he? Dan leans in to kiss her, and Roberta turns away, uncertain.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I have a confession -- my boys placed the ad behind my back.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Roberta feels badly about rejecting him.</context>
      <utterance>Look, Dan -- I went along with this 'cause it's been a while. Quite a while... And I had a very nice time... but I'm not sure if I'm ready to get involved with anyone right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta cracks up. Dan smiles at her.</context>
      <utterance>Does this mean I don't get any lasagna?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you guys still up?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? Is it late?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good try, Nick.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how was it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... he's nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Nice"? As in "let's just be friends" nice?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick looks disappointed.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know yet. We'll see.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's still a lot more letters.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts heading upstairs.</context>
      <utterance>Good night, Nick.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Mom -- can you loan me ten dollars?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts her stuff down, then looks at the kids.</context>
      <utterance>Guys, I'm so sorry -- I got stuck over at CPE 2...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on? Where are all your violins?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We heard you got fired.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it true?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you come in my office?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's true? You're firing me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta takes this in, momentarily speechless. In the b.g., the beginners slip into the hall to watch.</context>
      <utterance>It's not me, Roberta. The Board of Ed. cut the budget, the District had to comply, and as of the end of this term, the violin program has been... excessed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excessed.  They specifically said that my violin program has to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They've slashed the budget -- music and art programs got hit the worst.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Dennis' classes?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta looks at him, then back to Janet.</context>
      <utterance>I'm tenured, Roberta.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When was this decided?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Things happened very quickly... I wanted to tell you myself --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just... I can't even believe this is happening!</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not? You're a sub. Your position has never been permanent.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They leave Dennis standing there, looking as if he's had his face slapped.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up, Dennis! You're not helping!  Come into my office, please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's gotta be a way to fight this!</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fight it with what? I don't have any other extra programs to give them instead.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I see. So after ten years, after fourteen hundred children have learned to play the violin, this is just an "extra program."</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know I don't feel that way and you know damn well I've been standing by you all these years! You think I haven't noticed what you've done for these kids?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then do something!</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta's fury starts to give way to grief. She looks terribly wounded. Janet looks at her helplessly.</context>
      <utterance>I've been on this phone for the past three days trying to "do something" -- the District office can't even stand the sound of my voice. Believe me, there are some people around here I'd much rather get rid of. But as far as the Board's concerned, violin classes are not a priority.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat, and Roberta exits.</context>
      <utterance>I don't have the power here, Roberta. I'm so sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>sitting at the kitchen table with a glass of wine, her face ashen.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lexi moves to comfort her.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a good teacher. I've worked so hard to give these kids something to be proud of.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so sorry, Mom. I can't believe they did this to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's like when my father got killed. For twenty years, he followed every safety rule the factory had, and then someone else flips the wrong switch...  It's not fair. You do everything right and then...</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the wrong analogy. You couldn't do anything about Grandpa's death. It was irreversible. This isn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell that to the Board of Education.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta and Lexi look at Nick, baffled as to the relevance of the question.</context>
      <utterance>Let me ask you something. Why did you risk your life for a bicycle?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did not risk my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course you did! That building? Threatening Henry? And for what -- two hundred dollars?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Not for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat as she realizes what she's just said. The boys look at her and the three of them stop walking.</context>
      <utterance>When someone steals something that belongs to my kids, I'm not gonna sit back and let that happen!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guys -- you need to think about this. If I try to fight this -- with no salary coming in -- I could lose the house, screw up your college plans... It would be a lot safer to just go out tomorrow and get a job in a private school.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but is that where you really want to be?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FOLLOW ASSUNTA to the DOOR. She opens it, revealing JANET, who's carrying two bags of groceries. Assunta's demeanor instantly cools when she sees her. In the b.g. Roberta sees Janet and turns off the vacuum cleaner.</context>
      <utterance>Someone's early.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Assunta. How are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSUNTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd be a lot better if my daughter had a job next year.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ma!</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Janet briskly walks into THE LIVING ROOM, puts the grocery bags down on a table, and begins to take things out of them. Roberta watches her, mystified.</context>
      <utterance>I would too.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta watches Janet for a beat, then addresses Assunta.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry I'm early, but I figured we'd need time to set up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Assunta hesitates for a beat, then gets the dog and exits. Janet continues unpacking the bags as if there's nothing unusual about her being there. Cheeses, crackers, bread, salads, fruit, paper plates, napkins, etc. She sees Roberta's confused expression.</context>
      <utterance>Mama, why don't you take Allegra out for a walk?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are having a meeting here tonight, right? Parents and teachers?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, yes, but ...</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds up two wedges of cheese.</context>
      <utterance>Take it from me. If you want to get parents to help you with something, you have to feed them.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta crosses into the kitchen and returns with a cutting board and a knife.</context>
      <utterance>You have a cutting board for these?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls out an Entenmann's blackout cake.</context>
      <utterance>And if you think parents are bad, teachers are even worse, no offense. If you don't feed them, you never get anything extra out of them. That's why I got this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta continues to stare in amazement at Janet.</context>
      <utterance>Entenmann's gets them every time.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Don't tell me you expected me to bring something homemade.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, no... I --</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. Because take it from me -- my own family begs me to stay out of the kitchen.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I didn't expect was for you to be here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta smiles. Janet holds up a baguette.</context>
      <utterance>Why not? We've gotta figure out a way to fight this.  After ten years, Roberta, I can't imagine walking through those hallways and not hearing that off-key, screechy, scratchy, nails-on-the- blackboard violin music.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think? Cut it into slices now, or leave it whole?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Janet hands her the bread. A beat as the two women exchange a private smile, then return to their respective tasks.</context>
      <utterance>Let's cut it now. It'll be less messy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't they realize how much this program helps the kids?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. ADAMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Simon's our third child to study with Roberta. James is pre-med, April's valedictorian -- now that says something!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. KLEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we should inundate the Board and the District with letters.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Disappointed grumblings.</context>
      <utterance>You're wasting your time. The Board and the District are not gonna pay for this program, no matter how many letters they get.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if we raise the money ourselves?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat as people take this in.</context>
      <utterance>I can't see how they'd object to that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONCEPCION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well once that newspaper article comes out, that should help bring in money.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but what if it doesn't? For all we know, it's gonna be buried on the back page. Besides, who says anyone's gonna give a damn about our kids?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if you do a benefit concert? We can raise a batch of money from ticket sales, and then the concert itself could be great publicity. There's word of mouth... you could get reviewed...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some people laugh but we see the anxiety on Roberta's face.</context>
      <utterance>It better be a good concert!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to offer something more than me and the kids.  Do you think maybe your husband would perform with us?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This gets people's attention.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sure I could persuade him with a little pillow talk. And maybe he can get another violinist too -- Itzhak Perlman, perhaps.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That would be fantastic.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We could rent a place like the 92nd Street Y -- it's perfect for this. It seats about nine hundred people and if we charge between fifty and a hundred a ticket --</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We could probably raise enough to reinstate your program for a year.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds like a plan.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The DOORBELL RINGS and Roberta crosses to get it. DAN enters, holding copies of the NY POST, the DAILY NEWS, and a couple of other papers. Each paper has been opened to a specific page.</context>
      <utterance>It better be a good concert.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta grabs the top one -- the POST -- opened to page 5.</context>
      <utterance>Take your pick.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dennis storms in.</context>
      <utterance>Kids, listen to me -- it's really important that you don't look at the camera and you try to act as natural as possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who authorized this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Janet.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kids quiet down and watch them argue. A CAMERA GUY starts shooting the argument and Dennis sees him.</context>
      <utterance>Well Janet's not here today and I want these people out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turn that off, you hear me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you doing this? We're not bothering anyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're disrupting school and I want them out of here -- now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She points to the kids. They're silent, waiting to see if Roberta got through to him. A beat.</context>
      <utterance>You still don't get it, do you? I don't care if you hate me, Dennis -- that's your business. But think about the students for once. Every time you interfere, you're not hurting me -- you're hurting them.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get these people out of here or I'm calling the police.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat and he exits. Roberta takes a deep breath, then turns back to the kids who are watching her, impressed.</context>
      <utterance>Go right ahead, call them. That'll look real good on the eleven o'clock news.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't hear no sirens.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It CUTS TO Roberta's beginners speaking to the interviewer.</context>
      <utterance>I'm from a blue collar family, and if it weren't for the lessons I got in public school, I never would have learned the violin.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How does it make you feel to lose your violin program?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It makes us sad!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, like we're never gonna have no more violin lessons --</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WIDER - REVEAL Roberta, Lexi and Nick watching the TV.</context>
      <utterance>And it's bad because... because we love violin class.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I've gotten offers from two private schools, but this is where I want to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHEA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>WIDER - REVEAL a comfortable Upper East Side apartment and DOROTHEA watching T.V. while ARNOLD practices violin. There's FRAMED PHOTOGRAPHY on the walls, signed by Dorothea.</context>
      <utterance>Arnold, these kids need help.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't we send them a donation?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They need something bigger. And you can't just write a check -- you have to get involved.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The look on her face tells him it's more than he bargained for.</context>
      <utterance>Involved how?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-oh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The students give her their attention.</context>
      <utterance>Listen up, everyone! Quiet down!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods to Rachel who starts handing out sheets of music.</context>
      <utterance>You are my very best beginner and advanced violin students and I've chosen you to play in Fiddlefest because I trust that you can handle the pressure. It's gonna be a lot of work -- a lot. Right now, we've sold some tickets, but I'm not gonna be back here in the fall if the audience storms out of their seats, demanding a refund!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ramon looks through his music sheets.</context>
      <utterance>Rachel's gonna be my lieutenant and I expect you to listen to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bach's "Minuet One"?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kids read the contracts. Carlos' eyes widen.</context>
      <utterance>People are gonna be paying good money for this concert -- we're not just gonna play "Twinkle."  I'm passing out a contract that you and your parents need to sign.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every Saturday and Sunday?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kids look sobered by this.</context>
      <utterance>Plus night time rehearsals during the week. There's only six weeks till the concert, so classes in school won't be enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lots of grumbling: "Say what?" "No way!" "Before school?" I'ma be sleepwalking!"</context>
      <utterance>Come to think of it, we'll probably also need to meet before school.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANOTHER ANGLE - Two young men and two young women walk in, carrying violins. We realize from the scar that one is NAEEM (20), now a strikingly handsome man, over six feet tall. With him is DE SEAN (19), a short guy with dreadlocks, looking more like a rapper than a violinist. GUADALUPE (19), walking with a cane, is now a beautiful young woman, her long braid pinned up. The fourth is a reserved Puerto Rican woman (20).</context>
      <utterance>You've heard of Navy Seal Training? Well, this is gonna be Roberta String Training.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hugs her, then looks closely at the other woman.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my god! Naeem! De Sean!  Guadalupe!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woman snaps her fingers and smiles. Roberta laughs and embraces her, then turns to the students.</context>
      <utterance>Lucy? Is that you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kids, these are four of my very first violin students and I've asked them to play in the concert with us.  I was just telling them how hard they're gonna have to work.</utterance>
   <speaker>DE SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take it from me -- this lady don't lie. Y'all are gonna work your butts off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TEAMMATE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Carlos! Where ya goin'? We got a game, remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I know, but... I can't make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAMMATE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you talkin' about?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just can't make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEAMMATE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>You got a date with the violin teacher?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He dashes off, a barrage of Spanish and English curses behind him, and crosses to his sister, waiting for him DOWN THE STREET. He takes the violin from her and carries it himself.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They play a few more bars and still sound pretty bad.</context>
      <utterance>Frog! Frog! I need more accents on the down beat! More bow! More!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop! Stop!  You sound horrible! Isn't anyone practicing?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some kids laugh, including Stephanie.</context>
      <utterance>How can we practice? We're rehearsing all the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vanessa yawns and Roberta sees her. Uh-oh.</context>
      <utterance>You think this is funny, Stephanie?  You think the four hundred people who've bought tickets so far will think it's funny too? You think Itzhak Perlman will think it's funny that he's donating his time and you're all gonna stink?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I boring you, Vanessa?</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. It's 7:30 in the morning. I'm just tired.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no time to be tired.  Let's try it again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I must have been crazy to agree to this. They're never gonna be ready. And you should hear the Bach Double! A disaster. So the good news is tickets are selling like hot cakes, but the bad news is that the kids sound like shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta looks at her, aghast.</context>
      <utterance>There's more bad news... We've lost the Y.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They had a flood -- a water heater burst... The concert hall was damaged and they've cancelled all events.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Until when?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Until further notice."</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This can't happen! We've sold tickets! We've done publicity! The concert's in three weeks!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both sink into the couch, completely undone by this.</context>
      <utterance>I've been on the phone all morning calling other theaters. Nothing's available.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just keep looking.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kids look at each other, daunted.</context>
      <utterance>Stop! Someone's playing the wrong notes! And you shouldn't need your music anymore! Except for the Bach Double, everything has to be memorized by next rehearsal!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you sound like you're sleepwalking. Your heart's not even in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta looks at her, and then notices the despondent looks on many of the kids' faces.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe 'cause we don't have a place for the concert.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you're right. This might all be for nothing. So we can either keep on rehearsing in case we find a place -- or we can just... give up.</utterance>
   <speaker>DE SEAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No one raises a hand. Roberta takes this in.</context>
      <utterance>Am I hearing right? Did you use the words "give up"?  Let's take a vote. How many of you want to give up?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUADALUPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See? You taught us well.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about in the Bronx?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's nothing.  Why don't you just do it in one of the schools? It'll be a lot smaller but --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We won't make enough money.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about postponing it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all look depressed. Lexi places an equally depressing- looking stack of pancakes on the table. There's a BANGING on the door, startling everyone.</context>
      <utterance>Itzhak and Arnold are booked all summer.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHEA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Nick opens the door and Dorothea rushes in, out of breath, talking a mile a minute.</context>
      <utterance>It's Dorothea.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have good news -- really good news. Arnold got a call from his friend Wally Scheur who heard about us losing the Y and wanted to see how he could help -- and then Wally had this brilliant idea and called his friend Isaac Stern and it's all arranged! We have a new place for Fiddlefest!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHEA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dorothea grins from ear to ear, Nick and Lexi whoop and holler, and all wait for Roberta to jump up and down for joy -- but she looks stricken.</context>
      <utterance>Carnegie Hall.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carnegie Hall?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MALE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Roberta turns to see ISAAC STERN approaching her. She's completely flustered.</context>
      <utterance>Incredible sound in this room, no?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my god -- Isaac Stern.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISAAC STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must be Roberta.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you so much for helping us.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISAAC STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you believe in 1960, they tried to tear this place down? They wanted to replace it with a bright red skyscraper -- we called it "the red terror."</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISAAC STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta takes this in, relating it to her own struggle.</context>
      <utterance>We had to fight like hell, but with a lot of help, we saved Carnegie Hall.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISAAC STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it's all right with you, I'd like to play in your concert. Maybe bring a couple of friends...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Isaac nods, then touches her shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, of course! That would be great!</utterance>
   <speaker>ISAAC STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't give up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just don't see how I'm gonna do this. It's huge. It's gigantic! It's Carnegie Hall! And listen to this: now Isaac Stern wants to play with us -- Diane Monroe, Michael Tree -- there's other people calling --</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's fantastic!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fantastic? I'll never get the kids up to speed in time, I'll never get myself up to speed. I'm gonna be playing side by side with the world's greatest violinists.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He offers her a forkful of some decadent-looking chocolate cake, but she shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>And "the world's greatest violinists" are playing side by side with you because they want to help you win this fight.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, but... you don't understand. Maybe there's a good reason why I never made it as a violinist -- maybe I just can't cut it. I keep blaming it on not having enough early training, but if I were talented, if I had a gift --</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes this in, looks at him gratefully and puts her hand over his. He strokes her hand.</context>
      <utterance>But you do have a gift. You're gonna put thirty East Harlem kids on stage at Carnegie Hall not because they're prodigies, but because you got them to stick with something that's hard as hell and to strive for excellence -- which, by the way, I certainly wasn't striving for when I was their age. Not to mention the other ten years' worth of students whose lives were changed because of you. That's your talent, Roberta.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm scared.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.  And by the way, I happen to think you're a pretty good violinist too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've barely heard me play.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta looks at him with trepidation. Dan takes another forkful of his cake.</context>
      <utterance>I've heard enough to know you're gonna do just fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta laughs. Dan smiles, glad he got her to lighten up.</context>
      <utterance>Besides, no one's gonna be paying attention to your playing anyway.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kids laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Teacher's late. I think she should be dropped, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A few kids start playing "CAN-CAN." It catches on, and more of them join in. PASSERSBY stop to listen, and some drop change into the open cases. RAMON and a couple of other kids grin at this. CARLOS steps in front of the kids as he plays, and begins an uncanny imitation of Roberta:</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I don't think we should let her play in Fiddlefest!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kids crack up, but a few spot ROBERTA heading quickly up the street. Carlos is oblivious to this -- and no one signals him that Roberta's watching.</context>
      <utterance>More bow! To the frog! You sound terrible! I can't believe how terrible you sound!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carlos senses a presence and turns to see Roberta. A tense beat as he awaits her reaction.</context>
      <utterance>You're gonna make everyone in Carnegie Hall sick to their stomachs! That's right, they're gonna pay a thousand dollars a ticket and you're gonna make them throw up on their gowns and tuxedos!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carlos freezes.</context>
      <utterance>If you're gonna imitate me, do it right.  Shoulders back. Violin higher. Check your feet. There.  G'head, Carlos. Continue.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta nods, and addresses the kids as she unlocks the gate.</context>
      <utterance>No, that's O.K. You can take it from here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kids start filing in. Rachel comes up the street and catches up to Roberta.</context>
      <utterance>He's right, by the way. You do sound terrible, and you are gonna make everyone in Carnegie Hall sick to their stomachs.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta sees how distressed Rachel looks.</context>
      <utterance>I need to talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be right in. Start on Minuet One.  What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're moving away.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Where are you moving?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a secret... My father... he's been hurting my mom... We have to leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel shakes her head no, then starts to cry a little.</context>
      <utterance>Has he been hurting you too?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands Roberta her violin.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry about Julliard... and the concert.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep it. Take it with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... I don't want to play anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel looks anguished. Roberta moves closer and touches her arm.</context>
      <utterance>What?! You can't give up violin, Rachel -- it's a part of you. A very important part.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please honey. Just take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta looks at her, pained, then hugs her. Rachel quickly kisses Roberta goodbye and exits. Roberta watches her.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kids say "the world's greatest violinists" along with her -- they've obviously been hearing this a lot. Roberta glares at them.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, no! Accent the up bow after the slurred notes and then it'll get you off of those slurred notes! You Double Concerto kids need to be working harder! This is the grand finale of the concert! You're each gonna be sharing a music stand with one of the world's greatest violinists!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we should forget the Bach Double.  And you guys are never gonna get Minuet One. I think we should drop that too.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! We can do it, Roberta!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops, takes a breath.</context>
      <utterance>And we'll get the Bach Double. We will.</utterance>
   <speaker>NAEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's gonna be O.K., Roberta.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All the kids nod. A few beats.</context>
      <utterance>You think?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick -- did you feed Allegra?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lexi, can you make sure the charts are still in my bag?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I already checked, Mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>ASSUNTA descends the staircase, dressed in a formal dress. She holds a small jewelry box and heads for the bathroom.</context>
      <utterance>Check again, please. And look for my repair kit too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSUNTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta sticks her head out and picks the earrings. Assunta enters the small bathroom to work on her own makeup.</context>
      <utterance>Bert, which earrings you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick? Get two more violins.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>You've already got two -- how many emergencies can there be?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick rolls his eyes and runs upstairs while Lexi organizes things by the door: Nick's cello, Roberta's papers, extra violins. Roberta rushes out of the bathroom, adjusting the earrings. She starts compulsively straightening the house.</context>
      <utterance>Get three more. And make sure a couple of them are half-size.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lexi -- can you call about the car again?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick comes running down the stairs with the violins and stares in disbelief at Roberta fluffing a couch pillow.</context>
      <utterance>Mom, they're not gonna forget to send a car!</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just straightening a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He throws the pillow onto the couch. Roberta heads upstairs.</context>
      <utterance>You're insane, you know that?  Finish getting dressed!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns around, revealing a RIP on the back of the dress, next to the zipper. The DOORBELL RINGS.</context>
      <utterance>Can you believe this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It can't be time! Is it time?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSUNTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll sew it in the car.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Mama.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSUNTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about it. You rip -- I sew.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Assunta stitches, remembering, and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Not just for that.  Thank you for getting me out of bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSUNTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't thank me -- thank Charles.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charles?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSUNTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta contemplates this. A beat.</context>
      <utterance>If that jerk hadn't of left you, none of this would've happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her last stitch finished, Assunta rips the needle from the thread.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Charles.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Janet looks at her, concerned.</context>
      <utterance>Where's Vanessa? Has anyone seen Vanessa?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE - Roberta sees MRS. ADISA enter the room with Naeem. The two women walk towards each other and embrace. As they start to chat, Roberta suddenly sees someone and excuses herself: BRIAN is walking towards her, wearing a tux. They smile at each other, but Roberta's clearly a bit shaken to see him. They're not quite sure how to greet each other -- he takes her hand, and then kisses her on the cheek.</context>
      <utterance>I'll call her house.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Congratulations.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>I knew you'd get here sooner or later. I'm glad I'm here to see it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GUADALUPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns around.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, Mr. Perlman?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUADALUPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles at her and they shake hands.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Guadalupe. I've wanted to meet you for a long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>ITZHAK PERLMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Guadalupe introduces him to her mother, CARLOS approaches.</context>
      <utterance>A pleasure to meet you, Guadalupe.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You nervous, Mr. Perlman?</utterance>
   <speaker>ITZHAK PERLMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should I be?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Itzhak Perlman laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Us kids are gonna be great -- I don't know about you guys. How much did you practice?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You called Vanessa's father and mother?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A Carnegie Hall staff person in a suit enters.</context>
      <utterance>No answer at either.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAFF PERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The room electrifies with nerves.</context>
      <utterance>Half hour call! It's now half hour call! So pace yourself accordingly. Don't get more than thirty minutes worth of nervous!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They stole the car!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. KLEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With the violin.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God.  Nick, Lexi --</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys rush over to the extra violins and look to find the right size.</context>
      <utterance>Done.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta comforts her and Janet moves in.</context>
      <utterance>And then when we were getting a taxi, I fell down.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE - DAN enters with a bouquet of long-stemmed red roses. He's in a tux and looks very handsome. He crosses to Roberta, hands her the flowers, and they hug.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon honey -- let's get you cleaned up.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're glowing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's terror.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MINUTES.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The tension in the room shoots sky high.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I became the principal of Central Park East Elementary, I envisioned a school where children could fulfill their highest potential, despite the challenges of poverty and racism. Ten years ago, Roberta Guaspari walked into my office because she needed a job, and because she had a vision that any child could learn the violin. We put our dreams together and created the East Harlem Violin Program which has helped more than a thousand students expand their vision of what's possible in their lives. When a program like this is cut, our children's future is compromised. I want to thank you for your support. Enjoy the concert.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They become quiet.</context>
      <utterance>Everyone -- attention please!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kids breathe.</context>
      <utterance>I want you all to take a second just to breathe, O.K.? Deep breath.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pats her heart.</context>
      <utterance>I would like you all to play with your heart, all right? Play like I know you can play. You'll be wonderful. Watch me, don't look out in the audience -- you don't need to be afraid. It's gonna be really wonderful. So play -- play from here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And this? What's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roberta and the kids laugh.</context>
      <utterance>The frog hair?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy smiles and shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Did you ever see a frog with hair?</utterance>
   <speaker>A FEW KIDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's horsehair!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One girl raises her hand with urgency.</context>
      <utterance>That's right.  But you're right, there is a frog. Can you show me where it is?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ooh! I know!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBERTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy points to the frog of the bow and Roberta smiles. And as she continues her lesson, her voice recedes and we:</context>
      <utterance>Sssh -- let him answer.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
