<movie id="403" title="My Best Friend s Wedding">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="62">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She doesn't like that idea at all. Shoots him a sharp look of doubt that makes him smile. Murmur...</context>
      <utterance>A variation on our squid ink risotto. Trace of Moselle, to sweeten the stock.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Places the moist lump of black rice before her. She takes a surprisingly small amount, rolls it over her tongue. Makes dead flat eye contact with Digger. And nods, it's actually quite nice. The Captain breathes with relief. She turns her dark eyes to him. The tone says they're pals...</context>
      <utterance>Don't kill us on this one, it's a long shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm writing it up as inventive and confident. Which it is. Off the record, I'll need an extra boat of the ink. Or a salt shaker.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the Captain splits, Digger looks around at the other tables, which makes many pairs of eyes awkwardly glace away.</context>
      <utterance>I'll toss a coin.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it ever embarrassing, having your bum kissed in public?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances at her two remaining waiters, who shamelessly fawn nearby.</context>
      <utterance>If your ass isn't chapped, you are not a good-writer of note.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it sad to be an editor, and bask only in reflected insincerity?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leans forward, as if sharing something conspiratorial.</context>
      <utterance>I've adjusted, and thanks for asking.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See the pull of a book like Twenty Chefs, is not who I put in. It's who I leave out.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which is everyone you couldn't get in.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pushes the risotte across to him. He lifts a fork.</context>
      <utterance>Plus some guys whose food I don't like.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shrugs. Pulls a cellular out of a large, jumbled bag.</context>
      <utterance>This fellow from Newsday ever call?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She dials. He tastes.</context>
      <utterance>I'll buzz my machine. Inventive and confident, yeh?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Needs salt.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is Newsday a real interview, or just some cute guy you're setting me up w...</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's punching in her code.</context>
      <utterance>... I don't send you men, anymore. You don't know what to do with them.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes I do. Like for two months.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Over the phone, we hear her answering machine... MAN'S VOICE (V.O., soft) Hey. It's Michael. And her face changes. Warms. Just to hear the guileless voice.</context>
      <utterance>... weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>She looks impressed and surprised. Fancy place for this guy.</context>
      <utterance>God, it must be, what, months, huh? I can't wait to talk to you. I'm in Chicago at the Ritz Carlton...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>As she hangs up. She still has that look in her eye. Digger has never seen that, and he likes it very much.</context>
      <utterance>Call me four in the morning, whatever, we gotta talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles. A sweet, natural smile that makes us like her, too. The Bohemian sophisticate has vanished.</context>
      <utterance>Who called? The man of the moment?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sounds desperate to talk.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, the opposite. That's my best friend, Michael O'Neal.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pushes the risotto back her way.</context>
      <utterance>The wandering sportswriter.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her gaze sharpens. Hmmn?</context>
      <utterance>I didn't know you two had a past.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She blushes. Shakes her head, no way.</context>
      <utterance>The look in your eye.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He knows her. She got restless.</context>
      <utterance>Sophomore year at Yale we had this one hot month. And, you know me, I got restless...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He knows.</context>
      <utterance>So I get up the nerve to break his heart. I tell him there's this dreamy exchange student from Pakistan who wants to, you know...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods, yeah.</context>
      <utterance>And he gets this... look. He says, "I knew I couldn't hold your interest", which, of course, makes me feel like the shallow bitch I've always been...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then he says, "But what makes me want to cry. Is I'm losing the best friend I ever had." Hears the feeling. In her voice.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence now. She covers with a smile.</context>
      <utterance>And when he said it, I knew. I felt the same.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I cried. For maybe the third time in my life. And I kissed him. And we've been best friends ever since. Ever since. Fingers turning her wine glass...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nine years, we've seen each other through everything. Losing jobs, losing parents, losing lovers... travelled all over, we've had the best times. The best times of my life, maybe. Just drinking and talking. Even over a phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kindred spirits.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No offense taken.</context>
      <utterance>No, he's nothing like me. He's like you. Only straight.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's the salt of the earth. Kind and loyal and generous. The one constant thing in my life, is he'll always be there.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That stops her. She has to say...</context>
      <utterance>He's still in love with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Something she probably hasn't confessed out loud before. Digger understands.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe. But it never gets in the way.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He wants her to know he sees that.</context>
      <utterance>Well, he has a true friend in you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whenever George tells someone how steadfast I am, he always makes me sound boring.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A young waiter arrives. Sets a boat of black squid ink beside her plate.</context>
      <utterance>Solid and genuine is not boring. Michael can be completely insane...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kid tops off her glass of meursault. Looking at her.</context>
      <utterance>There was this one night in Tucson, like six years ago... we got amazingly drunk, I mean, Keith Richards time...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waiter hanging now. Openly listening.</context>
      <utterance>God, I haven't thought of this in so long...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Digger sees the guy listening, gestures to her with his eyes. So she looks up.</context>
      <utterance>I can even believe we did this...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kid stunned, speechless. People lose jobs for a lot less.</context>
      <utterance>Could you give us a minute?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reddens and disappears.</context>
      <utterance>You won't miss much, I promise there was no sex.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've lost interest.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She places the tips of her index fingers together.</context>
      <utterance>He takes a razor from his dinky little dopp kit, cuts his fingertip, takes my hand, does the same to me...</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blood oath.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And laughs again. Can you believe that? But Digger isn't smiling. She wonders why. Begins to spoon black squid ink onto her risotto.</context>
      <utterance>He says, "Swear. When we're both 28, if we've never been married... we marry each other!"</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He still has this real serious look. She's still spooning ink.</context>
      <utterance>See, he figured that would be a sign from God, or someone of comparable authority, that we'd misunderstood our destinies.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And everything. Stops. She lifts her spoon, mesmerized by the gravity of his tone.</context>
      <utterance>We never talked about it again. I don't know what made me think of... DIGGER  I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holy. Fucking. Shit. It hits her like a ton of lead bricks. She shovels some swampy risotto into her mouth, without looking.</context>
      <utterance>You'll be 28 in three weeks. How old is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think...</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shovels in more drippy black goop. It is really disgusting.</context>
      <utterance>Desperate. To talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not proposing marriage, there's no way I'm buying one word of th...</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More goes in. Her lips and mouth completely black. Like a circus clown.</context>
      <utterance>Then why are you compulsively eating? If you're not hysterical?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He can't do that to me!</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ink is now dribbling out of the black hole of her mouth and down her face. She absently dabs a napkin, keeping some of it from reaching her sweater.</context>
      <utterance>We're about to find out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She realizes the full weight of the truth.</context>
      <utterance>When I turn him down...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll never be the same.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a suggestion...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll have to kill myself before I call him. Staring in each other's eyes. DIGGER  That was it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stops. Full-length mirror. She straightens her hair, to look her best.</context>
      <utterance>This is awkward timing, Michael, I just joined this convent, and they never give your deposit ba...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not enough.</context>
      <utterance>Michael, I'm married.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Changes tone...</context>
      <utterance>... and I have two weeks to live.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to continue pacing, and walks straight INTO a dresser. Stuns her, momentarily. Enough, already! She punches up the number, primping absently in the mirror. When it connects...</context>
      <utterance>Michael, I'm trying to be gay, don't confuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was calling Michael O'Neal, but seeing it's so late, I could just leave a mes... No such luck. Cut off. Waits. And then... JULIANNE  Good evening, sir. You've been enrolled in the Obscene Call Of The Month Club, and th...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>She forgets herself. Because it's good to hear his, too.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! God, it's so good to hear your voice.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been calling for days!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She swallows.</context>
      <utterance>Yeh, well my old machine kept eating messages. I tried constructively ignoring it in hopes of improvement, but finally... MICHAEL  Look, I have to ask you something.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Silence. Come on girl, suck it up.</context>
      <utterance>Something so incredibly important, that if you turn me down, I don't know what I'll d... JULIANNE  I just have to tell you this one thing first, okay? I mean this will hand you the biggest laugh of your adult life...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More silence. Really quiet.</context>
      <utterance>I was thinking about you, and I remembered this unbelievably insane night we spent together in Tucson, like a thousand years ago?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stops her. Like a brick wall. The sweetness in his voice.</context>
      <utterance>I mean, there's no way you could possibly remember the... MICHAEL  Are you kidding?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>She's going to have a heart attack.</context>
      <utterance>I think about that night all the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>She blinks. It's not. And just as a tsunami of relief begins to sweep away...</context>
      <utterance>But it's not why I called.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>And her smiles breaks off. Like a spine snapping. Because there is something in his voice.</context>
      <utterance>I called because I met someone.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's great. You haven't really had anybody since Dingbat Jennylee...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Never. She sits down, hard. Right on the floor.</context>
      <utterance>You don't understand. I've never felt this way about anybody!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And she's all wrong for me!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, somet...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Like when. Julianne's mouth is suddenly dry.</context>
      <utterance>I mean she's a junior at Chicago University, she's twenty years old! Like when I first met you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>She's finally making her mouth work...</context>
      <utterance>And her dad is like this billionaire who owns the White Sox and some cable empire, and you know how I've always been miserably awkward around those kinda stuffed suits...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But they're so down to earth, such wonderful people...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wow.</context>
      <utterance>You've met her parents. MICHAEL  Well. Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>There's a knife in her heart. She can scarcely breathe.</context>
      <utterance>See. We're getting married. This Sunday.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Michael, it's Wednesday night, you can't possibly be getting married on Su...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>I mean, is that responsible?</context>
      <utterance>Actually, it all starts tomorrow. It's one of those four-day weddings, with all the traditional events, and ten million people flying in from Madagascar such. JULIANNE  Aren't you... working this weekend?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, the Sox are at home. SI's letting me do a profile on the Big Hurt. That's Frank...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's staring at herself in the mirror.</context>
      <utterance>... Thomas, yeh.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A straw to lunge at.</context>
      <utterance>Jules. I'm scared.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, maybe we should talk ab...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>So heartfelt. A lifetime of emotion welling in her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I need you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Oh.</context>
      <utterance>If you can't come. And hold my hand. I'll never get through this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please come, please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sucks deep. Really deep.</context>
      <utterance>You can't get lung cancer and die in four days. Go to Plan B.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have no appropriate sense of emergency. My best friend is ruining his life.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, he's ruining yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Same difference. If you love someone, it's your duty to save them from themselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have a real philosophy of life.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is tight enough to snap. And at the edge of tears. Staring out at the skycaps, clinging to her cigarette, as he eases to the curb. DIGGER (gently) Why don't we have a drink? You could catch a later fl...</context>
      <utterance>It's called the Law of Love, asshole.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She finally looks at him. He doesn't say anything.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a busy girl. I've got four days to break up a wedding, and steal the bride's fella.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's adored me for nine goddamn years.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can see why.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's not. So her voice softens. Which shows the hurt.</context>
      <utterance>She knows him maybe five seconds, plus she has billions of dollars, plus she's perfect, so don't go feeling sorry for Miss Pre-Teen Illinois!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tears now. Stand in her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>And don't go feeling sorry for me, you don't know me that well. We're only friends. DIGGER  I stand corrected.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He wraps his hand over hers. She looks down at it.</context>
      <utterance>I'm making a big mistake, huh? DIGGER  Maybe you'll learn something.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She wraps her fingers around his.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna bring him back, man. Against all odds, y'know. Cos if I don't...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looks in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>... I gotta live with it forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jumps out of his car. Before she cries. Yanks her bags from the back. Brave smile. They trade small salutes. And then she's gone.</context>
      <utterance>And at my wedding. I'll be the only bride with her own best man. And she kisses his cheek.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her arms stay around the slightly dazed Julianne. The younger girl leans close, confides...</context>
      <utterance>This just makes everything so perfect.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All I've heard, from the day I met Michael, is Julianne this, and Julianne that...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we're...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pale gray eyes. Alive with joy and intimacy.</context>
      <utterance>I think the best part of marrying this guy is finding you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never had a sister.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My heart's in my throat, here. Right off, I have to ask this monstrous favor...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kim glances over. At eighty miles an hour. A bittersweet look.</context>
      <utterance>You need a few dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes at once admiring and regretful.</context>
      <utterance>Dry. Just like he said.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shakes her head. An endearing youngster.</context>
      <utterance>I can be quick. I can even be funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I can't be dry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you watch the road?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks back to the highway.</context>
      <utterance>See. Dry. It's in the delivery.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a very presumptuous and burdensome fav...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julianne studying the delicate, angular profile. Hard not to like this kid.</context>
      <utterance>... you want a menage on your wedding night. KIMMY  No, that wouldn't be burdensome.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looks over. The sweetest smile.</context>
      <utterance>My classmate Angelique shattered her pelvis line dancing in Abeline on Spring Break.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julianne just blinks.</context>
      <utterance>Be my maid of honor.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't believe what it'd cost to bring in a temp.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We CUT OFF a huge SEMI who BLASTS his horn. Kimmy fearless, oblivious, and analytical...</context>
      <utterance>Uh. How about promoting a bridesmaid? Someone you know for at least forty-five minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The bridesmaids are my only two female relatives under forty. Identical twin debutantes from Nashville, who are basically vengeful sluts. With amazing bodies!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which was the disqualifying factor?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sees the off-ramp, and SLICES across FOUR LANES of speeding bullets in a heart-stopping nanosecond. This kid could drive for Penske. Julianne has to pound her chest to get her heart started. Looks back to see if Michael fell out... ... he is absurdly wind-blown. Gives her a beautiful grinning thumbs-up. Loves this stuff.</context>
      <utterance>The twin part. I like to remain impartial in my contempt.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brings Julianne's eyes back...</context>
      <utterance>This means I have four days to make you my new best friend...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Easing off the freeway. She meets Julianne's glance...</context>
      <utterance>And since I already know everything about you. Including intimate facts I'm mortified to have heard, but too envious to forget. It's time for you to learn about me...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Force yourself. To get personal. JULIANNE  Sounds like a plan.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julianne shakes her head. This one is beautiful.</context>
      <utterance>If you'd rather the lilac...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought bridesmaids had to wear the same dress.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julianne glances over.</context>
      <utterance>Not you. You won't be comfortable unless you're distinctive.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What else did he tell you...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh. Well, yeah.</context>
      <utterance>... you hate weddings, you never go.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The look holds. The seamstress keeps working, as if she's deaf.</context>
      <utterance>You're not up for anything conventional, or popularly assumed to be female priorities. Including marriage. Or romance. Or even... And she stops. Not wanting to offend. JULIANNE  ... not even love.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why Michael and I were the wrong fit. Right from the start.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stands up. Walks to the platform. Smooths her hand over the fabric down Julianne's back, along her hips. Communicating to the seamstress with her irritated expression.</context>
      <utterance>He said that, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pins start to come out. Kimmy points, these, too!</context>
      <utterance>Well, I thought I was like you. And proud to be. Until I met rumpled, smelly old Michael...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leans forward. So they can look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>And then I found I was just a sentimental schmuck. Like all those flighty nitwits I'd always pitied.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julianne swallows. It is that.</context>
      <utterance>Funny world, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And before anyone can breathe, she steps OFF the platform RIPPING the living shit out of the gown, right down the side. The seam- stress' eyes FLASH OPEN in abject horror. Julianne, a deer in headlights, looks quickly around at the evidence of her screw-up in six different mirrors. Kimberly just steps to her, fingers the tear...</context>
      <utterance>I need a smoke.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And UNZIPS Julianne down the back. In her rush to step out, Julianne STUMBLES, but her arms are pinned by the pulled-down dress and she just... ... TOPPLES like a felled oak, THUDDING on her face, the gown RIPPING some more, the seamstress SCREAMING like an idiot. Then. Silence. Julianne looking up helplessly, a trussed hog, bound in her dress. KIMMY (firm) Just. Don't. Move. Like you talk to a three-year-old. Deftly, Kimmy pulls the dress free, leaving Julianne in her underwear. Signals to the seamstress, let's go.</context>
      <utterance>It's mostly the seam. Let's get this to Carlos.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you have to be somewh...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Opens the door...</context>
      <utterance>... just my bridal shower. And Michael has to meet our dads and the groomsmen at Comiskey for a one-thirty game.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Closed SOLID. Gone.</context>
      <utterance>Other than that...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stops. Because it's Michael who has entered. With the dress.</context>
      <utterance>Come in, and shut the...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>So he does. She flushes and SNATCHES up her own clothes, which were characteristically tangled in a heap, and tries desperately to untangle them enough to cover herself. He is amazed and amused by her embarrassment. MICHAEL (laughing) Should I turn around, or someth...</context>
      <utterance>... door.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's TEARING at her clothes, only making more of a mess.</context>
      <utterance>Michael, I'm in my underwear!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She seems ready to rip her clothes apart, so he gently takes them from her hands. She tries to stand unselfconsciously as he easily untangles them.</context>
      <utterance>We've seen each other a lot more naked than this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She GRABS the clothes and covers the front of herself. Looking at him with a mix of emotions she couldn't begin to sort out.</context>
      <utterance>I mean, we were skinny-dipping in Greece, just as pals, less than two years ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks in her eyes. And nods, a little sadly. Guess they are. MICHAEL (softly) Well. I leave with two thoughts in my mind. He walks to the door. Puts his hand on the latch. Looks back... MICHAEL (even softer) You're still a very pretty girl. The look holds. And holds. There is such feeling on both sides, she doesn't know what to make of it. She swallows.</context>
      <utterance>Things are different now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the sec...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he's gone. She looks around at six different VIEWS of her uncovered backside. Hmm.</context>
      <utterance>Mirrors.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="60">
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... luckiest guy in the Northern Fucking Hemisphere, is all I'm s...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Because I'm a little understand...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The valet gives Kimmy her ticket.</context>
      <utterance>... most sentimental schmucks I pity want a honeymoon after their wedding. Just to top it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're walking fast toward the garage elevators...</context>
      <utterance>I can't expect the NBA to hold up the playoffs...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm excited Sports Illustrated gave him this kind of shot, he's only there a ye...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Well...</context>
      <utterance>So your honeymoon is exactly where?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It depends. If San Antonio sweeps Sacramento, we could start there. Or Phoenix. Or depending on Indiana- Clevel...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the elevator. Kimmy SLAMS the button.</context>
      <utterance>... garden sports, all. Little swing of maybe fifty degrees Fahrenheit, represents a packing challenge, but there's fine food and cocktails at a choice of Embassy Suit...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>End of story. Okay?</context>
      <utterance>It's his career, I'm supportive. Look, I've been everywhere, I've seen the world, I've laid on a beach. I want to be with the man I love. That's what makes it a honeymoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An empty elevator arrives. They get in.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just saying he's lucky.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kimmy SLAMS the penthouse button. Looks at her calmly. Go on.</context>
      <utterance>Takes one woman in a billion to put up with his array of shit. The guy is a one-man festival of idiosync...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well. You've been introduced to the symphonic range of...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julianne imitates an incredibly annoying high-pitched SNARL. Three times. Kimmy nods.</context>
      <utterance>... his snoring, yeah. He says it's worse than ever. That snaffle one...?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stopped at the lobby. A family of four gets in. Oblivious, Kimmy DEMONSTRATES the phlegm rattle. Really gets into it. As the family watches, Julianne tries her own version. Like that? No. More like this. The family is looking at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Well now it has this sorta phlegm rattle behind it...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh.</context>
      <utterance>Guess what? Earplugs work.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sucks in a breath...</context>
      <utterance>... cigars in bed? I broke him on that. But the bathroom's a swamp, he wears Reeboks to dinner, tells the same, admittedly funny, jokes three hundred times...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ninth floor. The family gets out. The door closes.</context>
      <utterance>... loves action movies, subscribes to Playboy for godsake, reads over my shoulder, can't keep track of the checks he writes...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He sucks soup through his front teeth.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A trademark move, don't touch it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But he sure can kiss.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's been awhile. I'll take your word.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She SLAMS the EMERGENCY STOP button. We JOLT to a halt.</context>
      <utterance>After two weeks of cataloguing all his faults, I made a command decision that changed my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>I threw the list away.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From her heart.</context>
      <utterance>He's not a balance sheet, so many wonderful qualities, so many faults. He's Michael.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And loving him means loving all of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you get nervous in small confined spaces?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So it's sweet of you to be protective...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me rephrase that...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But nothing ever could, ever did, give me a moment's pause about this marriage...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you get hysterical in small confined spa...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julianne's face. Stops.</context>
      <utterance>... except one.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kimmy nods. Confides...</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A stopper.</context>
      <utterance>You.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll always be there. In his mind. The perfect creature he loved for all those y...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, perfection can get wearing after whi...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not joking. I had to face up to all my competitive drives, and believe me, I've got 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the answer was so simple.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was gonna predict that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julianne blinks. Excuse me?</context>
      <utterance>You win.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Which works out great.</context>
      <utterance>You're enshrined in his heart and memory. Unassailable.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've missed a step.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh. Julianne smiles. LUNGES for the EMERGENCY button, YANKING it so hard it comes OFF in her hand. A terrifying BUZZER ensures.</context>
      <utterance>He has you on a pedestal. And me in his arms.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, we're trapped!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ju...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Begins BANGING random buttons, out of control. Kimmy watching this. Julianne looks WILDLY up...</context>
      <utterance>No, this happened to me once, almost, it was excruciating!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RIPPING off her platform shoes.</context>
      <utterance>There's a panel up there, you could boost me...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kimmy taps her. Points to the lighted panel. It says PH, they've reached the Penthouse.</context>
      <utterance>You know how little air is in these things? I've seen statistics! Once you're trapped between floors...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Takes a heavy platform and begins BANGING the metal door with all her strength, sending resounding BOOMS throughout the area, as Kimmy reaches and... ... presses DOOR OPEN. The metal doors part, opening directly onto the banquet room, just as a mighty blow comes down, and the platform FLIES from Julianne's hand straight BETWEEN... ... two identical stunning YOUNG WOMEN, serving as twin hostesses for the shower. A beat of mutually-stupefied looks, and we hear the shoe CRASH somewhere, to a small spattering of SHRIEKS.</context>
      <utterance>God! Then the door is jammed!</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mah Gawd, it's the bride, and the woman she'll nevah live up to! KIMMY  That would be us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AMANDA and SAMANTHA NEWHOUSE, 19-year-old twins. True Southern belles, with the faces of angels and bodies made for hot oil wrestling. Mandy's hair is dyed ash blonde, Sammy's is amber. Otherwise, the experience is similar.</context>
      <utterance>Did she say th' wrong thang agin? It is so in character!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Julianne Potter, and...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We came in complementary colors.</context>
      <utterance>... we'd be the vengeful sluts.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you sized up the groomsmen, Jules? As M. of H., you get first fuck. Don't pick the short, hairy, rich one.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girls cast identical blank looks at Kimberly. KIMMY (to the sluts) Dry. I told you.</context>
      <utterance>... unless he has a hump.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>All eyes turn to an elegant woman of barely 40. She has her daughter's hair and eyes and slender form. But the bearing rules half an empire. Fonda would envy.</context>
      <utterance>Is this Michael's Julianne?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes both of Julianne's hands, and our heroine is sort of magically charmed. As if touched by Glinda the Good Witch of the North.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Isabelle Wallace, and my handsome new son scarcely did you justice, girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looking warmly in her eyes...</context>
      <utterance>Now, my husband says to scoot you over to the ballpark, so you can hang with Michael. But first, you have to meet a lot of really old women.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flicks a glance at the twins. Leads Julianne off... MANDY (O.S., pouting) We sayed one fuck.</context>
      <utterance>That is, if you've absorbed enough profanity.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SQUAWK. Static. Then...</context>
      <utterance>Desperate measures! Do you hear me? Digger, are you the...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Listens.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, hit men, whoopee cushions, saltpeter, something! The girl is impossibly impregnable. Even I want her to get the guy!!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes her head. What a guy.</context>
      <utterance>Tell him the what? The truth...??</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That desperate. May I never get.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One single tray. Holding fourteen beers. Balancing on one hand. Michael JUMPS UP, terrified at the impending mayhem this sight suggests...</context>
      <utterance>Which of you gents ordered two beers?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops in his tracks. The guys whistle.</context>
      <utterance>Wow! Lemme give you a ha... JULIANNE  Michael. You'll unwittingly imply that I'm clumsy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes first to the bodyguard.</context>
      <utterance>Think of that. And as well as I know you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BODYGUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Heads down the row...</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, ma'am, I'm on duty. JULIANNE  It's Miss. And thanks. That leaves two for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's nodding, flawlessly plucking two beers each from perimeter of the tray, keeping the rest perfectly balanced in the center. Michael is flat dumbstruck. Next, a tall patrician gentleman with rolled-up sleeves on his hand-stitched silk shirt...</context>
      <utterance>Julianne Potter, this is Hank and Gerry from SI, and you know Daniel...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Once again, she gracefully plucks two beers for the distinguished father-in-law...</context>
      <utterance>Oh. This is my father-in-law, Walter.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sets them down. The man has a smile wonderful in its ease. Murmurs...</context>
      <utterance>How are you doing this? You're on drugs.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If he gives you grief, I'll have him skillfully beaten, where the wounds won't show.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess getting him whacked would be politically out of the question.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Under the circumstances. Charmed to know you, Jules.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A nod between equals. She moves on...</context>
      <utterance>Nice meeting you, too, Walt.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sure does, and effortlessly balancing her one-hand load, she dips to kiss a porky, balding guy with big-time shoulders. Straight on the lips.</context>
      <utterance>And, this guy, you know...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They go way back. He is uncomfortable at this rich man's wedding, even as gracious as everyone has been. His watering eyes twinkle at her, and the voice has a trace of Boston...</context>
      <utterance>Papa Joe.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Despite SHOUTS from the others...</context>
      <utterance>You gonna be my boy's best man?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Best everything, Joe. But I'm going to dance with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her innocent smile.</context>
      <utterance>Dance? You don't dance! You learn to dance??</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BIG reaction from the guys, as she heads toward Michael with the last of the beers, not looking down at the FIELDER'S MITT which lies right in her path, and as his lips part to scream a warning, she skips... ... neatly AROUND it. He's in shock.</context>
      <utterance>Moves. You've never seen.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he takes away the remaining beers...</context>
      <utterance>You're an impostor! What have you done with my best friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hot dog? His eyes fix on her left breast. HUGE mustard stain. She can't believe it.</context>
      <utterance>And how was the hot dog?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cheap and unnecessary. We were looking anyway.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just admire your maturity, that's all. I mean, there are people who would find that kind of perfection boring. Day after day, year after year...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drinking their beers. Side by side. Both stare only at the game.</context>
      <utterance>... see, that's what I thought at first. How can you like someone that perfect? No potential for long-range livability.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luckily. The closer I watched, the more the fault came into focus. Each imperfection its own adorable slice of vulnerability.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Such as.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's too genuine.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hate that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you trust someone you can never mistrust?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Keep sipping. Never look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>What's next?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No matter how many times I leave the toilet seat up, she forgets and puts it down.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Endearingly absent-minded.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shakes his head. This one really gets him.</context>
      <utterance>My very point. Here's another one...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every day. She makes the bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quite the little eccentric.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is not the ammunition Julianne was hoping for.</context>
      <utterance>At first, I thought it was a gag, but she's always done it!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there a coup de grace in here, somewh...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She admires. Tommy Lasorda.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Waiter! Check, please!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She finds him "personable."</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks over now. And Michael is looking back. Smiling the most wonderful smile. Her reaction shows that she thinks it's for her, until...</context>
      <utterance>Can that kind of defect be passed on genetically?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hating herself for asking, but seeing no way out...</context>
      <utterance>Then again. She has a few good traits.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gimme like, eight and nine off the top ten list...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First girl I ever knew. Who lets me give her a bath. The look in his eyes. She can hardly bear it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He seems so deeply in love.</context>
      <utterance>And when I hug her, even in public. I don't have to let go right away. She lets me hold her as long as I want.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. A slow nod. A quiet...</context>
      <utterance>Nice kid, don't you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like, from here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kim shaking her head. Looks admiringly to Michael...</context>
      <utterance>How'd you find this pl...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches slender fingers. Traces one back along his hair.</context>
      <utterance>Lived here my whole life, never heard of it. Until our first date.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He finds all these spots, everywhere he goes, it's a mystical gift. MICHAEL  Jesus, one d-back from the Bears knows a place...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not just clubs. This guy always knows the best everything. The best guitar store, the best beef ribs, the best Horowitz record, was he always like the...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... always. The best dim sum, the best camping stuff...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop, we're embarrassing h...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... best valley in New Zealand, best... women's shoes...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now he's grinning at Julianne. And she likes that a lot.</context>
      <utterance>I tried those on. When you weren't looking.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where was that, Florence, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Together in the memory. As Kimmy watches.</context>
      <utterance>Firenze.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Vespa? Me hanging on behind in the rain all night?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And, the first sniff of left-out...</context>
      <utterance>Till the gas ran out.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julianne's eyes flicker. Could this be a teensy opening? Keeps her eyes, her easy smile, and her killer instincts trained on Michael.</context>
      <utterance>I love Florence.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods, okay.</context>
      <utterance>Take her there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He draws a breath...</context>
      <utterance>I mean, now. She's perky, she deserves a honeymoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the happy couple look at each other. They are awkward. Julianne's heart soar like eagle.</context>
      <utterance>I heard. If San Antone sweeps Sacramento. What is this shit? You gotta get off the road by September anyway, when does Fall Quarter start?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Could this be. The Mother Lode?</context>
      <utterance>Uh. I'm not coming back. For senior year.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The couple still staring in each other's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Don't architects find a degree, sort of... an asset?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Right now...</context>
      <utterance>Well, the school will be here. Architecture will still be around.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I travel every week. College ball, motor sports, training camps...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she smiles. Beautifully.</context>
      <utterance>The most important thing. Is being together.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>the time... in the world.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just a baby. I've got all...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I could come...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kim smiles. He kisses her, tenderly, through the open window. She waves past him at Julianne. KIMMY (to both) Enjoy each other. And drives off. As he watches after, Julianne comes up behind him. Slips her hand up onto his shoulder muscle. Starts giving a little massage.</context>
      <utterance>To the twins' soiree? So they can paw you and drool...? JULIANNE  They're gonna drool anyway!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should I whistle down a cab?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Turns his head, to see her. She's still rubbing his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, cabs are expensive. I'm cheap, remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Share a smile. As always, it covers a lot of years.</context>
      <utterance>Sometimes. About the dumbest things.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks around. It is an issue. But she remembers...</context>
      <utterance>The El's right down the street. Unless you're afraid of the neighborhood.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She means that. He takes her by the hand. They begin walking...</context>
      <utterance>No. I'm always safe with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Make that kind of sacrifice.</context>
      <utterance>Pretty amazing girl, you've got.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, leaving school...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... all of it. She's leaving her family, her friends, everything she knows. She's putting her career on hold, and she seems a pretty ambitious, driven, kind of pers... MICHAEL  In her way.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's let go of her hand now. Looking down at the pavement before him, fists in his jacket pockets. JULIANNE (softly) I don't think she's naturally the... submissive type. Aren't you afraid she's gonna choke on this stand-by-your-man shit after awhi... MICHAEL (real quiet) No. Hit a nerve. This is promising.</context>
      <utterance>All to follow you in this dumb job, where you travel 52 weeks a year to College Station, Texas, and such. It's not a job for a grown man, Michael, Peter Pan never married.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean Walter owns the Sox, cable sports... most girls in her spot would be angling to get Daddy to offer you some juicy gig right here in t...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paydirt. Julianne's Geiger Counter is going berserk.</context>
      <utterance>She would never. Never. Even think of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>controlling... emascula...</context>
      <utterance>I guess you're right. That would be deceitful... manipulative...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks over at her. No smile on his face. An edge we haven't seen. She shrugs...</context>
      <utterance>I got the point.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still. All's fair in love and w...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They've reached the stairs to the El. A rickety train RATTLES above them. As they start up, she slips her arm around his waist... JULIANNE (murmurs) Forgive me, okay? I was talkin' crazy. He slides his arm around her shoulder. Pals. They climb out of frame.</context>
      <utterance>That would be a girl. I don't even know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>... it becomes truly disgusting lumpy green mud.</context>
      <utterance>It's Albanian, I think. Or Mongolian. Or Canadian. One of those. I bought it downstairs...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Follow the hand up as it SLATHERS the shit across her face in great green dripping gobs. She's juggling the wall phone, trying to keep it mudless, as she assures Digger...</context>
      <utterance>I figure, what the hell. Can it make me look worse?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More green slime. The Julianne we know disappears.</context>
      <utterance>Dig, of course. Of course, of course, of course, of course I have a plan. Certainment!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Desecrates three hotel towels, wiping her hand.</context>
      <utterance>How? I ask myself, what would Lucy Ricardo do in this situa...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THROWS them in the bathtub. Fastidiousness a short suit.</context>
      <utterance>Well, one worked, once.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reaches for her toothbrush, absently. All her attention is on the conversation and the hideous green face in the mirror.</context>
      <utterance>Ricky wouldn't let her in the show.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without looking, picks up a tube of hotel shampoo...</context>
      <utterance>I recall it differently, but we digress.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Squeezes it all over the toothbrush.</context>
      <utterance>So in the version, you're Ethel, with better fashion instincts.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lifts it toward her mouth, liquid shampoo dripping from the bristles.</context>
      <utterance>This puts you in charge of Plan B, the unprincipled and insanely dangerous back-up plan...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the last second. She stops. We don't know why, because she's still never looked at the brush.</context>
      <utterance>In case simple lying doesn't work.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Turns on the tap. Tries to scrub the toothbrush clean, and DROPS the phone into the green swamp, which SPATTERS all over her front. Euucch. She's stymied, agitated, circling the sink, leaning down to it...</context>
      <utterance>Question. What happens if you brush your teeth with shampoo?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lifts the toothbrush and tube of paste from her kit.</context>
      <utterance>You okay? This is one of those problem phones.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Squeezes on the paste, lifts the brush to her mouth...</context>
      <utterance>Right. Your role. You know guys from Sports Illustrated, yes? I mean, you can walk right in there...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stops. The funniest look on her face. Down to the toothpaste tube... Which says BEN GAY. Oh.</context>
      <utterance>You could get access to letterhead, for example. JAMS it in her mouth, brushing as... JULIANNE  ... or even, maybe, their fax.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="50">
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hmm?</context>
      <utterance>It's an homage thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kimmy doesn't. But wipes a blue glob from Julianne's face.</context>
      <utterance>Awkward girls grow up on Audrey Hepburn movies. You wouldn't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wrong?</context>
      <utterance>Anyway, I think you're wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before?</context>
      <utterance>What you were saying before.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About Michael's job.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, that. I forgot I even said th...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just think you're wrong, is all.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Points to some jade pins. Kimmy wrinkles her nose.</context>
      <utterance>Probably am. Forget I brought it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, he loves his job.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Bad games, bad towns, bad pay, bad flights, bad hotels, real bad food. Homeless, rootless, lonely, maybe your copy gets into one issue out of four...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>None of this is lost on Kimmy. She's wondered the same.</context>
      <utterance>What's not to love?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But he always says...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kim nods slowly. Way ahead of her.</context>
      <utterance>... whatever is manly and independent.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kim stares back. A strange look.</context>
      <utterance>Why would he trade that for running, say, a big piece of the PR at a powerful, complex, challenging conglomerate like your dad's?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julianne just blinks. Amazed.</context>
      <utterance>That's just the sort of thing my father and I discussed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pointing to tiny golden scissors in the novelty case. Kim so absorbed by the main topic, she has to force herself to focus on...</context>
      <utterance>I'm not stupid. Say, how about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For the twins? What in the world is th...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Points to the tiny hand-lettered sign. Indeed. Kimmy shrugs, not quite it.</context>
      <utterance>Gold nose hair clippers.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you don't think Michael's as happy with his job as... Julianne points to a matched pair of large...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gold dog collars? They don't have dogs.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kim nods, oh. But can't keep her mind off...</context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hmm?</context>
      <utterance>You think he'd accept?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh, well...</context>
      <utterance>Michael. A job like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kimmy nodding slowly. Her yearing achingly apparent.</context>
      <utterance>By any yardstick that involves sanity, it would be the greatest thing that ever happened to him. Present company excepted.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A very sweet smile.</context>
      <utterance>On the other hand, he's proud. Last thing a man wants to admit, is being trapped in a dispiriting dead-end job that can never support a family.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kim nods again. Right. They are so bonded at this moment.</context>
      <utterance>Throw a man a life preserver. He'll say, "Thanks, anyway, I'd rather drown."</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So... one almost has to...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kimmy bites her lip. Her eyes go down. Self-conscious to admit...</context>
      <utterance>What you said. Make it appear that he's doing you the favor.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That brings the gray eyes up. Julianne bats her dark ones...</context>
      <utterance>I couldn't really... do that. After, you know... Her voice trails off. JULIANNE  ... lying. All the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, darling, my pitiful desires and ambitions are dirt beneath the manly boots of your priorities! Kimmy has to smile small. A self-awe gal. JULIANNE  Two hundred seedy motels a year? Dinners out of vending machines? Waiting for you in vermin-infested corridors of dark crotch-rot locker rooms? This stuff makes me hot!!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julianne 'thinks it over.' Kimmy waits for guidance.</context>
      <utterance>The very words I've used.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simple.</context>
      <utterance>We make Dad your co-conspirator. Michael does a favor for Walter.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kimmy nodding. Hope overriding reason.</context>
      <utterance>Walter's reorganizing his public relations, needs a brilliant guy who's close to him, who he can completely trust.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Turns up her palms. Viola!</context>
      <utterance>So you beg. Michael, please do this for Daddy, please, please, please, blah, blah, blah... it's only for six months... it would mean so much to me to help him out...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'll see right through it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They share a smile.</context>
      <utterance>Only. If he wants to.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In six months, he'll be happy, settled, successful...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He won't get mad, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR.  MOONEY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Mr. Mooney is the most gracious Brit salesperson ever to offer kindness, intelligence and thoughtfulness to a customer. He is large, sixty, with disappearing hair, watering eyes, and a manner that makes you think of immediately hiring a butler.</context>
      <utterance>May I be of any help, whatsoever?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bridesmaid gifts for two, well, assertive, outspoken, Tennessee debutantes. KIMMY  He won't be mad? JULIANNE  Nothing here seems to quite capture their distinctive personalities.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR.  MOONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ah. Julianne nodding. Reflecting.</context>
      <utterance>Something customized, perhaps? We can fashion most any item from gold.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR.  MOONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julianne digs through her jumbled bag...</context>
      <utterance>An object that might represent what is closest. To their heart. KIMMY  Don't even think dildo.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tossing an object on the counter...</context>
      <utterance>Could you do this...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They smile at each other. More bonded than ever.</context>
      <utterance>In 24 carat? It is a MASTERCARD. A gold one. KIMMY  Bingo.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Can Julianne even make herself do this?</context>
      <utterance>You don't think he'll be mad.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your call. You can live a lie. In a fabulous selection of Red Roof Inns. Or you can make one desperate stab at hap...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What do you think? Julianne stares into the soft gray eyes. It's now or never. The smile of a dear sister...</context>
      <utterance>I just don't want to freak him out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How mad could he get?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>MAITRE D'</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Points to an escalator, leading to the mezzanine. Behind a glass wall, what looks like a British men's club. Thirty guys and a billion cigars. As Julianne starts toward it...</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Mr. Wallace and his guests have retired to the humidor.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAITRE D'</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns back. Loves this shit.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Mademoiselle.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAITRE D'</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's unofficial, of course. But, traditionally, the humidor is for gentlemen, only...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her look is every bit as hard as his. He gestures to the escalator. She takes Kimmy's hand, and up they go. We can see Walter in a big leather chair, enjoying a major stogie. Kimmy licks her lips. They enter. Every head turns. A nice range of reactions, from offended to attracted and points in between. JULIANNE (murmurs) Piece of cake. I'll hang, and think happy thoughts... Kimmy nods. Heads over toward her father. Julianne walks, confidently, even provocatively, to the wall lined with bins of cigars. Every eye in the place is on her butt. She runs her fingers over a few contenders. Plucks one out, examines it, puts it back. Walks a little farther. Selects another, big and black. Rolls it expertly in her fingers. Sniffs along its length. A guy comes over. Could be 40, successful, a broker's pin-stripe. Nearly as attractive as he thinks he is.</context>
      <utterance>Great. I've got this girlfriend at the Justice Department? With all this time on her hands?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Little lady, huh? She glances at his coven of buddies, who pretend not to notice. Then, straight to the guy's blue eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Know what you're looking for, little lady?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ah. Wit. She holds up her cigar...</context>
      <utterance>I asked first.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Runs it under her nose.</context>
      <utterance>I like 'em long and hard. Kind of... big around.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Takes a match from a cut crystal bowl.</context>
      <utterance>Smell is important, I'm a believer in that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she does. Moistening the full length of the cigar. The boys are laughing openly. She STRIKES the match. As she lights up...</context>
      <utterance>But you never know what you've got. Till you run your tongue over it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances at his wedding ring. Then, straight into his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I meant. What you're looking for in a man.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The way she says that. The guy swallows. We can see some of the air has been sucked from the room.</context>
      <utterance>Actually, I'm partial to married gentlemen.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Explosive LAUGHTER from the peanut gallery. As she jams the big Clemente Churchill into her mouth, she sees Kimmy waving her over from across the room. Without even looking at the guy she's just put away... ... she crosses the room, Walter stands politely, looking very dapper, very powerful, and focusing on her with considerable interest. He waits until she sits on the edge of a costly leather hassock.</context>
      <utterance>It's so much time. When I phone the wives.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She can't read this guy. Maybe that's how he built an empire. She nods, yeah.</context>
      <utterance>Your idea?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sits on the arm of his chair. Close enough to speak quietly.</context>
      <utterance>You're a woman of insight.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puffs his cigar. Julianne puffs her. Kimmy looks on, a kid watching the grown-ups...</context>
      <utterance>My wife and I love this marriage, and deplore its circumstances.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As you guessed, my daughter is unhappy about giving up her life. And, in my opinion, cowardly in avoiding the necessary confrontation. Then he stops. As if reading Julianne's eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One more puff.</context>
      <utterance>Mike has a world of ability. I'd do anything to have him in my company.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julianne is a little stunned. Kimmy looks helpless.</context>
      <utterance>Except ask him.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No smile on his lips. Straight talk.</context>
      <utterance>He'd resent it. And me. And, most important, Kim.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spreads his hands...</context>
      <utterance>He's a great kid, but he's still a kid. Instead of recognizing that his resistance comes from insecurity, he'd turn it to anger. To protect himself...</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks to his daughter now.</context>
      <utterance>... from realizing that he's ignoring my daughter's needs, despite how very much he loves her.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They've got time.</context>
      <utterance>They both have some growing up to do. But they're good people, they're starting with love.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes come back to her. A little sharply.</context>
      <utterance>I think you're making a mistake, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A formidable guy. She meets his gaze.</context>
      <utterance>And that interests me. How someone who knows him so well could be so wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From her heart.</context>
      <utterance>See, I love him, too, as much as anyone here. And for a whole lot longer.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I know best what would make him happy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She closes her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay, okay, okay, I hear you, all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deep drag on the cigarette. For strength.</context>
      <utterance>It is stupid, dishonest, desperate beyond belief, and can't possibly ever work. It can only end in humiliation and disgrace. Now can I say two words?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's striped her gears. COUGHS horribly.</context>
      <utterance>Do it! Do it! Do it! Do it! Do it! Do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, twelve words.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TEENAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julianne nods to the kids. They nod back. Damn straight. She exits the restroom, into... ... glaring sunlight. We are in the middle of the BROOKFIELD ZOO. And sitting on a bench, eating popcorn from a bag...</context>
      <utterance>You do it, girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shudders.</context>
      <utterance>Wow. What was going on in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some crazy person.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not eating.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never eat when I'm serene.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You never eat when you're despondent.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She swirls a single nacho chip in cheese. But her heart isn't in it.</context>
      <utterance>I switched that around when you weren't looking.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last zoo we were in was... Beijing, yeah? Sure. The rhinos were fucking.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And when she looks over. His eyes are waiting.</context>
      <utterance>Boy, those were the days.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're passing the hippo pen. But they don't notice.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, they were.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>So was that. He's feeling restless, something. Doesn't know quite what to say.</context>
      <utterance>That was nice. The way you said that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's weird being the groom. All these things Kimmy has to take care of...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds her eyes. Then looks down. Awkward. And the way he's doing it begins to excite her.</context>
      <utterance>You need a baby-sitter. That's what I'm here for.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up, neither one of them noticing that as they walk, she is about to... ... CRASH into a chest-high metal stand that displays animal facts. We have followed him as she is WIPED from frame. His face from shock... to amusement.</context>
      <utterance>Say it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... to tenderness. PAN back to see her wearing everything from her cardboard container. Nachos, fudge sauce, Diet Coke, the works. It is really awful. Kids, bystanders, laughing cruelly. Her eyes fill with tears, and she tries bravely to smile against it...</context>
      <utterance>Now, there's my girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes out his handkerchief. And with that and his hands, gently scoops the worst of the mess off her. The fact that he's touching her breasts and her body is something they pretend not to notice. She laughs softly, and a few tears fall, even though she doesn't know why. Such an odd, raw, confusing moment. To the world looking on, they are lovers.</context>
      <utterance>See, I can only do it with beer.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he kisses her face. Not quite her lips. But only an inch away. We can feel her heart pounding. He strips off his shirt, only a tank top underneath.</context>
      <utterance>See, better already.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Okay? She sniffles, okay. Swallows.</context>
      <utterance>We'll go back to the bathroom, you'll put this on...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts his arm around her.</context>
      <utterance>Bet you're glad I'm here to take care of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holds her close, as they start toward the restroom...</context>
      <utterance>Bet I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We're on their backs...</context>
      <utterance>Hope that crazy person's not still there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She doesn't scare me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is anybody watching?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches into her big bag. Pulls out a single folded sheet of paper.</context>
      <utterance>I hope so. This is all too mysterious to waste on just me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His face darkens. The easy smile fades. He holds up his palms...</context>
      <utterance>I picked up Michael's messages for him, at our hotel. I stole one...</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Julianne, reading my son-in-law's mail, is not something...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His smile returns. Just a little.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, this is important! Haven't you ever in your life cut one corner, to make something important turn out right?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The look holds. She thrusts the paper out. He still doesn't take it.</context>
      <utterance>Matter of fact, that's how I got married.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a fax from Sports Illustrated from Ben Isaacson, Michael's boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens the paper.</context>
      <utterance>I know Ben.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes the paper. We see it now. Looks authentic.</context>
      <utterance>"Mike. We still have no answer to our E-mail of Wednesday. Which option do you select? I don't mean to rush you, but Personnel needs to tie up the loose ends."</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think he's been fired.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't say th...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up. He's listening. Closely.</context>
      <utterance>He's said some things over the past few weeks. Look, this is why I came up with the idea of you offering him a job.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She bites her lip. Seems so earnest.</context>
      <utterance>And why I couldn't say anything before in front of Kim.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He does.</context>
      <utterance>I just think of how... desperate he must be feeling. He's marrying a rich man's daughter, and he's about to become destitute. You know the kind of job market he'll be facing?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you think he's kept this to himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's staring at her. But his mind is working behind his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>He's too proud to beg for help. And if you wait till this comes out, your offer will be like charity. Completely humiliating.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He taps the paper with the back of his knuckles.</context>
      <utterance>If you do it now, it's like he's helping you. He can accept with dignity.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods. She knows that.</context>
      <utterance>This fax could mean... any number of things...</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe. I should call Ben.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes the paper back.</context>
      <utterance>Then it could all come out, sooner or later. Nobody should be in on this. Just you and me. Or, more correctly, I.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The long straight look. Maybe he's hooked.</context>
      <utterance>What if, what if I could find that E-mail?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never noticed. Kimmy has your eyes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's flirting her ass off.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, again.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she reaches across the desk with her lovely, slender hands. Does it for him. Her fingers brush his chest on the way back. We can assume a woody.</context>
      <utterance>You still haven't straightened that tie.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He does. His eyes flick toward his stately female SUPERVISOR, helping another guest across the way.</context>
      <utterance>You know, my friend, the one whose message I picked up... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy swallows hard.</context>
      <utterance>Well, he's still with the wedding party. And he asked me to get something he needs real badly from his room... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's in 1526. If you could just let me ha...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not only does Julianne see her. The woman is looking back, while she's talking to her customer. Not a pleasant look.</context>
      <utterance>See that woman?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She said, if I ever pull a stunt like that again...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll lose your job...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... tear my pecker off. Is what she said.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The maid can only blink.</context>
      <utterance>Help me!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And looks frantically up the hall, mortified that any moment a stranger could happen upon her predicament. Her eyes dart back to the maid. PLEASE. The maid just stares. Stares.</context>
      <utterance>I locked myself out, 1526, please hurry!!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh.</context>
      <utterance>Uno-cinco-does-ses.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Those words make her bite her lip. Damn, I'm becoming a senti- mental slob. TYPES in...</context>
      <utterance>You wouldn't change your password, would you? You never change anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yes! We're in! Punching keys. Letters flying across the screen. Okay, we're ready. Types...</context>
      <utterance>Shoeless... Joe.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mike. I hate this downsizing shit as much as you do. But I know this can't become as a complete surprise...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reads. Reads. Reads. All the air comes out of him.</context>
      <utterance>Mike. I hate this downsizing...</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes her head. Nope. No way.</context>
      <utterance>And Kimmy doesn't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods, gravely. Right. He looks in her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I'll tell her I've reconsidered.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She forces up a fleeting smile of gratitude. But Walter isn't smiling at all.</context>
      <utterance>You're a smart girl, Jules.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wish my daughter. Bad your guts.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="41">
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks really scared. Turns her drink in her hand. Looking down at it.</context>
      <utterance>Sure you're okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not just a gag, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes her hand, tenderly.</context>
      <utterance>No, it's, uh... a real big favor.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles up at him. The best she can.</context>
      <utterance>I wish you'd just... come out with it. I mean why are we waiting for Jules?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She loves him so much, and she is sick with worry.</context>
      <utterance>Moral support.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stops. Gestures with her eyes. Because her big sister has just entered... ... looking fabulous. Julianne wears a long sleek sarong, slightly see-through. Her hair is bound up with silver pins. As she moves through the room toward us, we can see that, for once, her make-up is flawless, understated. When she arrives at the table... ... Michael is beaming, admiringly. He stands up.</context>
      <utterance>What's good of having a big sister, if she...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow and wow. You have a date, after this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds her chair. She exchanges an intimate smile with the anxious Kim.</context>
      <utterance>Never can tell.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he starts humming. The song is, "The Way You Look Tonight."</context>
      <utterance>You make me think of that song, we used to...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They sit. He looks from Julianne to his bride.</context>
      <utterance>Someday. When I'm awfully low...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kim's eyes flick to Julianne, who nods, supportively. The kid takes a breath.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, kid. You're on.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His face sort of comes to a stop. Nothing she can read, yet. He nods, yeah...?</context>
      <utterance>It's really my father. Who needs the favor.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes flick to Julianne. She looks down.</context>
      <utterance>He's... he's reorganizing some of the divisions of the company...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He never mentioned that. Neither did y...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She can see it now. In his eyes. She just can't tell how bad.</context>
      <utterance>... and public relations is a big problem area for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He needs someone incredible, someone really close, who he can trust...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>So quiet. So cold. She is terrified.</context>
      <utterance>Like family, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It would only be, maybe, six months? Or three or four? It would mean so much to him...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She swallows. Straightens her spine.</context>
      <utterance>To him.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And to m...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Real quiet. Against the noise of this place.</context>
      <utterance>... and you knew about this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just the thing. To bring that anger near the surface. He turns to Kim...</context>
      <utterance>I think you ought to listen to her, Michael. This is her life, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A demand. Sharp. Accusing. She doesn't like that...</context>
      <utterance>Well, which is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's trapped. Angry, scared. A deer in headlights.</context>
      <utterance>You gonna tell me Daddy thought this one up? All of a sudden, I'm the only jerk alive who can help him deal with the press?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you start being honest for one fucking sec...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Michael!!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>I am honest!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All of a sudden, I'm supposed to drop out of school, forget my family, forget my career, forget all the plans I had for my life...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He can't even believe he's hearing this.</context>
      <utterance>Well, forgive me for screwing up your plans!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure glad I'm hearing all this now, before it's too late!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is that sup...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>And what am I supposed to do with my life, huh? I am 28 years old! I work in a low-paying, low-status, zero-respect job which, unfortunately, I happen to fucking love. How inconvenient.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No problem. A little bullshit about Daddy's "needs," and presto, I'm a lap dog in high society.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Michael, it sounds like a wonderful opportun...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Glares in her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Does it, really? How come you never took some sell-out establishment job? You had plenty of chances!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Back to Kim...</context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you why. Because that isn't you. And it isn't me, either! We're the same person!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a sweet little picture. Mommy and Daddy aren't losing a daughter, they're gaining a eunuch!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if that's the way you f...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's crying now. Real tears on her face.</context>
      <utterance>Damn straight, it's how I feel! What's their wedding gift, a little gold collar that says "Mikey-poo"? Or do I have to change my name to "Binky"?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is sobbing now. She can't help herself. Which makes him totally crazy. He jumps up.</context>
      <utterance>Great! Tears! The big equalizer. You wait till two days before the wedding to drop this on me, and I'm just supposed to roll over and drool!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine. I'm an insensitive, chauvinist asshole, and you're well rid of m...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Choking back the sobs.</context>
      <utterance>Michael, you are so...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael blinks. Julianne blinks. For different reasons.</context>
      <utterance>... so right. And I am so very wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her fingers stretch, beckoning.</context>
      <utterance>We can't go down two roads. And still be together.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, Kimmy...?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Please, please, take my hand.</context>
      <utterance>We settled this. And I reneged. That wasn't fair.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>People are watching, staring. These two see only each other.</context>
      <utterance>You have to forgive me, and forget this ever happened...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A frozen, forever moment. He steps to her... ... LIFTS her up in his arms. Into the deepest, most heartfelt KISS. And as she clings to him, people begins to APPLAUD, and whistle, and laugh. Julianne. In her pretty dress. Closes her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>... or I'll die.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We CLOSE as she WHIPS around, startling us with her grotesque day- glo PURPLE face mask. The green was better.</context>
      <utterance>... see that's what I never counted on! I never heard of a brilliant moron before!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, the little twerp</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tears are flowing. Which, over this mask, is not a pretty sight.</context>
      <utterance>Michael and I are the same person! Self-absorbed and imperfect and vaguely loveable! We deserve each other!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She TRIPS over an open suitcase, and DISAPPEARS from frame. The THUD is slightly alarming.</context>
      <utterance>I'm out of hope, I'm out of sneaky ideas, I'm at the end of my rapidly-fraying hysterical little rope! Help m...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>HOLD. On nothing is particular.</context>
      <utterance>God, I hate this hotel.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I hate talking to your machine!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He touches his face, and she realizes!</context>
      <utterance>You stole my line.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Starts CLAWING at the overripe mask, but he grabs her wrists.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chill. We don't want your face coming off with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chill? Since when do you say ch...</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks in his eyes. Realizing at last.</context>
      <utterance>When I'm talking to children.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You flew all the way h...</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I noticed. I'm on the noon back. We have this thing with George's family in the Hamptons.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He still holds her wrists. She brings one of his hands to her lips. Kisses his knuckles.</context>
      <utterance>You're butting in.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I really resent this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And that is annoying as shit.</context>
      <utterance>What I mean, when I say annoyingly perfect, is that there is nothing annoying about her perfection. It is vulnerable and endearing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks up at him and WINCES, as the movement makes him scrape her face. He's sorry.</context>
      <utterance>If I didn't have to hate her, I'd adore her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looking in his eyes. Needs him to hear.</context>
      <utterance>Last night, she was crying, these big, real tears, when she thought she'd lost him. It was like there was a knife in her heart...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Can you believe this?</context>
      <utterance>... and I put it there. I hated myself, I grieved for her, I couldn't enjoy one second of it! And then, when it didn't work...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was devastated.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go figure you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds his wrists now. To stop him. To plead for understanding. Forgiveness.</context>
      <utterance>Because I realized. When I see him say "I do," that knife will be in my heart. And it will be there every...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She almost choked on that last part. So she composes herself.</context>
      <utterance>... every time I think of him, forever, which could be a lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She swallows hard. Fights for a grip on her determination.</context>
      <utterance>You watch a guy caress his girlfriend's butt. You see an Old Spice commercial. Sentimental moments are everywhere, when you're in the right frame of mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are 18,250 nights in the next 50 years...</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've been working on this, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sets her jaw.</context>
      <utterance>... and having "done the right thing" will only really be comforting, oh, maybe, five, six times.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I have to be ruthless.</context>
      <utterance>This is my whole life's happiness.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you believe that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes are gentle and merciless at once. No way she gets off this hook.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was in love with me every day for nine years. I can make him happier than she can.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not his happiness you're feeling guilty about...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know the meaning of the word guilt!</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Impressive.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am breaking her heart in the short run, but doing her a gigantic favor! She would be miserable tagging along after this insensitive doofus!</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The man you love.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beyond reason. The feminist warrior will rise up in this kid, and she'll be standing over his sleeping form with a butcher knife, selecting from a short list of body parts!</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someday she'll thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the defenses drain from her clay-ravaged features. The real Julianne is glimpsed.</context>
      <utterance>Let's not get carried away.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For...?</context>
      <utterance>I'd settle for. Someday, I'll forgive myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes tear up.</context>
      <utterance>For doing this terrible thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the tears fall, he wipes at them, discovering...</context>
      <utterance>Which, by the way, I can't figure out how to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus. You're supposed to take your make-up off before you apply the m...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He thinks about this. Following her eyes to the toiletries kit, he browses for a moment...</context>
      <utterance>Guess what I brushed my teeth with last night?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zit cream?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Neosporin?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try less appropriate.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben Gay.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops on that note.</context>
      <utterance>That was Thursday.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elmer's Glue?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I give.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now. He's curious.</context>
      <utterance>I can't even say it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches to test her curling iron, BURNS her finger, SHIT! KNOCKING the appliance into the half-filled sink. She LUNGES for it, and a terrified Digger GRASPS her arm...</context>
      <utterance>A hint. The first word is "Preparation." Then comes a letter of the alphabet, perilously close to G.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Huh?</context>
      <utterance>Considering the circumstances, I'm not wholly against suicide...</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh.</context>
      <utterance>Just not by electrocution in front of me!</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches to pull the plug from the wall, and now she LUNGES to grab his arm, slipping, her face falling forward, stopping an inch above the sink.</context>
      <utterance>I've got this noon flight.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know you can touch that plug? Are you a licensed contractor?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks from the plug down the cord, to the submerged curling iron. And back.</context>
      <utterance>What do you suggest?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's staring at her. Sweet, but intense.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe they just seal off this room. They have others.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh. Again.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looking at her. Looking at her.</context>
      <utterance>If I hear the words "tell the truth," or any paraphrase thereof, I dive into the sink and pull you with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go meet Michael. I'll wait downstairs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose it's too late to start over.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PULL BACK to reveal Michael in his wedding tux, submitting to a final fitting from a stylish fitter.</context>
      <utterance>It's too late to start over.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys are heartless, my bride picked this out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like I said, dazzling.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael smiles over. Digger smiles back. They live each other.</context>
      <utterance>Is she going to dress you every day?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it's in the contract.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael motions, okay, c'mon over. Digger rises, goes to Michael, the fitter steps back as Digger shows him...</context>
      <utterance>Well, then, I'll take it up with her.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fingers lightly traveling over the lapel, the side-stitching, the cloth straight down the spine...</context>
      <utterance>The cut here, here... this line...</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... trouser width, this is all classic. Which means safe, something I'd wear.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should look different.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yes? Michael's grin is back. Playful and friendly.</context>
      <utterance>You should look like you dressed yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I'm supposed to respect your fashion tips, because you're what, a New Yorker?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julianne loves that the boy are getting on.</context>
      <utterance>Something like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Long trip. Pretty nice of you to come.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Said so naturally. That embarrasses Michael, who looks down, his smile suddenly awkward.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm close to her. I wanted to meet the one that got away.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Steals a glance at Julianne. She rolls her eyes. What a goofball, my outrageous friend.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just glad someone finally put this thing in its proper perspective.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I honestly wish I could...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julianne comes over.</context>
      <utterance>I'll call George's parents. Tell them I need a best man who actually looks after me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She runs her hands over his jacket, smoothing it everywhere. With tenderness that approaches transparency. Glances back at Digger...</context>
      <utterance>They'd say that's my job.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pinches Michael's ear. Looks in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take it home from here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two words.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Major. Dish.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks down. Michael's nails are unclipped, with layers of impacted dirt. She touches his fingertips, a little more softly than she may have intended.</context>
      <utterance>Manicure...</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone looks down. She ZIPS Michael up.</context>
      <utterance>Fly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't miss much.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Part of being a New Yorker.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Digger just stares at her. Those maddening judgemental eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Bye, handsome.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going to say it, aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell him you love him. With all your heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm taking my next book to Viking.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell him you've loved him for nine years, but you were afraid to realize it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm moving this book to Viking.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Afraid of needing.</context>
      <utterance>Tell him you're afraid of love.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Needing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He touches her hair.</context>
      <utterance>To belong to someone.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Staring in her eyes. Even Julianne has run out of words.</context>
      <utterance>We all do, beautiful. I'm sorry about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell him you know this is the worst, dumbest, cruelest moment to do this to him. But there it is, and he has to choose.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Digger isn't smiling. His voice low, beneath the crowd...</context>
      <utterance>And what will he do?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up one finger. Almost touching her nose.</context>
      <utterance>He'll choose Kim. You'll stand by her at her wedding. You'll kiss him good-bye. And you'll go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wow. She looks frightened and moved, all at the same time. She kisses him on the lips. And walks away. He watches her go through the crowd. Take Michael's hand. Lead him back toward the taxi.</context>
      <utterance>This is what you've come to do. Now do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="44">
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big weddings are so strange.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Up ahead, the Wrigley Building draws closer...</context>
      <utterance>You keep saying that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kim has all this stuff to do, I hardly see her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>REVERSE ANGLE... they lean on the rail of a cruise boat, easing down the Chicago River. Wind-blown. Close together.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you've got the rest of your lives.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They smile at each other. Seem so comfortable together.</context>
      <utterance>Getting your bed made. Every day.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You miss her, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods. That you have. Staring in her eyes...</context>
      <utterance>No. I've got you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you throw up on boat?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she LURCHES over the railing, emitting a BARRAGE of incredibly disgusting sounds, her feet FLAILING in mid-air. He laughs, as he pulls her back down to the deck. Of course, it was all a joke. He brushes back her hair. Sighs. Stares.</context>
      <utterance>If you like.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been thinking a lot the last couple days. About us, actually.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has.</context>
      <utterance>Have you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well. There's a lot of memories to choose from...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That tightens her throat pretty good. When she tries to speak, out comes a dry CROAK that makes him laugh again. Softer, this time.</context>
      <utterance>It's more than that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops. Her eyes WIDEN in a burlesque of anticipation. So he smiles. She knows how to put him at ease.</context>
      <utterance>I mean, it's embarrassing to say it this way, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've sort of been... y'know, the woman in my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Passing under the Michigan Avenue Bridge. No one knows quite what to say.</context>
      <utterance>You've been the man in mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You know?</context>
      <utterance>And I was thinking this could be our last time. Alone. Together.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Except for the hot affairs we'll have twice a year.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's smiling so easily. Who would guess her stomach is double- knotted.</context>
      <utterance>Except for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can hardly wait for your wedding.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She watches his surprise.</context>
      <utterance>Me either.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, I never thought I'd hear you say that. Can I come? She holds herself together. Real soft with...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's glad to hear that. And then...</context>
      <utterance>I couldn't have it without you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Is this a change of direction? Or is it the direction she's been praying for.</context>
      <utterance>It's normal to have... second thoughts, huh? To be scared.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't know. I never had that many first thoughts.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods. Understands.</context>
      <utterance>I mean, you commit to a wedding. And then it seems like... this... momentum, you know? You forget you... chose it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We didn't.</context>
      <utterance>You and I. I mean, in all our relationships with other people... We didn't use the word "love" a lot, did we?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Long beat.</context>
      <utterance>Kimmy says. When you love someone. You say it, you say it out loud. Right now. Or the moment...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Off in distance, the Centennial Fountain SHOOTS an eight-foot JET of water across the river. For Michael and Julianne it goes unnoticed.</context>
      <utterance>... passes you by, yeah. She's a smart girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hmm?</context>
      <utterance>We don't have a song.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All Julianne can do is shrug. Then...</context>
      <utterance>Kimmy and I. We don't have a song. Is that a bad sign?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She doesn't want to cry. So she puts all the strength she has into fighting it back.</context>
      <utterance>Someday, when I'm awfully low... And the world is cold...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops. Smiles that sweet, boyish smile.</context>
      <utterance>I will feel a glow just Thinking of you... And the way you look. Tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dance card filled?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up his arms. And she moves into them. He begins to dance with her, turning so slowly. And, yes, people are watching.</context>
      <utterance>I'll check. I have it on powerbook, these days.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds him closer. Bites her lip.</context>
      <utterance>With each word, your tenderness grows, Tearing my fears apart...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops. He looks at her. She's still in his arms.</context>
      <utterance>And that laugh That wrinkles your nose, Touches my foolish heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did we first hear th...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Right to his eyes...</context>
      <utterance>The night we met.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't know what to do with that.</context>
      <utterance>The night we fell in love.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So we heard it... like, right that... that first...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just like this. A long beat. And he has to say...</context>
      <utterance>We danced to it. Just like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes close. Then open. Utterly lost in his.</context>
      <utterance>I won't lose you, will I?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Because I won't let you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought Michael was picking me up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meaning, you. They smile at each other. Then...</context>
      <utterance>I told him, get the important stuff, Kim's ring. I'll collect the inconsequentials.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julianne thinks back.</context>
      <utterance>Kim said, when he turned down the job, there was no friction.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles at her line reading. But his mind is always probing.</context>
      <utterance>Friction. No.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't caused... a problem, have I?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her bright grin. His eyes linger on it.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody has. So far.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you're a little early...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Could I use... your office?</context>
      <utterance>I need to make some calls.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sacred, filled with doubt and conflict. Her hands clutch at each other. Then, one flicks out. And the computer goes ON. The screen GLOWS. Waits for her. Her mouth is sand, her stomach water. She pulls the paper from her pocket... ... looks at it. Looks to the monitor. And begins. To type...</context>
      <utterance>You can do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And stops. Her heart is thumping.</context>
      <utterance>E-mail address. To Ben Isaacson, Senior Editor, Sports Illustrated, from... Walter Wallace.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doesn't look easy. Licks her lips.</context>
      <utterance>See, you can do it. It's easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sits. And recites as she types...</context>
      <utterance>You do it fast, it's over. Like it never happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Here we go. This is it. Types...</context>
      <utterance>Ben. I need a favor.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nods, okay. Breathing hard. Types...</context>
      <utterance>My daughter's every happiness. And my wife's. And, least of all, my own, are in your hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Touch, that. Thinks. It has to be. Types...</context>
      <utterance>Knowing you value our friendship, and the... cooperative relationship between our companies... I am hopeful of your help.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Almost there. Almost. Types...</context>
      <utterance>I have offered Mike O'Neal, my new son-in-law, a great opportunity in my company. This would also enable my daughter to settle in Chicago, near us, and pursue her dreams and plans.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stands up. Stares at the screen. Walks away. Walks back. Still standing, types...</context>
      <utterance>To his own detriment, as well as ours, Michael will not accept our offer. While he works for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Is there a SOUND? Outside the door. She HOVERS over the ESCAPE key. Waits. Waits. Silence. Types...</context>
      <utterance>My daughter joins me in this plea for your cooperation and discretion.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hits a KEY. The screen goes BLANK. The computer asks... DO YOU WISH TO SEND? She tells the computer...</context>
      <utterance>With gratitude. For your understanding. Walter.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Types NO. The computer asks HOLD FOR LATER? And she types YES.</context>
      <utterance>Are you crazy? Get him fired?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances to her huge bag. Rummages through, pulling out a manila folder. Lays it by the blank computer. Fans out a few pages in a natural, disorderly way. Takes a step back... And stares. Struck to her gut. But when she has done.</context>
      <utterance>Just till tonight when I bring him back. To look for...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slips on his coat. Oh... and by the way...</context>
      <utterance>Off to rehearsal. Send out this, and this, not this, this, and... that's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On his way through the door...</context>
      <utterance>I'm holding four or five E-mails I wrote over lunch...</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Send 'em out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>MANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reverend Dyer, this is Kimberly's somewhat butch maid of honor...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Today, the girls' voices are charmingly musically Southern, with none of the extreme accents we heard at the shower. The minister extends his hand...</context>
      <utterance>... Mr. Julianne Potter, prominent New York drag queen.</utterance>
   <speaker>MINISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes his hand, smiles graciously, but her eyes flick to Michael, now approaching up the aisle. The girls lead the minister away. Michael arrives. Looks her up and down.</context>
      <utterance>Billy Dyer, Julianne. And I love the suit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Takes me back.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles. One that glows a little.</context>
      <utterance>Well.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods.</context>
      <utterance>You sang the song. Least I could do was wear the outfit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh, yeah? Yes, ma'am. As she loses herself in his eyes...</context>
      <utterance>Except now you're better- looking.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls the box from his pocket. Somewhere, an ORGAN sounds. And as he is about to hand her the box...</context>
      <utterance>I got the ring.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDY/SAMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Such exquisite two-part harmony, Michael stops to watch.</context>
      <utterance>Swi-i-ng low-ow-ow... Wee-ee-eet Char-i-ot...</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDY/SAMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is amazing. Soulful vengeful sluts. He is enthralled. Julianne simply impatient. She wants his attention.</context>
      <utterance>Comin', to car-ryyy Me ho-o-o-me...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No accents today.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes the box from his hand. Opens it, as the singing CONTINUES throughout. The ring is delicate hammered gold. One of a kind.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Kim told me they were giving you their Dueling Scarlet's act. Actually, they're sophomores at Juilliard.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will she like it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's staring at the ring.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>His master's voice. He gives Julianne a smile. And goes. She's left with the box. Gazes at the ring. Lifts it out.</context>
      <utterance>My groom-person! Your family needs you!</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDY/SAMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slips it on her left hand. Ring finger.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I look over yon-der, And what did I see-ee-ee?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDY/SAMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Touches it. Turns it on her finger. So many emotions.</context>
      <utterance>Comin too car-ryyy. Me ho-o-ome...</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDY/SAMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tries to pull it off.</context>
      <utterance>It was a hand. Of a-a-angels. Coming' for me-e-ee...</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDY/SAMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It won't come. Not even close.</context>
      <utterance>Comin' for to carry me home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He COUGHS, unaccustomed to public speaking. Walter and Isabelle clap and call out support. So Joe lifts his mallet...</context>
      <utterance>Like to welcome ever'body to our little rehearsal supper...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And everyone does. With one exception. Trapped. She JAMS her left hand in her coat pocket, SMEARS her right palm sort of clean on the underside of the table, GRABS her mallet and JUMPS UP.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, everyone stand up!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone applauses by banging their mallets. Joe RAISES his high. Everybody imitates.</context>
      <utterance>To the bride, uh, goes the honor... of cracking the first crab!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And everybody SNATCHES up their beers with their left hands, as Julianne DROPS her mallet with a HORRIFIC CRASH, grabbing her beer, looking up to...</context>
      <utterance>But first, a toast!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A hugely embarrassing half-second. Bailed out by...</context>
      <utterance>I'm right-handed.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All turns.</context>
      <utterance>To our host, my cuddly Papa Joe.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a look at Julianne, Kim sets down her mallet gently, and performs a nasal HUM of the tropical standard, strikingly her nostril repeatedly for vibrato. It is charming, and everybody watches.</context>
      <utterance>Who taught me to play "Blue Hawaii." On my nose.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>MANDY/SAMMY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She JUMPS a foot, both hands FLYING UP, left one awkwardly slamming back into its pocket. The girls have snuck up behind her. They have changed into hot gowns that are really only wide ribbons wrapped around their bodies.</context>
      <utterance>Boo!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sinatra singing "Stranger In The Night." Hugely-muscled, half-naked black and white studs, serving enchanted blue-haired ladies.</context>
      <utterance>I know why you're scared of our party. It's too hip.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kimberly wanted to tickle the grandmas, so we figured, give 'em a cheap thrill. Walter supplied the decorative touches...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nose tackle from the Bears... power forward from the Bulls... defenseman from the Black Hawks... my personal favorite, the designated hitter...</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... I'm partial to the tight end.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now they stare at her. With identical, really odd, smiles.</context>
      <utterance>This is USDA Prime, largely available, beef. With no notice- able competition, present company excepted...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And yet here you are. All celibate and reclusive.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh.</context>
      <utterance>With those big, dark, haunted eyes. As if you were harborin' some... unspeakably... guilty... secret.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Something. Their expressions are deliciously, identically expectant.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm worried about something.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some...</context>
      <utterance>Oh. I left this really important file in Walter's office. I have to send my editor some...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uh-huh...</context>
      <utterance>... figures. On territorial sales. To close my book deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So Kim gave me the key. And Michael's on his way, to drive me down to Wal...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julianne blinks. Ring...?</context>
      <utterance>Oh. We thought it was the ring.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ah. That ring.</context>
      <utterance>The one you better get the fuck off your third finger left hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>reflex to see if it would...</context>
      <utterance>Well. See. That was a...</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... look good on Kimberly.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. And then it didn't want to come off. Exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's happy there.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh the way out of the crab house? We asked Michael if we could see the ring?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said you told him. It'd be safer with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julianne for once is speechless. To our amazement, the girls wear identical smiles of kindness and support.</context>
      <utterance>An so it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Let's get to work.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up, sugar, he's on his way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JANITOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sammy is rummaging through her handbag, pulling out...</context>
      <utterance>It's mental, lady, you ain't trying!</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... a tube of jelly. The letter K-Y. Julianne just gives her a look. Mandy pushes through with a butcher's CLEAVER...</context>
      <utterance>There is nothing so tight, this can't help it...</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The look has turned toward her.</context>
      <utterance>I saw this on Hard Copy. People cut off body parts and the hospital sew 'em back o...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw the show.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... well, maybe it works on fingers, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOWER GIRL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Everybody turns. The little girl in the doorway. Southern accent...</context>
      <utterance>Aunt Mandy...?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOWER GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everything gets real quiet. Mandy takes charge. She rolls down Julianne's left sleeve, RIPS the hem out of the cuff, so that it flaps down over her hand, covering the ring. Sammy wipes the black stuff from Julianne's fingers.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Michael's here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The twins lead her off. We're on their backs for...</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, baby. You could pick your nose with that finger and Michael would never notice. He's a man.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Personally, I think Mr. Michael's marrying the wrong girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMMY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're much more his type.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PULL BACK farther to see Michael still trying keys from a large key ring in the heavy lock. Sign over the door says WALLACE ENTERPRISES. Traffic hustles by, oblivious to her suffering.</context>
      <utterance>I can't believe this!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's no big deal, she just gave you the wrong keys that's s...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A good question. She needs a good answer.</context>
      <utterance>What is the big deal about getting this file tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From his face, that wasn't it.</context>
      <utterance>I promised Digger I'd E-mail him those figures.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Apparently. He's just staring at her.</context>
      <utterance>They are very important figures.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm up against a deadline.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me, too. I'm getting married tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now. He really doesn't get it.</context>
      <utterance>That's my point!!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>So?</context>
      <utterance>I mean, tomorrow... we'll all be busy with more important things. So...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sighs.</context>
      <utterance>... tonight's my last chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I forgot how cute you look. When you get impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helpless.</context>
      <utterance>It's just... up there... right in front of Walter's... y'know, computer. If memory serves.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>just E-mail those suckers right ou...</context>
      <utterance>We could use... his computer, to...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes fill with tears. He is mystified. Smiles tenderly.</context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow is Sunday. Nobody's doing business. Crack of dawn, Monday, Walter'll take you up there...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Touches her hair.</context>
      <utterance>Give it up, kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And slowly, he takes her hand. Leads her way. She takes one backward glance at the locked door. Her last dream dies.</context>
      <utterance>You can't win 'em all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="57">
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen up, huh? Even if you blow this deal, how big could it be?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's really concerned, can't bear to see her so upset.</context>
      <utterance>You're right. Easy come, easy go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She won't look at him. She wants to die. The bell RINGS, the doors open to her floor. She just walks out. And he follows. They stand now, she with her arms crossed, lip trembling. She can't believe how close she is to losing it.</context>
      <utterance>Jules?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This thing means that much to y...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods. Okay.</context>
      <utterance>It means a lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her mouth drops. She can't believe this.</context>
      <utterance>I'll call the house, Walter's probably not even asleep...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She THROWS her arms around his, HUGGING him so hard, so close. He laughs, she is so weird. She pulls back, beaming, glowing.</context>
      <utterance>I'll drive you out there, we'll get the key, we'll go back to the office...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She claps his hand. As they head down the hall...</context>
      <utterance>Come on, we'll call from your room.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's trying to flip through the message slips in his free hand...</context>
      <utterance>If I fall asleep on the altar tomorrow...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's at her door, turning the key. He looks at the envelope.</context>
      <utterance>... you better be there to... funny, these are all from Ben.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The fax is from Ben, too. Man, it's my wedding, and my boss can't leave me alone...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He follows her in, opening the envelope. Stops. Reads. And his face suddenly... freezes. To stone.</context>
      <utterance>... maybe it's congratulations.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Michael? What ha...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he looks up to her.</context>
      <utterance>Mike. I can't believe I'm doing this to you on the night before your wedding. But I think you need and deserve to know...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands it toward her. She takes it, hesitantly, and he walks past. Toward the phone.</context>
      <utterance>... what you're marrying into.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes BUG OUT of her head. Holy shit! We can hear him DIALING the phone. She keeps reading, it's all there. How did this happen?</context>
      <utterance>I received the following E-mail this afternoon... "Ben, I need a favor. My daughter's every happiness... "</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isabelle? I need to talk to Kim...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Mike, the funny thing is, he's offering you a gig you'd be stupid to turn down..."</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just tired. Please put her on? Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Maybe you should take the job. And dump the girl." And when she turns...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks more sick than angry. As if the heart has just been cut out of him. She doesn't know what to say or do, so she just stands, staring dumbly.</context>
      <utterance>Jules. Could you give me a minute?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods, stumbles out of her room, closing the door behind her. Now she's in the empty corridor, clutching her big jumbled bag, sinking down to sit on the carpet, her back against the door. She doesn't look elated. She seems frightened, distraught, and most of all, confused. Because she can't understand why. She digs absently through her bag. Cigarettes. Box of matches. She lights up. Draws deeply. Somehow, she seems near tears, and laughs bitterly at that. Shakes her head at how fucked-up she finds herself. Squeaking wheels approach, but she is too lost to hear them.</context>
      <utterance>Please?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks up. A small, wiry man of nearly 60, in a slightly faded but neatly-kept uniform. On his cart, a ton of bags.</context>
      <utterance>Miss, are you locked out, or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And inhales deeply. Leans back against the door, to look up at him more comfortably.</context>
      <utterance>No, I just stepped out, because... it's a non-smoking room.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's non-smoking floor, too. Maybe you could go to the...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That wasn't sarcastic. He doesn't know what to say.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you have me arrested?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another puff.</context>
      <utterance>I mean that. Arrested, convicted, put in solitary.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Waves her hand.</context>
      <utterance>See, I'm a dangerous, criminal person. I do bad things to honest people. This, see, this smoking? Tip of the iceberg.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now she seems angry. But not at him. Her eyes fill with tears.</context>
      <utterance>Make a citizen's arrest, I won't struggle. It'll be like getting Al Capone on tax evasion.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She squints at his nameplate.</context>
      <utterance>Can I... Can I help you, miss?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you smoke, Richard?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, ma'am, I do, but it's...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she takes the cigarette from her lips. Turns it around, holds it out to him. Go ahead. He doesn't move. Please! And so... ... he reaches down, takes the cigarette from her hand. Staring in her eyes, he takes a deep drag. Savors an expert nostril-inhale of his exhaled smoke. Hands the cigarette back to her...</context>
      <utterance>... a non-smoking floor, yeah. Well, you know what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She swallows. Wipes at her eyes. Finds a smile.</context>
      <utterance>My grandmother always said, "This, too, shall pass."</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He just nods. She waves. He waves back, pushes his cart down the hall. As she watches him go, the door behind her suddenly OPENS, and she... ... FALLS through it, flat on her back at Michael's feet. Staring up at him, seeing that he looks as bad as she feels, she takes raw, deep drag.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Richard. If you weren't on duty, I'd buy you a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And crouches down. Close beside her. The cigarette drops from her hand, unnoticed on the carpet. So he lifts it, crushes it on the heel of his shoe.</context>
      <utterance>It's over.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She just nods, obediently. Okay, I will.</context>
      <utterance>I want you to quit this shit, it'll kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She denied it. Said I was crazy and paranoid.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tries to smile. It's really hard.</context>
      <utterance>A bad combination.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lets the air out. Slow. So he won't cry.</context>
      <utterance>There's this big brunch tomorrow morning? At her place.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She said "How can I call everything off, what do I tell everybody?" Shakes his head. Can you imagine that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Michael...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's for the best, it really is. We were so wrong for each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe tomorrow, you'll feel dif...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julianne nods. Maybe that part is right. Maybe it would have ended anyway. Maybe she can pretend she's not a monster.</context>
      <utterance>The job thing would have broken us up, eventually, anyway. She couldn't have lived with it. I know that now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looks deep in her eyes. He's so glad she's there.</context>
      <utterance>And she's right, I'm crazy to fall for someone. I hardly knew.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds up her left hand, the flapping sleeve falls away. The ring is on a finger that is swollen and raw.</context>
      <utterance>Hey. You still got that ring?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles at that. A sad smile of friendship. Then takes her finger gently... ... into his mouth. It is something like a kiss. And when he removes her moistened finger... ... he pulls the ring OFF. Nothing to it. She blinks.</context>
      <utterance>I tried it on. But it won't come off.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't understand that.</context>
      <utterance>It's mental, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should we take a walk? Or maybe some food sent up, or something...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods, sure. He kisses her cheek. Stands up.</context>
      <utterance>I just want to be alone. Is that okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods again. Whatever you say. He steps into the open doorway...</context>
      <utterance>Maybe I'll go back to New York. Hang with you for awhile, huh? Ben'll understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or we'll go somewhere. If you have the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They smiles at each other. For real.</context>
      <utterance>If San Antonio sweeps Sacramento...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Imagine that. The look holds. Just above a whisper...</context>
      <utterance>I've never been to Texas.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then he's gone.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for coming to my wedding.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes find the pack of cigarettes. Next to her toiletries kit.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, handsome. Brevity this...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her fingers touch the pack. As if an object of significance. Takes it up.</context>
      <utterance>I won.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cradling the phone against her shoulder, she carefully tears the top of the pack completely open.</context>
      <utterance>Amazing, huh? I didn't do things quite your way. But... I got it down.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reaches the pack toward the toilet.</context>
      <utterance>And forty years and nine grand- children later, when I sit with Michael on some rustic porch, slogging through our sweet swamp of nostalgic memories...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Turns it upside down, emptying a dozen cigarettes into the john.</context>
      <utterance>No one is going to sweet the details...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of one weekend in Chicago. Drops the lid with a CLATTER. Hits the FLUSH.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lifts a tube from her toiletries kit. Stares at it, real close.</context>
      <utterance>Talk about celebration...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Turns it over, reads all the writing. Yep.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna brush my teeth with actual toothpaste.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Squeezes some paste onto her brush. Carefully.</context>
      <utterance>I guess I'm too exhausted to feel the elation I so richly undeserve...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Start brushing.</context>
      <utterance>So I'm gonna hold calls at the desk... while I get my...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Squints at her image. Laughs, spewing a little foam.</context>
      <utterance>God, it is toothpaste, they should sell this stuff commercially! Anyway, a girl does need her...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She SPITS. Tells Digger's machine...</context>
      <utterance>... well, we're a bit past worrying about beauty sleep. Let's just settle for not frightening small animals.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wipes her mouth. Stares off. The eyes a little dreamy.</context>
      <utterance>Anyway, I couldn't have done it without you. Even though I did, if you follow that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Well, you know.</context>
      <utterance>Three words: Happily. Ever.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ISABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Takes her arm graciously. This woman would make Anne Bancroft look coarse. As they walk...</context>
      <utterance>Jules. We're so glad you slept in.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julianne looking all around. Magic day it seems to be. Where the bell is a bride or a groom?</context>
      <utterance>Now, you have a choice. The idea is bride and groom shouldn't see each other on the magic day...</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pointing. THERE she is, obscured by a cluster of the appropriately fawning. She has the same hunted eyes and false, slightly manic smile Julianne wore yesterday. This, at least, makes sense.</context>
      <utterance>So Michael stays put in the garden. Kimmy stays in here...</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>CLOSE on Julianne. Watching the brave, frightened bride.</context>
      <utterance>... and the guests go back and forth. Where will you start?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She looks tense.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nerves. I would never have guessed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had the craziest dream last night? Walter and Kimmy had asked your boss to...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I came down here to face everybody. I didn't want to slink away like some coward...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But the Scotch salmon was so fucking good, you decided to stay for brunch!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She hasn't told anybody, what am I supposed to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She comes OFF the swing, PUSHES him back two feet.</context>
      <utterance>Get married, apparently.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you thinking of, the goddamn wedding is SIX</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is her family and her fault.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And your point?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well. How come she didn't...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>EACH OTHER.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He just blinks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thank you. She POKES his chest, punctuating...</context>
      <utterance>Hey. This is a serious matter.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be right back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at all this beautiful food, so lovingly prepared...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kimmy's lip trembles. This is not how she thought of her wedding. The din is so horrific, Kimmy leads them into a walk-in meat locker. Even here, two BUTCHERS are dressing Eastern-fresh corn- fed carcasses.</context>
      <utterance>They'll eat it anyway, you ever been to a walk?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men blink at each other.</context>
      <utterance>You guys want to give us a minute?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On that basis. They leave. Kimmy sits on a stack of packaged frozen fowl parts. Stares up with big, sweet, wet eyes.</context>
      <utterance>We'd like to be alone with our pork.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julianne cannot believe this.</context>
      <utterance>How's he doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who? The jerk who's running your life?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This must be... very, very, hard on him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leans in. Listen...</context>
      <utterance>What with the psychosis and all, yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When are you gonna come clean with your folks?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you see...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're waiting for "Do you take this man?", that's considered poor form.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stops Julianne cold. Your fault.</context>
      <utterance>... that this is all my fault?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harder and harder for Julianne to push. Her mouth is dry.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever delusions I drove him to, there is truth at the heart of it. I want him to work for my father. I want to stay in school. I want a life of my own!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, lots of couples are imcompat...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fragile and strong at once. A plea.</context>
      <utterance>I love him.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long beat.</context>
      <utterance>Tell him it's my fault and that I love him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be right back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I asked you...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He absorbs that. And then...</context>
      <utterance>She admits it's her fault.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We watch the struggle inside her. Her voice drops...</context>
      <utterance>Do you think she still loves me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now tears stand in both their eyes. The stoners are doing their Alvin and the Chipmuks impersonation festival in the B.G., singing in castrato harmony. But our two don't notice.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, she does. She's crazy about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Which is...</context>
      <utterance>I keep asking, how can I explain what happened? And I keep getting that same answer all night long.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julianne swallows. For obvious reasons.</context>
      <utterance>I can't. And it doesn't matter. I drove her to it, because I want things my way. And even if she did something tricky and unfair... she was blinded by love, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does that make it right...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The stoner are now helium-crooning "Bridge Over Troubled Waters." Actually, they're getting better.</context>
      <utterance>Love doesn't have to be right. It just has to be love.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's giving up half her life for me, and I'm bitching because it hurts her.</utterance>
   <speaker>STONERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sail on silver girl Sail on by...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's a saint! And I'm a worthless ingrate!</utterance>
   <speaker>STONERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your time has come to shine, All your dreams are on their way...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The stoners blend on the high note. It's pretty moving.</context>
      <utterance>Tell her. I'll marry her at six o'clock, if she'll still have me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be right back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julianne's eyes move over the young girl's face.</context>
      <utterance>So. What did he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kimmy YELPS in her ecstasy, FLINGING herself against Julianne, and they go DOWN full length across the organ's pedals, BLASTING the room with a MONSTER CHORD of china-rattling volume and horrifying disharmony. As grown men and women SCREAM in spontaneous terror below, Kimmy begins to... ... LAUGH. And KISS and hug her new sister. And holds her tight.</context>
      <utterance>He said. Marry me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank God you were here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was so confused, so conflicted, so... unstable.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They pass an expanse of lawn which has become the event parking area. Family vehicles, delivery trucks, service vans. Everything that couldn't fit on the circular front driveway.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it happens.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Searching for the right words.</context>
      <utterance>I might have thrown away...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... your one chance for true happiness?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... yeah, that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a vague Stepford Wife quality to her voice. He hears that now, and looks at her. Maybe he can't tell she's frightened. But he can tell she's something.</context>
      <utterance>You never want to do that, see, that's always a... costly turnover. As they say in the sport biz.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops walking. She can't look at him, so she looks around. Across the lawn crews are moving equipment into the brightly- colored tents, unfolding and setting up stacks of tables and chairs, raising the poles between which all those balloons will be strung. At the center of it all... .... a huge topiary White Sox batter, just completing a murderous swing. He's maybe fifteen feet tall. She points to it...</context>
      <utterance>Are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Big Hurt, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>So Julianne nods. Because she does too. Squints up at Michael.</context>
      <utterance>Nellie Fox. Walter likes the past. And he likes the little guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods, you bet. Worried for her. What is this? She looks in another direction, and we now see that we have nearly reached... ... a stage that's been set up for the band. Chairs, music stands, sound equipment. A gleaming dance floor, already in place over the lawn. Next to it, a shimmering white GAZEBO. Like the centerpiece of a wedding cake.</context>
      <utterance>Got a minute?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes his hand. They walk toward it.</context>
      <utterance>Why is the dance floor by the gazebo?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looking down at her.</context>
      <utterance>Kimmy's idea. She thought it would be such a romantic place. For our wedding dance.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's up?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Up the white steps now. Together. The gazebo floor has been covered with hardwood. The perfect place. For a wedding dance. And Julianne... ... turns, suddenly. He almost runs into her. She is staring up at him, so strangely, their bodies only inches apart. He is caught, transfixed by the intensity in her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Shhh.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The coronary part does. We can feel her heart beating from here.</context>
      <utterance>I have to say this quick, okay, or I'll have this massive coronary and you'll never have to hear it. Which you need to. Does that make any sense at all?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jules, what's wrong...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then, she does. She puts her hands flat on his chest. Looks in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>This is the dumbest thing I will ever do. So dumb, in fact, that I can't. I don't think.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A heartbeat passes.</context>
      <utterance>Michael, I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares at her, dumbstruck. She moves even closer.</context>
      <utterance>I've loved you for nine years, but I was too arrogant and scared to realize it. Now I'm just scared.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holds her breath. And...</context>
      <utterance>I know this comes at an inopportune time, but I have to ask this one really gigantic favor, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Choose me. Marry me. Let me make you happy. And in a half beat of excruciating silence...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes are loving. They care for her. She swallows, lost in them.</context>
      <utterance>I know. It sounds like three favors.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slides her arms around his neck, and raises her mouth... ... to his. The most beautiful kiss she will ever offer. All of her heart is in this, and as his hands touch her body... ... a SCREAM rips the world to pieces. They whirl to see... ... KIMMY, halfway up the path. Her hands across her mouth, as if to stem the horror that pours forth as she SHRIEKS from her soul, and... ... runs. Back Down the path. Michael BOLTING after her, SHOUTING her name. A frozen moment, and... ... Julianne TAKES OFF after him. All three running, SCREAMING their various emotions at the top of their lungs, as workmen stop to watch from neighboring countries. Kimmy, staring from halfway there, has an insurmountable lead. LEAPS into her convertible and PEELS OUT, just TEARING up the gravel as she ROCKETS out of sight. No way to catch her. Still... ... Michael is racing for the cars. Julianne, sprinting her guts out, losing ground with every stride. Michael JUMPS into a Cherokee...</context>
      <utterance>But when you think about it...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>YOUNGER FIELD MAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She TEARS the door open. SCRAMBLE OUT...</context>
      <utterance>Uh, this is One Monkey Zebra. It wasn't bees in the gal's wall, it was cats!</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNGER FIELD MAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>WITH Julianne now, RACING through the lot, Michael vanishes INTO the Station, she PLUNGES in after him, BOUNCING off bystanders, apologizing, lunging on, gasping for breath, past exhaustion, threatening clumsily through the crowd like a staggering drunk, catching a lucky glimpse as he heads... ... DOWN a staircase to the TRACKS. My God, what's he doing? A second wind, fueled by panic, and she BOLTS after him, DANCING down the steep staircase somehow without killing herself, reaching the concourse to see him, running for... ... Track 29, a train already RUMBLING, ready to pull out, she SPRINTS after him.</context>
      <utterance>She says gas 'em, anyway, she'll pay cash. Uh... how do I pay this?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He just blinks at this sweaty, ripped-up, maniacal figure.</context>
      <utterance>Don't speak!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh. I saw that moving...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This. He's waiting to hear.</context>
      <utterance>I have to make a confession. Another confession. Besides that I love you. This is even worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You. WHAT?! Synapse overload.</context>
      <utterance>The E-mail? You thought Walter sent your boss? I wrote that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>you're saying that y...</context>
      <utterance>You're not saying you actually...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... wrote it, yeah. I'm the bad guy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="48">
   <speaker>ARE YOU ON DRUGS???</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shakes her head, like a two-year-old.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>how could you do that?</context>
      <utterance>I mean, do you realize what you've... well, of course you realize, that's why you're confessing, I mean... I mean...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And watching. As this begins to sink in.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't know it would get sent. I just wanted you to... get mad at Kimmy... and...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Staring in his eyes. Eyes she can't read at this point.</context>
      <utterance>I've done nothing but slimy, underhanded, despicable, not even terribly imaginative, things. Ever since I got here. Trying to...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tears in her own eyes now. Big ones.</context>
      <utterance>... to win you. To win you back.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shaking her head...</context>
      <utterance>And I was blinded by love. Like you said.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No...</context>
      <utterance>But that doesn't excuse any part of it. I am pond scum.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually. Lower. I am the fungus that feeds on pond scum. Lower. The layer of mucous that cruds up the fung...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lower.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lower.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The pus that infects the mucous that cruds up the fungus. And to her amazement. The trace of a smile...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She blinks at that. Which squeezes out a tear.</context>
      <utterance>On the other hand, thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shrugs. Just above a whisper...</context>
      <utterance>For loving me that much, that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's pretty flattering.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Except it makes me fungus.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's never loved him more.</context>
      <utterance>Well, that part I knew.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Okay?</context>
      <utterance>So you have to marry Kim. Because she will actually make you happy. I, in contrast, am a shallow, neurotic psychopath, with relatively little to offer.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods his head, still smiling. Her tears are running now. Maybe she doesn't notice.</context>
      <utterance>Kim. Nod your head. Do as you're told.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She chokes back a sob.</context>
      <utterance>Just promise you'll never tell me who you would have chosen. If I hadn't confessed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods, slowly. Because he's supposed to.</context>
      <utterance>Cos if you would have chosen me. Then I threw away a perfectly good life. Just to be a decent person. Which is a questionable trade-off. Right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ah. His smile keeps getting smaller. More loving. More wonderful.</context>
      <utterance>And if you would have chosen some 20-year-old punk over me. I'd have to kill myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Good. She looks around.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take it to my grave.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so glad you didn't jump on that train, before...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For her. The words leave a silence.</context>
      <utterance>I came here, looking for her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would she come here...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stares deep in her eyes. She needs to hear this.</context>
      <utterance>This is where I proposed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grins. Has to admit...</context>
      <utterance>I had to cover a game in Milwaukee. She saw me off. And when the train started to leave... I jumped up on the step, I help the handle, and without...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I did. Now her eyes tear up again. And she doesn't know why.</context>
      <utterance>... without a thought in my head. I shouted, "Marry me."</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What a girl.</context>
      <utterance>And she gasped, and covered her mouth, and the train was pulling out, and suddenly she screamed YES! Just once. And blew me a kiss.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never forgot that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's two weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Almost three.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Which makes him reach and touch her hair.</context>
      <utterance>That is so romantic.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Do you?</context>
      <utterance>I just wonder if you know why.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tears in his eyes now. First time.</context>
      <utterance>It's because romance isn't mystery, and tricks, and doubts, and halting, unspoken longings. That's not the real romance.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Does she know that now? He looks at his watch.</context>
      <utterance>The real romance is saying yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh. That.</context>
      <utterance>Woulda been a nice wedding.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't believe you've lost her! Sooner or later, you'll find her, and you'll look in each other's eyes, and you'll see all that love...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Course, if it's later rather than sooner, I'd hate to be you at six o'clock.  You've got a lot of explaining to...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just thinking of how she's hurting. Lost. Alone. Like her life is over.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glares at her.</context>
      <utterance>That's little egotistical.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She claps her hands, galvanized by the emergency.</context>
      <utterance>But, undoubtedly accurate.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, we'll split up. You go to every romantic place you guys have, I'll go... someplace brilliant, and the first one who...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Strange tone. A gentle warning.</context>
      <utterance>If you find her...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The kiss. May be hard. For you to explain.  Because the only fear she really has, is...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looks at her own watch. Shit!</context>
      <utterance>... me, yeah. And she likes Tommy Lasorda. Case closed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks up.</context>
      <utterance>But if you do get to her first...</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is something you are authorized to say.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MANDY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wallace egregious residence, Mandy speaking.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Jules, you guys haven't had a call from, say, Kimberly, have you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A shallow laugh...</context>
      <utterance>Oh, she's slipped out, the little monkey. Prob'ly with Michael, doin' the nasty.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Julianne's face SNAPS to alert.</context>
      <utterance>Or crying in her nachos, down at Comskey Park.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ex-cuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had this crank call? From some guy who thinks he saw her? I said, what would a bride be doin', on her wedding...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Signals the driver, let's GO!</context>
      <utterance>You are so right. What a nerve on that guy! Bring my dress to church, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to pick up a little something for the ceremony.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BODYGUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sighs. Feels terrible about all this.</context>
      <utterance>She wouldn't confide in me, so I called the house.</utterance>
   <speaker>BODYGUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julianne nods. Yeah, big break, there.</context>
      <utterance>Luckily, I got her cousin.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Going to the john, she said?</utterance>
   <speaker>BODYGUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could be there awhile.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now everybody's really interested. Julianne ignores them, strides to the stall. KNOCKS, like it's a door. No answer.</context>
      <utterance>In here, you bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me in, baby, or I'll rip this damn thing off its non- code-compliant hinges...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh. Scattered laughter. Julianne moves down the line. Stares at the door. We hear the soft, muted crying from within. Slowly, Julianne... ... drops to her knees. Bends her head low. PEERS under the door. What she sees, prompts a sad warning...</context>
      <utterance>Over here, nitwit!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she crawls UNDER the door, on her belly. We go WITH her to see... ... Kim fully dressed, perched on the closed toilet lid, her knees drawn up, her arms around them.</context>
      <utterance>Incoming.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And pulls herself up to her knees. Kimmy tries to glare, but it just isn't in her.</context>
      <utterance>Pitiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The world gets real quiet. An entire bathroom is listening. Julianne cocks her head to one side.</context>
      <utterance>Haven't you done enough?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In one minute. You are going to feel so foolish.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Irony? Kimmy sniffles.</context>
      <utterance>Have you ever heard of. Irony?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And leans close. As Kimmy flinches.</context>
      <utterance>I threw my arms around your husband. And kissed him with all my heart. Because I was so happy. For you. Nitwit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A stunned pole-axed moment. And Kimmy's eyes SPRING open. You mean...?</context>
      <utterance>He's going to take...  The job!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everything inside Kimmy BURSTS free in a torrent of tears...</context>
      <utterance>With your dad, yeah. Can you guess why? Bitch?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kisses the top of Kimmy's head.</context>
      <utterance>Well, of course, he loves you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kimmy holds her tight. From her heart...</context>
      <utterance>Hell, even I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never want to go through this again.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLES... outside the stall. Julianne's feet sticking out under the door.</context>
      <utterance>That's entirely understandable.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The two BURST out of the stall, hand-in-hand, at a desperate DEAD RUN past us. HEAR them EXPLODE out the door, and... ... five stalls OPEN. Women exit, crying.</context>
      <utterance>Shit! THE TIME!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SAMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever hap...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kim WAVES at her mom by the chapel entrance. And takes Julianne's hand for support.</context>
      <utterance>We were bonding, we lost track, we're officially sorry, now let's put it behind us.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everybody nods.</context>
      <utterance>Believe me, we got a bride who's worth waiting for, yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out of our way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don't worry.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, sugar.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The words stronger. Because there is no smile.</context>
      <utterance>When he looks at you, it will be as if...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE on the bride's perfect slippers. HOLD. And...</context>
      <utterance>... he's never seen a woman before. PAN DOWN the white until we are...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>REVERSE ANGLE... Kim's POV, the chapel, every pew packed, every neck craning this way, the white satin carpet down the endless aisle to where... Michael waits. Also in a zone of pseudo-consciousness. From which he attempts a smile. Not comforting. Kim's POV WHIP PAN the groomsmen, the twins, LOCKING FOCUS on Julianne, standing strong and beautiful, a glow of her own in the daffodil dress. She sends her little sister a WINK across the trackless miles of aisle. You can do this, kid. So... ... Kimmy does. On her father's arm, she walks the gauntlet of the world's intrusive admiration. One step at a time. The most beautiful she will ever be. She is dazzling the crowd and managing to not throw up at the same time. And she's there. At his side. She glances back to her maid of honor, just to make sure she's not working without a net. So Julianne... ... CROSSES her eyes. Which lets the kid smile and finally take a breath. Have a little fun, huh? Kim nods, got it, turns to... The Minister. Who stands before them with a calming presence. Thank God someone has done this before. The crowd has hushed. The Minister's eyes are only for two. His words are for all...</context>
      <utterance>Left foot.</utterance>
   <speaker>MINISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A ripple of laughter. Gentle and fine. They are setting in.</context>
      <utterance>Michael and Kimmy wrote these words. She asked me to confide, mostly Michael.</utterance>
   <speaker>MINISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A surprise. A pleasant one. The crowd adjust in its seats. As Michael begins...</context>
      <utterance>So he gets to say them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And on these words. We SNAP to Julianne. Share her interest in the bluntness, the simplicity, the unorthodoxy of this beginning.</context>
      <utterance>Why do people get married anymore?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Her eyes. She's listening.</context>
      <utterance>Why not live together amicably, with no sense of obligation beyond the moment?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>PANNING now. Other faces. Isabelle. Proud to the bone.</context>
      <utterance>As long as the sex is good. As long as no one more interesting has wandered into view. As long as the thousand conflicts of two individual wills remain comfortably compromised.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Walter. His eyes damp. Against our expectation.</context>
      <utterance>And when one feels the urge to move on, to explore the new. No guilt, no disgrace, no promise broken.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Joe nods, as he hears...</context>
      <utterance>No agony of having dishonored a time. When our hearts. And the world were different.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Julianne once more. No breath. Rapt.</context>
      <utterance>Marriage is a lot to put up with.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Her eyes have clouded. As if Michael is talking to her.</context>
      <utterance>The answer must be. That there is some need basic to the human heart. That embracing... the obligation of commitment... fulfills.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>And suddenly, ALL the feeling rises in her throat.</context>
      <utterance>Some need to belong to one another in a way which rages against the notion... that all is impermanent. Against the notion of mortality.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>And the tears come. They come freely, unhidden, unnoticed. As if they were needed. Michael now. Looking at his bride.</context>
      <utterance>Our love is bigger. And longer. Than life itself.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kimmy smiles at him. With love bigger than life itself.</context>
      <utterance>That's what we want. And marriage. Is what we do about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is done. There is a silence.</context>
      <utterance>We are fools in this. Thank God Almighty.</utterance>
   <speaker>MINISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>People LAUGH. The Minister holds up a sheet of paper. For the crowd to see. Mostly paragraphs crossed out in red ink.</context>
      <utterance>Boy, that was good!</utterance>
   <speaker>MINISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More laughter.</context>
      <utterance>Michael and Kim also edited what they want me to say...</utterance>
   <speaker>MINISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bigger LAUGHTER. The Minister waves this off, his little joke. Turns to the best man, pantomimes the ring. As the hammered gold circle is handed to Michael, Julianne absently scratches her still- swollen finger. Mandy taps Julianne on the arm, and produces... ... a matching ring. Take it! Gives it to her. So Julianne steps forward. Places the second ring into Kimmy's waiting hand. Their eyes meet, and hold throughout...</context>
      <utterance>The idea was, we're only marrying once. We have to remember it forever. Let's keep to the good stuff.  You may kiss the bride.</utterance>
   <speaker>MINISTER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Julianne CLEARS her throat. Kimmy's heart flutters. In the silence... Julianne's wonderful smile. Just kidding. Michael reaches for Kim's hand, turns her gently to him. Places his ring on her finger. Holds her hands.</context>
      <utterance>If anyone here can show just cause why this man and woman should not be married, speak now. Or forever hold your peace.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She swallows. Smiles a fleeting, beautiful smile. Fumbles slightly, putting the ring on his finger.</context>
      <utterance>Kimberly. I promise to love. And respect and comfort you. To hear your voice and your heart. Until we are parted by death.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Staring in each other's eyes. A moment so fragile, the Minister waits an extra beat.</context>
      <utterance>Michael. I promise to love and respect and comfort you. To hear your voice and your heart. Until we are parted by death.</utterance>
   <speaker>MINISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For the record, you each agree to marry the other?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Minister joins their right hands.</context>
      <utterance>I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MINISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE now on Julianne. For the inevitable moment.</context>
      <utterance>We haven't said much about God this evening, I know. But He is here. And He is happy. To bless His wonderful children.</utterance>
   <speaker>MINISTER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Unnoticed by the world. Her eyes are close.</context>
      <utterance>In that Michael and Kimberly have given themselves to each other by solemn vows, and the exchanging of rings...</utterance>
   <speaker>MINISTER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The eyes open. Wet, brave, ready for...</context>
      <utterance>I pronounce them husband and wife. Those whom God has joined together, let no one put asunder.</utterance>
   <speaker>MINISTER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Julianne watching. As Michael does.</context>
      <utterance>Now. Kiss the bride.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She raises her glass. Everyone at the table does the same.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a writer, too, not as good as Michael. But I do steal from quality.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shouts of support, a few whistles. Silence. She tells Michael...</context>
      <utterance>This is to my best friend. On the occasion of his wedding.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She has to stop. Swallows. Because she will not let herself cry.</context>
      <utterance>If I have truly come to know your bride as my new sister. This is in her heart...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Understand. I'll slip quietly away from the noisy crowd when I see the pale stars rising, blooming, over the oaks." Deep breath. Looks in his eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A hush. SHARP applause. From four hundred hands. But not from his. He is too moved. Too understanding of what he has heard.</context>
      <utterance>"I'll pursue solitary pathways through the pale twilit meadows, with only this one dream: You come too."</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that the band begins. The opening phrases of a song we have come to know. Michael seems overwhelmed. Julianne nods toward the gazebo... ... Michael takes his bride's hand, leads her up the stairs, into his arms, as the twins step to the microphone, and guests begin to applaud an unscheduled wedding dance...</context>
      <utterance>I don't have a wedding gift. But this is on loan. Until you two find your song...</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDY/SAMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Soft two-part harmony. As perfect as the words.</context>
      <utterance>Someday, when I'm awfully low, And the world is cold, I will feel a glow just thinking of you, And the way you look tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANDY/SAMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julianne can cry now. Because she's tied with half the place.</context>
      <utterance>You're lovely. With your smile so warm, And your cheeks so soft, There is nothing for me but to love you, Just the way you look tonight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deep, deep breath.</context>
      <utterance>Wherever I go. However far... She sobs. Holds him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And to her surprise...</context>
      <utterance>You win a few, you lose a few. Some get rained out.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>To her greater surprise. There are a few tears left, after all.</context>
      <utterance>You have a good time?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did what I came to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She just can't speak now. So she doesn't.</context>
      <utterance>Good girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>This fucking guy. God, she loves him.</context>
      <utterance>I was thinking. Maybe you might visit us for awhile. We've got the room made up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll think about it. I'm okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Just above a whisper...</context>
      <utterance>Oh, you're more than okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with the last of her strength...</context>
      <utterance>You, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A chuckle. At the other end.</context>
      <utterance>If the sun comes up, I'll see you tomorrow, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We hear the CLICK. She turns her back on the stars. Shoulders straight. Chin up. She walks from frame.</context>
      <utterance>I'll play those odds. You have sweet dreams.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
