<movie id="405" title="My Week with Marilyn">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>1 EXT. TILBURY DOCKS. DAY. 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>"This is a fairy story, an episode out of time and space, which nevertheless was real" - Colin Clark. Then, FADE UP ON: Newsreel footage of SIR LAURENCE OLIVIER AND VIVIEN LEIGH arriving back at Tilbury Docks to be greeted by an excited crowd of fans. As they progress down the gangplank and stop to sign autographs we HEAR an excited commentary OVER:</context>
      <utterance>Over a DARK SCREEN we see the caption:</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMENTATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As OLIVIER and VIVIEN smile for the photographers, we -</context>
      <utterance>"Returning to England are Britain's acting royalty Sir Laurence Olivier and Lady Olivier, better known as stunning Gone With The Wind star Vivien Leigh. Sir Laurence has added a new string to his bow with the announcement that he is to direct and star in a screen version of Terence Rattigan's stage play The Sleeping Prince with none other than Hollywood siren Marilyn Monroe. When the world's greatest actor romances the most famous woman alive, we can be sure that sparks will fly. Now, now Lady Olivier, don't worry - any romance is strictly for the camera!"</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KENNETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN pauses briefly and hurries towards them. Throughout the scene there is a sense of his urgency and desire to go. The whole thing should be played at breakneck pace. KENNETH beams affectionately.</context>
      <utterance>... and this is one of Carracci's earlier works and one is able to see the emergence of his now famous Baroque style, which is clearly rooted in the tradition of high renaissance and antiquity...</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has the avuncular air of a benign academic, affable and a little eccentric. COLIN smiles hurriedly at the students, no time to waste.</context>
      <utterance>Colin! Come in. Have you met James and Anna? Two very brilliant pupils.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm leaving for London now, Pa.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts a friendly arm around COLIN's shoulder and starts to walk him back to the door.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, yes. Well, bon chance, dear boy...</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN's smiles but before he can reply JANE CLARK whirls into the room, a ball of energy, talking nineteen to the dozen.</context>
      <utterance>I can always get you a research position at the V&amp;A when you've grown up a bit and got this film idea out of your system...</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kenneth, you might have told Cook we were another two for dinner. What is everyone supposed to eat? Cabbage soup? Oh, Colin, darling, there you are...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm off now, Mama.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Off?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But she is already continuing her journey. COLIN smiles hurriedly at KENNETH, who gives him an affectionate wave as COLIN dashes after his mother. She leaves the Library.</context>
      <utterance>My job interview, remember..?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't you stay for dinner? There's nothing to eat but I'm sure the conversation will be charming.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As COLIN hurries after JANE he is nearly run down by an elderly GARDENER with a lawn mower, and has to take lightning evasive action. JANE doesn't notice.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to be late in the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I know your father's put in a word.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sure they won't mind. You'll be a famous film director in no time.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops so abruptly he nearly slams into her. JANE looks around the garden with a frown.</context>
      <utterance>I wish he hadn't done that. I can manage on my own.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she's off again, with COLIN still following. He can't help smiling at the madness of it all.</context>
      <utterance>I have to watch Jenkins like a hawk. One more of his murderous prunings and we'll lose the tea roses for ever.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN wants to protest but before he can get the words out JANE sees a YOUNG GARDENER walking at the side of the house with a wheel barrow. Her face lights up.</context>
      <utterance>Now go and have a lovely time, darling. We're always here when you're ready to talk your future.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She dashes away after the GARDENER, turning back as an afterthought to blow a kiss at COLIN as she goes. COLIN smiles, then pauses for a moment to look at the house. We can sense both his affection for it but more pressingly his need to get away. He gets in, puts the car in gear and the Bristol pulls out of the drive and across the moat. In the last rays of the sun, the countryside looks magical, but Colin only has eyes for the road ahead.</context>
      <utterance>Mullins! Be an angel - find Cook and ask her how many pork chops we need for tonight. Then bring the car round. I must get to the village before the shop shuts...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not in Mr. Perceval's diary.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pauses dubiously, then reaches for her telephone. We hear a man answer in an office down the hall, his voice carrying irritably.</context>
      <utterance>Larry told me to come.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stresses the proper name in disapproval of Colin's familiarity.</context>
      <utterance>I have a Mr. Colin Clark here. He says Sir Laurence sent him.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context>VANESSA looks at COLIN with amusement. His smile falters as he feels himself coming down to earth with a bump.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, God... not another one of Vivien's pretty boys.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A job on your Marilyn Monroe film.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh really, what as?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles with as much charm as he can muster. PERCEVAL isn't impressed.</context>
      <utterance>I want to work on the production side.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are no jobs yet. We don't start shooting for eight weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I wait?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Until there's a job.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For eight weeks?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PERCEVAL is distracted as the telephone rings.</context>
      <utterance>Something might come up.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Terry? Larry wondered how the script was coming...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are no jobs.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just in case.</context>
      <utterance>I'll come back tomorrow morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sounds as though he rather regrets it.</context>
      <utterance>It's a free country.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you going to sit there all day?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I have to.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're very determined.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd do anything to be in the film business.</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She winks. COLIN grins. The phone rings. He picks it up.</context>
      <utterance>You can answer the telephone while I'm at lunch, if you like.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laurence Olivier Productions...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vanessa asked me to...</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, did she? Why didn't you put that call through?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PERCEVAL looks at him grudgingly.</context>
      <utterance>There didn't seem any need to bother you. But if you want me to transfer every single one...</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hesitates and looks back.</context>
      <utterance>Use your judgement.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>COLIN realises this is a test. He thinks quickly.</context>
      <utterance>I need a number for Noel Coward. It won't be in the book, so you'll have to track him down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode>ON PHONE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Mama.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Colin, darling! How are you getting on?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode>ON PHONE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is urgent. I need Noel Coward's London number. My life depends on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How exciting. Let me see... it's Sloane 2965. Ask him if he's coming to Saltwood for the bank holiday.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will. Mama, you're an angel.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was quick.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PERCEVAL looks at him shrewdly.</context>
      <utterance>I had a bit of luck.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I supposed to be impressed? Did Mummy and Daddy help? Don't think they can do the job for you. The only way you'll get on in this business is through bloody hard work.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs, but then notices VIVIEN's less than enthusiastic response. Seeking refuge in some distraction he notices COLIN hovering by the sofa.</context>
      <utterance>Do you know, Hughie, it is simply impossible to get Marilyn Monroe on the telephone? The darling girl spends the entire day asleep. But great beauty has its way...</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He smiles vaguely and glances at VIVIEN for help.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, boy... remind me?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You remember Colin, darling. You met him at the Clarks' party.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>NO IDEA</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course. What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OLIVIER has no recollection of this and fumbles in his pockets to cover his confusion, bringing out a packet of cigarettes and offering them to COLIN with breezy charm.</context>
      <utterance>You said there might be a job on your film.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns quickly to PERCEVAL.</context>
      <utterance>Have a cigarette. Keep the pack.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There won't be any film unless Miss Monroe gets her splendid posterior out of bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The House Committee are threatening to withhold Miller's passport. They say he's a communist. No Arthur, no Marilyn.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts an arm around PERCEVAL's shoulders and they disappear together into Perceval's office. VIVIEN lingers behind, smiling radiantly at COLIN who looks dumbly at the packet of cigarettes in his hand. He now sees they are called "Oliviers". VIVIEN wrinkles her nose in amusement.</context>
      <utterance>I'll have a word with the American ambassador. I'm taking him to see Vivien in South Sea Bubble on Thursday... now, tell me, Hughie, are Terry's rewrites in?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She cups Colin's cheeks with her hands and studies him in mock awe.</context>
      <utterance>They named them after Larry. The first actor since Du Maurier to have his own brand and they pay him an absolute fortune.  I'm afraid they're rather ghastly.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't he gorgeous, Vanessa?</utterance>
   <speaker>VANESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VIVIEN's eyes sparkle. OLIVIER emerges from the office with a handful of script pages and VIVIEN looks at him slyly, getting her own back for his tactless over-praise of Marilyn's charms as she strokes COLIN's cheek.</context>
      <utterance>I suppose he's all right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VIVIEN</speaker>
      <mode>TO COLIN</mode>
      <context>Olivier glances over with a faint look of exasperation. VIVIEN winks at COLIN and takes her husband's arm.</context>
      <utterance>Let's elope together and have the most glorious affair.  Oh, but then, who'd look after my poor Larry?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>OLIVIER looks hunted. There is no way out. He glances back at PERCEVAL as he comes in.</context>
      <utterance>Now, darling, you must do something for Colin. You absolutely promised.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN grins in triumph. VIVIEN smiles at him.</context>
      <utterance>Let's try to find him something to do, Hughie.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She flirtatiously offers up her cheek for COLIN to kiss. COLIN's smile falters as he sees PERCEVAL looking at him grimly.</context>
      <utterance>You will take care of my precious Larrykins, won't you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode>TO CARDIFF</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Larry says he particularly likes this dress. She looks radiant.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARDIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly - we need to tone her down a bit.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN laughs. He immediately regrets it. Both men turn to look at him. PERCEVAL turns off the projector and gazes at him stonily.</context>
      <utterance>How the hell do you tone down Marilyn Monroe?!</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN nods eagerly, anxious to get out. He is already at the door when PERCEVAL barks at him again.</context>
      <utterance>Marilyn Monroe's publicist is flying in tomorrow. He wants to see the house she'll be staying in. Find something suitable.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN had forgotten the tray. He blushes furiously, puts it down and hurries out.</context>
      <utterance>And leave the bloody tea.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>COTES-PREEDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out of the question. I can't have a lot of awful film people tramping through the house in dirty boots.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'd pay a hundred pounds per week for 18 weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>COTES-PREEDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My wife would never agree.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COTES-PREEDY double takes.</context>
      <utterance>That's a pity. I'll have to tell Miss Monroe to look elsewhere, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>COTES-PREEDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marilyn Monroe?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode>NODS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's making a film with Sir Laurence Olivier. The Sleeping Prince. From the play by Terence Rattigan.</utterance>
   <speaker>COTES-PREEDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw it in the West End a couple of years ago. Vivien Leigh was marvellous.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COTES-PREEDY smiles transparently.</context>
      <utterance>It's Marilyn Monroe in the film.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning, Mr. Jacobs. I hope you had a pleasant flight.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACOBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's the fucking car?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>27 EXT. TIBBS FARM. DAY. 27</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>unimpressed. COTES-PREEDY follows him proudly with COLIN at his side. JACOBS takes a long, unimpressed look at the property.</context>
      <utterance>JACOBS slouches out of the house, magnificently</utterance>
   <speaker>JACOBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COTES-PREEDY's face falls.</context>
      <utterance>What is this place? A brothel?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>COTES-PREEDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's one of the best houses in the area.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACOBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus. And I thought you Brits had taste.</utterance>
   <speaker>MY WEEK WITH MARILYN 15.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He glances at COLIN.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACOBS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this the best you can do?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's very near Pinewood.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACOBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. We'll take it.  But ditch the wallpaper. It's given me a migraine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>News travels fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACOBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That house was perfect for Marilyn.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't use it now.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stare to him in surprise. He looks at them boldly.</context>
      <utterance>Yes we can. I knew Cotes-Preedy wouldn't be able to keep this quiet.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When you asked me to find a house for Miss Monroe I took the precaution of finding two. The other one, Parkside, is much better and the owner is very discreet.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But now we have two expensive houses when we only wanted one.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought someone else on the production might want it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a dangerous moment when things could go either way. COLIN has gambled everything in a bid to impress them.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, did you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JACOBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OLIVIER looks at COLIN, then bursts out laughing.</context>
      <utterance>I guess Milton could use it. It's near the studio, near Marilyn.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances at COLIN with amusement.</context>
      <utterance>What are we paying you, boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing...</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>LAUGHING</mode>
      <context>PERCEVAL sighs grimly.</context>
      <utterance>See to it, Hughie!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JACOBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(Pause) And green.</context>
      <utterance>Marilyn hates red. And blue.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about white?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACOBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OLIVIER glances mischievously at Colin.</context>
      <utterance>I'd have to clear it with her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JACOBS considers this, unaware that Olivier is teasing him.</context>
      <utterance>Beige, then. Beige is rarely controversial.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACOBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess that's okay. She's never said nothing about beige. Paula will need the room next door.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paula?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACOBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OLIVIER looks at him darkly. JACOBS shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Strasberg. Marilyn's acting coach.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACOBS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's nuts about the Method.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and walks away. JACOBS frowns uncertainly.</context>
      <utterance>Stanislavski and the Method are perfectly fine in the rehearsal room but they don't belong on a film set. Time is too tight. I'm sure Marilyn understands.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACOBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the hell is this Commie Stan Slavski?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ORTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know why Hugh Perceval sent you here. There's nothing I can do for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you in the union?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ORTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you can't have a job on the film.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do I get in the union?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By getting a job on the film.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you just said I couldn't have a job on the film unless I was in the union.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN looks at him helplessly. ORTON relents a little.</context>
      <utterance>Exactly. It's called a closed shop.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose I might be able to sort something out. The Union owes me a few favours. We haven't got a third yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A third?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Third Assistant Director.  You do know what the job is?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Assisting the director?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ORTON walks to the door, then looks back.</context>
      <utterance>Christ, no! That's the last thing you do. Lesson One. The third's job is to do whatever the fuck I tell him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - SHOUTS</mode>
      <context>COLIN scrambles to follow him out.</context>
      <utterance>What are you waiting for?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ORTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN jumps as ORTON glowers at him.</context>
      <utterance>Colin!</utterance>
   <speaker>ORTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lesson Two. You don't shit on your own doorstep. Got it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he sneaks a look back at LUCY as he goes.</context>
      <utterance>Got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>33A EXT. PINEWOOD STUDIOS. DAY. 33A</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>ORTON and COLIN hurry through Pinewood.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you staying?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father's place in the Albany.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grins, enjoying himself.</context>
      <utterance>You can forget that. Lesson Three. The Third always stays nearby, not in some bloody palace in London.  Book a room at the Dog And Duck down the road. It's a bit rough but you'll get used to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now make yourself useful. Marilyn needs a bodyguard. Sort something out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure you understand the sensitive nature of the job, Superintendant?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No need for the title. I'm retired from the force.  Something about looking after a cinema actress?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets no reaction from the stolid ex-policeman.</context>
      <utterance>Not just any actress. Marilyn Monroe.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never had much time for the pictures.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excellent.  For the next four months you never leave her side, day or night. There will be crowds.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PERCEVAL pauses awkwardly.</context>
      <utterance>That doesn't bother me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her behaviour is reputedly a little... erratic.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She drinks?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amongst other things.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PERCEVAL leaves a tactful pause.</context>
      <utterance>Pills?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>domestic situation.</context>
      <utterance>It would be useful if you could keep us informed of her...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Perceval and Roger understand each other perfectly.</context>
      <utterance>You want me to spy on her?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith takes this in his stride; he seems wholly immune to the glamour of the movies.</context>
      <utterance>Just the odd early warning if you know she's going to be late on set. That kind of thing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JACOBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OLIVIER rolls his eyes behind JACOBS back. COLIN grins.</context>
      <utterance>Of course he is. All those pain in the ass New York intellectuals are reds.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERCEVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It means Marilyn will be flying in next week on schedule.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACOBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She'll have to be met.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naturally, Vivien and I will be there to greet her. But let's keep it low key, shall we?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACOBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. I've got it all under control.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A voice suddenly rings out from the back of the previously attentive crowd.</context>
      <utterance>It is a deep happiness to me to be translating Terence Rattigan's magnificent play to the screen...</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As one, the entire crowd turns away from Olivier and rushes towards the plane. Suddenly abandoned, OLIVIER and VIVIEN look momentarily startled before VIVIEN glances at him with a half-smile.</context>
      <utterance>The plane's landed!</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It seems we're not top of the bill anymore, darling.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The REPORTERS surge forward. COLIN follows their collective gaze. She looks exactly as she should. The radiant smile, the platinum blonde hair, the sexy wiggle. The most famous film star in the world, so much herself it is almost unreal. Walking through the crowd MARILYN smiles easily, whereas MILLER looks stern and a little dazed by the sudden flurry of attention. Flashbulbs pop as the POLICE struggle to contain the crowd. MARILYN puts her arm around MILLER, who grins blankly. The flashbulbs burst in front of them, a solid wall of dazzling light.</context>
      <utterance>There she is! Marilyn!</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marilyn! Over here, Marilyn!</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ARTHUR JACOBS observes the chaotic scenes with obvious relish, grinning towards ROGER and COLIN.</context>
      <utterance>Marilyn, this way..!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACOBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ROGER looks at COLIN.</context>
      <utterance>Beautiful. You're looking at tomorrow's front page, boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN barges his way through the scrum behind ROGER and briefly finds himself directly in front of MARILYN. For a moment he is transfixed by her beauty and charisma but she doesn't even see him as she follows the commanding ROGER obediently, tugging Miller along behind her, leaving Colin in her wake.</context>
      <utterance>We have to get them to the hall.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A great actress on her first trip to London whom I have no doubt...</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you like being married, Marilyn?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like it a lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this third time lucky?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OLIVIER smiles tolerantly, mildly put out at this. MARILYN takes off her sunglasses and blinks. She takes MILLER's arm and looks at him adoringly. He bites down savagely on his unlit pipe.</context>
      <utterance>You bet it is. Arthur's the greatest man I ever met.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marilyn, are you planning to see the sights?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a appreciative laughter from reporters.</context>
      <utterance>I'd love to see the little fellow with the bow and arrow in Piccadilly Circus.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it true you want to be a classical actor now?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to be the best actress I can be.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a rumour you're going to be in The Brothers Karamazov on Broadway.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm considering it.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER 3</speaker>
      <mode>SHOUTS</mode>
      <context>The agenda is clear - Marilyn is the dumb blonde and should act accordingly. But she takes it in her stride, smiling sweetly.</context>
      <utterance>Which of them will you be playing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be playing Grushenka.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>REPORTER 3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you spell that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. Can you? There is laughter at the reporter's expense.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So would you say you're an intellectual now?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks adoringly at Miller, who smiles vaguely.</context>
      <utterance>My husband is.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your definition of an intellectual, Marilyn?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This time the laughter is emphatically on MARILYN's side. One of the reporters turns to VIVIEN.</context>
      <utterance>I guess you could look it up in a dictionary.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vivien, you created the part of Elsie Marina on stage. Do you have any advice for Marilyn?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The reporters laugh with her and OLIVIER smiles graciously. But as she smiles at him we detect just a flicker of jealous hurt in her eyes. OLIVIER intervenes quickly to continue his prepared speech of welcome.</context>
      <utterance>I am sure if Miss Monroe needs any advice she'll get it from her director. I hear he's terribly good.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops as a REPORTER shouts over him.</context>
      <utterance>In The Sleeping Prince we have discovered the perfect vehicle for Miss Monroe's luminous and justly celebrated talent...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACOBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marilyn, is it true you wear nothing in bed except Chanel No</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VIVIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are all your press conferences like that, darling?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vivien smiles at the wry joke. ARTHUR JACOBS watches the proceedings with an eagle eye.</context>
      <utterance>Well, that was quieter than some.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACOBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the group breaks up, MILTON GREENE, handsome and dark- haired, now approaches OLIVIER and COLIN.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, let's get a snap of the newlyweds. Smile, Arthur. It's not a firing squad.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances at the house. Olivier smiles generously.</context>
      <utterance>This is some place you found.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have my new assistant Colin to thank for that.  This is Milton Greene. You must be very nice to him. He owns half of Marilyn Monroe Productions.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>GREENE (34) offers them a tired smile. OLIVIER produces one of his branded packets and offers a cigarette to Milton.</context>
      <utterance>Forty nine per cent, Larry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have a cigarette.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>If he notices the "Olivier" name he doesn't show it. OLIVIER looks mildly put out.</context>
      <utterance>I don't smoke.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Let's talk.</context>
      <utterance>Milton - Marilyn and rehearsals.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MILLER and MARILYN are now being photographed on their own. ROGER moves over to JACOBS and murmurs discreetly in his ear. JACOBS nods and moves in to end the session.</context>
      <utterance>Sure. And the studio wants a new title. OLIVIER escorts Milton away.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACOBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The boys at the gate are getting restless.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ROGER waves to the POLICEMEN, who open the gates. The PRESS come pouring in like a mob of revolutionaries storming the Bastille.</context>
      <utterance>Let's give them two minutes and then we're done.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>VIVIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN looks at her shrewdly, sensing he is being tested.</context>
      <utterance>Marvellous, isn't she? I suppose you're quite smitten.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's all right. A bit common.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIEN</speaker>
      <mode>LAUGHS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Larry fell desperately in love with her in New York. He's determined to seduce her.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But she's only been married three weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives him an arch smile and leans in intimately.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Colin, I thought you were a man of the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>MY WEEK WITH MARILYN 27.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>VIVIEN   Of course, Larry would never leave me.  But, if anything were to happen, you would let me know, wouldn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a flash of sudden anger in her expression.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sure he loves you very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN looks shaken and she touches his hand in contrition.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, don't be such a boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least you still adore me, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a wintry bleakness in her face for a second.</context>
      <utterance>Of course. Everyone does.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes to protest but she stills him with a finger to his lips, her smile quickly restored.</context>
      <utterance>I'm 43, darling. No one will love me for much longer. Not even you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BARRY takes a dusty ledger from beneath the bar, spins it around for COLIN to sign.</context>
      <utterance>Colin Clark. I booked a room.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What brings you up this way?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The LOCALS look up from their pints, unimpressed.</context>
      <utterance>I'm here working on a film.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What film's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The darts player, ANDY, doesn't turn. His aim remains steady.</context>
      <utterance>It's called `The Sleeping Prince'.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds lousy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANDY doesn't look away from his game.</context>
      <utterance>Ignore, Andy - not a film fan - are you, Andy?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN tries to impress.</context>
      <utterance>Can't be bothered.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marilyn Monroe's in it. I'll be working with her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The regulars grin unkindly into their pints. ANDY doesn't look away from his game, as he offers laconically:</context>
      <utterance>Oh, will you now?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There are supportive snorts of derision from the LOCALS. COLIN takes it on the chin. BARRY hands him a key.</context>
      <utterance>The Queen and Prince Philip popped in for a pint earlier. Pity, you just missed them.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN takes the key and his bag, just as BARRY adds, with perfect deadpan timing:</context>
      <utterance>The room's three quid a week, first week in advance. You're in number two.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARRY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The LOCALS laugh into their beer. COLIN smiles gamely.</context>
      <utterance>You'll be sharing with Grace Kelly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WATTIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a wonderful adventure, Dame Sybil.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYBIL THORNDIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN stands by the door. OLIVIER looks at his watch and shoots him a questioning glance.</context>
      <utterance>Such a lark! I long to see her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door opens sharply and a small, bohemian looking woman in her 50s stands staring at him. This is PAULA STRASBERG.</context>
      <utterance>Miss Monroe?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir Laurence sends his compliments. He's ready for the</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARILYN glances up at COLIN in the mirror and smiles with unexpected simplicity.</context>
      <utterance>But Marilyn is not ready. She's preparing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She finds her dark glasses on the dresser and puts them on.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse the horrible face.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gestures to the company.</context>
      <utterance>Marilyn, here you are, everyone is so excited to meet you...</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>SYBIL THORNDIKE looks sweetly at MARILYN from across the table and indicates the empty one at her side.</context>
      <utterance>Let us begin. Do sit down, please...</utterance>
   <speaker>SYBIL THORNDIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PAULA bursts forward, steering Marilyn away instead to an empty seat on the other side of the rectangle of tables. She looks at RICHARD WATTIS, the actor occupying the seat next to the empty one.</context>
      <utterance>How lovely you are. Here, I kept a place for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The startled WATTIS gets up graciously and troops all the way around the table to the seat next to SYBIL THORNDIKE.</context>
      <utterance>I have to be next to Marilyn!</utterance>
   <speaker>SYBIL THORNDIKE</speaker>
      <mode>TO MARILYN</mode>
      <context>PAULA looks at her in truculent apology.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, dear, we won't bite.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She likes me by her side.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYBIL THORNDIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a good idea! I wish we could all bring a friend. One does get so terribly nervous. It's just like the first day at school, isn't it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pleased with his over-contrived rhetorical flourish, he gives Paula a pointed look. She glowers back, obscurely sensing that she has been insulted in some way. MARILYN also looks up in confusion at Olivier's well intentioned but clumsy joke. Oblivious to her reaction, he opens his script with a sentimental flourish.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome dear Marilyn, to our little fraternity.  We may seem a little strange and quaint to you at first, but I hope that in time you may come to find your method in our madness.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He is momentarily close to tears. WATTIS rolls his eyes discreetly, earning a grin from the actor PAUL HARDWICK. There is a rustle of pages and a few coughs, a mood of eager nervousness in the air as they all prepare for the reading.</context>
      <utterance>So. My very noble and approv'd good masters, let us now embark on our great voyage of discovery together.  With boldness and  good fortune, may we strive to create a work of art that, led by your good graces, will be cherished as long as motion pictures may be remembered.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>AS REGENT</mode>
      <context>MARILYN stares at him for a beat then reads haltingly.</context>
      <utterance>"Were you surprised to get my invitation?"</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>AS ELSIE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"I'll say I was surprised. I was so surprised I couldn't hardly think you meant me."</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>AS REGENT</mode>
      <context>MARILYN drops out of character with a sweet, nervous smile.</context>
      <utterance>"oh but of course I meant you. I had your name most carefully marked down on my programme. In matters of this kind I assure you I am most methodical. Who did you think I meant if not you?"</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There are private grins amongst the actors. OLIVIER smiles kindly.</context>
      <utterance>Gee, Mister Sir, I could listen to your accent all day.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flustered, MARILYN looks at her script.</context>
      <utterance>You are amongst friends, my darling angel. Just plain Larry will suffice.  When you're ready..?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>AS ELSIE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Well, Maisie Springfield...</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>AS REGENT</mode>
      <context>PAULA leans across, mounting a whispered running commentary in Marilyn's ear as OLIVIER speaks.</context>
      <utterance>"Oh, no, no, no not Maisie Springfield, she's quite what I would call old hat...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OLIVIER waits patiently.</context>
      <utterance>Remember why you're in the embassy, Marilyn. What does the Grand Duke want from Elsie? She thought there were going to be a lot of people here and it's just her.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's your line, Marilyn.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This time OLIVIER stares at PAULA.</context>
      <utterance>Locate the experience, Marilyn. Look for the memory that helps you. Remember when you went to that party at Chaplin's house and you were the only guest? How did that make you feel?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is only a readthrough, Paula.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marilyn has to begin finding the character.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The character is on the page.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RICHARD WATTIS whispers to PAUL HARDWICK.</context>
      <utterance>The words, maybe. Not the character.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATTIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DAME SYBIL THORNDIKE frowns with regal disapproval and smiles warmly at MARILYN.</context>
      <utterance>She's half cut!</utterance>
   <speaker>SYBIL THORNDIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't we going to have fun?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't have two fucking directors!</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marilyn wants Paula.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? She's got me!</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paula is costing us two and half thousand bucks a week. We might as well use her.  Listen Larry, accept Marilyn on her own terms and you'll be okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come out with me tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm working.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow night, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm washing my hair.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops to look at him, attracted but cautious.</context>
      <utterance>Your hair's lovely.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I have two rules. One, never touch the talent...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone has a lot of rules around here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... and two, never go out with thirds.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because they're all randy little buggers who just want some fun during shooting.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him sceptically.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode>SIGHS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm free on Saturday.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORTON</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context>COLIN ducks into a rack of clothes, making a face at Lucy. She can't help smiling back.</context>
      <utterance>Colin!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SYBIL THORNDIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How kind of you to meet us. Dear me, you do look cold.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're ready for you in make-up Dame Sybil.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYBIL THORNDIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How exciting! Don't you love the first day of a new production?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DAME SYBIL gazes at him with wistful sadness.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, Dame Sybil. I've never had one before.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYBIL THORNDIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She blows him a kiss and the car rolls in through the gate. Almost immediately OLIVIER's chauffeur driven Bentley appears.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, to be young again!</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marilyn here yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ORTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck's going on? I thought you had a contact in her house.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do...</utterance>
   <speaker>ORTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well bloody use him, then.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ORTON</speaker>
      <mode>ON PHONE</mode>
      <context>COLIN glances upstairs as he tries to think what to say.</context>
      <utterance>Well? What's happening?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's... getting into character.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door finally opens and MARILYN emerges, with PAULA on one side and MILTON on the other. In her figure-hugging shimmering white sheath of a dress she is ravishingly beautiful. Her hair is like a halo of light around her head. No one can take their eyes off her. Slowly, all work on the set stops. MARILYN walks to the set, acutely aware of the scrutiny of the crew. She smiles nervously, then suddenly hesitates, feeling the weight of everyone's attention. Anxiety flits across her face. She whispers something to PAULA and bolts back towards her dressing room. OLIVIER stares after her in shock.</context>
      <utterance>She's kept Dame Sybil Thorndike waiting in full costume for two hours. It's simply not fair.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OLIVIER loosens his collar irritably and glances at ORTON.</context>
      <utterance>She wasn't happy with her make- up.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stalks away, followed by Cardiff and Orton.</context>
      <utterance>Right, Mr. Orton you wanted me to check the back projection. Please join us, Mr. Cardiff.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SYBIL THORNDIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't she pretty though?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like to sit down, Dame Sybil?</utterance>
   <speaker>SYBIL THORNDIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Colin sees her chair by the camera and goes innocently to fetch it. But as he picks it up he is confronted by a stern looking crew member in overalls.</context>
      <utterance>How kind of you, Colin. Yes, why don't we all sit down?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>TREVOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you a member of NATTKE?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>TREVOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Every eye is suddenly on Colin. Taking his shock for stubbornness TREVOR turns to the set and bellows.</context>
      <utterance>That chair is a prop. Props are NATTKE. If ACT members are going to do NATTKE jobs, I'm calling my men out.</utterance>
   <speaker>TREVOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Half the crew immediately down tools. COLIN looks on in horror. SYBIL THORNDIKE frowns in reproach.</context>
      <utterance>Strike meeting!</utterance>
   <speaker>SYBIL THORNDIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure we're all good union members here. There's no need to fall out over something so trivial.</utterance>
   <speaker>TREVOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN stares at him, frozen.</context>
      <utterance>It might be trivial to you, Dame Sybil, but it's my livelihood. He's not in the union.  Put the chair down.</utterance>
   <speaker>TREVOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>COLIN drops it as though it was on fire. It clatters to the stage. SYBIL THORNDIKE bears down on TREVOR majestically.</context>
      <utterance>Put the chair down now!</utterance>
   <speaker>SYBIL THORNDIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TREVOR pauses, not at all sure about this, but then shrugs magnanimously.</context>
      <utterance>I rather think you've made your point. Solidarity is the important thing here. When unions fall out, it's only management that benefits.</utterance>
   <speaker>TREVOR</speaker>
      <mode>TO COLIN</mode>
      <context>He turns to one of his men.</context>
      <utterance>If I see you doing a NATTKE job again I'll close this set down quicker than you can blink.</utterance>
   <speaker>TREVOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dave, Dame Sybil needs a chair.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MY WEEK WITH MARILYN 38.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles nostalgically as ORTON appears to hustle COLIN away, muttering furiously.</context>
      <utterance>SYBIL THORNDIKE  Now that was a strike. We were all Bolsheviks then!</utterance>
   <speaker>ORTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't they teach you anything at Eton? Now fuck off and see if you can get me a bacon sandwich without starting World War III.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DENYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Camera running.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very quiet, everyone...</utterance>
   <speaker>DENYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CLAPPER LOADER clicks the clapperboard.</context>
      <utterance>Speed.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAPPERBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty two, take one.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Action!</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>AS REGENT</mode>
      <context>SYBIL THORNDIKE sweeps through the door right on cue, with MAUD, her lady-in-waiting, following. She is effortlessly in command of her lines.</context>
      <utterance>"Now, before you meet my mother- in-law I must warn you she is a little vague and can be very deaf... on occasions."</utterance>
   <speaker>SYBIL THORNDIKE</speaker>
      <mode>AS QUEEN DOWAGER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"My dear, such boredom! The decorations hideous, and the music... catastrophe! Our friend, the ex-King of Moravia drove me home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SYBIL THORNDIKE</speaker>
      <mode>AS QUEEN DOWAGER - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is now called the Duke of Strelitz, he cannot of course go to the Abbey tomorrow, but he is most anxious you should invite him to the room you have taken in the Ritz for Nicky. Maud?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSAMUND GREENWOOD</speaker>
      <mode>AS MAUD</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Yes, Ma'am..."</utterance>
   <speaker>SYBIL THORNDIKE</speaker>
      <mode>AS QUEEN DOWAGER</mode>
      <context>Olga Bosnia..."</context>
      <utterance>"Oh there you are my dear, I did not see you, give me a glass of that champagne I see over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>AS REGENT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Might I present Miss Elsie Marina?"</utterance>
   <speaker>SYBIL THORNDIKE</speaker>
      <mode>AS QUEEN DOWAGER</mode>
      <context>They all look at MARILYN... and nothing happens.</context>
      <utterance>"Oh yes, my dear, of course I remember you well."</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gee. I forgot my line. I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SYBIL THORNDIKE smiles cheerfully.</context>
      <utterance>Cut.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYBIL THORNDIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's so easily done, isn't it? I'm sure I went wrong somewhere there too. Shall we have another go, Larry?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SYBIL THORNDIKE</speaker>
      <mode>AS QUEEN DOWAGER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Oh yes, my dear, of course I remember you well."</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>AS ELSIE - HALTING</mode>
      <context>It is not clear whether Marilyn's hesitance is acted or not but the others press on gamely.</context>
      <utterance>"Oh, I'm quite sure you don't, your royal..., oh, I mean, your, uh, Imperial... your uh... serene majesty."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SYBIL THORNDIKE</speaker>
      <mode>AS QUEEN DOWAGER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"What does she say?"</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>AS REGENT</mode>
      <context>MARILYN jumps in, shouting her line over the top of him.</context>
      <utterance>"She says she is deeply flattered and compliments you on your wonderful memory."</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>AS ELSIE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"I'm in The Coconut Girl at The Avenue." There is a pause. SYBIL THORNDIKE hesitates.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYBIL THORNDIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't I have a line somewhere there, dear?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cut.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ORTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Action!</utterance>
   <speaker>SYBIL THORNDIKE</speaker>
      <mode>AS QUEEN DOWAGER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Thank you, my dear.  Sweetly pretty. She should use more mascara. When one is young one should use a lot of mascara, and when one is old one should use much more. What do you do, my dear?"</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>AS ELSIE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"I'm in The Coconut Girl at The Avenue".</utterance>
   <speaker>SYBIL THORNDIKE</speaker>
      <mode>AS QUEEN DOWAGER - TO OLIVIER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Dear?"</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>AS REGENT</mode>
      <context>MARILYN looks at him, hesitant but just about in character. OLIVIER glances at ORTON who nods.</context>
      <utterance>"She says she is an actress."</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cut it there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Check the gate.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FOCUS PULLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gate's good.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a near-audible sigh of relief around the set. SYBIL THORNDIKE smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Print.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYBIL THORNDIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARILYN smiles awkwardly, not really believing her but SYBIL carries on with complete conviction. SYBIL THORNDIKE (cont'd) Perhaps we could practise our lines together later? You'd be doing me such a kindness. At my great age it's just so hard to make them stick! Why don't you come for tea tomorrow? In fact Sybil is word perfect every time, and everyone knows it. But it is a kind and tactful gesture. MARILYN's face lights up.</context>
      <utterance>That was perfect, Marilyn. You're Elsie to the life!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's impossible. I should have cast Vivien.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If anyone can make her great, it's you. You're a genius.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OLIVIER looks at him, wanting to be reassured. He fumbles for a cigarette with shaking fingers and COLIN hurries to light it. He smiles wryly.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes. The world's greatest living actor, so they say.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's hope I'm as brilliant as you think I am.  Now be a good boy and keep an eye on her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just can't figure this movie out.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You were divine.</context>
      <utterance>You were wonderful. You are the most gifted actress I have ever known. You were superb, Marilyn.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was angry with me, I could tell.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops abruptly and gets down on her knees in the corridor in front of Marilyn. COLIN stops awkwardly, his path blocked.</context>
      <utterance>You were great. You are a great, great actress. All my life I have prayed for a great actress I could help and guide.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like this. I prayed to God on my knees. And he has given me you. You are that great actress, Marilyn.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Paula, get up.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARILYN smiles, her mood slowly lightening.</context>
      <utterance>Not until you admit you were great.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN glances at her, seeing his chance to help.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, okay. I guess I was.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARILYN smiles vaguely. PAULA gives him a fierce look - COLIN moves past quickly.</context>
      <utterance>You really were very good, Miss Monroe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure you can afford all this?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, it's all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It must be costing a week's wages.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LUCY can't help being charmed.</context>
      <utterance>It's worth it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not the average third, are you? Most of them would be happy with a swift half and a grope in the pub car park.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not living off my parents, if that's what you mean. I want to make my own way, no matter what.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By making eyes at Vivien Leigh?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who told you that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Word gets around.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vivien's a friend of my father's.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles mysteriously and leans in to kiss her. She avoids him coolly.</context>
      <utterance>So there's nothing in it? You and Vivien?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The WAITER approaches with a bill on a silver salver and offers him a pen.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not that easy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN blushes violently.</context>
      <utterance>You'll be signing on your father's account, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The WAITER nods discreetly and leaves. LUCY looks at COLIN with a teasing smile.</context>
      <utterance>Certainly not. I settle my own bills.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was always going to pay, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her, but there is no hint of mockery in her smile and he is grateful.</context>
      <utterance>Of course you were.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think Marilyn is beautiful?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LUCY laughs, COLIN looks hurt.</context>
      <utterance>Not compared to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to try so hard to be charming. You're nice enough as it is. Well, you could be.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know Marilyn's really still in love with Joe DiMaggio?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So they say.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She married Miller on the rebound. The papers are calling them "The Hourglass and the Egghead".</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She bursts out laughing. Her eyes sparkle and she looks captivating in the glistening lights. He goes to kiss her and this time she doesn't stop him.</context>
      <utterance>Which one is which?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a while, crocodile.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him shrewdly.</context>
      <utterance>I really do like you, Lucy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hears heavy footsteps in the bedroom above.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She gives Colin a swift peck on the cheek as she tidies herself. A moment later the door opens and Lucy's father, MR. ARMSTRONG comes in, wearing his dressing gown over pyjamas. He glances at COLIN with a suspicious smile as he looks at his daughter.</context>
      <utterance>That's my dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. ARMSTRONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Time to be thinking about bed, darling. Early start tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN and LUCY share a small, private smile. He takes his cue and stands up.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Daddy. We were just going over tomorrow's schedule.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He offers the surprised MR. ARMSTRONG a confident handshake.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I should be off. Colin Clark. Pleased to meet you, Mr. Armstrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a very nice house you've got.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. ARMSTRONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know this part of the world?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode>THROWN</mode>
      <context>Lost for words they stare at each other for another moment before MR. ARMSTRONG smiles vaguely then goes. LUCY follows him with a smile at COLIN. He grins and whispers.</context>
      <utterance>Umm... not really. My family are more country people.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She nods. He follows her out into the hall.</context>
      <utterance>Next Saturday?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SYBIL THORNDIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands him a bright red woollen scarf. COLIN is touched.</context>
      <utterance>Colin, dear, I thought you looked cold so I bought you this.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Dame Sybil.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYBIL THORNDIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles as her car drives away. He wraps the scarf around his neck and looks up and down the road again.</context>
      <utterance>Film sets and rehearsal rooms are the coldest places on earth.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She should be on time, like everyone else.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She is a star.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks around in frustration.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a fucking star!</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we nip this behaviour in the bud perhaps it won't be repeated.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Marilyn you're talking about.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marilyn, darling you are an angel, and I kiss the hem of your garment, but why can't you get here on time for the love of fuck?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him in surprise. She looks sedated, not quite there. PAULA leaps protectively to her defence.</context>
      <utterance>Oh... you have that word in England too?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OLIVIER gives her a freezing look then takes Marilyn's hand, leading her forward like a child.</context>
      <utterance>Marilyn has to prepare properly. She has to find in herself all that lies under the surface. Acting isn't just a case of putting on a costume or some ludicrous false nose.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARILYN reddens with humiliation as he takes her arm.</context>
      <utterance>You must apologise to Dame Sybil.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry...</utterance>
   <speaker>SYBIL THORNDIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A radiant smile spreads slowly across Marilyn's face as the older woman's words sink in.</context>
      <utterance>My dear, you mustn't concern yourself. A great actress like you has many other things on her mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I'm a great actress?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARILYN glows at his praise.</context>
      <utterance>That one's pretty damn good. You knocked it out of the park.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OLIVIER frowns. For all his greatness as an actor he will never be a film star like the maddeningly instinctive Marilyn. And the injustice of it is like a stab through his heart. At the back COLIN only has eyes for the screen. He watches MARILYN's image, enthralled. Until now he has taken Marilyn entirely at Olivier's valuation, but as he watches her on screen he begins to see things differently.</context>
      <utterance>When Marilyn gets it right you just don't want to look at anyone else.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN can't resist blurting out a comment.</context>
      <utterance>We've only been shooting for four days and we're already two weeks behind.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks self-conscious as they both turn to stare at him.</context>
      <utterance>Why not only show her the good takes? Then she might feel better about herself.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The kid's right. She could use the confidence.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I believe it's traditional for the producer of the film to watch rushes. Besides, she's an experienced actress. She should learn from her mistakes.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They just upset her.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not half as much as they upset me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your script...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Calmly she takes the towel from her hair and wraps it around herself. She smiles quizzically.</context>
      <utterance>I found it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He hesitates a beat, surprised that she knows his name, before he fumbles for the door.</context>
      <utterance>You can go now, Colin.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They kiss again. He pulls away.</context>
      <utterance>Tell him he can start sending them up. Women first.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He looks at her uncertainly.</context>
      <utterance>I'm looking forward to Saturday.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our date?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode>AWKWARD</mode>
      <context>Marilyn wants to go shopping.</context>
      <utterance>I forgot. I can't do Saturday.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since when do you work for her?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles sardonically, teasing him, but a little hurt.</context>
      <utterance>Larry asked me to help out.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, of course you must do what Larry says.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shrugs in agreement.</context>
      <utterance>Next Friday instead?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He smiles, a little too glibly, and hurries away. LUCY gazes after him. He doesn't look back.</context>
      <utterance>I'll pick you up. Eight o'clock.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gee, it's quiet.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops to window shop. MILTON lowers his voice to COLIN.</context>
      <utterance>It's Saturday. Early closing. But they're expecting us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one's recognised her.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least she can shop in peace.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks around anxiously. But then a PASSER-BY suddenly narrows his eyes and takes a second look. His face lights up and he shouts -</context>
      <utterance>Marilyn's a star. Stars don't even pee alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>PASSER-BY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARILYN gives him a radiant smile and within seconds is surrounded by a crowd of SHOPPERS alerted by the fuss. A feverish excitement grows out of nothing as people come running to look, pushing and shoving to see. MARILYN is quickly hemmed in by the heaving mob. To begin with she enjoys it, smiling and posing happily for the cameras that appear out of nowhere. But as the crowd press towards something in the mood of the gathering changes; it becomes wild and over-excited mood as people scream Marilyn's name and shove bits of paper to sign in her face. A WOMAN is pushed to the ground and MARILYN is forced back against the shop window. COLIN sees a flicker of panic on her face.</context>
      <utterance>It's Marilyn Monroe!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God, she'll be torn apart...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN and ROGER hurl themselves into the crowd doing what they can to keep the excited fans at bay. They manage to force a path to the car, drag the door open and bundle MARILYN and MILLER into the back. MARILYN is pinned against the door and COLIN has to put his arm around her shoulders as he helps her in. He hurls himself into the front, with Milton running alongside the moving car to dive in beside Marilyn. People run alongside, hammering wildly on the windows in violent hysteria. MILTON does his best to put a cheerful gloss on the chaos.</context>
      <utterance>Get her out of here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As COLIN looks in the rear-view mirror he sees MILLER shaking his head in dazed horror as MARILYN slumps half-collapsed into the seat beside him.</context>
      <utterance>Jeez, Marilyn, they really fucking love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN shifts his gaze to her in the mirror and his eyes meet Marilyn's. He sees - or imagines - a terrible sadness before she quickly replaces her dark glasses.</context>
      <utterance>Madness. Someone's going to get hurt.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>AS ELSIE</mode>
      <context>OLIVIER looks out from behind the camera, patient and charming.</context>
      <utterance>"Well we're still the first ones, aren't we? Gee, this is all right, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARILYN smiles vaguely. HAIR and MAKE-UP rush to do last minute checks.</context>
      <utterance>Cut. The line is "Gee, this is all right too, isn't it". It's a tiny word, my darling, but it matters. Let's go straight away.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Camera running.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOUNDMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Speed.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The clapperboard clatters down. Take two. WATTIS and MARILYN come in again on their cue.</context>
      <utterance>Mark it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>AS ELSIE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Well we're still the first ones, aren't we? Gee, this is all right, isn't it?"</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Take three.</context>
      <utterance>Cut. Nearly there, but Terry did work so very hard on this and we must try to get it right for him. Straight away, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>AS ELSIE</mode>
      <context>By now there is a panic-stricken edge to her voice.</context>
      <utterance>"Well, we're still the first ones, aren't we? Gee, this is... all right, isn't it?"</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cut.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't we just drop it?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The point is that you have already admired the downstairs hall in an earlier scene. Now you are admiring this room as well.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OLIVIER looks startled. PAULA comes scurrying across. MARILYN appeals to her, turning away from OLIVIER.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, sure.  Paula!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't get it. He's such a strange man. I think she'd figure out he only invited her to sleep with her.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode>TO OLIVIER</mode>
      <context>OLIVIER takes out all his pent-up frustration on PAULA.</context>
      <utterance>The reason Marilyn can't remember the line is because she doesn't believe the situation her character is in.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PAULA bristles at this insult to her husband's work.</context>
      <utterance>Then she should pretend to believe it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretend? We're talking about the difference between the truth and artificial crap.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe we should try for another take.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marilyn needs time to give a great performance. You should give her as long as it takes. Chaplin took eight months to make a movie.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Throughout all this MARILYN herself looks lost. COLIN watches her as she feels the crew's irritable collective gaze. Flustered, she flutters her hands in a calming gesture, then goes to the side of the set to lean on a bar put there for her to rest on (her costume is too tight to allow her to sit down). PAULA accompanies her. MARILYN looks up at her in anguish.</context>
      <utterance>Eight months of this? I'd rather kill myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PAULA looks at her adamantly.</context>
      <utterance>I can't do this. I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARILYN looks at her, desperately wanting to believe it.</context>
      <utterance>You can do it. You can't fail. You will have more pain, you will suffer more but you will create. All you need is time.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember, Marilyn, a tree is never just a tree. What kind of tree is Elsie? An elm tree? A birch tree?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Under his breath to</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN)</speaker>
      <mode> COLIN)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God knows, but I'm a weeping fucking willow.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode>TO MARILYN</mode>
      <context>MARILYN listens intently, a frown flitting across her face. She goes back to her mark. The whole crew is on tenterhooks. Camera running, speed, mark it... Action! Take four.</context>
      <utterance>Think about the things you like, instead of him. Frank Sinatra. Coca Cola. Be specific. The character comes alive if you know what you're doing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>AS ELSIE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Well we're still the first ones, aren't we? Gee, this is all right, isn't it?"</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A look of near-panic creeps into Marilyn's eyes at her inability to remember the line.</context>
      <utterance>Cut.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>AS ELSIE</mode>
      <context>There is a stunned moment. WATTIS gapes and MARILYN looks around uncertainly. Did she say it? OLIVIER gestures frantically from behind the camera that she should carry on. She hesitates... ... there is an agonising beat... ... and then she panics and bolts for the side of the set.</context>
      <utterance>"Well we're still the first ones, aren't we?  Gee, this is all right too, isn't it?"</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paula!</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes her arm and whisks her away to the side of the set, lowering his voice, trying to conceal his exasperation with a honeyed tone.</context>
      <utterance>Cut. What's the matter now?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forgive me, Marilyn. This is my failure, not yours. Tell me how I can help you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know who Elsie is. I can't act her if I don't know who she is!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elsie is all in the script</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't find her. She's not there.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you have her precisely, you know her inside out. I'm in awe of your gift. We all are.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's not real.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not simply rely on your natural talents?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OLIVIER is bewildered by her inability to appreciate her own natural talent - as he sees it. He looks at her in genuine anguish.</context>
      <utterance>Are you saying I don't need to act?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marilyn, you are the most attractive woman in the world. I'm simply suggesting you be yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>SHOUTS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to be myself!  I want to be an actress playing a character.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARILYN flinches as though slapped. Tension ripples through the set. COLIN watches in dismay.</context>
      <utterance>All you have to do, dear Marilyn, is be sexy. Isn't that what you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want Lee.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Speak to me.</context>
      <utterance>You've already got Paula, for heaven's sake. I'm the director.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am only Lee's representative.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's five in the morning in New York.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"O, now, for ever Farewell the tranquil mind/Farewell content/ Farewell the plumed troop and the big wars/That make ambition virtue O, farewell/Farewell..."  Paula's not an actress. She not a director, not a teacher. Her only talent is buttering up Marilyn.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It would be worse if she wasn't around.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what would make Marilyn Monroe a real actor? A season in rep. They wouldn't stand for this kind of nonsense at the Hippodrome in Eastbourne.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to be patient with her.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MILTON gives him a look but says nothing. Instead he picks up his bag and opens it. It is stuffed with bottles of pills. He takes one of them, checks the label and puts it in his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Trying to teach Marilyn how to act is like teaching Urdu to a badger.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I better go see her. She'll need something to help her calm down. COLIN holds the door for him as he goes out.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pills to sleep, pills to wake up. Pills to calm her down, pills to give her energy. No wonder she's permanently ten feet underwater.</utterance>
   <speaker>MY WEEK WITH MARILYN 59.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>COLIN looks at him tentatively.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe she's scared.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're all scared. It's part of being an actor.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you have the training to deal with it. OLIVIER turns from the mirror to survey him.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sighs wistfully.</context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't buy the little girl lost act if I were you. Though heaven knows it's tempting.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>COLIN isn't so sure but wisely holds his tongue.</context>
      <utterance>And I think Marilyn knows exactly what she's doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You better get over to Parkside and make sure the poor girl's all right.  And Colin? Don't forget who you work for.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure they won't mind?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He frowns darkly.</context>
      <utterance>Help yourself. They can spare it.  Marilyn's okay. She's taken some pills and gone to bed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>It makes her easier to control.</context>
      <utterance>They like to keep her doped up.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean Miller?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The others. They're terrified their cash cow will slip away. He smiles grimly and raises his beer bottle.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cheers!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's nearly lunch time.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She isn't feeling the part.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a light comedy. How much feeling can it possibly require?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give her a few minutes...</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She can't hide in her bloody dressing room all day.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes she can.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How old are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>24.  Nearly</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You remind us of the young king in the movie. Kind of honest and innocent.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode>WOUNDED</mode>
      <context>She turns her head and her beautiful face comes fully into the light.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not innocent.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your job on this picture?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the third assistant director. Just a gopher really. Go for this, go for that...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shrugs awkwardly.</context>
      <utterance>You're Larry's assistant too.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What were you doing in my house last night? Did he send you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MY WEEK WITH MARILYN 63.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>COLIN hesitates. It seems pointless to deny it.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was worried about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you spying on me?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sighs, and looks away.</context>
      <utterance>No! Of course not. Why would anyone spy on you?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He waits hesitantly, but she seems to have drifted off. But then, suddenly, she turns back to him, her eyes huge.</context>
      <utterance>Are you all right, Miss Monroe?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN stares at her. She looks utterly beautiful and vulnerable in the shadowy light. There is only one answer anyone could give.</context>
      <utterance>Colin? Whose side are you on?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rewards him with a brilliant smile, her whole face lighting up.</context>
      <utterance>Yours, Miss Monroe.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is suddenly overwhelmed by a rush of sympathy. She looks so lost and vulnerable. Perhaps he means it. Perhaps he is on her side now.</context>
      <utterance>Call me Marilyn.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WATTIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Larry will get jealous.</context>
      <utterance>Marilyn's got a new boyfriend.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARDWICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives a camp laugh. COLIN tries to shrug it off with a lightness he doesn't feel.</context>
      <utterance>You can say that again.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing happened.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paula was with us the whole time.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATTIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN smiles but his expression freezes as he looks up to see LUCY nearby. She has heard every word of the exchange.</context>
      <utterance>The mind boggles, dear.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OLIVIER smiles but MILLER looks dazed.</context>
      <utterance>I dreamed last night I could hear singing. And then I realised it wasn't a dream. There was a male voice choir serenading Marilyn under our window. At two in the morning. It's a circus. A freak show.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>I need a break.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going back to New York for a few days. I need to see my kids.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That won't help Marilyn.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pauses for a second.</context>
      <utterance>I can't help her.  You know what she loves to do most? Sleep. It's what she lives for. Sleep is her demon.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>OLIVIER looks at him. MILLER shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>I've disappointed her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He pauses for a second, weighing every word carefully.</context>
      <utterance>She thought I could smash all her insecurities with one magical stroke. That I could make her a new person.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Just a few ideas.</context>
      <utterance>She wants me to protect her but I can't. I can't even protect myself.  She read some notes I made. They were nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up and nods slowly.</context>
      <utterance>About her?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaves a long, uneasy pause.</context>
      <utterance>She took them the wrong way.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MILLER plays with his whisky.</context>
      <utterance>But you do love her? Your new bride and all that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Forgotten in the shadows, COLIN listens attentively to every word.</context>
      <utterance>I can't work. I can't think.  She's devouring me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>VIVIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sees ORTON and takes his hands.</context>
      <utterance>I hope Larry isn't making you all work too hard. I know what a dreadful slave driver he can be.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>David, he would be lost without you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tough as he is, he melts visibly. She moves on to JACK CARDIFF, the lighting cameraman, looking at him in mock misery.</context>
      <utterance>Just doing my job.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm getting old, Jack. I need you to work your miracles on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARDIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She laughs and turns to COLIN, looking at him severely.</context>
      <utterance>You're more beautiful every year, Vivien.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, you are looking after Larry like I told you?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VIVIEN glances away to see MARILYN standing nearby, awkward and excluded. She has come straight from make-up and wears only a towelling robe, slippers and curlers in her hair.</context>
      <utterance>I'm doing my best...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VIVIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses her on both cheeks and holds her hands.</context>
      <utterance>Darling Marilyn!</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Larry tells me you are quite, quite superb. I'm wild with jealousy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, but everyone says you were a wonderful Elsie on stage.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances at OLIVIER with a fluttering laugh. He smiles back with a haunted look in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>But I'm too old to play her in the film. Larry was quite brutal about that. You see, the truth is all that matters to him. That's why we all admire him so very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The crew press around her. MARILYN watches, feeling more than ever the odd one out. COLIN watches her from the edge of the crowd. She cuts a lonely, vulnerable figure. He is totally preoccupied with her, so much so that when VIVIEN comes up behind him he turns guiltily as though caught out. VIVIEN stares at him. All her exuberance has vanished and she looks suddenly tired and older. It as though the facade of a beautiful building is beginning to crack. She gazes at him with bitter disappointment.</context>
      <utterance>Now, I must let you work. I only came to wish you good luck! Goodbye, everyone!</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He wants to protest but VIVIEN is already turning away.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Colin. Not you too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>VIVIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't think she would be so beautiful. She... shines on that screen.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shouldn't upset yourself. You are ten times the actress she will ever be.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you could see yourself. The way you watch her...</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She laughs hysterically.</context>
      <utterance>There's never been anything between Marilyn and me.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only because she didn't want you.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're imagining things.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him venomously, a dangerous, unbalanced hatred seething in her expression. VIVIEN (CONT'D) (cont'd) But she saw through you, didn't she darling? Take away the actor and what's left of the man? You can't even play the husband properly without a script. (slaps him hard across the face. ) I hope she makes your life hell!</context>
      <utterance>Do you think I'm a fool? You didn't think the little tart could resist the great Laurence Olivier.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She storms out. After a beat, COLIN tentatively enters. OLIVIER looks at COLIN in muted apology.</context>
      <utterance>Vivien..!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>COLIN looks down awkwardly. OLIVIER sighs.</context>
      <utterance>She hasn't been well. There was a baby... she... we... lost it...</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>COLIN hurries to offer him one of his "Oliviers". OLIVIER grimaces wryly.</context>
      <utterance>Do you have a cigarette, Colin?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>COLIN finds a woodbine in his other pocket and gives it to OLIVIER, who lights it with a shaking hand. He inhales deeply.</context>
      <utterance>Not one of those awful things.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He looks at COLIN, his feelings raw and exposed.</context>
      <utterance>Vivien's right... I did think I would fall shatteringly in love with Marilyn. What a joke.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember, boy, when it comes to women you are never too old for humiliation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ROOM/PARKSIDE. DAY.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>COLIN pours whisky for OLIVIER. MILTON comes in.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marilyn won't shoot today. She's gone back to Parkside. She's upset about Arthur leaving England.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's only going to visit his children.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The phone rings. OLIVIER picks with a sudden burst of optimism.</context>
      <utterance>You don't leave Marilyn alone. She can't handle it. She thinks everyone's going to abandon her.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps she's come back.  Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir Laurence? It's Roger.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Roger. What's up?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context>He frowns and looks at COLIN in bewilderment.</context>
      <utterance>Is Colin there, Sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Puzzled, COLIN takes the phone as OLIVIER stares at him.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, he's here.  It's for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CUT TO PARKSIDE, where, to Colin's astonishment MARILYN comes on the line (Roger is not in shot).</context>
      <utterance>Roger?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>ON PHONE</mode>
      <context>CUT BACK TO PINEWOOD - MILTON recognises Marilyn's voice instantly.</context>
      <utterance>Colin, why don't you drop by here on your way home?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the heck?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN looks around helplessly.</context>
      <utterance>Why is Marilyn on the phone to my third fucking assistant?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CUT TO PARKSIDE. MARILYN smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I'm sure I can do that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>ON PHONE</mode>
      <context>CUT TO PINEWOOD: COLIN replaces the phone in its cradle. MILTON and OLIVIER stare at him.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Don't tell anyone though. She hangs up.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well? What did she want?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She wants to see me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His angry - and jealous - frustration is in stark contrast to OLIVIER, who looks at COLIN with a new interest, wondering if there is anything in this odd situation that can work to his advantage. He smiles calmly.</context>
      <utterance>He shouldn't be talking to her. He's just a kid. Supposing he says something?  Why the hell didn't she call me?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a warning as well as approval in his tone.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sure Colin knows what he's doing. Don't you, Colin?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at COLIN dubiously as he goes out. COLIN is nervous and not quite sure what to do with himself. He looks at the drinks in their decanters on the sideboard and is suddenly desperate for some Dutch courage. He finds the brandy and picks it up -</context>
      <utterance>Miss Monroe said for you to wait. She won't be long.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context>COLIN wheels in surprise. MARILYN stands in the doorway, casually but beautifully dressed in silk trousers and a pale cream shirt. COLIN looks guiltily at the brandy.</context>
      <utterance>Help yourself to a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks to the sideboard, standing only a few inches away from him. He can't take his eyes from hers. He drops his gaze, only to find himself staring at her breasts. He looks up again sharply but not before she notices. She takes the decanter from his hand.</context>
      <utterance>I was just... checking you've got everything you need.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pours some brandy into a glass and gives it to him.</context>
      <utterance>Here, let me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you frightened of me, Colin?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Colin doesn't know what to say. MARILYN gazes at him.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Because I like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She looks at him, her eyes wide. COLIN feels himself sinking into her gaze.</context>
      <utterance>I want you to help me. Will you do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm only the third. Just a messenger, really.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shrugs in helpless agreement.</context>
      <utterance>But you know what's going on. You can see both sides of the situation.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She indicates a chair and COLIN perches on it awkwardly.</context>
      <utterance>I want you to be honest. Tell me everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He doesn't know how to reply and Marilyn misreads his silence. Her eyes widen in dismay.</context>
      <utterance>Relax. I thought you weren't scared of me.  Are you hungry? I'll have them send in a tray. I'm starved.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, gee, I'm sorry. Am I interrupting something? Maybe you have a Mrs. Colin waiting for you at home?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no Mrs. Colin.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods uncertainly. She frowns.</context>
      <utterance>So we can talk as long as we like?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why is Sir Olivier so mean? He talks to me as if he's slumming.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops, breathless, knowing he has gone to far. She stares at him, wide-eyed with surprise. Horribly self- conscious he takes a too large swig of his brandy, reddens and coughs. She laughs.</context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you what's wrong. It's agony for him because he's a great actor who wants to be a film star, and agony for you because you're a film star who wants to be a great actress. And this film won't help either of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure you can handle that? You don't look old enough to drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm 23, Miss Monroe.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Marilyn.  I'm 30. I guess that makes me an old lady to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles then sits opposite him.</context>
      <utterance>Seven years is nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know I've been married three times already? How did that happen?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were just looking for the right man.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles wistfully. Her presence is overwhelming. The silence stretches for a second, pregnant with strange possibilities. Suddenly the phone rings, making him jump. Automatically he picks it up.</context>
      <utterance>They always look right at the start.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at MARILYN's voluptuous figure. MARILYN looks back innocently and mouths the word "packages". She giggles. He turns crimson with the effort of trying to suppress his own laughter but MARILYN isn't helping. She teasingly makes shapes in the air of just how large the packages might be. He covers the phone, agonised, before they both collapse in irrepressible laughter. COLIN finally pulls himself together.</context>
      <utterance>Everything's fine. Miss Monroe just had... some large packages she needed handling...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>There is a long silence at the other end of the line.</context>
      <utterance>Hello? Milton?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up quickly. They both laugh helplessly. MARILYN smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Milton. I have to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She giggles. COLIN's heart contracts as she casually takes his arm.</context>
      <utterance>Let's walk in the garden. See if we can find any more reporters in the bushes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know it was so pretty out here.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should get out more. See the sights.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She giggles again, her mood lighter.</context>
      <utterance>I am the sights.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at us. We're just like Elsie and the young King. What would Sir Laurence say if he could see us now?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think he'd mind.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him innocently. COLIN hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>I wanted to be an artist. To grow as an actor. I was so proud to be working with the great Olivier.  Now he thinks I'm the enemy.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He doesn't understand your kind of actor. He's hated the method ever since Vivien worked with Elia Kazan. It's all too new and strange. You're the future, and it frightens him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him, her eyes huge. COLIN feels his senses swim as he stares into them... ... and then ROGER suddenly appears on the steps.</context>
      <utterance>Every time I walk into the studio I feel this sense of doom come over me. He looks at me like he's smelling a pile of rotten fish. And the crew hate me. Paula is the only person I can trust.  Except for you now, maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARILYN goes back up the path towards the house, glancing back briefly at Colin.</context>
      <utterance>Phone call for you, Miss Monroe. It's Mr. Miller.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN stares after her. It is a second before he realises that ROGER is gazing at him sternly.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Colin. Thanks for telling me the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll be leaving now, I expect.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hear you spent last night with Marilyn.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't spend the night with her. We just had a chat.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OLIVIER offers COLIN a lewdly suggestive grin.</context>
      <utterance>I heard them chuckling.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps if Colin is very diplomatic Marilyn is more likely to behave herself.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She just wants a chum, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He barges out of the room, slamming the door behind him. OLIVIER checks the effect of his Grand Duke in the mirror and sighs abruptly.</context>
      <utterance>A chum? Jesus Christ, what is this, Goodbye Mr. Chips? Grow up, kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gazes at himself thoughtfully.</context>
      <utterance>I thought working with Marilyn would make me feel young again. But I look dead in the rushes. Dead behind the eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He leans back.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps I'm angry with her because in my heart I know my own career is in a terrible rut. I wanted to renew myself through her but all I see reflected in that magnificent face is my own inadequacy.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>COLIN waits, uncertain why OLIVIER is confiding in him.</context>
      <utterance>You know, I admire Marilyn. I really do. Despite her behaviour. She has taken everything Hollywood can throw at her and triumphed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He glances up at COLIN in the mirror, shrewd and sympathetic.</context>
      <utterance>An actress has to be pretty tough to get even a tenth as far as she has.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But be careful, boy. She doesn't need to be rescued. Not really.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SOUNDMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was Marilyn like then, Col?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARDWICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Going over her lines with her, were you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOUNDMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is all good-natured stuff but COLIN feels strangely protective, not so much on his own behalf as Marilyn's.</context>
      <utterance>Will she be in today or is she too tired?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was just being friendly.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATTIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There are hoots of laughter. COLIN retreats to a corner only to find RICHARD WATTIS pursuing him.</context>
      <utterance>I'll bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATTIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ever heard of the Venus Fly Trap? There you are, Colin the innocent little fly buzzing about happily, when suddenly a heavenly scent attracts you and - Snap!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, fuck off, Dickie. You've never slept with a woman in your life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ORTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It has just dawned on COLIN that he has missed his date with LUCY. Before he can react he is jerked violently behind the scenery and pushed up against the wall by an angry MILTON.</context>
      <utterance>Three minutes, ladies and gents. Three minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arthur Miller called me. He's not happy with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He doesn't even know who I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marilyn must have said something.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ORTON turns around frowning furiously at the voices behind the set. MILTON pushes COLIN off the set ahead of him.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe she was trying to make him jealous...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN is about to protest but MILTON ignores him.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, kid, I've known Marilyn for seven years. I fell in love with her, just like you've done.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We had ten days together and that was it. She picked me up, she put me down. That's what she does. She breaks hearts. She'll break yours. My advice to you is to quit before you get burned.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't need your advice. And I'm not in love with her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I waited for you on Friday.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I've just been so busy.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, God... I'm sorry... I forgot...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode>SHARP</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I hear.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode>SHRUGS</mode>
      <context>There's nothing in it.</context>
      <utterance>You know how crews gossip.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN is put out. Up to now he has never fully confronted the possibility of Marilyn wanting him, but he doesn't like the idea being dismissed so lightly. Lucy sees it and her eyes widen in surprise and hurt. Before she can respond MARILYN herself coming towards them in her gown, her hair up in towel, surrounded by PAULA and her MAKE-UP people. She offers him a dazzling smile.</context>
      <utterance>Of course there isn't. Marilyn Monroe fancying you? Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN smiles, self-conscious. MARILYN stops and frowns, looking at Lucy.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Colin.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She looks at him expectantly and suddenly his growing fantasy that she might actually be interested in him kicks in hard. He shrugs casually.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, are you guys dating? That's what I heard.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His voice trails off lamely as he realises he is repeating what he has just said to Lucy. MARILYN smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Of course not. You know how crews like to gossip.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks off with her retinue. There is a long pause. COLIN looks up to see LUCY staring at him in dismay. There are sudden tears in her eyes, which she wipes away angrily.</context>
      <utterance>Too bad. You look cute together.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you were different.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lucy, I really like you. We've had such fun...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shoves the rack of clothes back towards the wardrobe department. Part of him knows he should go after her, but in the end he just stays where he is. He can't help feeling an unworthy sense of relief.</context>
      <utterance>And now it's time to set your sights a little higher. I get it.  Who do you think you are, Cary Grant?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN looks at him in confusion. The studio doors open and MILTON emerges. He glances darkly at COLIN and ROGER.</context>
      <utterance>Get in.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any problem, Roger?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN looks surprised. MILTON notices. COLIN stubs out his cigarette and hurries to the passenger door.</context>
      <utterance>Just dropped by to take Colin out to lunch.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not taking him to Marilyn? That would drop us all in a whole ocean of shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MILTON sees a bulky blanket on the back seat.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you have in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN looks at him, bemused. He gets in quickly. MILTON frowns but shrugs and walks off with a wave.</context>
      <utterance>Just a picnic. We've been looking forward to it, haven't we, Colin?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inside the car COLIN looks at ROGER.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, well, have a nice time boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the same moment MARILYN herself erupts from under the blanket in the back.</context>
      <utterance>Is she okay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jesus - She laughs, looking wonderfully naughty.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roger and I decided to take you out for an adventure. Didn't we Roger?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode>PAINED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Indeed we did.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tries to scramble out but MARILYN hauls him back gleefully.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, God. If Milton sees me with you... I'll be sacked...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pats the seat next to her.</context>
      <utterance>No one can sack you, Colin.  Except me, of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Before COLIN can respond he sees the curious MILTON running back, having spotted MARILYN in the back.</context>
      <utterance>I don't like being on my own in the back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He peers into the back window. MARILYN screams and buries herself back under the blanket. COLIN scrambles to get over into the back seat while ROGER stamps on the accelerator and the car roars off.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - SHOUTS</mode>
      <context>COLIN winces. ROGER looks at him sympathetically. MARILYN emerges from under the blanket, tousled and laughing.</context>
      <utterance>Colin! Get back here, you little bastard! You're fired! Do you hear me? Fired!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN can't help laughing. He finally tumbles into the back seat with MARILYN as the car speeds away. She scoots up to make room for him.</context>
      <utterance>Do you think he saw me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She threads her arm through his. He gazes down at their hands meshed together. ROGER's disapproval registers in the faintest flicker of his eyes. In the background the defeated and frustrated MILTON watches the car speed away.</context>
      <utterance>Snuggle up. This is fun.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN smiles. Impulsively MARILYN hugs him.</context>
      <utterance>This is how I ought to feel every day.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He turns ashen.</context>
      <utterance>Let's run away together.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - LAUGHS</mode>
      <context>She looks around happily. COLIN smiles at her.</context>
      <utterance>Just kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have today, anyway. One day to do whatever we like. We can go back to real life tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only one day?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, maybe the weekend.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grins. She takes his hand, walking contentedly at his side.</context>
      <utterance>Or a week?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What shall we do?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARILYN's face breaks into a smile of pure delight.</context>
      <utterance>We could go to Windsor Castle, if you like.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the policemen see MARILYN their eyes widen.</context>
      <utterance>Detective Chief Superintendant Smith. I'm escorting this lady and gentleman for the day. They'd like to look around the castle.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares in disbelief. ROGER smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Christ, is that..?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's not Diana bloody Dors, is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ROGER looks stumped at this. He turns to Marilyn.</context>
      <utterance>Does she know anyone here, sir? We need to write down a contact name in the book.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know Her Majesty, by any chance?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We met at a movie premiere. She said my dress was pretty.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure that quite...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode>INTERRUPTING</mode>
      <context>The POLICEMAN looks sceptically at Colin's casual clothes.</context>
      <utterance>My Godfather works here. He's the Royal librarian, Sir Owen Morshead.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Name?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The POLICEMAN retreats into his box. We hear him talking on the telephone. ROGER looks at COLIN. He shrugs sheepishly.</context>
      <utterance>Clark. Colin Clark.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A moment later the policeman returns, looking surprised.</context>
      <utterance>My father knows everybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He says to go straight up the hill, sir. You'll be met at the door.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MORSHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles at MARILYN, showing no sign whatever of recognising her.</context>
      <utterance>Colin, my boy! Come in, come in. Forgive the dust.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORSHEAD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>MARILYN looks around in awe.</context>
      <utterance>You are pretty, my dear. I'm sure you and Colin have so much in common.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gee, I'd love to read all these books some time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MORSHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He finds a portfolio on the table and opens it.</context>
      <utterance>Luckily one doesn't really have to. A lot of them just have pictures in.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORSHEAD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>MARILYN smiles at a portrait of a young woman.</context>
      <utterance>These are by an artist called Holbein.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORSHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was the daughter of one of the King's courtiers, nearly 400 years ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope I look that good when I'm</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MORSHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And these are all by Leonardo Da Vinci.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him, wide-eyed, playing up to her image as the dizzy blonde. In fact she knows exactly who Da Vinci is, and MORSHEAD is tactful enough to acknowledge it gracefully.</context>
      <utterance>I've heard of him! Didn't he paint that lady with the funny smile?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORSHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Mona Lisa.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have that one here too?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORSHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He closes the portfolio and takes MARILYN's arm briskly.</context>
      <utterance>Alas, that one got away.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORSHEAD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>MARILYN looks at him, wide-eyed.</context>
      <utterance>Now, let's go to the Queen's apartments. She's not here at the moment, but she will be sorry to have missed you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MORSHEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shares a sly smile with COLIN. He knows exactly who Marilyn is and is enjoying every second of her company. He leads her out, with COLIN trailing in their wake.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes. Why, she was only saying to me the other day, "what must it be like to be the most famous woman on earth"?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORSHEAD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some of the rooms are very opulent but I think there's something you might like better than all that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN kneels at her side.</context>
      <utterance>Look, Colin.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She sees a perfect doll family inside, husband, wife and two children. She points at them, her eyes shining.</context>
      <utterance>I sure never had a dolls' house like this when I was a kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She smiles wistfully and puts her hand on his arm.</context>
      <utterance>This is me, that's you, and these are our kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Her eyes fill with sadness for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Our daughter's so pretty. All little girls should be told how pretty they are. They should grow up knowing how much their mother loves them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We look like such a happy family, don't we?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She jumps up onto a step and strikes a pose - hip out, shoulders back, bosom thrust forward, the classic Marilyn "look". The delighted crowd bursts into cheers. COLIN stands proudly nearby, content to watch Marilyn being a star, basking in the certain knowledge that she will be leaving with him. One of the spectators turns to him.</context>
      <utterance>Shall I be "her"?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPECTATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you somebody, mate?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode>SMILES</mode>
      <context>COLIN stares at MARILYN. She catches his eye and smiles, just for him. He feels like he's tumbling into the abyss, but no longer cares.</context>
      <utterance>I'm no one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN smiles.</context>
      <utterance>This isn't a school, it's a palace!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eton is 500 years old. It was founded by King Henry VI.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's like walking through history.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stop as COLIN points up at a window.</context>
      <utterance>Take that room up there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARILYN looks at him in shock.</context>
      <utterance>That's where the boys were sent if they didn't work hard enough. Where we were whipped.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whipped?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks appalled.</context>
      <utterance>Beaten.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(pause) How long were you here?</context>
      <utterance>I'd never send my kids away.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five years. But I was sent to boarding school when I was eight.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what we do in my family. She smiles at this, looking at him shrewdly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It seems to me that you've had most things pretty easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him, sympathetic but pushing a little harder.</context>
      <utterance>In one way, yes. But when you're brought up in a house of over- achievers, it's hard to make your own mark.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how are you going to do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe it will be in films, but if not, there are so many possibilities out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles warmly, liking him a lot more for his openness. We sense their relationship has moved quietly to a different and deeper level. But before either of them can say anything a SCHOOLBOY turns the corner in his Eton uniform.</context>
      <utterance>Sounds pretty good to me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A gawky young teenager near the front shouts out cheekily.</context>
      <utterance>Work hard, boys! I don't want anyone whipping you!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARILYN laughs in delight. There are cheers as COLIN escorts her away.</context>
      <utterance>You can whip me anytime, Marilyn!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hurry up, slow poke.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops in mid-sentence as he sees MARILYN unbuttoning her blouse and throwing it off carelessly.</context>
      <utterance>But we haven't got any...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is great.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if a boat goes past? We could be arrested.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds her head and he looks at her with concern.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. Roger will fix it. Oh, darn it...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He swims across to her, very aware of her naked body under the water. She holds her head up to him.</context>
      <utterance>I have something in my eye.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't see anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tips her head back. He looks deep into her eyes - and suddenly she grabs him and kisses him on the lips. Before he can respond she laughs playfully and swims away.</context>
      <utterance>Get closer.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She swims happily, totally relaxed. COLIN is much more self- conscious, keeping one nervous eye open for pleasure boats. Finally she swims back into the shallows and wades to the shore. She glances back, catching Colin looking. He glances away, embarrassed.</context>
      <utterance>That's the first time I've kissed anyone younger than me. There's a lot of older guys in Hollywood.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>COLIN wades awkwardly to the shore, trying to conceal his erection with his cupped hands. MARILYN giggles.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be shy, Colin. It's nothing you haven't seen before.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He grins. She reaches for her blouse and stands shivering as she tries to dry herself. COLIN goes to take her in his arms.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Colin! And you an old Etonian!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She snuggles into him gratefully, her teeth chattering. He rubs her naked back briskly, her thin blouse the only barrier between their bodies. Slowly his embrace becomes more sensual, his hands slowing, stroking rather than rubbing, his face buried in her hair, his arms pulling her</context>
      <utterance>Let me warm you up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him, her expression knowing but sweet.</context>
      <utterance>Don't spoil it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He tries to kiss her but she ducks her head away gently, her expression wistful.</context>
      <utterance>I want this to be the perfect date.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She suddenly looks much younger, her smile a poignant echo of a lost childhood. He steps back politely, allowing her to put on her blouse. As she buttons it, she gazes at him, then impulsively leans forward to kiss him chastely on the lips. The kiss is as sweet and innocent as any 13 year old might wish. The kiss lasts for a few seconds, their lips touching gently, the river shimmering magically in the sunshine behind them. When they finally break apart she rewards him with a radiant smile.</context>
      <utterance>I haven't had a real date since I was 13 years old.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She looks wistful for a second but quickly brightens.</context>
      <utterance>That was nice. I don't get kissed much.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>COLIN looks at her, knowing it is time to return to the real world but reluctant to face it. There is a discreet cough and ROGER appears.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, what do we do now?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles, a little sadly, then gets up, walking past him as she puts on the rest of her clothes. ROGER averts his eyes respectfully and waits for COLIN. The two men look at each other for a second.</context>
      <utterance>Time to go home, I think, Miss Monroe.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>COLIN knows he isn't talking about the river.</context>
      <utterance>Be careful not to get in too deep, son.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="143" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles sweetly.</context>
      <utterance>Hi Milton.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He looks at her in shock then bitterly at COLIN.</context>
      <utterance>Next time I come on set, you better make sure Colin is there.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - TO ROGER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take him home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="144" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You spent the day with her. What frame of mind was she in?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>HUGE SELF-CONTROL</mode>
      <context>He stalks off. COLIN sees WATTIS grinning at him.</context>
      <utterance>Well, find out what's going on. There's a good chap. Perhaps we can persuade her on this splendid day to do the work she's paying herself to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't start, Dicky.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATTIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You won't get any sympathy from me, dear. Frankly I wouldn't care if Marilyn dropped dead tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's trying her best.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATTIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN doesn't laugh. WATTIS looks at him sympathetically.</context>
      <utterance>She's Marilyn Monroe. This is her life. Pills, booze, sex, more pills.  God, it must be wonderful!</utterance>
   <speaker>WATTIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, dear. Little Colin's in love.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="145" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MILTON looks at him for a long moment, masking his hostility in barbed politeness.</context>
      <utterance>But she was wonderful yesterday.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you did to her, kid, but she got nervous. I had to give her some pills to calm her down.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She doesn't need pills! She just needs someone to care for her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN reddens. MILTON shakes his head patronisingly.</context>
      <utterance>Someone like you?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you, I'm not in love with her!</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You kissed her.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She said that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN stares at him, feeling hopelessly out of his depth.</context>
      <utterance>Spare me the bullshit. I know everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He comes very close, his tone fierce but wounded.</context>
      <utterance>You messed her up, kid. Confused her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He goes back to the house, pausing at the door, speaking more in sorrow than anger.</context>
      <utterance>I've got every penny I ever made tied up in Marilyn. She owes me. If it wasn't for me she'd still be on contracts that make slave wages look good. I gave her back her freedom, and now Miller's turning her against me. That's what you get for trying to help Marilyn Monroe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="146" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context>COLIN opens his eyes, his mind drugged with sleep.</context>
      <utterance>Colin!  Colin!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roger? What's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context>A cold dread clutches at COLIN's stomach. He stumbles out of bed and opens the door. ROGER stands in the doorway</context>
      <utterance>It's Marilyn.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is she dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I think she might be in a coma.</context>
      <utterance>She's asking for you. She's sick.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can she be asking for me if she's in a coma?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just bloody get dressed!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="147" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She hasn't made a sound for over an hour.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should break down the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many pills did she take?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN knocks gently.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jesus, who knows? I wasn't counting.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is no reply.</context>
      <utterance>Marilyn?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="148" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points with his torch. The window is open. COLIN shins up the ladder while ROGER holds it.</context>
      <utterance>That's her window.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll open the door once I'm inside.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="149" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A shaft of moonlight reveals MARILYN lying naked across the bed, her body partly covered by the sheet. Half empty pill and champagne bottles are scattered all over her dresser; there is also an old photograph in a silver frame of her mother Gladys.</context>
      <utterance>Marilyn?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>For a second he fears the worst, but then suddenly she groans and sits up, looking at him blearily.</context>
      <utterance>Marilyn?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="150" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh hi, Colin.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you okay? Everyone was worried about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pats the sheets at her side and settles down sleepily on the pillow.</context>
      <utterance>Phooey.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She is instantly back asleep. COLIN fumbles his way to the door. He searches for the key on the side table and quickly finds it. He goes to unlock the door, but then pauses, looking back at Marilyn. He puts the key back and bends down to whisper at the keyhole.</context>
      <utterance>Get in.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's me. She's fine but I'm going to keep an eye on her. I'll sleep on the sofa.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Colin, open up.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't find the key.  You can all go to bed now.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context>COLIN goes back to the bed and gazes at the sleeping Marilyn, his expression suffused with a tenderness we have never seen in him before. He pulls up the sheet so that it covers her nakedness, then tentatively lies down to rest his head on the pillow.</context>
      <utterance>Colin, open this door! She needs me...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="151" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He realises this doesn't sound reassuring.</context>
      <utterance>I came in through the window...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She stares at him in puzzlement then breaks into a dazed smile.</context>
      <utterance>Milton thought you were sick.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches instinctively for the pill container on her bedside table.</context>
      <utterance>The window? Is there a balcony, like in Romeo And Juliet? How romantic.  But I'm not sick. What makes them think that?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She frowns, clutching the pill bottle in one hand. He reaches out and prises it gently from her grasp. As he puts it back on the side he glances at the framed photograph. COLIN (CONT'D) (cont'd) Who's that?</context>
      <utterance>Please don't take any more pills.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her expression softens as she looks at the picture.</context>
      <utterance>My mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Alongside her mother's photo is another framed picture, this time of Abraham Lincoln. COLIN frowns.</context>
      <utterance>They took her to the Sanatorium when I was a kid. I grew up in other people's homes, mostly.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Abraham Lincoln?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles, then looks at Colin wistfully.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know who my father is so it might as well be him. Why not? I can pick any father I want.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have a home, Colin? A real one?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="152" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And a mother and father who still live together?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And do they love you?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods. She smiles sadly.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sure they do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes fill with tears. She looks up at him anxiously.</context>
      <utterance>You're lucky.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He stares at her. She looks lovely but desperately vulnerable.</context>
      <utterance>Do you love me, Colin?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches for the pills and pours three or four into her palm. COLIN gently takes her hand and takes two of them away. She smiles, not objecting as he settles her back gently on the pillow.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you and I come from different worlds. You're like some Greek Goddess to me...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles, teasing him. He smiles back. She takes his hand, looking at him in appeal.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not Greek.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to be a Goddess. I just want to be loved like an ordinary girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares at him, her face going blank with misery.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Miller loves you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I found his notebook. It said I'd let him down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="153" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him, her eyes full of pain.</context>
      <utterance>Writers scribble all kinds of things. It doesn't mean anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks so wretched, so completely baffled, that COLIN responds with sudden passion.</context>
      <utterance>He wanted me to find it. It said he should never have married me. That I was unpredictable and a woman-child, flighty and self- centred. He's left me, Colin. Why do the people I love always leave me?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles and embraces him gratefully. She sighs.</context>
      <utterance>I'll never leave you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lies down next to her, taking her awkwardly in his arms. She sighs sleepily.</context>
      <utterance>All people ever see is Marilyn Monroe. As soon as they realise I'm not her, they run.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She looks across at him, their faces inches apart.</context>
      <utterance>Boy, there's a lot of men in this business. And they all think you've got to sleep with them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>COLIN stares back at her guiltily. She smiles.</context>
      <utterance>You're not like that. That's why I like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should date that Wardrobe lady. She's pretty.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares at him and tears gather in her eyes again. They stare intently at each other, their mood fragile, touched with both sensuality and a longing for something less tangible. MARILYN leans forward and kisses him gently. The embrace grows in passion and they kiss properly, hungrily. He kisses her eyes and her face and she sighs happily. He wants her more than he has wanted anything before.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to.  I love you, Marilyn.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="154" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter? Don't you want to make love?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe we should just be friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She wraps herself around him, curling up so their bodies cradle each other like spoons in a cutlery draw. As she buries her head in his neck he feels her breasts against his back. She curls against him.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is nice. Like spoons. I used to do this with Johnny.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's Johnny?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her voice is blurred and drifting with sleep. With her body warm against him COLIN's resolve nearly snaps but he is clear eyed now and determined.</context>
      <utterance>Johnny Hyde. My agent, back in the old days. He was thin, like you...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She mutters softly in reply.</context>
      <utterance>Marilyn?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do one thing for me? Come into the studio on time tomorrow and show everybody what you can do. Show Larry you're a great actress.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>BLURRED</mode>
      <context>He smiles and turns out the light.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="155" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at him thoughtfully, then shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Morning, boy.  Christ, you look rough.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>If she ever does.</context>
      <utterance>Let me know when Marilyn arrives.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OLIVIER gives COLIN an odd look.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm pretty sure she'll be in this morning.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="156" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WATTIS</speaker>
      <mode>AS NORTHBROOK</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Your Grand Ducal Highness.."</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>AS REGENT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"This is intolerable"!</utterance>
   <speaker>WATTIS</speaker>
      <mode>AS NORTHBROOK</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"With the deepest respect, sir, my message was so important I had no choice but to intrude".</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="157" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>AS REGENT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Revolution?"</utterance>
   <speaker>WATTIS</speaker>
      <mode>AS NORTHBROOK</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"No, sir, Miss Marina's aunt has been in a motor accident. The hospital is calling for her most urgently."</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>AS ELSIE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"What?  Oh, go away, you silly man."</utterance>
   <speaker>WATTIS</speaker>
      <mode>AS NORTHBROOK</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Miss Marina, your aunt... you realise how serious her condition is?"</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>AS ELSIE</mode>
      <context>MARILYN is utterly adorable. The crew, COLIN, amongst them, can't take their eyes off her. OLIVIER glances at ORTON behind the camera. They have a good take and they know it.</context>
      <utterance>"Well, it's her own fault. She has no right being out at this time of night. She's 93!"</utterance>
   <speaker>ORTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARILYN is as happy as we have ever seen her. She seeks out COLIN amongst the crowd and beams at him. Half the crew, including OLIVIER, notice the look. COLIN blushes self- consciously but we can feel his pride.</context>
      <utterance>Cut it there!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="158" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OLIVIER grins slyly and COLIN doesn't bother to protest. The phone rings. OLIVIER picks it up.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever it was you did to her, boy, keep doing it.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>His face falls as he listens to the voice at the other end of the line.</context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="159" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is taken aback by her passion. She smiles bitterly then walks on. COLIN hesitates. She looks back briefly.</context>
      <utterance>From the first moment all I have felt is Olivier's loathing and contempt. He thinks I'm unnecessary. Me, her drama coach, surrogate mother, nursemaid. On call 24 hours a day to help her act, dole out pills, bolster her ego, keep her sober enough to work.  Me. Unnecessary.  No me, no Marilyn.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can come up now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="160" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I can act, don't you, Colin?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PAULA looks at MILTON, then moves between them busily.</context>
      <utterance>Of course I do. You were wonderful today.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marilyn's tired now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want him to stay with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A flicker of terror crosses MARILYN's face. COLIN turns on them angrily.</context>
      <utterance>What would Arthur say if he knew Colin was here?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You heard what she said. She wants me here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="161" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have no idea of your position in the world, Marilyn. You are the greatest actress there's ever been. Not just actress. The greatest woman of this or any time. I love you like a daughter. COLIN is surprised to see tears in her eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Paula's love and sincerity are obvious. She means it. COLIN watches her in silence. MARILYN squeezes her hand and PAULA gets up with a heavy sigh, bitterly reluctant to leave. Finally she drags herself out, leaving them alone. As the door closes MARILYN curls herself up in the bed.</context>
      <utterance>It's hard now, but believe me you will survive this and go on to better things. Your life is ahead of you. You're young, just beginning.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN looks at her, his heart breaking at her anguish.</context>
      <utterance>I'm so tired of feeling scared. Life is so shitty. I hate it. It hurts too much.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives him a wry look, teasing but thoughtful.</context>
      <utterance>I'm here now. I'll look after you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is an edge to this. He gazes at her, shaken, but she smiles and touches his face gently. He gets on the bed, fully clothed, to fold her in his arms.</context>
      <utterance>Good old Colin. Looking after me, looking after Larry, looking after Vivien. Always putting everyone before yourself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="162" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is doubled up, clutching her stomach, sweating and frightened. COLIN sees a dark red stain on the sheets.</context>
      <utterance>It hurts! It hurts, Colin!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>COLIN looks at her aghast.</context>
      <utterance>The baby. I can't lose the baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He hurls himself off the bed and runs to the door.</context>
      <utterance>It's a surprise. For Arthur. Don't tell anyone. Promise me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="163" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN turns the handle but the bathroom door is locked.</context>
      <utterance>The doctor's coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marilyn, unlock the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>OFF</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't let anyone in.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MILTON gives him a sharp look but he no longer cares about anything except Marilyn. There is a shuffling sound and the door is unlocked. At the same moment PAULA comes rushing in, hair awry, gown flapping, a wild look in her eye.</context>
      <utterance>I won't.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marilyn! Marilyn, my baby, what has Colin done to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't done anything. She's just... got a stomach ache. He reddens with embarrassment. ROGER coughs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="164" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think he means her monthlies.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What will Arthur say if she dies?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The HOUSEKEEPER now appears at the door with an elderly man at her side. He nods briskly.</context>
      <utterance>She's not dying, for Christ's sake.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Dr. Connell. Is the patient in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CONNELL calmly extracts himself from her grasp.</context>
      <utterance>Please save her... it's Marilyn Monroe. You can't let her die.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As COLIN shepherds the others out MILTON turns on him bitterly.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps you'd all like to give us a little privacy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Happy now, kid?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="165" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MILTON, PAULA, ROGER and COLIN all step forward as one. CONNELL gives them a wry look and shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Who's in charge here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>PAULA leans forward and almost snatches the prescription from his hand.</context>
      <utterance>I've given Mrs. Miller an injection and the bleeding has stopped. She needs to stay in bed tomorrow but after that she'll be fine. I suggest someone stays with her.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She'll be safe with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MY WEEK WITH MARILYN 109.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She looks bitterly at Colin.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="166" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN holds the door open as he gets in.</context>
      <utterance>Well, goodnight then.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was she really pregnant?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at COLIN with cool disapproval, then closes the door and drives off. COLIN stands watching, shivering in his shirtsleeves.</context>
      <utterance>I think that's a private matter between Mr and Mrs. Miller.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="167" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles wistfully at the fantasy.</context>
      <utterance>We have to say goodbye now, Colin. Arthur's on his way back. When this film is over I'm going to settle down and be a good wife to him. I'm going to learn to make Matzo ball soup as good as his dad's.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to forget this ever happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He struggles then suddenly bursts out passionately.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to forget.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She smiles sadly.</context>
      <utterance>Let me protect you from all this...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="168" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want to do? Marry me?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is close to tears, suddenly looking very young. She looks at him with a sad, sweet smile. He shakes his head stubbornly, taking her hand in passionate appeal.</context>
      <utterance>Why not? You could come and live at my parents place. You'd love it. It's a castle, like in a fairy tale. We wouldn't even have to live together. You could have your own suite of rooms...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could quit. Forget Marilyn Monroe, forget Hollywood. Let it all go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is what I've worked for my whole life. I couldn't just give it all up.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes widen in surprise. A flicker of nervous insecurity dulls her expression.</context>
      <utterance>Why not, when it drives you crazy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I'm crazy?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean that. I just meant you could be happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles tentatively, but he sees a terrible fear in her eyes. He looks down, realising with a cruel stab of pain that Olivier was right. There is no way back. She doesn't want to be rescued. He finally looks up, smiling despite the tears in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I am happy. I got everything I ever dreamed about.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles, reassured. He drags himself off the bed and goes to the door, pausing for a second as he looks back.</context>
      <utterance>Of course you're happy.  You're a star. The biggest star in the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right, Marilyn. We have to forget all this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="169" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She giggles with some of her old playfulness.</context>
      <utterance>From now on I'm nobody. Just the third. You don't even know I exist. We'll never look at each other again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles, looks at her just once more, and then goes out. As the door closes we see Marilyn's smile fade to be replaced by a bleak, frightened expression.</context>
      <utterance>Well, maybe just a wink. Once in a while.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="170" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're ready for you on set, Sir Laurence.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marilyn?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's just arrived.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles, then stands up, straightening his uniform.</context>
      <utterance>Only an hour late. Not bad by her standards.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe we will finish this bloody film after all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="171" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She smiles up at their uneasy expressions, struggling to understand herself and their expectations of her.</context>
      <utterance>I hope you will all forgive me. It wasn't altogether my fault. I have been ill.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>This oddly moving and open confession is received in silence. No one quite knows how to react to her lacerating honesty. Perhaps they think it is just another performance.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like you to remember I tried.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="172" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>AS ELSIE</mode>
      <context>She sings with touching delicacy, nailing it perfectly. There is pin drop silence on the set as the crew watch. COLIN is amongst them. It is a moment of almost unbearable poignancy for him. He suddenly realises that SYBIL THORNDIKE has crept up silently behind him to watch the scene. As he turns to her she smiles with infinite wisdom and compassion, murmuring softly so that only he can hear.</context>
      <utterance>"..I found a dream and lay in your arms the whole night through, I'm yours no matter what others may say or do. Be light of heart and fancy free, that's the way to start, there will be nothing to lose till you lose your heart.."</utterance>
   <speaker>SYBIL THORNDIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She touches his cheek gently and smiles, perhaps lost in a long ago memory of her own, before retreating quietly into the darkness at the back of the set.</context>
      <utterance>First love is such sweet despair, Colin.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="173" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ORTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The big overhead lights switch on with a series of heavy clunks.</context>
      <utterance>Very quiet, studio! Going for a take.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Camera running! Speed!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="174" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>AS REGENT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"My dear..."</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>AS ELSIE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"I've got a solemn word of warning for you."</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>AS REGENT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"What's that, my beloved?"</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>AS ELSIE</mode>
      <context>CLOSE on MARILYN as she smiles, her face radiating joy and vitality. And then, in the split second before ORTON calls `cut', MARILYN turns her head just a fraction and winks at Colin. He grins. OLIVIER looks up from the sofa, notices and smiles indulgently.</context>
      <utterance>"You know what's going to happen? I'm going to fall in love with you, because I always, always do."</utterance>
   <speaker>ORTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a smattering of applause from the crew. MARILYN leaves the stage.</context>
      <utterance>Cut! Okay boys and girls, that's a wrap!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="175" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MILTON indicates a trestle table at one end of the studio, loaded with gaily wrapped parcels. He ushers the crew over.</context>
      <utterance>If you'd all like to step this way, you'll find something I think you'll like.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A parting gift to each of you from Marilyn. Men on the left, ladies on the right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="176" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't you going to throw yours away?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles. She shrugs and turns to leave.</context>
      <utterance>Of course not. It's from Marilyn Monroe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="177" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns back to look at him.</context>
      <utterance>Lucy?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was wondering if you're doing anything this Saturday.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods, accepting this as no more than he deserves. She goes but then stops to look back at him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm washing my hair.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did she break your heart?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is no malice in her response, just an awareness that he is older and wiser now, and perhaps a better man for the experience. He nods, accepting the rebuke.</context>
      <utterance>Good. It needed breaking.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>COLIN smiles. She goes out. He looks down at Marilyn's present in his hands.</context>
      <utterance>I might be free on Wednesday.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="178" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These our actors,/As I foretold you, were all spirits and/Are melted into air, into thin air...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Prospero.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>SMILES</mode>
      <context>COLIN sits down next to the great man. They watch in silence as another sequence is projected for them. The sequence shows MARILYN improvising in the champagne and caviar scene. She serves herself food and drink before collapsing, drunk. The endless retakes and fluffs gone, what remains is a gifted comic performance by a luminous beauty.</context>
      <utterance>We are such stuff/As dreams are made on, and our little life/Is rounded with a sleep..."</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He seems almost lost in awe. COLIN gazes at him in surprise.</context>
      <utterance>She's quite wonderful. No training, no craft, no guile, just pure instinct. Astonishing.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should tell her that.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles wryly.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I will. But she won't believe me. That's probably what makes her great. It's certainly what makes her so profoundly unhappy.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He signals to the projection box and the film stops as the lights come up.</context>
      <utterance>I tried my best to change her, but she remains brilliant despite me.  Directing a movie has to be just about the best job ever invented, but Marilyn has cured me of ever wanting to do it again.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And now I'm going back to the theatre. John Osborne is writing a piece for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you hated all that Royal Court stuff.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="179" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>SMILES</mode>
      <context>He goes to the door and pauses.</context>
      <utterance>Miller made me see things differently.  You have to find new worlds to conquer, if you want to be the best. And believe me, most of the time, I really am the best.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLIVIER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He goes out. COLIN looks back up at the projection box.</context>
      <utterance>You've done a good job, boy.  Welcome to the circus.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The lights go down. MARILYN's face appears on the screen, laughing and happy. It is another sequence, the one where Marilyn does her sweet, uninhibited little dance (Scene 90), a performance both sexy and yet touchingly innocent. HOLD on COLIN for a long moment, gazing at her image in the darkness, then -</context>
      <utterance>Run it again, please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="180" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN doesn't turn. He recognizes the voice and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Buy a girl a drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BARRY for once is silent, pours a pint. The regulars try not to stare.</context>
      <utterance>Can I get another one of those please, Barry?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't want to leave without saying goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>MY WEEK WITH MARILYN 117A.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>MARILYN hands COLIN a package.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Colin opens the package. It's her copy of the script. On the first page she has written a message scrawled in ink: TO THE</context>
      <utterance>The first time you saw this, all I had on was the radio.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="181" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't forget me.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As if I could.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone else on the picture wishes they could.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles, touched.</context>
      <utterance>Everyone else doesn't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be a gentleman and walk me to my car?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="182" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that for?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARILYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ROGER walks around the car and looks over at COLIN.</context>
      <utterance>That's for being on my side; and remember, when you see me wink, that's for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was that really Marilyn Monroe?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="183" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE SECRETARY pushes a piece of paper at him.</context>
      <utterance>Any messages?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN looks down at the message. There is a Los Angeles phone number and then the name - Marilyn Monroe.</context>
      <utterance>It's probably just someone having a joke.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did she say anything?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="184" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COLIN stares down at the paper.</context>
      <utterance>She just asked you to call.  It is a joke, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably.  Book a call as soon as you can. Los Angeles, California. Brentwood 1890.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
