<movie id="406" title="Mystery Men">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BIERCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one can deny the horrendous nature of Mr. Frankenstein's crimes, but in the twenty years he has been with us, I have never seen a patient turn his energies to more productive use. CASANOVA, the picture of remorse and repentance.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIERCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON SEVERAL OF THE BOARD getting misty eyed at the memory of that brilliant performance...</context>
      <utterance>Just look at his accomplishments... three volumes of poetry, two rock operas, a sculpture garden, four romance novels... and who can forget his touching portrayal of Billy Bigelow in our all-psychotic production of "Carousel"...</utterance>
   <speaker>BIERCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON DOCTOR ANABEL LEEK, the hospital's icily beautiful, ultra cool, top shrink. A moment later Casanova addresses them... His manner is charming, sincere, his voice soft, filled with emotion. He is a master of seduction.</context>
      <utterance>Directed by our own Doctor Anabel Leek.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doctor Bierce wipes the tears from his eyes. Reactions from the board, moved, as Casanova weeps convulsively. Doctor Leek shows no reaction.</context>
      <utterance>Twenty years ago I was a lost soul. Loveless...  Fatherless...  A... psycho!  Oh! How could I have done it? The murder... the mayhem... all of those lovely young girls!  I'm sorry! I'm SO SO SORRY!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the hospital EXPLODES in a HUGE FIREBALL that completely consumes it.</context>
      <utterance>Boom.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those gas leaks can be murder.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>RED EYE 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Several more Red Eyes emerge carrying a sawn off bike rack with bikes still attached, a barber pole, a Virgin Mary lawn statue, and a top of the line baby stroller... while their leader, BIG RED, stands in the door to the boxcar, watching approvingly.</context>
      <utterance>Golf anyone?</utterance>
   <speaker>RED EYE 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not a bad night's work.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Red Eyes laugh... as Red Eye 3 takes the cover off the baby stroller and sees... that there's a BABY still in it.</context>
      <utterance>Who said crime don't pay?</utterance>
   <speaker>RED EYE 3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crooks gather around the baby, a jolly little kid who just laughs at them.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Boss, we got a stowaway.</utterance>
   <speaker>RED EYE 4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who you laughin' at, punk?</utterance>
   <speaker>RED EYE 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's just a tyke. Lighten up.</utterance>
   <speaker>RED EYE 5</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's kinda cute.</utterance>
   <speaker>RED EYE 3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you like drool.</utterance>
   <speaker>RED EYE 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others think that's a great idea, but Big Red doesn't.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, why don't we sell him back to his parents? For a million bucks!</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others hadn't thought of that.</context>
      <utterance>And what if he rats on us?</utterance>
   <speaker>RED EYE 3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what should we do with him?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others think that's a good idea and look around for a brick.</context>
      <utterance>Stick a brick in his Pampers and dump him in the lake.</utterance>
   <speaker>RED EYE 3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But suddenly there is another presence... A man in a blue turban and cape with the initials "BR" on his chest has appeared... He is THE BLUE</context>
      <utterance>Come on, kid, you're goin' for a swim.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another man steps into the light. He wears a construction helmet and mask. There is an "S" on his chest, and he carries an old shovel. He is THE SHOVELER.</context>
      <utterance>Not so fast, gentlemen--and I use the term loosely... Unhand that youngster...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He brandishes his shovel for effect. The Red Eyes look at these two, highly amused.</context>
      <utterance>Or you're mulch.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A third man steps out. His costume is less dramatic than the others. He wears only an old leather jacket and a faded, torn shirt with flames on it, but the fierce look on his face and the atrociousness of his haircut make it very clear that he is the craziest and most dangerous of the three. He is MISTER FURIOUS.</context>
      <utterance>What are you guys supposed to be... superheroes?</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We ARE superheroes!</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? Did you mother make those costumes? The crooks howl with laughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is our territory. Beat it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Big Red turns to the others and shakes with pretended fear.</context>
      <utterance>Over YOUR dead body.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Red Eyes laugh, but suddenly, a small silver projectile whizzes through the air and implants itself in Big Red's backside. He howls with pain, pulls it out and examines it... It's a silver dessert fork.</context>
      <utterance>0ooooo, he's scary.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Raja holds up his hands, each of which hold a spread of silver forks.</context>
      <utterance>A fork!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Big Red gives a shrill whistle, and a dozen more Red Eyes step out of an old caboose... including MIKEY, a four hundred pound behemoth. He is eating a container of Ben and Jerry's like it was an ice cream cone, taking huge bites out of it, container and all. RAJA AND SHOVELER, reacting... Gulp. This was more than they'd bargained for. But Furious just growls; he's game.</context>
      <utterance>And there's plenty more where that came from.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RED EYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crush him, Mikey!... Mash him!... Mush him!</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that all you got?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mikey, sweating, bears down... but suddenly, a calm, very authoritative voice is heard.</context>
      <utterance>Your mother!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>0.S.</mode>
      <context>Everything suddenly stops, as the Red Eyes look up and see... CAPTAIN AMAZING standing on tap of the boxcar, hands on hips, framed in the light at the moon, his biceps bulging, his state of the art physique sculpted body armor gleaming in the moonlight, his cape wafting heroically in the wind. He is superhero perfection incarnate. ON THE RED EYES as their viciousness turns instantly to panic...</context>
      <utterance>Is there a problem?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>RED EYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Police cars and a TV truck come screeching into the train yard... and the scene is suddenly flooded vith light and swarming with cops and reporters... Our three heroes try to approach Captain Amazing (who still looks fresh as a daisy).</context>
      <utterance>We give!... We're sorry!... We had terrible childhoods!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Amazing just walks past them, ignoring them completely, as if they didn't even exist. He goes to greet DAWN WONG (Champion City's answer to Connie Chung).</context>
      <utterance>Nice work, Captain.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMAZING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. Dawn.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like you've done it again, Captain.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMAZING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Our heroes just watch, feeling ignored, humiliated. Furious growls. Suddenly, TWO COPS are accosting them.</context>
      <utterance>It's what I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, show's over. Move it. On your way.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute, Officers. You don't understand-- we're superheroes, and we just busted up this gang.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cops crack up. Furious growls at them. The cops yank out their nightsticks.</context>
      <utterance>Really? Let me guess-you're Towel Head and he's...  Captain Pooper Scooper!</utterance>
   <speaker>COP 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Move it!</utterance>
   <speaker>COP 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get a life!</utterance>
   <speaker>COP 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shoveler and Raja pull Furious away before he gets into real trouble... The cops watch as our three heroes disappear into the night.</context>
      <utterance>And leave crime fighting to the real thing!</utterance>
   <speaker>COP 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wannabes.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pathetic.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's Lance Hunt! Just take off the glasses-- and it's him!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a vague similarity.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A vague similarity? IT'S THE SAME GUY!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We take the licks and he gets the chicks.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long do you have to chase a dream before you realize it's not gonna happen?</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need a break, that's all! Nobody'd ever heard of him until he busted Casanova Frankenstein!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But look at him... and look at us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A depressed silence. Furious turns his attention to the napkin dispenser.</context>
      <utterance>The camera loves him.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I lost another fork tonight. She's getting suspicious, I know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So why don't you just tell her!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I can't! Okay? She wouldn't understand!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave him alone. She's his mother, not yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We had an off night, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A WAITRESS is standing at the table.</context>
      <utterance>So when are we gonna have an on night?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at her, taken aback. She's very pretty.</context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're... new.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE ON FURIOUS, smitten by her, but almost afraid to look at her. Under all that rage, he's in fact shy.</context>
      <utterance>It's my first night. My name's Monica.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys going to a costume party?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're superheroes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Furious growls.</context>
      <utterance>Really? Like Captain Amazing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you famous?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're like... struggling superheroes?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We prefer to think of ourselves as unsung... I am the Blue Raja, Master of Silverware...</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And these are my associatiates, the Shoveler.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Mister Furious... His anger is his power.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Usually a superpower is a magical endowment or a great skill. In his case, it's entirely emotional.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what can I get you?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She likes you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Definitely.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ask her out.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roy, when was the last time you had an actual date?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're chicken?</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monica stands at the counter placing her order. Furious approaches her, leans against the counter. For a moment he just stands there, fuming, unable to think of anything to say. She isn't sure what to make of this.</context>
      <utterance>Who's chicken?</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't it piss you off the way the when you really want to talk to somebody you can't think of anything to say!</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess... Are you always so angry?</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only when I'm awake... You busy after work? She shrugs.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's visibly turned off by that.</context>
      <utterance>Want to go out and get drunk?</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or talk?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(picks up an order and walks away)</context>
      <utterance>Not tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you should try a more romantic approach.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like what? Cutting off my own ear?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or flowers.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Furious kicks his engine started and speeds off into the night as the Shoveler opens the door of his battered Ford Esquire station wagon, and the Raja gets into his ancient Datsun.</context>
      <utterance>See ya tomorrow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, when are you guys gonna clean this place up?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When you're on TV.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE JR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right--like that will ever happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>LENORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON THE SHOVELER, silent, hurt.</context>
      <utterance>Save any babies lately?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Faster than a speeding turtle--</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More powerful than a deodorant--</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE JR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Able to eat twelve donuts in a single sitting--</utterance>
   <speaker>LENORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, snoring in his chair--</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE JR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sitting on the john--</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kids all laugh (in that derisive way that kids do so well) as the Shoveler dejectedly walks into the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>It's... Supergut!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeffrey!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh hi, Mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing in the silver drawer?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She just looks at him, very suspicious.</context>
      <utterance>Looking for... the TV Guide.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's on the television.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her and goes into the next room. CAMERA HOLDS ON MOM; she doesn't trust him.</context>
      <utterance>Of course. I'm such a fool... Thanks, Mummy. Go to bed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope you enjoy these cigars. I had to kill a dozen Cubans to get them.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY P</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ummm.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you considered my offer?</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY P</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, Mr. F, me and the boys always loved workin' for you. You had such style: the clothes, the dancin', the elegant way you'd snuff a babe. You were the King... Casanova accepts this graciously.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY P</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But times have changed, and you been in that bug house a long tine. I can see you still got the style, but I dunno for sure you still got the edge.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY P</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Captain Amazing?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMAZING</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Casanova and Tony P look up and see Captain Amazing, posed noncalantly on the iron catwalk, gazing down at them. Tony P jumps out of his chair, scared. But Casanova just smiles at his ancient rival, cool as a cucumber.</context>
      <utterance>Good question.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew you'd cone. I left that skylight open for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMAZING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew you'd know.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMAZING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you knew I'd know.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But did you know I knew you'd know I'd know?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMAZING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tony P makes a move for his pistol, but Captain Amazing instantly whips out his pistol, getting the drop on him.</context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMAZING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd hate to waste a good bullet on a piece of scum like you, Tony. Tony freezes.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMAZING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The jig is up, Casanova. I've spent six months watching you, and know exactly what you're up to.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMAZING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nervous reaction from Tony P.</context>
      <utterance>I know that you're recruiting your old henchmen...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMAZING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Icy reaction from Anabel.</context>
      <utterance>I know who your girlfriend really is...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMAZING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I know the terrible revenge that you plan to inflict on this city.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess you know just about everything, don't you, Lance?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMAZING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um-hmm.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Except for one little thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMAZING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That I've hot wired the city's entire power supply through that catwalk.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMAZING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Casanova suddenly throws a secret breaker switch, and the ugly hum of a million volts instantly fills the room...</context>
      <utterance>What--?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many times I gotta tell you about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sally, that's a Herkimer Battle Jitney! They don't make 'em like that anymore. It's a classic!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks away. Furious growls. He picks up his iron bar and is about to wedge it under the front bumper of the Herkimer...</context>
      <utterance>It's a hunk of junk. I want the iron. Do it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we don't know for sure it's the same guy. Furious groans.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, look.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE ON A MODEL of a huge concrete bunker-like institutional structure (i.e. the Getty)</context>
      <utterance>Well, Don, I've done some terrible things in my life, but now I'm cured, and I just want to give back something to my old home town... That's why I'm using what's left of my fortune to build...</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Frankenstein Center for the Arts.</utterance>
   <speaker>DON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've changed, haven't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BACK ON FURIOUS, RAJA, and SHOVELER -</context>
      <utterance>Oh yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No he hasn't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait!... Look!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Disco Boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The who?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The most vicious gang of thugs this city ever produced. Twenty years ago they were Casanova's personal bodyguard. But after he was busted they crawled into the woodwork.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well they've crawled back out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We may be getting in over our heads here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This looks like a job for Superman--</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or Batman--</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or both.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you guys get it? If Captain Amazing is still in there, we can rescue him--and get on</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything's going exactly as we planned.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not quite. You haven't announced our engagement yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It must have slipped my mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your mind is so slippery.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, Pootchkie. My womanizing days are over. You're my Lady Macbeth, my Imelda... my Nicole.  We're such an incredible team. Who could possibly stop us?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't crunch the leaves.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(bumps into a lawn chair)</context>
      <utterance>Be a Mohican.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all listen; there is a low rushing sound... It is the sound of water rushing through pipes. Suddenly, the lawn sprinklers all pop up... and our heroes get drenched. They duck off the lawn, behind the cover of a large tree.</context>
      <utterance>Wait.  I hear something.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm soaked.  Oh great.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shhh.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be a Mohican.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Furious sees a pair of French doors, off a small patio. One of the doors is slightiy open.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start sneaking toward it, but as they cross the patio... they trip the automatic security lighting, and suddenly find themselves bathed in light.</context>
      <utterance>Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As our heroes look around as a dozen Disco Boys, armed with pipes, chains, brass knuckles, step into the light and encircle them... The French doors open and Tony P steps out.</context>
      <utterance>Uh-oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh I'm sorry. We must have the wrong house.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY P</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Disco Boys attack. The Raja is instantly clubbed down. The Shoveler deflects only a blow or two with his shovel before he goes down, too... These guys are not the Red Eyes. Only Furious holds his own. He grabs a pipe away from one of them and swings fiercely, keeping the others off. Suddenly, the Disco Boys pull back. Furious doesn't know why, until he turns and sees... Casanova, standing right behind him, smiling.</context>
      <utterance>You sure do.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a cat-like move Casanova slashes his gold chain viciously--and repeatedly--across Furious' face. Furious, stunned with pain, lunges at Casanova, who neatly steps aside, then catches him with a fast combination of spinning disco kicks. Finally he lassos the chain around Furious' neck, and pulls it tight, strangling him. ON THE DISCO BOYS, watching, snapping their fingers with admiration... Casanova releases Furious, who slumps to the ground. Casanova steps away, and the Disco Boys gather around Furious and kick him viciously... as Casanova and Tony P watch, amused, chuckling.</context>
      <utterance>Hi there.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Superheroes.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY P</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should I kill them?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why bother?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here you go.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ow.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you guys ought to forget this Superhero stuff and join Kiwanis or something. A FUSSY CUSTOMER is calling out from another table.</utterance>
   <speaker>FUSSY CUSTORER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves off.</context>
      <utterance>Miss!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe she's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What have the famous superheroes got that we don't?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Agents?</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Archenemies! Casanova isn't just a criminal-- he's a supervillain. Stopping him could be our ticket to fame, fortune--and babes!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And it would be the right thing to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah yeah--and that, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But there's only three of us, and he's got the entire brotherhood of evil at his disposal.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then maybe it's time for us to form our own brotherhood...</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>a brotherhood of righteous, crime fighting, skull cracking, Disco Boy bashing, warriors of the night!</context>
      <utterance>FURIOUS</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm liking this.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I say we send out the word--and summon all of the unsung superheroes we know!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They take a long moment to ponder this.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but... who do we know?</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shoveler and Raja make disgusted noises.</context>
      <utterance>Well... there's the Spleen.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do we have to?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got this cousin. He's a real doofus, but he claims he can become invisible.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you ever seen him?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How could I see him if he's invisible?</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good point.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And there's the Sphinx.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The who?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a legendary masked Mexican crime fighting superwrestler and master of the machete.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds good.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one's sure that he actually exists, but they say he can be contacted by leaving a message on a crumpled up napkin at the Tacky Taco down by the bus station.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get outta here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure that's how you spell it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, let me get this straight. You have the power to become invisible.</utterance>
   <speaker>INVISIBLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But... only when no one is looking.</utterance>
   <speaker>INVISIBLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If someone looks at you, you immediately become visible again.</utterance>
   <speaker>INVISIBLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're only invisible... to yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>INVISIBLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>OUR HEROES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No?</utterance>
   <speaker>INVISIBLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I look at myseif, I become visible.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're only invisible, when abuolutely no one is looking at you?</utterance>
   <speaker>INVISIBLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how do you know that you've ever been invisible?</utterance>
   <speaker>INVISIBLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Our heroes are less than impressed.</context>
      <utterance>I just know.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, kid, we've got a lot of heroes to interview--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SPLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts the mustard dispenser to his lips and squeezes it straight into his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Boy I can't tell you how thrilled I was when you guys called--You gonna eat that pickle?  I've always dreamed of being a member of the a real superhero team--and to have friends--real friends--I mean guys I could live with--sleep with--die with--eat with...</utterance>
   <speaker>SPLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Furious, Raja, and the Shoveler react; they can't believe they've actually invited this guy to join their group.</context>
      <utterance>I love mustard.</utterance>
   <speaker>INVISIBLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what exactly is your superpower?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans over the table and lets just a little tiny drop of spittle dribble onto the table...</context>
      <utterance>Well, when I was a kid I grew up on Love Canal- -remember that?--and my brothers and I used to go swimming in it--make Kool-Aid out of it-- stuff like that. Anyway my brothers all died, but I lived, and I grew all these like weird organs that have never been seen in humans before. So now I can do things like this!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Spleen inadvertently gives the tiniest little burp, and our three heroes duck out of the way or under the table.</context>
      <utterance>Cool, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS, RAJA, &amp; SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The people in the next booth give a cry of revulsion, put their hands to their mouths, and immediately leave.</context>
      <utterance>Watch it!... Look out!... Whoa!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, why don't you just put a cork in it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tried that once. The cork melted.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's just not enough of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we know they're out there. Hundreds--maybe thousands of lonely, unknown superheroes, who desperately need a cause...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And a social life.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but how do we get to them?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They ignore that suggestion.</context>
      <utterance>Obscene phone calls?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you throw a barbecue?  ON OUR HEROES, realizing that's it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="37">
   <speaker>SPLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In fact, the water is turning a yellowish green... The rest of our heroes sit around on cheap folding chairs. No superheroes have shown up. The Shoveler, at the grill, serves burgers to his kids, who stand in line waiting for them.</context>
      <utterance>Come on in! The water's great!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great picnic, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE JR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big turnout.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are these guys real superheroes?</utterance>
   <speaker>LENORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kids scoff... A moment later they head back to the house with their burgers.</context>
      <utterance>They think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But where's Captain Amazing?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE JR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They go into the house. No one says anything. The Shoveler just stares at the burgers on the grill. Vic Damon sings. Furious chugs his beer; he's working himself into a really morose mood. ON THE SPLEEN, munching on a chlorine tablet.</context>
      <utterance>He wouldn't be caught dead here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raja looks at his watch.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, these pool mints are delicious!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe there was traffic.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are we kidding? No one's gonna show. We're living in a fantasy!</utterance>
   <speaker>INVISIBLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, guys--we're fighting against evil.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good or evil, what's the difference?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a big difference.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I used to believe that. Now I'm not so sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roy, remember, it is all within your power. The only thing that's in your way... is you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, there is a knock at the gate. Everyone immediately perks up.</context>
      <utterance>Oh shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>INVISIBLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A moment later they open the gate and see... HALF A DOZEN BURLY GUYS wearing various superhero outfits.</context>
      <utterance>They're here!</utterance>
   <speaker>THEIR LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, man, is this the superhero wingding?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is it. Come on in!</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPERHEROES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At first glance these guys seem promising... but their outfits are decidedly improvised: weird goggles and sunglasses, shower curtain capes, baseball caps with beer cans on them. Their leader holds a squeegee with a long handle... Furious is suspicious.</context>
      <utterance>All right! Party!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am the Blue Raja, Master of Silverware.</utterance>
   <speaker>THEIR LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am Squeegee Man, and these are my compadres, the Invincible Dudes! The Invincible Dudes spot the keg.</utterance>
   <speaker>INVINCIBLE DUDES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They go immediately to the keg and start filling beer cups and guzzling them down. The Raja tries to hand out some forms.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa! Brews! Party!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you mind filling out these forms; names, addresses, description of superpowers, that sort of thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>INVINCIBLE DUDES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON FURIOUS, watching, starting to get pissed off.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, dude. No problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>INVINCIBLE DUDE 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, man, like where are the babes?</utterance>
   <speaker>INVINCIBLE DUDE 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It said on the card there'd be babes!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually we lied about the babes, but there's plenty of burgers.</utterance>
   <speaker>INVINCIBLE DUDES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's false advertising!... We came all the way from South Champion, man! We coulda gone plinking!... We coulda gone bunqee jumping!</utterance>
   <speaker>SQUEEGEE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No babes. No peace. INVISIBLE DUDES  No babes--no peace! No babes--no peace! No babes--no peace!</utterance>
   <speaker>SQUEEGEE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's trash the place!</utterance>
   <speaker>INVINCIBLE DUDES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Furious, fed up, confronts Squeegee Man.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah!</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're a superhero, what's your power?</utterance>
   <speaker>SQUEEGEE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Invincible Dudes are cracking up.</context>
      <utterance>I am Squeegee Man.  Touch my squeegee... and you die.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you fly?</utterance>
   <speaker>SQUEEGEE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wanna bet?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>They look up, see her standing there, and aren't quite sure what to make of her.</context>
      <utterance>Who died?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the Bowler.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Bowler? I remember him from when I was a kid. He was killed years ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Our heroes share a look.</context>
      <utterance>I'm his daughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, honey, being a superhero... it's a guy thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes her bowling ball and spins it on the tip of her finger (like a Harlem Globetrotter). For a long moment she just looks at them, smiling. ON THE OTHERS watching, almost mesmerized by the spinning ball... Suddenly, she gives an ear splitting battle cry and starts swinging the ball around her in wide ferocious arcs, like a cannibal with a war club--or a twirler on meth, going so fast she almost becomes a blur... Then, just as suddenly, she stops, aims and rolls her ball... It shoots straight through Invisible Boy's legs...</context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON OUR HEROES, left absolutely speechless.</context>
      <utterance>Good ball.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns and walks out. Our heroes share an amazed look, then run after her...</context>
      <utterance>If it could zip up its own bag, then you'd be impressed, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey... Can I buy you a beer?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes his arm and they all start to walk back into the Shoveler's backyard... but the CAMERA PANS ACROSS THE STREET to the dark place between two houses, where a MAN WEARING A STRANGE STEEL MASK with a frightening, impassively powerful expression stands in the deep shadows, watching them in motionless, predatory silence. We do not know who he is, and we cannot tell if he is good or evil.</context>
      <utterance>I thought you'd never ask.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The others, touched by this, have gathered around the Bowler, who is holding the old snapshot in her hand.</context>
      <utterance>He was more than just a superhero... He was my father...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>containers don't just fall on people. He was murdered... After that I fell apart. I dropped out of school, became a mud wrestler, married and divorced a jerk. When my mother died I hit bottom... but then, when I was cleaning out her attic, I found my father's old bowling bag and costume, almost like he'd left them there for me... and I knew what I had to do.</context>
      <utterance>And then one day, he didn't come home. The police said it was an accident. But cargo</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So who killed him?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Disco Boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know something? Those guys are really starting TO PISS ME OFF!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But there's still only six of us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's two more than the Fantastic Four.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Half a Dirty Dozen!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twice the Three Stooges!</utterance>
   <speaker>INVISIBLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And only one short of the Magnificent Seven.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you can't count Horst Buckholtz anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was cute though.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But they all had one thing we haven't got.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Girlfriends?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all think about it for a moment. You can almost smell their brains overheating.</context>
      <utterance>A name. All the great superhero teams have got a fabulous name.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about... the Savage Six?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Inscrutable Six?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Six Pistols?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Exterminators!</utterance>
   <speaker>INVISIBLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Obliterators!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Eradicators!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Emasculators!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets beaned by a couple of empty soda cans.</context>
      <utterance>Wait--I got it!... The Spleen Team.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MUSIC UP as Furious stands and starts out. The others stand and follow him... as our heroes form up for their first HEROIC GROUP SHOT.</context>
      <utterance>To hell with a name. Let's get to work.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TONY P</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Disco Boys howl with laughter.</context>
      <utterance>Not these guys again!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The D Boys laugh. Furious stares at Casanova, and Casanova stares right back at him, as cool as a snake.</context>
      <utterance>Nice car.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you do with Captain Amazing?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain who?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm his daughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY P</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The villains laugh, and Mister Furious EXPLODES INTO RAGE. He swings open his car door, mashing it into the limo and leaving a big dent.</context>
      <utterance>His daughter? Well guess what, sweetheart? I'm the one who squished your Daddy. And he squished real good!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tony and the boys all reach into their coats for their pistols--but as they yank them out, the Spleen sticks his head out of the station wagon, puts his face right up to the open window of the limo and lets loose with a TREMENDOUS BELCH... As the villains choke and gag in the noxious fumes, Mister Furious goes on a DEMOLITION RAMPAGE, working his way around the limo, punching big dents with his fists, breaking the windows with his head, flattening the tires by kicking them, knocking off the rear view mirror with the back of his hand... Then he leaps up on top of the limo... While inside the villains gasp for air as big dents are stomped into the roof above them... ANGLE THROUGH THE WINDSHEILD as Furious leaps down onto the hood, and gazes in at them.</context>
      <utterance>Waste him!</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He plunges his hand through the metal of the hood, pulls out the car's dip stick, and checks it.</context>
      <utterance>Shall I check your oil?</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tosses the dip stick away, then leaps off JUST AS Tony P gets off a shot, EXPLODING the windshield of the limo. Furious lands safely on the hood of the station wagon. As the Shoveler throws the Esquire into gear, Furious shouts...</context>
      <utterance>Looks fine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That boy's got talent.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY P</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I'm gonna nip it in the bud.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To us!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They toast and drink.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever our name is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raja and Bowler sit at the bar, deep in it.</context>
      <utterance>Even his snores smell bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But she's your mother. You gotta tell her.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>INVISIBLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad thinks all this superhero stuff is a stupid waste of time.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But he plays golf, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>INVISIBLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm her only son, and she always had such high hopes for me. Medicine. Law.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you're a superhero.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The cape. The turban. She wouldn't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know... My girlfriends all dumped me after I put on the mask. They thought I'd lost it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They clink their glasses and drink.</context>
      <utterance>But in fact... you'd found it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is your dream... and you can't ever give it up. The Spleen makes weird noises in his sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>INVISIBLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wonder what he dreams about?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Furious sits alone in the corner, brooding, lost in his own angry thoughts..</context>
      <utterance>We don't want to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>OUTSIDE THE BAR - CONTINUOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A black van drives slowly past the bar.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's late. I'm headin' home.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Junior, it's a school night.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUST OUTSIDE - A MONENT LATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As our heroes, carrying the Spleen, leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But suddenly the world is a whirling sass of chains and clubs as they are bushwhacked by the Disco Boys...</context>
      <utterance>Anybody up for a little White Castle?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TONY P</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Furious struggles, but he has been secured with some very heavy tire chains. Tony P takes out a large caliber revolver, flips it open to make sure it's loaded.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, cutie.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY P</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six losers. Six bullets. Perfect... Got any last words, Angry Boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Disco sucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY P</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and points the pistol right at Invisible Boy's head. Furious struggles against his chains--to no avail.</context>
      <utterance>Disco sucks. Very good. You know what I'm gonna do, Angry Boy, since you're so colorful? I'm gonna save you for last.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY P</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Invisible Boy closes his eyes... Tony P cocks the pistol... But suddenly, there is the ring of steel--a broad blade sweeps through the air, and Tony P's pistol is sliced neatly in half.</context>
      <utterance>Sweet dreams, punk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MAN IN MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buenos naches.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY P</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Disco Boys rush the newcomer, but he slices through their baseball bats with his machete, and sends them reeling and crashing into each other with expert forearm blows, whacks with the flat of his blade, and head butts with his mask. Furious struggles to break free and join the fight, but the chains are too strong... and the stranger doesn't need any help. Tony P flicks open a big switchblade and lunges at the stranger, who sidesteps him like a matador and swings his machete at him. Tony P turns, about to charge again.</context>
      <utterance>Get him!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN MASK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like me to trim the sides?</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY P</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tony P feels the top of his head, and realizes that the blow from the machete has neatly sliced off the top his disco-do, leaving only stubble on the top of his head.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the Sphinx.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPHINX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He raises his machete above Furious' head... and then slices clean through the chains.</context>
      <utterance>And you are a fool.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SPHINX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You call yourselves superheroes? A rooster fights more intelligently than you! You have shown yourself to your enemy and revealed your powers to him--and what have you accouplished for this? You have destroyed his car. Brilliant! If you want to survive you must fight like a wolf pack--not like a six pack! Furious sulks, but the others get the point.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPHINX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The wolf is cunning. He knows that stealth is his greatest weapon, and he always fights as a team...  SPHINX   Not like some drunken Tejano on Saturday night. Furious grunts.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPHINX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Casanova Frankenstein is a a master of evil. You will need more than shovels and dessert forks to stop him... What else have you got? They are silent.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what else has Superman got?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got the fact that he's Superman!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Furious sulks again, feeling that the others are turning against him.</context>
      <utterance>Bullets bounce off him!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Firepower costs money.</utterance>
   <speaker>INVISIBLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A silence.</context>
      <utterance>Anybody got any?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We didn't think this through very well.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure he's still lives here?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure he's still alive?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was the last time I saw him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When was that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is about to knock, but the door is suddenly yanked open, and an eighty year old guy is standing there. He's got a wild head of white hair (that looks like a living explosion), and he wears a stained old lab coat with stickum mtssages to himself stuck to it, non-matching slippers, and a pair of thick glasses with frames that have been composited of half a dozen different old pairs all taped and welded together into a fantastic concoction. He is DOC HELLER.</context>
      <utterance>I was eight.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doctor Heller?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's me... Elizabeth.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth! Little Elizabeth! Why you're so... middle aged!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's your dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Furious throws a look at the Shoveler and Raja. This guy's out of it. They're wasting their time.</context>
      <utterance>Oh that's right--they squished him... Heck of a guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doc, these are my friends. We're superheroes, and we need your help.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I give to the United Way, and I feel that sort of covers--</utterance>
   <speaker>SPHINX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doctor, we need your weapons.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My weapons? You need my weapons?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, Doc... where's the machine guns?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The bazookas?</utterance>
   <speaker>INVISIBLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The lasers?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Furious groans, and the others share a look. This guy's really a nut.</context>
      <utterance>You don't need that junk! You see, for thousands of years mankind has been immolating, disemboweling, and exploding itself. Why? Because we have this built-in screwed up need to go to war!  HELLER  So as a young man I thought, why nat have the fun and excitement of war, without all that unnecessary bloodshed. That's why I have devoted my life to developing an arsenal of highly sophisticated non-lethal military weapons.  Air cannons... Blame throwers... Feet seeking missiles... And perhaps my ultimate invention...  The canned tornado.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now here's a beauty!  I call it the Shrinker! I developed it after years of studying the worst dry cleaners I could find. It instantly shrinks fabrics to half their size. Anyone caught in its spray is immediately immobilized by their own clothing!</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Furious turns and goes out, and the others start to follow. But the Bowler picks up a canned tornado.</context>
      <utterance>Let's get out of here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Furious stops, turns back.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Mister Bad Mood.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tosses the can to him. He catches it--just as a small angry tornado FUNNELS out of the can. It catches Furious and lifts him high in the air... then dissipates to nothing... A beat later Furious lands on the ground with a painful thump. ON THE OTHERS, amazed. Furious gets to his feet, unhurt, but really pissed off. He starts back toward the barn, violently kicking the empty can. The others get out of his way, as, muttering angrily to himself, he goes back into the barn... And emerges a moment later, toting the air cannon.</context>
      <utterance>Catch.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others think he's going to use it on them and scatter for cover. but Furious steps out into the yard, looking for a suitable target... He sees an old abandoned outhouse, puts the air cannon to his shoulder, aims, and fires... There is a loud WHOOOOMPH of compressed air, and the huge recoil of the cannon instantly flings Furious back against the wall of the barn. But the big rush of air hits the shed dead center... and BLOWS IT TO PIECES, leaving only the old seat. Furious gets up, dusts himself off, and moves to Doc Heller.</context>
      <utterance>He's got the air cannon!</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(hugs him)</context>
      <utterance>Doc, you're a genius!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPHINX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others ignore Furious and listen to the Sphinx.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPHINX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others nod in agreemnt... while Furious fumes.</context>
      <utterance>We are not yet ready. Now we must learn to fight together... as one thing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty years ago all the major hoodlums of this city were united into one great brotherhood of evil, and Casanova was their king.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crime was rampant. It wasn't safe to stay in your home.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Much less go outside.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then Captain Amazing appeared.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He busted Casanova and sent the crooks packing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And this has been a pretty nice place to live ever since.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPHINX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The wise snake coils before he strikes.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Furious and the Sphinx square off, their faces only inches apart.</context>
      <utterance>And a skunk stinks!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPHINX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You drink too much.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When are you going to take off that mask?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPHINX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I am sure I am among friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roy--</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON THE RAJA, hurt.</context>
      <utterance>Go dance with your mother, Jeffrey!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPHINX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your rage is a very great power, but it blinds you to your heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My heart died a long time ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPHINX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is not dead. It is hiding.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blow it out your bean hole, Pancho!... And to hell with the rest of you!... Look at you. Bunch of rejects. I didn't need you before-- and I don't need you now!  The great ones RIDE ALONE!  Adios, muchachos!  ON THE OTHERS, watching him...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Has he always been like this?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An old sign reads "BAR" as the family car pulls into the parking lot of a single adobe building out in the middle of nowhere. They park.</context>
      <utterance>Oh this place looks great.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They get out, lock the car and head for the bar, leaving the windows up. Little Furious watches them go, never suspecting that his entire life is about to change. He sits quietly in the backseat and plays with the little superhero figurines that he's brought with him.</context>
      <utterance>Now honey, you just wait in the car. Mommy and Daddy will be right beck.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pow! Bang! Wham!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's nice and cool in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Barkeep, a couple of cold ones.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mom and Dad have a good laugh.</context>
      <utterance>And here's a banana for your monkey.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Couple more?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE FROM OUTSIDE TUE CAR as Little Furious, sweat and tears pouring out of him, his hair wet and sticking out (and starting to take on that familiar look), pounds on the window.</context>
      <utterance>You bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>as back in the bar his parents, now very drunk, down more beers and chasers as they play a spirited game of pinball. ANGLE ON THE MOHAVE SUN - beating down mercilessly barely able to breath, Little Furious flops back onto the seat, his face a mask of heat and terror... But suddenly, a change begins to take place in him, as some primordial defense mechanism kicks in... and his fear begins to give way to rage... His teeth bare.</context>
      <utterance>Mommy! Daddy! Mommy! Daddy!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode>0.S.</mode>
      <context>He looks up and sees Monica.</context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alone tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Every night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INVISIBLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode>0.S.</mode>
      <context>Invisible Boy hesitates for just a momnt, then gets up and runs down the hill.</context>
      <utterance>Where are they going?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the small convoy drives past, Invisible Boy slips out from behind some trees, runs after the truck, jumps up and sits on its rear bumper. The Spleen comes running after him, and Invisible Boy reaches out, grabs his hand and pulls him up alongside him. Invisible Boy tries the rear gate. It's open. The two of them pull it up just a foot, squirm inside, then pull it closed behind them.</context>
      <utterance>Kid!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DAWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...still no sign of millionaire Lance Hunt, and now, in an unrelated story, another one of Champion City's leading citizens has apparently disappeared. Captain Amazing has not been seen or heard from in a week. Authorities believe that the hard working superhero may just be taking a well deserved rest.</utterance>
   <speaker>DON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cancun perhaps?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Furious sits in the booth drinking coffee as Monica serves him his burger and fries.</context>
      <utterance>Sounds good to me, Don.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Date?</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I get off work in fifteen minutes. Walk me home?</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was easy.  ON FURIOUS, feeling a whole lot better.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(hangs up, starts off)</context>
      <utterance>Wait. I'll be right there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A minute later Casanova and two or three Disco Boys drive off in one of the sedans... as the crate is loaded onto the truck, and the gate is pulled closed... and locked.</context>
      <utterance>Head hunting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I admire you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Being a superhero, wanting to save the world. It's so... unselfish.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Most people just want to make money or be famous or something. But you risk everything, just to help people.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't mind being famous.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the shadows behind them... Casanova follows, stalking them, as silent as a vampire.</context>
      <utterance>Who wouldn't?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never been able to figure out what to do with my life, which is why I guess I'm still a waitress.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing wrong with being a waitress.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your real name?</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods.</context>
      <utterance>Have you always lived here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me too... I love this stupid old town. It's noisy. It's smelly. It's falling apart.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's home.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA'S POV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE 0N CASANOVA; he wants her...</context>
      <utterance>Monica, smiling, looking lovely.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've thought of leaving, going to Chicago or New York, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What have they got that we ain't got?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Champion's going to bounce back, and I want to be here when it does.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shrugs. And they kiss, very tenderly.</context>
      <utterance>You don't seem very angry right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what? Underneath all that anger I think there's just a little boy who wants everyone to love him.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just want to be a superhero.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns and climbs the stairs of an old apartmnt building and goes inside, as Furious watches, feeling emotions hees not used to. He really likes her. He starts walking back down the street, past a man sitting on the stoop. The man looks up. It's Casanova Frankenstein.</context>
      <utterance>That's what I mean... 'Night, Roy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Furious is caught completely by surprise--he takes a stand, ready to fight.</context>
      <utterance>Going my way?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take it easy--take it easy. I just want to have a little chat... That was quite a number you did on my car. You've got a lot of violence in you... and I like that in a guy. Furious, silent.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Furious reacts to the fact that Casanova knows his real name.</context>
      <utterance>You know what the difference is between good and evil, Roy?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE ON FURIOUS as, out of the corner of his eye, he catches movement in the alley across the street... he knows what it is.</context>
      <utterance>Evil is more fun. When you want something, you just take it, and if somebody gets in your way, you kill them... You seem like a very frustrated guy, Roy. Unhappy. Unfulfilled. What is it that you've always wanted, always desired? Because whatever it is, I can give it to you... Fame?  Easy. Fortune? Even easier. Women?  The easiest of all.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll let you in on a little secret, Roy. In two days this entire city will belong to me, and there's not a damn thing your little pals can do about it. It's the perfect time to switch teams... So what do you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're nuts.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They always call the great ones nuts.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the nuts always call themselves great.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you with me... or against me?</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Against.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gunfire rings out from the alley as the Disco Bays step out, their pistols blazing. But Furious has anticipated them. He leaps right at Casanova, pins his arms in a bear hug and holds him in the line of fire.</context>
      <utterance>Too bad. PLUG HIM!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for reminding me which team I'm on.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Furious releases Casanova, then runs for it and leaps over the wooden wall at the end of the lot... as the Disco Boys open fire again, and their bullets punch holes through the wall... Furious runs down a back street and escapes into the night.</context>
      <utterance>So are you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>GUARD 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Freeze!</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They freeze, their hands held high.</context>
      <utterance>Hands up!</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Our heroes are mute.</context>
      <utterance>What are you two doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not talking, eh? That can be fixed. Turn around, start walking up the hill--</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Invisible Boy and the Spleen turn, hands in the air, and start up the hill, the guards right behind them.</context>
      <utterance>And no funny business.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Invisible Boy pinches his nostrils--and the Spleen lets out with a horrendous fart. The guards gag and choke violently in the fumes as our heroes turn and run for it... escaping out the gates.</context>
      <utterance>Pinch 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>INVISIBLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others consider this, then hear a familiar voice.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever was in that crate... is from Russia.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode>0.S.</mode>
      <context>They look up and see that Furious has just returned... The Sphinx moves to him. For a moment they stand face to face...</context>
      <utterance>Is there room in the pack for one more wolf?</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sphinx takes off his mask, revealing that he is the busboy from the Tacky Taco.</context>
      <utterance>I was wrong... I need my friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPHINX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A few mimutes later. The others are gathered around Furious, listening to his story.</context>
      <utterance>Amigo. They embrace.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Casanova said that in two days the entire city would belong to him... and there wasn't a thing that we could do about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did he mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Through the window the moon is seen rising over the hillside, the Frankenstein Center silhouetted ominously against it. Raja, Shoveler, and Furious gaze at it.</context>
      <utterance>I dunno.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's time we checked that place out.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But how do we get in?</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We just become like the wolf... who wears the sheep's clothing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So where's the art?</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He hasn't stolen it yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This place is built like a fortress.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hear a WILD BURST OF DRUNKEN LAUGHTER echoing through the hall.</context>
      <utterance>Because thats what it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They approach a doorway. The noise is coming from within.</context>
      <utterance>Come on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>ON THREE INSIPIDLY EVIL LOOKING GUYS in hip suits...</context>
      <utterance>The Bone Heads from the South Side...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>ON A DARK HAIRED WHITE GUY dressed as a rapper...</context>
      <utterance>The Bland Boys from Downtown...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>ON A GUY with a frightening assortment of metal things piercing his face...</context>
      <utterance>Italian Ice...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Stapler...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode>0.S.</mode>
      <context>A more degenerate group of criminals never sat down to lunch. Furious recognizes one of the waitresses... It's Monica. Casanova's got his eye on her, too, and he remembers her from the night before on the street with Furious. ON ANABEL, noticing his interest. Our heroes see Monica walking straight toward them. They turn away, lean against a wail, trying to be totally inconspicuous... But as she passes them, not noticing them... Casanova approaches her.</context>
      <utterance>The Elvis Brothers.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops, turns to him, while our heroes listen in, only a few feet away...</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE ON FURIOUS, getting jealous.</context>
      <utterance>Monica... Beautiful name. It suits you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope you won't take this the wrong way, but I couldn't help but notice... that you're a dead ringer for Veronica Lake in "The Blue Dahlia".</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Furious growls. Raja gives him an elbow.</context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you an actress?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a waitress.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mister Furious is fuming. The strands of his perfectly coiffed disco- do start to stand straight up.</context>
      <utterance>You underestimate yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know I'm writing a play--it's just a little Broadway thing, but thure's a part in it that I think you'd be perfect for.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd love to hear you read it. Could you stick around after the luncheon?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure--I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns and walks into the kitchen. CLOSE ON CASANOVA, watching her; his intentions are sinister... He turns and sees... our heroes, hanging by the wall.</context>
      <utterance>Terrific.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you three doing here? This is invited guests only. Out. Our heroes skulk out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was too close.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we gotta find out what's going on in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Furious has spotted... a large covered dessert table, waiting to be wheeled into the hall.</context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She calms down, and he takes his hand off her mouth.</context>
      <utterance>It's me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you guys doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA &amp; SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waitresses leave; the big doors to the dining room are swung closed, and the cigars are lit. The meeting has begun. Casanova takes the podium.</context>
      <utterance>Shhhh!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tony P chuckles loudly, but the joke goes over like a lead balloon with the rest of the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you all for coming. I hope you enjoy the cigars. I had to kill a dozen Cubans to get them.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty years ago, this town was yours! AND I</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guests think Casanova's completely lost it. Italian Ice speaks up.</context>
      <utterance>They thought I was crazy? Well the joke's on them--because tonight at precisely midnight--on the twentieth anniversary of my tragic arrest-- every man, woman, and child in this city is going to turn into a RAVING PSYCSOTIC! Mothers will murder their tots! Old ladies will strangle their cats! Children will bump off their babysitters!</utterance>
   <speaker>ITALIAN ICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're outta your mind!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I beg your pardon?</utterance>
   <speaker>ITALIAN ICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody could drive a whole city crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell you what, Ice. I'll mke you a friendly little wager. It I can't do it... you can blow my brains out. If I can, I'll blow out yours. Now the hoods' interest has been perked.</utterance>
   <speaker>ITALIAN ICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Done.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anabel puts on a pair of heavy duty sound deadening ear protectors, then presses a button on a small remote control device. ANGLE ON A SPEAKER, placed above the podium... as the air is suddenly filled with a weird, stridulating, HORRIFIC NOISE (somewhere between the sound of a fire siren and a hornet trapped in your ear) and everyone in the room (except Anabel) goes COMPLETELY BERSERK... CAMERA PANS the tables as the guests laugh dementedly, punching, gouging, strangling, and stabbing each other... Under the serving table our heroes go crazy... Casanova, in a state of psychotic ecstasy, whips out his pistol and empties it into Italian Ice... who drops to the floor, dead. Anabel presses the button again; the sound winds down and stops, and everything returns to normal. The entire event lasted only a few seconds, but the guests are dazzled.</context>
      <utterance>Honey, give the boys a taste.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>amplified across this entire city. Murder and mayhem will reign supreme! And Champion City will be ours again! This will be our castle! And I will be our king! And there's no one to stop us! Suddenly, a familiar voice is heard.</context>
      <utterance>Tonight, at midnight, that sound will be</utterance>
   <speaker>AMAZING</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>A pair of curtains suddenly part... and Captain Amazing (looking a bit singed) is standing there in classic superhero pose. CAMERA PANS the crooks, as their criminal ecstasy turns instantly to terror. They yank out their pistols, dive for cover under the table, throw up their hands in surrender, etc... But Casanova just grins.</context>
      <utterance>Not so fast, Casanova!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Casaova reaches behind Captain Amazing's back and pulls a string (like the ones they used to have on those old talking dolls).</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, fellas...  I killed him... and I've had him stuffed.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMAZING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON OUR HEROES, under the table, stunned.</context>
      <utterance>Isn't my butt cute in these tights?  Blue is my color.  Oh, my abs are killing me! The crooks are beside themselves with laughter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELVIS BROTHER I</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The King is back!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELVIS BROTHER 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crooks fire their pistols exuberantly into the air, as disco music fills the air and Casanova dances, basking in their adoration... And our heroes slip out from under the table and make good their escape...</context>
      <utterance>Long live the King!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What could have made such a horrible noise?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got the Psychostridulator.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The what?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Psychiatric Warfare Division developed a prototype for a weapon that emitted a fluctuating alternative frequency noise that produced a violent psychotic reaction in any mammal within hearing distance. But when the old Soviet Union fell the stridulator and its brilliant inventor, Doctor Kopov, disappeared.</context>
      <utterance>Ten years ago the Kremlin's top secret</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This Kopov, what happened to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They react to that piece of news, and then the Bowler opens up the newspaper.</context>
      <utterance>Not him... her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE ON A PHOTO of Anabel and Casanova, announcing their wedding engagement.</context>
      <utterance>Did she look like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence; this is bad.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe it won't work.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It works.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another grim silence, as they realize how desperate the situation is. For the first time, they're really scared.</context>
      <utterance>A village in Siberia was wiped out when a cleaning woman switched it on by mistake.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've got to warn the city.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one will believe us.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA CUTS BETWEEN THEM as they look at each other--their frightened faces, their sad, faded costuznes. Even the Sphinx looks scared.</context>
      <utterance>They'll think we're just a bunch of weirdoes.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at him.</context>
      <utterance>We know what we gotta do.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're outnumbered twenty to one.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's suicide.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe. But this isn't about living or dying. It's about good versus evil, and we're good, whether we like it or not... Maybe we look a little funny...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>bulletproof and we can't fly. But we're superheroes--and that means doing what's right- -even when it's impossible... This is our city- -these are our friends, our famlies--and if we don't save them, nobody will! So I say we take a ride up that hill, blast our way in there, destroy that Psycho-whatchamabob-- and teach those deviants a lesson they'll never forget!</context>
      <utterance>And smell a little funny. We're not</utterance>
   <speaker>SPHINX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you're talking.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds good to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're all with him. Monica steps forward.</context>
      <utterance>And we'll take a bunch of 'em with us!</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just want you guys to know--I may not be a superhero, but I'm with you--and I want to help!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh that's great... Thanks, Monica...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We could really use some coffee--</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And some sandwiches--</utterance>
   <speaker>SPLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With mustard!</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A few minutes later, Monica serves sandwiches and coffee as our heroes plan...</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But that place is huge and we don't know where this psycho thing is--</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or even what it looks like.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And he must have it well hidden.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON MONICA as she gets an idea. A moment later she slips a canned tornado into her purse... as the others put their arms around each other in a group huddle\embrace.</context>
      <utterance>We'll just have to get lucky.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go do what you gotta do. We'll meet back here at sunset... Do or die.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do or die.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPHINX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HEROIC MUSIC as...</context>
      <utterance>Victoria o morte.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Baby, if I don't make it... find yourself... a normal guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A few minutes later... In the living room the Shoveler's kids lie sprawled in front of the television. The Shoveler, in battle array, steps into the room. Be wants to say something to them, but the kids don't even take their eyes off the TV look at him... He turns and walks out in silence.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want a normal guy. And they kiss.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeffrey, YOU THIEF!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mother... it's not what you think!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And why are you wearing that silly costume?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON HIS MOTHER, shocked.</context>
      <utterance>Because... I'M A SUPERHERO!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Mother, I'm sorry. I know how much you wanted me to be a doctor or a lawyer with a family--but it's just not who I am!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But... the silverware?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I use it... to fight evil.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeffrey... this is wonderful.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I always knew that you were special.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ever since you were a little boy...  Come with me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Raja opens the box and registers astonisha~nt as he sees... A FABULOUS VICTORIAN SILVER SET packed with formidable looking servers, cake knives, ice cream forks.</context>
      <utterance>This is for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Raja lifts up and handles a large heavily engraved pie server.</context>
      <utterance>Your Great Great Grandmother's wedding silver.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bitchin'.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Invisible Boy, sitting behind the wheel, tries the ignition of the Herkimer, and the old engine grinds as it turns over, but doesn't catch.</context>
      <utterance>Try it again!</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, baby... Come on, baby... I SAID COME</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(tosses him the phone)</context>
      <utterance>Mon Capitan, it's for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you nuts? Get out of there!</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Casanova may be a supervillain, but he's got a weakness, and I'm it. Maybe--just maybe--I can trick him into showing me the location of the whatchamathing.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a psycho! He'll kill you!</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just shut up and listen. Hold off the attack as long as you can. If I can discover the location I'll call you--</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what if you get killed?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then at least I will have died trying, right? Furious silent, taken aback by her courage.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roy... We might never see each other again, so I'd better tell you now... I think you're wonderful.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(and she hangs up)</context>
      <utterance>Bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monica!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could you tell Mr. Frankenstein that Monica is here?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, doll.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey... you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you'd chickened out on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes roam all over her; he knows she's up to something, but she looks yummy, and this is just the sort of cat and mouse game he loves.</context>
      <utterance>Just wanted to... powder my nose.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How 'bout giving me "the tour"?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's the artist?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raja and Shoveler share a bewildered look. The bird sings again.</context>
      <utterance>Listen. He's lonely... and he doesn't care who knows it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>dreams, our seeds are all just a brave attempt to live forever. (blows the dandelion seeds into the wind)</context>
      <utterance>We're all the same really. Our songs, our</utterance>
   <speaker>SPHINX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is in love. His anger is gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great timing!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns down the lights and quietly closes and locks the big door to the room. CLOSE ON MONICA, sensing her danger.</context>
      <utterance>This is where I come to... be alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves out onto the balcony... as Casanova slips the gold chain from around his neck and follows her.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, look at that view.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Snap out of it!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get on to yourself!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I just don't feel it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's turned into a completely normal person!</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Normal. What's normal? Does normal exist? And if it did, how would we know it? The Shoveler slugs him, sending him sprawling.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, Eddie, that was really uncalled for.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns, elegantly avoiding him, and moving back inside.</context>
      <utterance>I'm chilly.</utterance>
   <speaker>BACK TO THE BARN/LAB - CONTINUOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spleen holds up Furious' favorite sunglasses.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(snaps them in two)</context>
      <utterance>Look! Your favorite sunglasses!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(hurls it against the wall)</context>
      <utterance>Your Roy Rogers coffee mug!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(breaks the head off it)</context>
      <utterance>Your Spiderman Pez dispenser!</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, you win. I'm pissed off. I'm seriously peeved. The others groan with frustration.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not that kind of girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why are you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Curiosity.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, he hears high heels in the hall. A key is put in the lock-- Casanova leaps off the bed, grabs Monica and roughly shoves her into the closet. He leaps back onto the bed, just as the door opens, and Anabel, dressed in a lab coat (and wearing high heels) enters. Casanova is completely relaxed, nonchalant.</context>
      <utterance>Remember the cat.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing all alone in the dark?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She crosses the room to the wolf sculpture.</context>
      <utterance>Fantasizing... about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you were done?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens a secret panel on its back, REVEALNG a FLASHING HIGH TECH INTERIOR... and Monica, watching from the closet, realizes that she has found the Psychostridulator.</context>
      <utterance>One last tweak.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON FURIOUS, a pair of headphones on his head. The music is so loud that we can hear it even though it's being played only through the headphones. ON THE OTHERS, gathered around him, waiting to see if this will work. And then Furious begins to respond... as his face turns into a contorted grimace.</context>
      <utterance>If this doesn't do it, nothing will!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Furious groans and writhes... The others are thrilled; they've done it!</context>
      <utterance>It's working!</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to weep. The others give a collective groan of defeat.</context>
      <utterance>This music is just SO BEAUTIFUL!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's time.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With or without him, we gotta go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ANABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our guests are waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes out. Casanova listens as the sound of high heels fades away, then he goes to the closet and lets Monica out.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be down in a jiffy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd better go.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a spy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw him walk you home.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She makes a sudden try for the door, but he blocks her way, a cold look in his eye that makes her step back in fear.</context>
      <utterance>Roy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lets the gold chain drop loose in his hand, then starts coming for her, a sadistic grin on his face. This is the real Casanova. Monica pulls back, then reaches into her purse and takes out A CANNED TORNADO, which she holds out threateningly.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be afraid... I never hit a lady...</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay away!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs dementedly as Monica pops open the can and A SWIRLING FUNNEL OF AIR SHOOTS OUT OF IT and ENGULFS Casanova, throwing him across the room... Monica grabs the handset of a cordless phone and runs out the door. ON CASANOVA, pulling himself together.</context>
      <utterance>Or you'll what? CAN ME?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That bitch!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But she still might call!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you coming or not?</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll drive.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shoves him in the back, closing the heavy steel door behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Not a chance!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, we hear Casanova's voice on the line.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, guys... Pick up...</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter...</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody home?</utterance>
   <speaker>BACK TO M0NICA - CONTINUOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>as she moves quickly down the hall.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He forces the stick into gear and the Herkimer lurches forward.</context>
      <utterance>Here we go!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've got lift off!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May the forks be with us!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First is good.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want her alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA PANS UP the top of a staircase... where Monica is crouched, listening.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Mr. Frankenstein.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LITTLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Daddy, what is that thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A couple of GRIZZLED CHARACTERS stand in front of a bar.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, son.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUNK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A Herkimer? Those yuppies will drive anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSIDE THE HERKIMER - CONTINUOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>ON FURIOUS AND THE OTHERS in the back.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPHINX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amigo, we need you.</utterance>
   <speaker>INVISIBLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Furious closes his eyes and tries, but it's hopeless.</context>
      <utterance>Just GET MAD!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GUARD 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They have a good laugh at it, then hold up their hands for it to stop... But the Herkimer just rolls past them, hitting the iron gates and snapping them open as if they were made of match sticks.</context>
      <utterance>Looks like... a Ford Dumpster.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But then they all hear... the sound of gunfire.</context>
      <utterance>It's showtime.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY P</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By whom?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE OF GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't know!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>INSIDE THE HERKIMER - CONTINUOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>as our heroes encourage the Herk.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, baby!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON ITS WHEELS, grinding, chewing up the concrete...</context>
      <utterance>Do it, big boy!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BACK INSIDE THE HERKIMER - CONTINUOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>our heroes cheer, pat the Herk.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Atta, girl!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Atta, boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE OF GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Frankenstein, they're in!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well kill them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where am I going?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Through there!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But suddenly something under the hood blows up; the engine gives a long groan, and the Herkimer rolls to a dead stop...</context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON CASANOVA AND THE CROOKS, watching the monitor and laughing as bullets pulverize the Herk.</context>
      <utterance>No good! She's dead!</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY P</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butsuddenly, the Herkimer's door is thrown open, revealing our heroes-- holding down Doc Heller, his air cannon at the ready. He fires--there is a WHOOMPH of air--and the mounted gun and a dozen guards are sent tumbling...</context>
      <utterance>Spam in a can! The crooks laugh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cover me!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bullets dancing all around him, Furious runs a desperate (but impressive) zig-zag pattern across the floor... He performs a wild somersault, comes up on his feet, pops open the can, and executes a perfect jump shot, lobbing it right into the balcony. The tornado funnels out, and the guards are sent flying. ON CASANOVA AND THE TOP CROOKS watching...</context>
      <utterance>With what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELVIS BROTHER 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WHILE BACK IN THE HALL our heroes rally around a shaken Mr. Furious.</context>
      <utterance>Who are those guys? CLOSE ON CASANOVA, who knows who they are.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not bad for a normal guy!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPHINX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amigos!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do or die!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to... a man shaped pile of charcoal, all that remains of the unfortunate guard.</context>
      <utterance>Wait! Look!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laser eye... and it's a humdinger.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Raja takes out a butter knife, aims, and hurls it straight at the eye, but laser beams intercept the knife and instantly melt it into... a formless blob of silver.</context>
      <utterance>No problem.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TONY P</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll take care of these clowns.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELVIS BROTHER 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Piece a cake.</utterance>
   <speaker>BONE HEAD LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No sweat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the Doc is stymied... Suddenly they hear a woman's voice calling down to them.</context>
      <utterance>Doc, there's got to be a way.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's up here! It's up here!</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monica!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'll never make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meanwhile, Invisible Boy stands staring at the security eye, a look of fierce determination on his face. This is his moment.</context>
      <utterance>Think positive.</utterance>
   <speaker>INVISIBLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a deep breath, closes his eyes, and concentrates... ON FURIOUS as the fingers of one hand lose their grip and a toehold gives way... For a desperate moment, Furious is dangling off the wall by the tips of the fingers of one hand. Only his incredible rage keeps his fingertips taut. Suddenly, there is a flash of silver, and a large cake fork embeds in the concrete not far from his head. Furious grabs hold of it, and throws a grateful look down to the Raja... Who salaams up at him... As Invisible Boy, eyes closed in concentration, walks very slowly, hands at his sides, in an almost Egyptian pose... toward the eye... which stares down mercilessly, waiting for its next victim... we notice that Invisible Boy has become... just slightly transparent.</context>
      <utterance>I can do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, we hear someone cursing Casanova in Russian. He turns and sees... Anabel standing there, pistol in hand.</context>
      <utterance>Some girls just know how to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You two timing psychotic bastard.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Darling, you've got the wrong idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANABEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A look of terror comes across her face as she sees the murder in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>There's just one thing...  I don't need you anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, Darling. I never hit a lady.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA HOLDS ON OUR HEROES, wincing as Anabel hits with an ugly thud. Suddenly they hear Invisible Boy calling to them.</context>
      <utterance>Heads up!</utterance>
   <speaker>INVISIBLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all turn and see... Invisible Boy, totally visible, but standing on the other side of the arch.</context>
      <utterance>Guys, I did it! I did it! I'm invisible!</utterance>
   <speaker>INVISIBLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you see me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>INVISIBLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nuts.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Invisible Boy turns and sees... a computer screen built into the wall (with the same image of the eye on it that was on Casanova's computer), but he doesn't have a clue how to turn it off. Suddenly, he hears running feet, turns and sees... The top crooks and the Disco Boys rushing towards him through the giant sculptures. He gets an idea... and stands right in front of the computer screen.</context>
      <utterance>Kid, turn that thing off!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The villains form a line, bristling with pistols... as our heroes, led by Sphinx, Shoveler, and Bowler come running through the arch. The threesome go shoulder to shoulder (with our other heroes right behind them) as the villains open fire, laying down a deadly fusillade... ON SHOVELER, BOWLER, AND SPHINX, standing together, deflecting their bullets with shovel, bowling ball, and machete... (as they practiced with pebbles at the farm)... with the Raja right behind them, hurling silverware... ON THE VILLAINS, rapid firing... but their own bullets ricochet back into them, dropping them... They start to fall back.</context>
      <utterance>This is it! DO OR DIE!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the light goes out...</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode>0.S.</mode>
      <context>Casanova turns and sees... Furious, standing on the balcony.</context>
      <utterance>Frankenstein!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Furious starts at Casanova, who aims Anabel's pistol at him. Furious hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>Roy... What took you so long?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me guess... Bullets don't hurt you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Furious lunges at Casanova--who gets off a shot before Furious grabs the gun out of his hand. Casanova ducks clear. Furious tosses the pistol away... then realizes he's bleeding from a shoulder wound.</context>
      <utterance>They hurt... BUT THEY DON'T STOP ME!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns on his stereo and the sound of DISCO MUSIC fills the air...</context>
      <utterance>Smarts, doesn't it?... Shall we dance?</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY P</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They charge en mass at our heroes... who are waiting for them... pinching their noses closed, the Spleen bent over at their forefront... While Casanova dances around Furious like a cat... Furious, fighting the pain of his bullet wound, lunges at him, and Casanova neatly sidesteps him... The crooks and Disco Boys fall back, gasping, choking in the noxious fumes... As Casanova attacks... Advancing shoulder to shoulder, fighting as a team, our heroes wield machete, fork, shovel, bowling ball, and canned tornado... forcing the villains back... Casanova comes at Furious relentlessly, kicking and spinning... and Furious gets the worst of it. Suddenly, a squad of Disco Boys comes charging at our heroes from the flank... but Doc Heller turns to face them, shrinker spray held Rambo- style on his hip. He lets them have it, blasting them with a DENSE</context>
      <utterance>Let's rush 'em!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DISCO BOYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>While, downstairs, the Shoveler dispatches the Elvis Brothers with some nifty shovel work... But suddenly, the Bland Boys, pistols blazing, are advancing on him, forcing him back against the base of a sculpture. But the Raja suddenly leaps up onto the sculpture.</context>
      <utterance>Help!... Get me out of this!  Upstairs, Casanova pummels Furious...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode>0.S.</mode>
      <context>The Bland Boys look up and see... the Raja, both hands filled with silverware... which he HURLS... A beat later the Bland Boys, bristling with forks and grapefruit spoons, run screaming through the sculptures... as Tony P, pistol in hand, skulks out from behind a sculpture and spots... the Bowler. Upstairs, Furious goes flying against a wall...</context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roy, you're making this too easy. As Tony P takes a careful bead on the Bowler.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY P</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens fire, but she goes instantly into her ball svinging frenzy... He fires, missing--she's too fast to keep a bead on... Finally, his gun clicks empty. She turns and faces him.</context>
      <utterance>Say hello to Daddy for me!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She HURLS the ball at him--like a fiery softball pitch.</context>
      <utterance>Daddy says hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASANOVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches into his pocket and takes out the remote device (that Anabel used at the luncheon). He presses a button... ON THE WOLF SCULPTURE as the jaws open, its eyes glow red... and the dreadful sound of the Psychostridulator grinds up and FILLS THE NIGHT</context>
      <utterance>Let's change the tune.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He touches her face, her eyes open, and she looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Monica...</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes her tenderly in his arm... as the Raja, the Shoveler and the others rush into the room and see... Furious and Monica embracing.</context>
      <utterance>You're beautiful when you're angry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is there, waiting up for him.</context>
      <utterance>Mama!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They embrace.</context>
      <utterance>I'm home.</utterance>
   <speaker>DON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON THE SHOVELER'S KIDS, on the couch, still rattled by their psychotic episode, glued to the TV -</context>
      <utterance>Few details have emerged...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>ELVIS BROTHER I</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know who those guys were--but I never want to see 'em again.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELVIS BROTHER 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Especially that big dude with the shovel...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELVIS BROTHER 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON THE KIDS' COLLECTIVE REACTION as they realize who it was... and then they hear the front door open... In the front hall the Shoveler enters wearily; his shoulder hurts, his back is killing him... as his kids come running to him.</context>
      <utterance>He was the worst!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad!... Dad!... You okay?... You hurt?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm okay--I'm all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE JR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lean on me, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>LENORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They lead him back into the living room, and give him the prime spot on the couch.</context>
      <utterance>I'll hold your shovel, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want a soda, Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs to get it as Eddie Jr. slides a footstool under his feet and Tracy puts a pillow behind his back. Roland, the little one, cuddles up next to him, puts his arm around him.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice work. Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Roland.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Shoveler nods. A few minutes later... The Shoveler sits on the couch, feet up, soda in hand. The television is off. His kids all huddled around him, hanging on his every word.</context>
      <utterance>You really are a superhero, aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that's when the engine blew up.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON LUCILLE as she comes in and sees... her husband surrounded by his kids, a happy man at last.</context>
      <utterance>Well...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monica (in her waitress outfit) sits close to a bandaged Mister Furious.</context>
      <utterance>Heck no. I just chuck 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's been twenty-four hours since the deadly psycho-sonic attack and bloody shoot-out that left Casanova Frankenstein and dozen of the city's top hoodlums dead... But tonight the question remains... Who were these heroic mystery men who saved our city?...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Could have been anybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute... That's it. That's our name. We're... the Mystery Men. They all like it, except for the Bowler.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, do I look like a Man?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well we can't call ourselves the Mystery People.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER &amp; RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOWLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eat your mustard.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't matter what we call ourselves. We know who we are.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Obie-wan.</utterance>
   <speaker>INVISIBLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others see... that the Sphinx's chair is empty. Raja spots a crumpled napkin on the table, opens it up, and reads.</context>
      <utterance>Hey... he's gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A silence... Reactions from our heroes as they realize that the Sphinx is gone...</context>
      <utterance>"Until you need me again... Adios."</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOVELER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, somewhere in the night, a burst of gunfire and screams are heard. THE FINAL MUSIC BEGINS...</context>
      <utterance>I miss him already.</utterance>
   <speaker>FURIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Mystery Men wolf their burgers, then stand and start for the street... As Monica watches them leave, a PATRON asks her:</context>
      <utterance>Amigos, duty calls.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miss... who are those guys?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
