<movie id="409" title="New York Minute">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Startled, Drew shoots herself in the eye with the water pick. Parker's ENTERED from her side. Drew shuts off the water pick, dries her face.</context>
      <utterance>Morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why the young executive look?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker, sleepy, stretches, unaware she's exposing her new belly ring.</context>
      <utterance>I have my interview at NYU today.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Self-consciously, Parker drops her arms, pulls her shirt down.</context>
      <utterance>No way Mom knows about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And she never will. At least until after I'm married.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't it hurt?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew shivers.</context>
      <utterance>Like hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A little BEEP BEEP from her preset WATCH ALARM goes off.</context>
      <utterance>Piercings are so... unhygienic.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morning, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morning, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's the book coming?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, sweety, my writing process is a lot like a giant hydroelectric dam. For a long time I just let the great ideas build up and build up until the sheer weight of them spills over and the words just come pouring out.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still stuck, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker ENTERS with her Blackberry in hand, smooches her pop, then takes a sat. Parker's clearly a chip off her Dad's block. Both pour milk first into their bowl, then Charley drops in Super Sugar Crisp while Parker pours in Count Chocula. Both hit 'em with a couple of spoons of extra sugar. Mom takes a seat, too, primly eating a piece of dry wheat toast that she slices in half first. Like Mom, like Drew. Drew spots the BLACKBERRY JPEG of Warren before Parker can turn it over.</context>
      <utterance>Not a word.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Another one for the trophy room, huh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boys can be fun. You should try one some time.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ready for your interview?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've prepared a color-coded itinerary based on dividing the day into fifteen minute increments alternating blue/red, double- checked the train schedule, confirmed with the Weather Channel and rehearsed a couple of alternate scenarios last night, you know, just to account for all the possible glitches.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll take that as a yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm proud of you for sticking to your plan all these years, sweety.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still don't understand why you want to finish college in two years? What's the big hurry?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to hit the ground running. All those football games and the partying and the whole dating scene. It just seems like a lot of wasted time that could be spent more productively.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Accelerated program would look great on your med school application.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker looks to her dad. He shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Football games I get. But partying? A waste of time?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CHARLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To each her own.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everybody stops what they're doing for a BEAT.</context>
      <utterance>Well, Drew. I have a surprise.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I took the day off.  I'm going into the City with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew CHOKES on her granola and a little milk trickles out her nose.</context>
      <utterance>What -- ?!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't that great! We can do some shopping, have lunch, real girl stuff. Won't that be fun?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew is still choking -- pretty badly.</context>
      <utterance>If you want to have fun, I'm the one who should go, not Mother Teresa over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WHOOSH! The granola goes down and she sucks air.</context>
      <utterance>Let me know if you want me to do the Heimlich. It'd be cool to have you owe me your life.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blue and red! It won't work.</context>
      <utterance>No... I mean, it's... impossible. I've got every minute accounted for right up to the interview.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just thought... you know... I've been working and we haven't had a chance to spend much time together...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>QUINN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes her plate and goes to the sink and Parker follows her, putting an arm around her shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>... and both my babies are going away to college next Fall.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew throws an arm around Quinn's other shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be sad, Mom. Just think, when Drew leaves for school, you won't be losing a daughter, you'll be losing an anal-retentive social misfit who will be voted most likely to die a virgin.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Mom. It's really sweet of you. But don't worry. Parker will be living here with you forever since no college on earth will ever take her.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mom blows her nose.</context>
      <utterance>Stop it, you two.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not fair you guys get to go into the City and I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you have a chem test, young lady?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chemistry? Please. Name one time you ever used chemistry in your life.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good point.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I use chemistry every day.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The BEEP BEEP of Drew's alarm WATCH signals time to go. Drew is trying to cover up, but she's reeling from the news that her mother's going to accompany her.</context>
      <utterance>You're a doctor, Mom. I'm not going to be a doctor. I can't even say the word 'orifice,' let alone put a finger up one.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Time to go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>QUINN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>With a shiver, Drew closes the book, looks up into the mirror, takes a squirt off her inhaler to calm herself and tries some self-reassurance.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, honey! Let's tear up Manhattan!</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tries to sell herself on this by smiling, but something in the smile suggests SHE'S SCREWED. Collecting her Dayplanner, purse, interview file and cell phone, she drops them into her matching Coach shoulder bag. EXT. DRIVEWAY - MacLEOD HOUSE - MORNING Quinn hops in her Saab. ANGLE ON the doorway, where Drew pauses, takes a deep breath to brace herself, then walks like a condemned prisoner to her mother's car and climbs in.</context>
      <utterance>You're smart. You're resourceful. You'll find a way to make it work.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>QUINN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frustrated, Mom hangs up and with a look of profound disappointment, turns to Drew.</context>
      <utterance>Doctor MacLeod...  I'm sorry, but my itinerary is booked solid today. Call Dr. Wessels. He's covering for me.  He did?  Are you sure it's the baby's head?  All right. I'm coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew musters her best sad, sad face for her mom.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, hon. It's a Blue Light special in Maternity. Every bed's full and some poor woman is about to give birth in the gift shop. I have to go in.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, darn it, Mom. That's a shame. It's like fate is conspiring against us.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You absolutely, positively have to promise me we'll do it another time.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quinn gives her daughter a smile and a kiss.</context>
      <utterance>I promise. I better hurry. Have Parker drop you at the train station on her way to school, will you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>QUINN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kill 'em in that interview.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom, you know, I might not get in.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew smiles, hugs her mom and jumps out, waving as her mom backs down the drive and disappears down the street. With the weight of the world suddenly lifted from her shoulders, Drew looks to the sky and mouths, "thank you." This is when Parker comes hauling down the driveway in her Honda Accord. Drew signals her to stop, so of course her sister IGNORES HER and jets into the street.</context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding me? You're Drew MacLeod. Nobody's smarter, nobody works harder and nobody, and I mean nobody, is ever more prepared.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew takes off running after the car!</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Stop!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew pauses, holding the door open.</context>
      <utterance>Good luck with your interview.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, Parker. Chemistry is important. When you think about it, everything's made of chemicals.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew shuts the door and hustles off into the train station. Parker SIGHS, looks to the BLACKBERRY on the seat next to her.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm interested in chemistry. Just not the kind with all the numbers and stinky test tubes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, chemistry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think you're doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looking for a seat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew pinches herself too hard.</context>
      <utterance>This can't be happening. Wait, I know. This is one of those Ground Hog Day dreams, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ow!  I'm awake now. You're supposed to disappear.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I just got this itch.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then scratch it and get back to school.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm too... distracted today.</context>
      <utterance>I couldn't concentrate anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A look from the Exec reminds Parker of her headphones and she pulls them off.</context>
      <utterance>You're permanently distracted. It's called Attention Deficit Disorder.  Is this about that chat room guy? It is, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! It's about spontaneity, which you obviously wouldn't know anything about.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I swear to God, Parker, you go through boyfriends like Junior Mints. It's pathetic.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pathetic? You want to talk about pathetic?! At least I don't count getting accidentally felt up in dodge ball as my first date!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes back to his paper.</context>
      <utterance>Is this any of your business?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is ridiculous. I don't have time for this today. Fine. Don't graduate from high school. Make a mess of your life over some complete stranger. I don't care. But leave me out. I have something important I need to accomplish today, so please go away.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like this seat so you two can fight?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW/PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew's ALARM WATCH BEEPS.</context>
      <utterance>No thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to mentally preview my day now. I can't talk anymore. Parker turns to go, then remembers something.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew just rolls her eyes and turns her back on her sister. The Executive peers over his spectacles at Parker with the old paternal reprimand look.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, Drew? Do you have any money? I don't have enough for a ticket.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. Like you never ditched school.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But when she spots the CONDUCTOR ENTERING the front of the car, she abruptly stops, slips down in he seat and slides past the COMMUTER LADY next to her into the aisle.</context>
      <utterance>'You don't know how you met me...'</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker heads the opposite direction from the ticket- taking Conductor and out the back of the train car.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CONDUCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ticket, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't I save the b.s. story and just ask you to cut me a break this one time because I know you've got a big heart and you remember what it was like when you were young and... and...  ... randy?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CONDUCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONDUCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes her by the arm.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew scrambles to grab her bag, jacket, the little inflatable lap desk falling to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONDUCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tried to be nice about it, but if you want the police involved, this is the way to do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Police? I didn't do anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONDUCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No ticket, no train ride.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! That's not me! That was my twin sister you threw off!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONDUCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Young lady, in thirty years I have heard every possible line but that's the lamest ever.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's right there!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DREAM GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm... ouch.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONDUCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the Conductor escorts her down the stairs, she and Dream Guy share a last look before she's... ... left on the platform just as the train's pulling out. Still no sign of Parker and Drew doesn't have all her wits about her.</context>
      <utterance>She's fine, considering she should be in jail.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She drops her bag, contents spilling willy-nilly. On her hands and knees, she frantically searches for her ticket in the mess. The Conductor, however, is already on the train stop as it pulls away. He just waves, victorious. Parker steps back out onto the platform and the Conductor spots her. He looks from one sister to the other -- oops, mistake. But it's too late. Sheepishly, he climbs inside and the train is gone.</context>
      <utterance>This can't be happening! I have a... a... little paper thingy. What are they called? Ticket! I have a ticket! It's right...</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker stoops to help collect a couple of things but Drew, mad at hell, swats her hand away.</context>
      <utterance>You get kicked off, too? Why didn't you just buy a ticket?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to your head?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, just a minor concussion I sustained while the Conductor was throwing me off the train because he thought I was you sneaking back on the train!</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew throws her bag over her shoulder and heads for the ticket counter. The WELT on her forehead is gonna be a doozey.</context>
      <utterance>I'll bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am! Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To see when the next train leaves.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I already -- But Drew's inside the stationhouse.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker follows into the stationhouse.</context>
      <utterance>-- did. They said something about a delay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That can't be. I have to be there before two!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAIN CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, maybe if you flap your arms real fast you can fly there, because you won't get there on a train.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you just say?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on. Hurry. I got us a ride.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Parker drags her away. Drew shoots a look back at the Clerk, who sticks out his tongue at her.</context>
      <utterance>Let go of my arm.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A car service.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Bennie opens the door for Parker like he's done it a thousand times.</context>
      <utterance>Car service? You couldn't have called for a...</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morning, miss.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew KNOWS SOME SKETCHY SHIT IS GOING DOWN buy she's only got this instant to consider. She glances at the STRANDED MOB descending on a lone approaching CAB, engulfing it.</context>
      <utterance>Good morning. Thank you. My sister's coming, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew lets herself be pulled inside. Bennie shuts the door and waddles around to his side.</context>
      <utterance>You want to make that interview, or not?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're headed to the Teamster's Hall on Second Street?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She checks his Chauffeur's License up front: Benjamin Loyola.</context>
      <utterance>You know, Mister...</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Loyola.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bennie.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bennie doesn't seem perturbed a bit.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Bennie? We have a slight change of itinerary. We need to go into Manhattan. 57th and 5th will be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's pre-paid. No skin off my nose.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pre-paid? What's 57th and 5th?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Barneys.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not Barneys.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He FIRES UP the LINCOLN and off they go. Drew now has a pretty clear inclination as to what's going on. She leans into her sister and WHISPERS.</context>
      <utterance>We've got five hours. Relax.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This was supposed to be someone else's car, wasn't it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, Bennie tosses the sign, which he'd stashed on the dash, onto the seat next to him, face up so Drew can read:</context>
      <utterance>So?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Scarpelli'? We're supposed to be Italian?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Northern Italian.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is so... wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is when Bennie's CELL PHONE RINGS and he answers it.</context>
      <utterance>What? You need to get to that interview. We now have a ride. We will pay for the ride. End of big deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bennie glances into the REARVIEW MIRROR, smiling at the girls...</context>
      <utterance>Yeah?  No. The city.  What'a you talkin' about?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... but his smile TURNS DOWN AT THE CORNERS as he listens. The girls exchange doubtful looks. It gets worse.</context>
      <utterance>I already got 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bennie RAISES THE PRIVACY GLASS but doesn't realize he's left the intercom button on so they can still hear his half of the conversation. The girls are PETRIFIED.</context>
      <utterance>They're right here in the car.  'Scuse me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not good.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's happening?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>YES THEY CAN and they're now scared as hell.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you think that's a little severe? I mean, they didn't see nothin' yet. They can't hear nothin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girls want OUT OF THIS CAR!</context>
      <utterance>You're the boss.  Take it easy. I'll fix it.  No, I don't have a shovel. Not today. It'll be a big mess. Besides, I just had this suit cleaned.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew yanks out her inhaler and sucks on it.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take 'em to the wharf, what difference does it make?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker sees the LIGHT AHEAD TURN RED.</context>
      <utterance>Parker, I think maybe we should get out.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just as Bennie brakes for the light, Parker throws her door open and pulls Drew into the street! An ONCOMING BUICK LOCKS UP its BRAKES as they dash for the sidewalk.</context>
      <utterance>I agree. How about... NOW!</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey?! Where you goin'?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VRROOOM! Here comes the Lincoln storming around the corner.</context>
      <utterance>He's stuck at the light!</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They run into the first ALLEY and hunker down by a GARBAGE CAN. The Lincoln flies past. They dash back out, the same way they came. SCREECH! Bennie LOCKS UP the WHEELS! They round the same corner going the opposite way and Parker pulls them into the first door...</context>
      <utterance>He has no respect for traffic laws!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DEFENDS CROWN."</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PARKER'S POV -- slowly, the Lincoln cruises the street, Bennie scanning the neighborhood for them.</context>
      <utterance>Parker peers over the top and out the window.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What did you get us into?</context>
      <utterance>Is he gone? I can't believe this.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We lost him. Wow. That was a rush.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A rush? Are you out of your mind?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUM</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Spooked, they both turn to find a scraggly HOMELESS GUY with a Slushee in his hand. They stand. Parker reaches in her pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Hey. Give me a quarter, will ya?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MINI-MART CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get outta here, Uncle Jerry!</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... just as the Homeless Guy reaches for the dollar and the SLUSHEE IS KNOCKED FROM HIS HAND. We watch in SLOW MOTION AS THE SLUSHEE TAKES FLIGHT, THE</context>
      <utterance>Parker, you're only feeding the poor man's disease. Buy him a healthy snack.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FACED, DRENCHING HER.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Homeless Guy snags the dollar.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOMELESS GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he EXITS. Parker SNIFFS.</context>
      <utterance>I gotta go.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The MINI-MART CLERK approaches them, shaking his head.</context>
      <utterance>Ew. That stinks. That's not just Slushee.</utterance>
   <speaker>MINI-MART CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew appears STUNNED, unable to form words so Parker speaks for her.</context>
      <utterance>It's Mad Dog. Look at that mess. It's gonna smell up the store all day.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cherry syrup and cheap wine concoction drips down Drew's blank face.</context>
      <utterance>May we use your bathroom please?</utterance>
   <speaker>MINI-MART CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gas station at the end of the block. Have a nice day.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, it's not my place to say, but you young girls got your whole lives ahead of you. You shouldn't be drinkin' at this hour of the day.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I keep telling her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Round the side.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See? New York. We made it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could be arrested for vagrancy looking like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen. I've got an idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. No ideas. I'm going straight to that interview and wait, without moving or speaking, especially to you, for four hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on! We're going to the Plaza! We can be Eloise! We'll get a nice room, you can take a shower and I'll swap clothes with you! Simple as that!</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have the slightest clue what that would cost?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew's suddenly looking at her EMPTY HANDS.</context>
      <utterance>So? You've got the emergency credit card Mom gave you, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. My. God.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's your, uh, stuff?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I left it in his car.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He knows where I live. He's going to hunt me down and kill me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker digs in her pockets.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Drew. I don't think even the Mafia kills people just for scamming a ride. Quit being paranoid.  So, we don't do the Plaza. I've got...</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six dollars and thirty-two cents.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That won't get me hosed down at a car wash.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are we thinking? You've got your secret-safety twenty!</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My secret-safety twenty. Of course. But it's only for emergencies.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew takes off her shoe, lifts the inner sole and pulls out a twenty, then realizes:</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, how'd you know about my secret-safety twenty?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker points to hotel where the dilapidated sign reads:</context>
      <utterance>That's not important now. But let's just say that it's a good thing for you I think those shoes are so ugly I never borrowed them.  Hey, how about there?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I want to get clean, not contract hepatitis.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty-six dollars and thirty-six cents.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker leads them inside.</context>
      <utterance>We touch nothing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DESK CLERK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The girls look behind them, nobody. Behind the bars? Still nobody. What the hell?</context>
      <utterance>Keep your pants on. What'dya want?</utterance>
   <speaker>DESK CLERK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't got all day.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESK CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sixty bucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESK CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want the room or not?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sixty dollars an hour for this --</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- really nice place. How much for half an hour.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESK CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe if you two were in school you could figure out that half a sixty is thirty.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've only got twenty-five.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DESK CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think because I'm short you can just charm me into making some deal, is that it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all we have. Twenty-six dollars and thirty-six cents.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESK CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you the one that stinks so bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had a little accident, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>DESK CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He retrieves a key and holds it up just out of reach between the bars.</context>
      <utterance>All right, all right, don't get your underwear in a bunch. As a public service, just 'cause you stink so bad, you can have it for twenty-five.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESK CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten-dollar deposit on key.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What part of 'That is all the money we have' didn't make sense to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, that's every last cent we have in the world. I swear to you, we aren't planning to steal your key.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESK CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I give you some special deal, the next thing you know, you two are telling everybody, hey, this midget was a real sap. We gave him some sob story and the little guy just busted up into crocodile tears and handed over the key.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will we, Drew?</context>
      <utterance>I promise we won't tell anyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grudgingly holds out the key for Parker, who takes it and hands it to Drew while she gets the money out. ON DREW -- sensing something, she looks down at her feet where a HUGE RAT is licking the sweet stuff off her shoes. There's a rather LONG BEAT while this horror sinks in, then:</context>
      <utterance>Not a word. Girl Scout's honor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker follows her.</context>
      <utterance>Drew?! DREW?!</utterance>
   <speaker>DESK CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Desk Clerk jumps off his stool, opens his cage and follows them into the street.</context>
      <utterance>Come back with my key!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MRS. GREENSPAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you see that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. GREENSPAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey? The baby? Please?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>NYPD OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker pulls Drew out of the pile-up and grabs the key, tossing it away from them, sending the Desk Clerk scrambling after it. The two girls HIGH TAIL IT around the corner. Winded, they stop.</context>
      <utterance>All right. Who's the wise guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, that little guy could really motor. Why'd you bolt?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was a rat, Parker. A rat the size of a Doberman eating my foot.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was all our money.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our money? OUR MONEY?!</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Key down, you're going to have an attack.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Parker's not listening. She's staring intently... ... ACROSS THE STREET where several TOWN CARS are parked, the DRIVERS chatting next to a HOT DOG/PRETZEL CART. Among them is Bennie, sipping coffee. Parker spots him and freezes.</context>
      <utterance>Parker, it was not 'our' money and this is not 'our' day in New York. What it is, is quite possibly the most important day of my life. I've resigned myself to the fact that you don't give a crap about what you do with yours, but if you could find it in your heart, your tiny, cold steel heart, to respect what this means to me, I would appreciate it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not even listening. That's typical. Look, we're splitting up. Give me back my secret safety money.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know how I told you not to be paranoid?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paranoid?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker tries to subtly indicate with her eyes that Drew should look across the street.</context>
      <utterance>What I meant was, it isn't paranoia if someone really is chasing you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with your eyes?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd he find us?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's just coincidence!</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or maybe WE TOLD HIM WHERE WE WERE</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker leads her into traffic, HORNS BLARING, as they weave their way across. On the far side, a HORSE CARRIAGE pulls away from the curb and at the last minute, Parker spots a fresh pile of... ... HORSE SHIT, which she manages to leap. Drew, however, ISN'T GOING TO MAKE IT OVER. She closes her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew stumbles, wrong-foots the takeoff but somehow manages to get across it to the curb. For just a BEAT, we see her surprised face. Hm. I did it. Then they see Bennie crossing in traffic, huffing and puffing after them and not seeing the pile, which he hits in full stride, slips on, and PLOPS INTO on his ass. This gives the girls the opening they need and they ditch inside some revolving doors.</context>
      <utterance>Jump!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to do this anymore. I want to be done. No more rats, no more mob hit men.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Cinderella, your wish has come true.  Voila, La Plaza, mademoiselle.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So? Hello? No dinero?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I've got what I'd like to call a 'creative solution' to that.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I'm calling Mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What good will that do?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll have her... uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have her what? Hi, Mom? Could you leave that baby halfway outta there and drive into the city?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, hey. Drew. Complete loser. Couldn't get to an interview by myself, need full bail out. Yeah. I'm the one who was going to change the world, I just couldn't get across town.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn it, Parker, my itinerary is shot to hell! Blue, red -- Her WATCH ALARM BEEPS.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker starts to look.</context>
      <utterance>I don't even know what that means! I'm running out of time.  Is that guy looking at me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't look.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew drags her behind a palm. Sure enough, across the lobby, a guy dressed as PLAINCLOTHES HOTEL SECURITY (MORTY SESTERO) now pretends he wasn't keeping an eye on them.</context>
      <utterance>When you ask a question like that, the person is going to look.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think he was.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drew, we haven't done anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ELEVATOR behind them opens.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but I'm standing in the lobby of the Plaza looking like a deranged street person who might attack at any moment. In fact, I might attack at any moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girls slip into the elevator. When it closes, Morty's watching.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are we doing? And why am I whispering?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're getting you a shower. Blake Greer pulled this at the Sheraton after the prom.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great. Now we're emulating Blake Greer, voted most likely to commit a felony before having to shave.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not going to steal anything. We're just going to sneak in, use a little soap and water and get out.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, we're not going to steal anything. Super. Just a little 'breaking and entering.'</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not going to break anything.  We are going to enter, however.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. No. No.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DOWN THE HALL a door swings open and MR. AND MRS. LO BIANCHO, wealthy Bostonians, EXIT their suite.</context>
      <utterance>Shhh... here comes somebody.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hurry up!</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON DREW -- bracing herself, she turns slowly.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't want to have to do this, but... look in the mirror behind you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drew, you're not a criminal. You just smell like one. This way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, no. Oh my god. A... a...  What the hell is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A dog?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew backs away -- she's about to break for the door.</context>
      <utterance>I'm itching already. See? Are my arms red?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker approaches The Emperor.</context>
      <utterance>Key down. I'll take him in the living room and keep a lookout. You just get in that shower.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, little guy. You don't look so tough, huh? You don't look much like a dog, actually. More like Woody Woodpecker. Happy to give the company, The Emperor practically jumps into Parker's arms.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes him into the living room and moves to the door.</context>
      <utterance>You're cute, aren't you, in a freakazoidal kinda way.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker, holding The Emperor, opens the door a crack to keep a lookout.</context>
      <utterance>Was your daddy a rat? Is that it? Well, I still like you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and RUNS for the stairwell door marked EXIT. Parker, completely baffled, finally calls after him:</context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Bye bye. No.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not your dog! Hey!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a man in there!</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They reach the end of the hallway and are TRAPPED. Only one out. Parker HUFFS OPEN the window to the fire escape and they climb out...</context>
      <utterance>Somebody took the dog!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But DREW'S FROZEN WITH FEAR and to complicate matters, she's struggling to keep the curtain wrapped around herself.</context>
      <utterance>Hurry up!</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll, uh, go around.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you out of your mind?! It's only a little ways! JUMP!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MRS. LO BIANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When competing in a dog show, best to bring one's dog along, yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. LO BIANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you had him, dear.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. LO BIANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But now they both notice the DOOR to their suite is wide open.</context>
      <utterance>See? Empty.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. LO BIANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The elderly couple do their version of a panicked run inside.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, dear God!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MORTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Lo Biancho? I'm Mort Sestero, hotel security.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. LO BIANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please! Please help!</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone took your baby?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. LO BIANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Emperor is missing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Emperor is a dog, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. LO BIANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not 'a' dog, no. THE NEW YORK</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MORTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Remote One to base, Remote One to base. Code 12, I repeat, Code 12.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER SECURITY GUY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You goin' to lunch already, Morty?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Didn't you read your manual?</context>
      <utterance>Code 12 isn't lunch, Bruce!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER SECURITY GUY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call NYPD. We have a dognapping.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER SECURITY GUY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A what?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MORTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just call the damn police and patch me through. The Emperor's been kidnapped.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER SECURITY GUY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy cripes, why didn't you say it was political?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Political? THE EMPEROR IS A DOG,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANOTHER SECURITY GUY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want me to call NYPD about a dog?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That order.</context>
      <utterance>I am going to kill you, then fire you, Bruce. Got it? Kill, fire.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes you can!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No I can't!</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have fun in prison. Under 'Summer Internships' on your college application, you can write 'license plate manufacturing.'</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get out of there!</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MORTY'S POV -- The girls near the end of the alley. A small dog could easily be concealed under that shower curtain. ON THE GIRLS -- running full-tilt, Drew turns to Parker.</context>
      <utterance>Stop! Bring back that dog!</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He thinks we have the dog!</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A painter took it!</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WHAM! -- Drew's CLOTHESLINED at the intersection by a BIKE MESSENGER who, in a valiant attempt to avoid her, brakes so hard he flies off the handlebars and lands</context>
      <utterance>A pain --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DREAM GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O.S. SIRENS signal that the police are now involved.</context>
      <utterance>You know, one of us is gonna get hurt if we keep doing this.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker yanks Drew from underneath Dream Guy.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, complete stranger! Get off my sister!</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>College. Interview!</context>
      <utterance>I'm, uh, late for this place, thing, where I'm supposed to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREAM GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Parker's got her by the arm and she can only call back over her shoulder...</context>
      <utterance>Where at?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BOBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are they?! No more breaks! Do you hear me! We have a show to do, you nitwits! Models! BAH! You have hollow gourds for heads! The kind they make those Mexican rattles out of!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOWRUNNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maracas.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maracas! Maracas that take coffee breaks when I am paying them a</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BOBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is when he gets a load of Drew's matted hair, running makeup and shower curtain and does a double-take. Hm. Does he like it?</context>
      <utterance>Hair! Makeup!  Daywear!  Clubbing! Vite!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Showrunner shoves Drew one way, Parker the other -- Drew looks at her -- what the hell? Parker CLEARLY MOUTHS: HAIR! MAKEUP! CLOTHES! and TEAMS OF DRESSERS virtually surround them. INSIDE THE MOB OF DRESSERS SURROUNDING DREW the HAIR STYLIST raises his brush and scissors, but PAUSES. The rest of the team stops, watching him make his decision. He shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Is that Helmut Lang?  Go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE NEXT MUSIC CUE COMES UP and the SHOWRUNNER grabs Drew...</context>
      <utterance>Why does this not surprise me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, but I'm supposed to be going to my college interview.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOWRUNNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... and pushes her through the curtains and...</context>
      <utterance>That's rich. A model going to college. What next? Talking monkeys?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perfect.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Unfortunately for them, to get to the front door they have to pass by... ... the PLAZA MANAGER and the other HOUSE SECURITY AGENT, BRUCE (butch haircut, bad suit), consoling Mrs. Lo Biancho. When MORTY and the COPS come through the doors behind them, however, there's no choice. The girls try to look as inconspicuous as possible heading for the revolving doors but they overhear:</context>
      <utterance>Is this what they call 'returning to the scene of the crime'?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PLAZA MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I assure you, Mr. and Mrs. Lo Biancho, The Plaza will do everything in its power to see that The Emperor is safely returned and that the criminals are brought to justice.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. LO BIANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Justice?! I want them executed! Tortured first, slowly, and then beheaded!</utterance>
   <speaker>PLAZA MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morty spots the girls across the lobby just as they reach the revolving doors.</context>
      <utterance>The Plaza's policy is of course to serve you in any capacity we can.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OUTSIDE -- Parker sees Drew caught in the door as Bruce, Morty and the cops close in. Quickly, Parker pushes the door back, releasing Drew, who jumps in and swings out.</context>
      <utterance>Park...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd they go?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morty and Bruce take the cop's order and race off in separate directions. Neither Hogan nor his partner moves.</context>
      <utterance>They couldn't have gone very far. We'll split up.  You go that way! You take Fifth! Come on, get on your horse!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAMSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Williamson and Hogan step over to a hot dog cart set up next to a NEWSPAPER STAND.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAMSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two black.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do you think those two went?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAMSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beats me. They didn't have any stupid dog with them from what I could see.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Might have stashed it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WILLIAMSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cops giggle at this.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe they ate it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAMSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The rent-a-cop said the mutt's worth like 50 G's. That makes it grand theft, my friend. Five to ten.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Speedy. You didn't see a couple of blondes run past here, did you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPEEDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep. Couldn't miss 'em. Real criminal types. Looked like they were headed to Mexico.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's where they all go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WILLIAMSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See you around.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPEEDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cops head back to The Plaza.</context>
      <utterance>Not if I see you first.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I say we put Abbott and Costello on the ransom watch. I don't want to be stuck in the same room all day with Leona Helmsley's nasty stepsister.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SPEEDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whew. You know, it's not some old wives' tale about blind people having an acute sense of smell.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPEEDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So? What did you do with that dog?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We didn't steal it, I swear.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A painter did.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPEEDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You girls best give yourselves up and tell 'em the story.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's right, Parker.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew checks her watch.</context>
      <utterance>Of course he's right. We're going to march in there and give ourselves up right this minute. They will, of course, take us down to the precinct, call Mom and Dad, we'll give our statement, they'll grill us under hot lights for a few hours, force us to confess with some tricky good cop/bad cop routine and the next thing you know we're doing five to ten in Attica.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So we'll turn ourselves in right after the interview.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPEEDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I make one suggestion?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPEEDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A BEEP BEEP indicates Parker's BLACKBERRY is receiving a message.</context>
      <utterance>Hit the showers before you do anything else.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker reads the incoming MESSAGE from...</context>
      <utterance>We're facing felony charges, Parker. Maybe you can do your on- line flirting later. Better yet, he can see you during visitor's hours.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God. Warren works in the city.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Parker's typing furiously even as Drew rants on -- she has to lean around Speedy's legs. A GUY buying a newspaper peers down at the strange sight.</context>
      <utterance>Warren? WARREN?! So you lied, right to my face. No, Drew, this isn't about the chat room guy. Nah!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPEEDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guy pays for his paper, leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Take your daughters to work day.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Knock it off, Drew! This guy might be able to help. He lives here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Parker, you have completely lost your mind if you can be thinking about boys at a time like this!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The United Nations?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't possibly know somebody who works at the United Nations. Maybe he meant United Sub Sandwiches. Or United Skate Rats Store.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SOON.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Parker pockets the Blackberry.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So. We're going to the United Nations to use the restroom.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How convenient. You arrange a little date while your sister's future hangs in the balance.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Speedy opens the rear door of the newsstand.</context>
      <utterance>Look, he said he'd help and it's only a couple blocks away. You got a better idea?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SPEEDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coast's clear.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Mr. Speedy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPEEDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew SIGHS, then reluctantly follows Parker out.</context>
      <utterance>You're quite welcome. Good luck in that interview.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances at the screensaver, the same words pouring out.</context>
      <utterance>Wal-Mart?  Hey, Marvin. You bet. Typing away.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Today?  Gee, I'm on a real roll, Marv. The juices overfloweth, if you get my meaning. Don't want to plug the juices when they're overflowing, right?  How much?  Hm. I guess I could carve out some time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MRS. LO BIANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are those?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATERER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rumaki, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. LO BIANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A SOCIETY FRIEND of Mrs. Lo Biancho, BABS, arrives to pay her respects, shuffling her feet across and leaning in to trade air kisses.</context>
      <utterance>Rumaki! Yech! You might as well wrap dog turds in bacon. Take them away.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andrea, Andrea. How dreadful! I shudder to think how the poor Emperor may be suffering.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. LO BIANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When she turns on Morty and Bruce, they both jump a little.</context>
      <utterance>Dear Babs. I'm at wit's end.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. LO BIANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You! Tell the thieves I'll pay anything they want! Anything!</utterance>
   <speaker>BABS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course. What price on a loved one?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. LO BIANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Precisely!</utterance>
   <speaker>BABS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Babs nabs one of the rumaki on her way out. As soon as Babs is gone, Mrs. Lo Biancho looms over Morty and Bruce.</context>
      <utterance>I've got to run. That stupid groomer used a commercial conditioner on Coco and she looks like trailer trash.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. LO BIANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll give them ten grand, tops, but only if the dog's back before show time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to make it, Drew. You'll see. There's still plenty of time. You'll get cleaned up, we can trade clothes... this is a nice suit, huh? Right?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going to get accepted, then we can explain the misunderstanding about the dog to the police and everything will be okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe after the police forgive us for sneaking into someone else's hotel room, we can ask them to please keep the mob hit man from whacking us and dropping us into the marina so he doesn't get his suit dirty.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First things first.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Parker, I know you're trying to cheer me up, but I have to be honest. This is all your fault.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My fault? MY FAULT?! I didn't mean for any of this to happen!</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, right! Like you didn't mean to ask Bernie Lipscomb to the prom!</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that supposed to mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll bet that was just another accident of yours that happened to screw up my life!</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew didn't want to admit that -- it just slipped out under pressure.</context>
      <utterance>Bernie Lipscomb?  You...?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You liked Bernie, too?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know I did!</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No I didn't. I haven't seen you talk to a guy since we were in kindergarten and we thought Jerry Wester was a girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You asked Bernie just to snake him from me!</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did not!  Wow, the really spooky thing is, that would mean we liked the same guy. A block away, the United Nations building stands majestically against the sky.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shows the PHOTO to his PARTNER who's driving.</context>
      <utterance>Isn't that those two right there?</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But when they look up:</context>
      <utterance>I'll be damned.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the carriage clops past, however, the Policemen don't notice the Girls -- both clinging to the back.</context>
      <utterance>Where the hell did they go?</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>605 to Base. We spotted the dognapping suspects, corner of 1st and 49th.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Copy that, 605.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>605, do you still have visual?</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN #2</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>They're on foot.</context>
      <utterance>Negative. But they can't be far.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAMSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's over by the U.N.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zoom! Williamson blasts crosstown.</context>
      <utterance>See if you can pick them up. We're on our way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WILLIAMSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There they are.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVES' POV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- just a glimpse as they ENTER the building.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker consults the JPEG PIC on her Blackberry, then scans the group.</context>
      <utterance>Do you see him?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the head of the group, the U.N. TOUR GUARD, geeky in a Clark Kent way and nice enough looking but definitely not a male model, leans into a petite BRUNETTE and her LITTLE</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TOUR GUIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Brunette looks at him like he's a serial killer.</context>
      <utterance>I can't tell you how much I've looked forward to this.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUNETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her fierce-looking BABUSHKA MOM gets in the Tour Guide's face.</context>
      <utterance>Momma?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOUR GUIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is when Drew notices Williamson and Hogan ENTERING and approaching a U.N. SECURITY GUIDE, flashing their badges.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry. My mistake.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, shit. What now?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Warren? Does anyone know Warren Collier?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Warren moves back to Drew and Parker.</context>
      <utterance>Parker?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gee, Warren. Isn't that strange? I didn't recognize you from your picture.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I, uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't have time for this now.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have an office or someplace private we could go?</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Williamson and Hogan, led by the U.N. Security Guy, ENTER the lobby. Drew grabs Warren by the arm and turns him.</context>
      <utterance>I just have to do this tour and...</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll get back to that.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker looks Warren right in the eye. This is a test.</context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's important.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Warren leads them into a small adjoining office...</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Let me get somebody to cover for me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Angie? Take the 11:00.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angie heads out to take the tour. Parker turns on Warren.</context>
      <utterance>You owe me, Warren.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you a lying sack, or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was I supposed to do? I liked you. If I'd sent a real picture, would you have met me?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not the point.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That means no. At least this way I got to see you before you blow me off.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one is blowing you off, Warren. As a matter of fact, we're very happy to see you, aren't we, Parker?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And we're grateful for your help.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is my sister, Drew.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not-a-twin, huh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a joke.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well. I guess everybody would like the world to see them a little bit differently than they are.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Super. Now that that's all settled, is there a restroom I can get to without going out there?</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with going out there?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Police, for one thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Police? I thought you guys were joking.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the kind of joke that will be a lot funnier a few years from now.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker opens the office door, peeking out.</context>
      <utterance>Well that door's the only way out. There's a restroom at the end of the main hall.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They there?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't see 'em.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd you guys do, anyway? Mug a couple supermodels?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With Warren leading the way, they EXIT the office.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HOGAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! You two! Stop!</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Almost instinctively, they go COMPLETELY SEPARATE WAYS, Warren and Parker breaking left, Drew right. Drew makes a mad dash down a hallway, makes a turn, another turn, working her way deeper into the labyrinth. Even while running frantically, she tries to smile politely at everyone she passes until she spots a WOMEN'S room and quickly ditches inside.</context>
      <utterance>This way!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>CANADIAN REPRESENTATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ohhh... I'm so sick. The mussels at lunch. You have to help me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm kind of in my own private hell right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CANADIAN REPRESENTATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drew.</utterance>
   <speaker>CANADIAN REPRESENTATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A FILE FOLDER comes skidding from under the stall.</context>
      <utterance>Drew... it's vitally important.</utterance>
   <speaker>CANADIAN REPRESENTATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. You have to take this to Canada.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, Canada? It's sort of far away.</utterance>
   <speaker>CANADIAN REPRESENTATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the Assembly. Give the file to Mr. Wakefield, the Canadian representative.</utterance>
   <speaker>CANADIAN REPRESENTATIVE</speaker>
      <mode>GROANNN!!</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. I can't... get up.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want me to take this to the Canadian Representative to the United Nations?</utterance>
   <speaker>CANADIAN REPRESENTATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What can she possibly do?</context>
      <utterance>Hurry! This is a crisis!</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew EXITS the stall and goes to the door.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's the Assembly?</utterance>
   <speaker>CANADIAN REPRESENTATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew peeks out the door. It looks clear. Out she goes.</context>
      <utterance>To the left. Run!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker pops up from the same sack. Face to face, there's an awkward moment of attraction between them.</context>
      <utterance>He's gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have nice breath.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.  Maybe we should get out of this sack.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHINESE REP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Impossible! This would be globally destabilizing!</utterance>
   <speaker>BULGARIAN REP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hah! Posturing and rhetoric!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts a hand to his stomach -- he's struggling.</context>
      <utterance>Sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>CANADIAN REPRESENTATIVE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Even as she holds out the file, he races past her, puckering his bum. She watches him waddle up the stairs BUT AS HE EXITS, HE</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no. You didn't have the mussels at lunch, too, did you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This furrows some brows.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm not certain...</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON THE NORTH KOREAN REPRESENTATIVE leaning over to confer with the NORWEGIAN REPRESENTATIVE:</context>
      <utterance>... that I NEED to defend our position! Ah, yes, some knowing nods.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORTH KOREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is she new?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORWAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beats me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORTH KOREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's hot.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORWAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Weird hairdo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHINESE REP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is absurd!</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uhhh... where now? She notices the FILE the Rep in the bathroom gave her and holds it up, shaking it for emphasis.</context>
      <utterance>Absurd?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are we going to find Drew?</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Warren points to the MONITOR. Parker's jaw drops. Her sister is addressing the entire U.N. Assembly.</context>
      <utterance>Something tells me that won't be too tough.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Like Cinderella at Midnight, she turns and races up the stairs as the Assembly is in complete turmoil -- KOFI ANAN BANGS his gavel.</context>
      <utterance>And besides, who said absurd is necessarily bad? Sometimes absurd is good! For instance, absurd can be sort of... funny! In conclusion, I propose that all of you should talk amongst yourselves.  Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOFI ANAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Canada has proposed further debate.</utterance>
   <speaker>U.S. REP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The United States of America seconds the motion!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCREAMING LIKE BANSHEES, the Japanese Girls all pour outside, Warren and the Girls following.</context>
      <utterance>Jin zshe miya BRAD PITT!</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The JAPANESE GIRLS turn around and STORM BACK THROUGH THE DOORS, blocking Williamson and Hogan's EXIT. The three of them run for the line of taxis.</context>
      <utterance>Dingo cashito, BRAD PITT ezukai!</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You speak Japanese?</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Warren grabs a Taxi door.</context>
      <utterance>I may not look like an underwear model, but I'm smarter than a hundred of them put together.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't have any money!</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Williamson and Hogan have fought their way out through the little Japanese Girls. Realizing they won't reach Parker and Drew in time, they head for their own unmarked cruiser which is parked just ahead of... Bennie's TOWN CAR. He's holding the door for a cigar- chewing CLIENT but watching the Girls climb into the cab up ahead.</context>
      <utterance>I'm smart AND rich!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Follow that... uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're following US, Parker!</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The TAXI pulls away from the curb.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah. JUST GO!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAMSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe we should give them a little leash and see what they do with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In a BEAT, Bennie's Town Car follows, too.</context>
      <utterance>Fine. But we're gonna have to stop for lunch pretty soon, 'cause I'm getting heartburn. They pull into traffic, following the Cab.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, what were you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone was sick in the bathroom and they asked me to -- hold on, I don't owe you any explanation.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the one all 'I gotta get to this interview or I'm gonna have a nervous breakdown' and yet you have time to address the United Nations?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, technically, you have to have security clearance to enter the Assembly.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not now, Warren.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have a lot of nerve, Parker. It was you that got me tossed off the train! You had to give the bum that dollar! You get the suit, I get the leather bikini!</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which isn't so bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you got Bernie Lipscomb while I got Scrabble with Mom and Dad!</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's Bernie Lipscomb?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you, I didn't know you liked him! It was no big deal!</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was to me!</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How could I know? You never tell me anything!</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a good reason for that!</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that supposed to mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know very well what it means, Ms. Big Mouth!</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big mouth?! Ooh, I hope you miss that stupid interview!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oops. This just slipped out in anger. Parker's brain has to adjust, then:</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah? Well, the joke's on you, because there isn't any interview!</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No interview. I screwed up.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You screwed up what?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scheduling the interview. You deaf?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're Drew. Drew doesn't screw ANYTHING up, let alone scheduling. You're the Iron Chef of scheduling.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I missed the deadline.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew is near tears.</context>
      <utterance>After they made the first cut from the preliminary application, we were supposed to send in a form to secure our interview time and I filled it out and had everything ready to go in the mailbox and then...</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tsunami? Nuclear winter?</context>
      <utterance>And then what? Earthquake?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I forgot.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forgot?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I just forgot. When I found it in my bag a week later, I'd missed the deadline.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So today? All this? What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... I was going to try to meet Professor Spaulding and...</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were just going to jump him?</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A look from Parker quiets Warren. Drew's choked up. She just nods, yes.</context>
      <utterance>Sort of a guerilla interview? You know, I'm a big Michael Moore fan...</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew wipes her tears, then:</context>
      <utterance>I called and the secretary said there were no exceptions to the deadline so I was going to try to see him when he finished the other interviews. I knew it was hopeless, but... I was so... embarrassed.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens the door and jumps out!</context>
      <utterance>Oh, to hell with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker starts to open her door on the TRAFFIC SIDE! HONK HONK! It's nearly SHEARED OFF by a passing truck and she closes it just in time.</context>
      <utterance>Drew?! Drew, get back in this taxi!</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's pretty upset.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the taxi bogs down in traffic, Drew disappears around the corner up ahead.</context>
      <utterance>Gee, you really are a genius.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Talk about spontaneous.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is when she sees, parked just down the block... ROGER'S VAN with "Michelangelo's Painting" across the back door.</context>
      <utterance>Darn it! DARN IT DARN IT DARN IT!</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew quickly steps into the shadow of a doorway to keep out of sight and watch the van.</context>
      <utterance>That's... that's the painter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WILLIAMSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did one of them just get out?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think so. Maybe she's going for the dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAMSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe that's what they want us to think.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So we stay with the taxi?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WILLIAMSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unless you want to hoof it after the other one.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We stay with the taxi.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Emperor ignores him, happily watching the streets of New York go by.</context>
      <utterance>Get in the back, will ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But his CALL has gone through. He imitates a GIRL'S</context>
      <utterance>Stupid dog.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CONTINUOUS ACTION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Lo Biancho calmly answers her cell phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. LO BIANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morty and Bruce have their tracing gear rigged to her phone but have to keep following her around the box.</context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you want to see your dog alive again, listen closely. I want a hundred thousand dollars transferred into this numbered Swiss account --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MRS. LO BIANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks to her husband, who consults his watch and then holds up ONE FINGER.</context>
      <utterance>-- I'll give you ten grand but only if he's in Madison Square Garden in...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. LO BIANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bruce SIGNALS her -- keep him on the line!</context>
      <utterance>One hour. Take it or leave it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. LO BIANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hangs up. Bruce and Morty SIGH.</context>
      <utterance>You have one minute to decide.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd she go?</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think she took a right up there.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Follow my sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAXI DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought we were the ones being followed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They turn right.</context>
      <utterance>Stay flexible, will you please?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. LO BIANCHO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yesss?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Here's how we make the --</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. LO BIANCHO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- First of all, you forgot to disguise your voice.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn it!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. LO BIANCHO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Secondly, my husband will meet you in ten minutes on the corner of 43rd and Broadway. He'll have the money. Bring the dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Consider him Kung Pau!</context>
      <utterance>But that's ridiculous! You'll just bring the police! No way!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. LO BIANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't hang up!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. LO BIANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The police, it appears, have other priorities, like humans or something. And I assure you, the Hotel Security... people... will not interfere. In any case, little man, we just want the dog back before showtime, do you understand?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. LO BIANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hangs up. Roger does, too.</context>
      <utterance>Ciao.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No wonder you look so happy. As far as you're concerned, you've escaped from the Wicked Witch of the West.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whoosh! From behind, DREW GRABS THE EMPEROR and takes off running.</context>
      <utterance>Knock it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holding The Emperor at arm's length, Drew makes a run for it with Roger after her.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Give me that dog!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MR. LO BIANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't stop! I have to return this dog!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Puzzled, Mr. Lo Biancho falls in line behind Roger, keeping up pretty well for an old dude with a gut.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be right back!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, isn't that your sister?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It can't be. She's terrified of dogs.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Detectives exchange glances -- nice hunch -- and they</context>
      <utterance>I'm telling you, I got a hunch these girls don't have anything to do with this dog. Drew blows past them, holding The Emperor. The</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But SHOW OFFICIAL 3 appears from inside, taps the Policeman on the shoulder -- they need him inside. He turns and goes through the door just as... ... Drew reaches the loading dock and hustles up the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Officer?! Officer?!</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sprints past the other SHOW OFFICIALS checking in</context>
      <utterance>Officer?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SHOW OFFICIAL #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No entry without official credentials!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. LO BIANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Emile Lo Biancho! I demand to be let in!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAMSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the mention of POLICE, Roger's EYES GO WIDE. He slinks down, losing himself in the crowd and sidles off.</context>
      <utterance>NYPD! Move aside!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOW OFFICIAL #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll have to see identification, officers.  I'm so sorry, Mr. Lo Biancho. Go right in. AT THE CORNER, Parker and Warren keep their distance, not wanting to be seen by the Detectives.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think she made it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's faster than she looks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MORTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't that The Emperor, ma'am?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. LO BIANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good God. He's mauve.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please! I'll get hives!  Oh, go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW'S POV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Detectives appear above her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BACK TO SCENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She holds up The Emperor.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the other OWNERS and HANDLERS gather their dogs, Williamson hands The Emperor off to Mrs. Lo Biancho while Hogan handcuffs Drew.</context>
      <utterance>I, uh, just wanted to return him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. LO BIANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Flog her! Step aside and I'll whip her myself!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. LO BIANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't you say it was a man who called, Dear?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. LO BIANCHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Williamson and Hogan move Drew toward their car.</context>
      <utterance>So she had an accomplice! We'll beat the information out of the little wench!  Get him cleaned up, Emile.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't take her dog, I swear.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAMSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll sort it out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What now?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to go to the jail and tell them what happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What on earth did happen?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a SIGH, they turn to go and BUMP -- knock into Bennie, who's staring coldly down at Parker.</context>
      <utterance>Poor Drew. She wanted to get into that program more than anything in the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's paralyzed with fear.</context>
      <utterance>You goin' somewhere?</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God! Please don't kill me!</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kill?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bennie appears unmoved. Parker closes her eyes, trying to meet death with dignity.</context>
      <utterance>We don't know anything at all! We didn't see anything or hear anything and I'll swear to that in a court of law!</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just not in the face.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens one eye.</context>
      <utterance>What's the big idea? You two a couple a nutbags or somethin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indicating Warren.</context>
      <utterance>Nut bags? No. I mean, yes. Is there a right answer to that? See, my sister had this interview which turned out not to be an interview, really and I sort of messed things up because I wanted to meet him.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? You came into town just for me? Wow.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not now, Warren.  Drew was going to be late even though technically she wasn't going to be late since there wasn't an interview and that's when we got in your car. I promise we meant to pay. It was a true emergency.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bennie hands Parker Drew's daybag. Parker takes it, still trying to comprehend.</context>
      <utterance>I meant, why you runnin' when I'm trying to give you your bag back?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were just...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BENNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bennie waddles over to his Town Car and climbs in.</context>
      <utterance>I found your mom's number in the book. She said you needed it pretty badly for that big interview. Listen, I gotta go. It's my mother-in-law's birthday and I gotta plant some stupid rose bush and then take her out to dinner at the Pier. See ya around.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker looks at the daybag.</context>
      <utterance>Well, he certainly is a good Samaritan.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But now Parker's mind is elsewhere. She pulls out Drew's daybook, opens it.</context>
      <utterance>You guys lead a pretty interesting life, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I've never been to a jail before.</context>
      <utterance>We going to the jail, or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What time is it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode>INMATE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love your outfit.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it Bobo?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, as a matter-of-fact, it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OFF Drew's look of complete spiritual resignation we --</context>
      <utterance>He's a genius.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try to keep up, Warren!</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! I'm an intellectual! I never claimed to be athletic!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you mind? I'm a fanatic for Jimmy Choo.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands the high heel to Red, who enthusiastically pulls it on and models it.</context>
      <utterance>It's all yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOGAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Hogan ENTERS, opens the cell door.</context>
      <utterance>MacLeod?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're free to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No thanks. I'll just stay here with the girls.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hogan takes her by the arm in a fatherly way and leads her out.</context>
      <utterance>An eyewitness says he saw who took the dog. Didn't realize the guy was stealing it until he saw us grab you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>HOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's your alibi.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't even know him.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what he said. Go home. Get cleaned up, a good night's sleep. None of this will seem so bad in the morning. Hogan leaves them alone. Bike Guy steps over.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIKE GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As an answer, Drew merely points to herself -- look at me? Now answer for yourself.</context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIKE GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Jim Wessler.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Jim. How'd you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode>BIKE GUY</mode>
      <context>Reminded, Drew puts a hand to her face.</context>
      <utterance>Who could forget that face?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, realizing just how awful she must look, Drew becomes self-conscious.</context>
      <utterance>Huh. No hives.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks past him out the door.</context>
      <utterance>Well... bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait. Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for getting me out of jail but I have to go home now because my entire life is ruined.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bad day, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You turn understatement into an art.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Please?</context>
      <utterance>Can you just tell me your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Drew MacLeod. The girl who won't be going to the NYU Accelerated Program.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew looks at her watch.</context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because short of flying, there's no way to get from here to NYU in five minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure there is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. And I thought I was anal.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker checks herself in her reflection in the glass. Working herself into Drew form, she puts her hair into a conservative bun and then tries straightening her posture.</context>
      <utterance>This is no good. I don't do too well with the whole rehearsal thing. I'm more of a 'wing it' person.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's this look? Drewish?</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I've always had a thing for librarians.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Warren, honesty is fine. But you could edit a little, you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wish me luck.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good luck, Drew.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm here to see Professor Spaulding.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have an appointment.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um, no. However...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Professor Spaulding?</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR SPAULDING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I have a moment of your time?</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR SPAULDING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tries to make a move. Parker blocks him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, but I have a plane to catch.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. But this is very important.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR SPAULDING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this about?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Professor hesitates for just an instant, giving Parker her opening. She grabs his hand, giving it a vigorous, Young Republican shake.</context>
      <utterance>Life and death, if you must know.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Drew MacLeod.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR SPAULDING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ms. MacLeod, I hope this is interesting.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trust me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The old Drew is back. She scrambles out of the shrub...</context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... and up the stairs -- then stops, turns.</context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait right there.  I mean, I don't want to be bossy. You don't have to stay right there, if you don't want to.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She launches herself into the building.</context>
      <utterance>Great.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PROFESSOR SPAULDING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ms. MacLeod, I recall your application being one of the strongest we received. Not seeing your name on the interview list surprised me. I assumed, of course, that you'd changed your mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Not at all. This program is my number one priority.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR SPAULDING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A FUSS from the OUTER OFFICE interrupts them and suddenly the door bursts open and Drew BURSTS IN:</context>
      <utterance>Yes, well, I'm sure you can appreciate that with so many applicants for so few spaces there must be rules to govern the selection process.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Professor is not only thrown by the interruption, but by Drew's particularly bizarre, barefoot look.</context>
      <utterance>Professor Spaulding? I can't apologize enough for barging in like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR SPAULDING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew shuts the door and then is startled when she gets a face full of Parker, already there.</context>
      <utterance>No. Please. It looks like I'm taking the red-eye now anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Parker?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Parker.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, the Professor and I have had a wonderful talk about how important this program is to me and how it was my sister, Drew, who screwed things up.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR SPAULDING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm having a little trouble following this.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were... being me?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I saw them take you to jail...</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR SPAULDING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jail?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... I didn't think you'd make it. I knew I wouldn't be any good at it, but I figured at least there was a chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's... sweet.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not mad?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so sorry for today.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay. But let's talk about it later.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR SPAULDING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. Go right ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Parker, consider, just for a moment, whether this is the appropriate time and place.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>jealous.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, I considered. What I want to say is, I didn't purposefully set out to ruin your day, but that doesn't mean I'm not a little...</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jealous?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not like you. I don't have your intensity, your focus, your...</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR SPAULDING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fashion sense?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just mean, maybe, even if I don't intend to, maybe that jealousy, you know, gets in the way sometimes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean subliminally you're undermining me?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know if I'd get that technical about it. But yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, thank you for saying that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're welcome.  Aren't you going to confess now?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Confess what?</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR SPAULDING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's got to be something. Like how you lost your shoes?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you're secretly jealous of me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would I be jealous of you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew stops, ponders this deeply.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, let me see. Because I don't have a stick up my butt? Because I know how to have fun? Because I'm spontaneous and creative and men are all my love slaves?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then she smiles, only a teensy bit.</context>
      <utterance>Nope.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is the first moment in a long time when the sisters share a smile. Drew turns to the Professor.</context>
      <utterance>Well, maybe about the love slaves.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Professor, I'm Drew MacLeod.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR SPAULDING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you certain?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanted more than anything in the world to be a part of your program. I still do. But I failed. I didn't follow the rules. And honestly, before today, I didn't know how I was going to live with that. How to live with failure. I'm not good at it. I haven't done it much. But today I realized that I've lived in fear of it too long.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker looks horrified at the sight of Drew's daybook in the trash and fishes it out.</context>
      <utterance>... and lighten up.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shakes her hand.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for your time. Sorry if you missed your plane.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR SPAULDING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was worth it, I assure you. Now, could you clear up one thing for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW/PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR SPAULDING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this about jail?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sis?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker grabs Warren by the hand and blasts around the corner just as... Charley MacLeod pulls up in his truck and parks half on, half off the curb. He leans over, waving to Drew.</context>
      <utterance>Gotta go.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew goes over to the truck.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, baby!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was in the city. I tried to call you. Thought you might want a ride home.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that a new outfit?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Hey, one minute, 'kay?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew goes back to Jim.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're welcome.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I, uh...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to maybe... get together?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew leans over and kisses him on the cheek. Then she reaches into her bag and pulls out a card.</context>
      <utterance>First I want to take a shower. For about a week.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call me, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles, shrugs and climbs in her dad's truck. They pull away, leaving Jim waving. When they're out of sight, Parker and Warren come back around the corner of the building.</context>
      <utterance>You have a card? Aren't you in high school?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, man. I'm doomed. I'll never get home before them.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Warren pulls out a CELL PHONE, hits speed dial.</context>
      <utterance>Sure you will.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad? Hey. I need a favor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Warren, something tells me you're spoiled!</utterance>
   <speaker>WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes! But in a good way!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="143" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>QUINN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quinn steps in, grimfaced.</context>
      <utterance>Girls?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Girls share a look. Busted.</context>
      <utterance>How naive do you think I am?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We, uh, don't think you're naive, Mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quinn holds out her hand revealing a BELLY RING.</context>
      <utterance>No. Honestly, it was all an accident.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's almost a palpable sense of relief between the girls. They BOTH LOOK DOWN and pull up their shirts -- Parker's not the only one who has her naval pierced -- Drew does, too.</context>
      <utterance>I know what this is.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Parker, I'm disappointed you'd do something like this without consulting me, but Drew? What got into you? Do you know how unhygienic those places are?</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was... spontaneous.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds out her other hand, which has an envelope.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Obviously. Oh, by the way...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stare at the envelope -- NYU ADMISSIONS DEPARTMENT.</context>
      <utterance>This came in the mail.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a HONK.</context>
      <utterance>So? Open it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="144" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>DREW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker and Quinn simply continue to stare.</context>
      <utterance>It doesn't really matter one way or the other. Maybe I shouldn't be in such a hurry. Why don't we go out and have some fun. Besides, if this isn't good news, I don't want it to ruin our night.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jim and Warren share a look. This is a story best left untold.</context>
      <utterance>So, how'd you two meet the girls?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM/WARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A dance/A class.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charley smiles. He's not as out of it as he appears. Suddenly, all three women SCREAM JOYFULLY O.S.</context>
      <utterance>Dance class, huh? Stupid me. I figured it had to be that day in New York when Parker blew off her chem test and Drew was in jail.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chips?</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
