<movie id="411" title="Next Friday">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Jones laughs at himself.</context>
      <utterance>Craig! Craig! Off yo' ass and on yo' feet; this ain't the time to beat your meat!</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be out in about 35-40 minutes!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Jones continues on his way; dancing to the beat.</context>
      <utterance>Hurry up; today is Fri-day! And we gotta hit the high-way!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLOSE UP ON CRAIG JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>the doctor of this delicate operation.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>He's sitting on the toilet (dressed: not using it) putting the finishing touches on his masterpiece. He licks, rolls and slides the 'J into the fifth pocket on his Levi jeans. CRAIG (cont'd) (V.O.) I feel like the biggest punk around here. I wiped Debo's ass. He should be the one moving. He exits.</context>
      <utterance>Soon as my pops found out what Debo said to Ezal, he wanted me to move with my uncle and little cousin in Rancho Cucamonga. Til' things calm down, or Debo went back to prison. Whichever comes first.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps off the porch backwards and into "fresh Chihuahua shit." He slips and falls on the grass. MR. JONES (cont'd) I be got damn. Mr. Jones gets up. He brushes the grass off his uniform. He looks clean, but when he turns around dog shit is smashed all over his back and butt. MR. JONES (cont'd) Craig! Craig! Craig emerges from the house with his bags in hand.</context>
      <utterance>Craig! Let's go! I don't wanna hit that traffic.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here I come!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig slams the door and starts towards the truck.</context>
      <utterance>Well bring yo' ass on...</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Jones gets in the truck. Craig jumps in. They back out and pull off.</context>
      <utterance>I fell in some mud. Now hurry up!</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Out of nowhere, Debo jumps in front of the truck. Mr. Jones slams on the BRAKES.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't wanna leave my neighborhood at all. Especially my homeboy Smokey. But he went to rehab last week. I know I'mma miss him...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Debo reaches for his shank. Craig turns to Mr. Jones!</context>
      <utterance>Craig! Get out the car, boy! This the rematch!</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Jones floors it and hits Debo. He falls over the hood, off the car and in the street. The yellow truck speeds off. Debo jumps up staggering with scrapes and bruises.</context>
      <utterance>Daddy, punch it!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know I'mma find you! You can run ya' can't hide!</utterance>
   <speaker>BACK IN CAR - CONTINUOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Craig screams out the window.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Jones is a bit shaken up.</context>
      <utterance>You fake ass Suge Knight!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That nigga worst than them damn pit bulldogs or something! That's why moving wit'cha Uncle Elroy and Cousin Day-Day is the best thing for you right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya'll making me look like a punk.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It ain't about being a punk, son. It's about this... Craig smells something in the air. MR. JONES  My great, great grand daddy on my Momma side; had a saying... 'See a fool -- leave a fool.' Somebody else a get him. Plus, I don't want that fool shooting at my house trying to hit yo' ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Jones sniffs.</context>
      <utterance>What's that smell?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Must be your upper lip, 'cause I don't smell nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What it smell like?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Jones grabs the air freshener from under the seat. He starts to spray too much. Craig's window won't roll down. CRAIG (cont'd) What's wrong with the window?</context>
      <utterance>Smells like you didn't fall in no mud.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta get'em fixed. They don't roll down.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All damn.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just hold your breath.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="55">
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice neighborhood, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's alright.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>18-years of chasing dogs; and my lazy ass brother hits the lotto his first time playing. I still can't figure that one out.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uncle Elroy's house is royal blue with gold trim. All the other houses are painted in earth tones.</context>
      <utterance>Why they got to have the loudest house on the block!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig grabs his bags.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, son, don't be no hater. You know your uncle ain't got no taste. Just don't let him rub off on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You coming in?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'mma go on to work. I don't wanna hear Elroy's mouth. Now listen to me, Craig. It's gonna be different living over here. Don't let your uncle and your cousin get you into no shit. Understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As craig gets out; the front door flies open. It's DAY-DAY (22), Craig's crazy younger cousin. He yells back into the house.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Pops, I'm grown. Can't nobody get me in trouble no more.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day walks out to the car and gives Craig a pound.</context>
      <utterance>Daddy, Craig is here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's crackin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You. Hi, Uncle Willie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Day-Day. Where's yo' big head father?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, UNCLE ELROY (42) hits the door. Dressed in boxers and a T-shirt. This is Mr. Jones' (very loud) little brother.</context>
      <utterance>There he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Debo, heard you running from a ass- whippin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naw, it ain't like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you see that boy again, bite off his ear off like Mike Tyson.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, I'll remember that.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uncle Elroy laughs. Mr. Jones isn't amused.</context>
      <utterance>You know me? I would've shot his big ass.  Hey, Willie, how's it going? Still steppin' in dog shit every day?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make sure you look after my son out here. Don't get him involved with none of your bullshit, Roy.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uncle Elroy hugs Craig by the arm.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry 'bout nothin', big bro. He in the best fuckin' hands in Rancho Chocomunga, baby! This my world, you just a nigga late paying rent. Ain't that right, nephew?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Craig, remember what I told you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Jones pulls off. Uncle Elroy yells out to him.</context>
      <utterance>I'll remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Send Betty my love.  Boy you looking good.  I'mma take these in the house for you, man... and when you finish with this cat, come inside. I got something to show you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uncle Elroy starts towards to the house.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Unc.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know it's been over a year since we kicked it last? Up at the family reunion.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day laughs.</context>
      <utterance>I know, that's when Uncle Elroy cussed out everybody, and threw up in Aunt Faye's backseat.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep. I forgot about him cussin' out everybody. Damn that was fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, we had a good time. But ever since you guys moved out here, it seems like we've lost touch.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They do. It is quiet, except for a few BIRDS SINGING. DAY-DAY (cont'd) Shit sound good, huh? Just then, a maroon Cadillac low-rider on Daytons rolls up the block. It's the Jokers: JOKER (28), LI'L JOKER (21) and BABY JOKER (15). They pull into their driveway. DAY-DAY (cont'd) Aw damn. In SLOW MOTION: One by one they get out the car. They have a dog with them named "Cheeco." As they get to the front door they all look over at Craig and Day-Day. Day-Day looks away, while Craig keeps his eye on them. They disappear inside.</context>
      <utterance>I know; this a long way from Watts. But what I like about living out here is that you don't hear no helicopters, no sirens, no drive-by's, no nothing. Just peace and quiet. Listen.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Joker, he just got out of the pen. Li'l Joker, he just got out of Youth Authority. And Baby Joker, he just got out of Juvenile Hall.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They ever let you hit the switches on that Cadillac?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk over to his black BMW 325i on chrome rims.</context>
      <utterance>Naw, them dudes is assholes. Especially that dog - Cheeco. Watch this little ass, he's sneaky. Plus, I got something better than a Cadillac.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that's me. Just a little somethin' somethin' I picked up.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Must be nice. I wish we won the lottery. Come up on a million dollars like ya'll.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, after taxes, lawyer fees, and paying off my daddy's bad credit, we didn't end up with a million. We bought this house and I spent the rest on this. It's the bomb, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This my baby. I feel like a new nigga in this car. I get mo' phone numbers rollin' this, than I ever did on the bus.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS HO KYM</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>They turn to spot MISS HO KYM (67), the old Korean lady who lives next door. She's sitting on her porch nursing a cup of coffee.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Day-Day!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Mulan.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS HO KYM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you, Day-Day. Who's ya boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This my cousin, Craig. He just moved out here from L.A. Craig, this is Miss Ho. Day-Day smiles at Craig.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS HO KYM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name is Miss Ho Kym. Day-Day just trying to be a smart ass. Nice to meet you, Craig. Are you 'bout it, 'bout it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS HO KYM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig can't believe his ears.</context>
      <utterance>I said...are you 'bout it, 'bout it -- rowdy, rowdy?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'm 'bout it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS HO KYM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all look over at the Joker's house.</context>
      <utterance>Well, then, it's all good. Yo, Day-Day, something is going down with those Mexicans across the street? I've been seeing a lot of activity.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of activity?</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS HO KYM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Strange activity. I think they running drugs off Tijuana. Day-Day don't believe me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know for sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS HO KYM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know everything, playboy. Don't hate, congratulate.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day and Craig start to walk back to the house.</context>
      <utterance>I don't have time, Miss Ho, I'll see you later.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS HO KYM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See you later, Day-Day. Come by after work, I got the John Blaze shit for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice to meet you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS HO KYM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peace out, Craig.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, this a cool house.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A sad moment.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go on and make yourself at home. I'mma go get dressed for work.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah, where you work at?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pinky's Records and Disc in the shopping center. I'mma talk to my boss and see if he got a little position for you. 'Cause you been unemployed for a long time now, Craig.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day exits. Craig is left to look around, until something outside catches his eye.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for reminding me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Craig, I want you to meet my old lady, Suga. Suga, this is Craig.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives Craig a big, juicy hug and kiss, grabbing his ass in the process. SUGA (cont'd) (hugging and grabbing) You even cuter than your baby pictures.</context>
      <utterance>Oooh, ba-by!</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uncle Elroy un-hugs them.</context>
      <utterance>You know, I'mma be your new auntie. We can keep it all in the family if you want to.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay, that's enough. Go put on some damn clothes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elroy.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Suga. Go ahead and get us something to smoke on.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.  Bye, Craig.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suga walks out.</context>
      <utterance>Nice to meet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, that girl's gonna kill me one day. Viagra ain't working. My back keep going out... she don't never get enough. But check this out. I got to lay some ground rules.  Your my family and I love you. You're welcome to anything you want in my home. But I don't wanna catch you in the refrigerator or in my Suga bowl... you feel me knocking?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, let me in.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uncle Elroy, who's that girl by Day-Day's car? He looks.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day runs down the stairs to get a look. He's holding a piece of paper.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, that's D'Wana. His ex.  Day-Day, the crazy bitch is back!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs out the door.</context>
      <utterance>Aw, naw.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Girl, you supposed to be 1000 feet from my house. What you doing over here?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'WANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What it look like I'm doing? You can't quit me, I'm pregnant!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day charges D'Wana. She has her pepper spray ready.</context>
      <utterance>That ain't my baby! Day-Day spots the damage. He loses it. DAY-DAY   Oh, my God! What you doing?! Now he's a madman. DAY-DAY  Bitch! You keyed my car! I'mma kill you!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'WANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Wana sprays his face orange. He stops in his tracks; grabs his eyes and screams like a woman.</context>
      <utterance>I got your bitch right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awwwww....  Awwwww....</utterance>
   <speaker>D'WANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Wana runs to her car. She speeds off. Uncle Elroy goes for the water hose. Craig grabs Day-Day.</context>
      <utterance>I expect you to return all phone calls and take me to lunch today. I'll be back out here on my break. Nobody quits me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't see! I can't see! Daddy!</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig puts him on the grass.</context>
      <utterance>Lay down, Day-Day. Stop moving.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She pepper-sprayed me, man! She pepper- sprayed me!</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before he can say another word, Uncle Elroy nearly drowns him with the water hose.</context>
      <utterance>I know, be still.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig moves the hose.</context>
      <utterance>Boy, you got you a little fatal attraction, huh? I had two or three of them in my day. Day-Day is drowning. UNCLE ELROY  Craig, I hope you know how to deal with women better than this fool.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now Day-Day is blind and choking.</context>
      <utterance>That's too much water.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They get him up and into the house.</context>
      <utterance>Help him to his feet. Let's get him to the bathroom.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uncle Elroy turns on the cold water. Day-Day screams. He tries to get out. They push him back in.</context>
      <utterance>Hold on. What you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wet your eyes, boy. Stay in there for about 20 minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>20 minutes?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uncle Elroy slams the door. Day-Day stands in the shower fully dressed and soaking wet. UNCLE ELROY (cont'd) Let me show you my back yard. You know it's bigger than y'all back yard. They exit, leaving Day-Day in the shower.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, 20 minutes. Trust me. I've been pepper sprayed nine times. 20 minutes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you gotta have a little money to live out here, Craig. I never thought I'd be the kinda nigga to move to the suburbs. But as soon as I got my check, I was gone. Paid 230 thousand dollars cash on this house.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You paid cash?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's half-full with dirty water. An upside-down lawn chair floats in it.</context>
      <utterance>Cash money. They wasn't gonna stick me with no 30-year payment plan. That's for suckas. They got my daddy like that for a Cadillac years ago. I got the only house on the block that's paid for. That's why I'm the king around here. They walk over to the pool. UNCLE ELROY  You like that pool?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's cool, but where's the water?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't need water. We didn't have no pool in the projects...so none of us swim.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'all never use it?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(humping the air) But me and Suga can get real nasty in that Jacuzzi, though. The Jacuzzi water has a purple condom floating in it. Uncle Elroy reaches over and picks it out. UNCLE ELROY (cont'd) (shaking the water off the condom) You welcome get in it anytime you want to. Shit, you my brother's son.</context>
      <utterance>Never...</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's okay, Unc. I can't swim, either.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CRACK DEALER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Suddenly the door flies open and Ezal comes flying out on his ass.</context>
      <utterance>Ezal, I'm sick of you coming around here wit no money.</utterance>
   <speaker>EZAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets up and brushes himself off. He heads back into the crack house. EZAL (cont'd) Now look here, man. I'mma preferred customer and I can take my credit card somewhere else. SMACK! SMACK! SMACK! Ezal is roughed up some more and flies through the picture window. GLASS rains down. EZAL (cont'd) Oh, my neck, oh, my back. Man, I quit! I'm retired! Officially! Life shouldn't be this hard for a crackhead! Ezal lays there in pain. Out of nowhere, a bicycle comes INTO FRAME. Ezal looks up at the rider. It's Debo.</context>
      <utterance>I be damned.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did Craig move to?</utterance>
   <speaker>EZAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Debo rolls on top of him with the front tire. Ezal is smashed and in more pain.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, Debo.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>EZAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He moved out to Rancho Cucamonga with his cousin Day-Day.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rancho Cucamonga?</utterance>
   <speaker>EZAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rolls off of Ezal. Relief.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Debo thinks about it. EZAL  I can't breathe.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get on.</utterance>
   <speaker>EZAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, we can't ride to Rancho Cucamonga on that.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ezal hops on the handlebars quick. They start to ride off.</context>
      <utterance>Get on!</utterance>
   <speaker>EZAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Debo rides over the curb and into the street. The journey begins. EZAL (cont'd) Watch my balls!</context>
      <utterance>Just don't go over the curb.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You straight?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day's face looks sunburned.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'm alright. Is my face still orange to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't taste nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter with your girlfriend?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, it's a long story. I met D'Wana three months ago. She had a little pudge in her stomach but I didn't pay it no attention. Come to find out, she six months pregnant. Saying I'm the daddy!</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I broke up with her two Fridays ago and she's been harassing me ever since. She don't care about the restraining order or nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Restraining order? Where the hell you meet this girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I went back to Watts to sell my old car and met her on the way. Worst day of my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn, you got a stalker.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That ain't the worst part. Her little sister, Baby D. She's the one that gets real physical. But I got a restraining order on her, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a restraining order on a little girl named Baby D?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day exits. Craig is close behind.</context>
      <utterance>You don't know Baby D. He looks at his watch. DAY-DAY  I gotta get to Pinky's before I get fired like you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig and Day-Day are mesmerized.</context>
      <utterance>Hi!</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo know what? I'm starting to like Rancho Cucamonga.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know what 'cha thinking. I thought the same thing. But it can't happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day walks over to his Beamer. Craig follows.</context>
      <utterance>Because, it's been a little tension between us ever since they got out the joint and ran their momma crazy. And I'm just trying to keep the peace. We moved out here to get away from that shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE-UP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big scratch on the side of Day-Day's car.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>DAY-DAY  It ain't that bad, is it? Craig is still looking at Karla. DAY-DAY  Craig! It ain't that bad, is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it's bad. And that scratch make it ugly. Day-Day is starting to get mad. CRAIG  It's long and crooked...make you not wanna even drive it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karla looks at her watch and starts to walk up the street. This is Craig's chance.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, alright... I see what you talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He trots after her.</context>
      <utterance>Hold up, Day-Day.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karla is still walking.</context>
      <utterance>Let it go.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Hey! She stops and waits for him. CRAIG  I'm Day-Day's cousin, Craig. What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Karla.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Craig and Karla, damn that sound pretty good together. Where you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To the Cucamonga shopping center.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah, why you walking?</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day is about to have a heart attack. He's looking back and forth between Craig and Karla, and the Joker's house where somebody is looking out the window.</context>
      <utterance>My brothers won't give me a ride.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Back at the "Love Connection," Craig has Karla smiling.</context>
      <utterance>Just get the number and come on. Just get the number and come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want us to give you a ride?</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig starts to trot over towards Day-Day. Day-Day is frantically waving Craig to hurry. CRAIG (cont'd) What are you worried about? Day-Day's eyes get as big as golf balls.</context>
      <utterance>What you mean, you don't know? Just wait here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig turns to see the pit bull "Cheeco" running right after him.</context>
      <utterance>Cheeco!</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig runs right towards Day-Day's BMW.</context>
      <utterance>Cheeco, no!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both jump on top of Day-Day's BMW with CHEECO coming up fast. He's BARKING viciously.</context>
      <utterance>Oh shit, jump!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at my roof. Big dents in the roof of his BMW. DAY-DAY  Man, why you do that? I told you not to talk to that girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day gets into the car.</context>
      <utterance>Why not? She was cool with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you mean, so?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slams the door, starts the car and backs up. Leaving Craig standing there. He sees Karla walking away. He looks over at the Jokers. They're still staring hard. Craig just looks away and walks into the house.</context>
      <utterance>If you 'get into it' with them S.A.'s and start a feud, you can always go back to home. I gotta live here. Just remember that.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uncle Elroy is sitting on the couch. He has a Phillies' Blunt (cigar) in one hand, a razor blade in the other. UNCLE ELROY (cont'd) We about to start a little puff, puff give in this mothafucka. Are you down? Suga is sippin' on a glass of wine. She moves over, making room in the middle.</context>
      <utterance>Nephew, you got perfect timing...</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you smoke weed, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why you say that?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uncle Elroy takes the razor and starts to cut the cigar the long way. UNCLE ELROY (cont'd) All I smoke is blunts. Them fuckin' Zigzags don't do nothing for me. Uncle Elroy scrapes the cigar shavings into a nearby trash can (that's overflowing with cigar shavings already). Suga presses against Craig.</context>
      <utterance>'Cause your lips is getting black.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like a glass of wine, baby?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uncle Elroy stuffs the open cigar full of weed. He's concentrating.</context>
      <utterance>No thank you. It's too early.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, I can roll a blunt better than them bitches in Havana. I know Willie don't let'cha smoke in the house, but I'm ya uncle. I don't care how high you get in my house. Long as you let me hit it... He licks and rolls. UNCLE ELROY  Look at that. It's perfect.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uncle Elroy grabs the lighter.</context>
      <utterance>Fire it up, Roy.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lights the blunt. Craig's watching, so is Suga. Uncle Elroy holds the smoke in for a very long time. Maybe too long...'cause his eyes start to bulge, and he starts to toke (cough with your mouth closed). And toke. And toke. And toke. It looks like he's about to bust when he lets out a big puff of smoke. Then he starts to cough, and cough, and cough out of control. Craig and Suga are amazed at this display. Uncle Elroy falls to the floor on his hands and knees. Still coughing. He falls on his back and passes the blunt to Craig. UNCLE ELROY (cont'd) (still coughing) It's the Bombay. Craig takes the blunt and puts it up to his lips. He hits it, holds it in and looks at Suga. Suddenly, his eyes bulge out and he starts to toke, and toke, and toke, and toke. He starts to cough out of control and he falls next to Uncle Elroy who's still coughing. Craig passes the blunt to Suga, who looks at it for a moment and then looks directly INTO the CAMERA. (As if to say, "Shiiiiiiiiiiiit.").</context>
      <utterance>Now I'mma show you the real "Puff Daddy."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks over at Uncle Elroy who's looking over at him.</context>
      <utterance>Suga.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Negro, what the hell you doing to my woman?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know!</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Suga!</utterance>
   <speaker>SUGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you doing to my nephew?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, baby...I thought this was you.  Craig, what are you doing to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, I think I passed out or something. I don't remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Passed out? Can't hang, huh? Boy, I knew you was a lightweight. Passed out on one funky ass blunt. They don't make 'em like they used to, baby. Uncle Elroy staggers to his feet. UNCLE ELROY  Come on, woman. I'm faded and feeling X- rated. It's Mr. Nasty time.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Nasty time?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Nasty time.  But take it easy on me, girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suga takes Elroy's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Craig, you ain't the only lightweight around here.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both stumble upstairs leaving Craig all alone. It's too quiet now. He grabs the remote and TURNS ON the TV. Flicks a few channels. He picks up the blunt and the lighter.</context>
      <utterance>Make yourself at home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>His eavesdropping is interrupted by a loud KNOCK on the door. Craig is so comfortable, he doesn't want to move. The KNOCKING gets LOUDER.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, baby, right there. Right there...bite the nipple, baby. Bite it! Bite it! Yeah, mothafucka -- yeah, come on, baby, get busy...</utterance>
   <speaker>DELIVERY GUY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Delivery!</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig gets up slowly and starts to clean the area. The</context>
      <utterance>Hold on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DELIVERY GUY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Delivery!</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said hold on!</utterance>
   <speaker>DELIVERY GUY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Craig stops what he's doing and swings the door open.</context>
      <utterance>Could you hurry up, please... it's kinda hot out here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELIVERY GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice house. Didn't expect you to answer. You must be one of those entertainers. What team you play for?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't play for no team.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELIVERY GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, jerky, you can tell me. Got a white wife, huh? Blonde bombshell type. Remember what happen to O.J... what team do you play for? You're not related to the Jacksons, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naw, I play for the Chocamunga Cracker Killers. You want tickets?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELIVERY GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig signs.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, buddy. Don't send your entourage out here to do a 187 on me. It's just a certified mail delivery. He hands Craig a letter. DELIVERY GUY  Sign here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELIVERY GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs and walks off singing the "Good Times" jingle. DELIVERY GUY (cont'd) '...temporary layoffs? Good Times...hustling and surviving... Good Times...ain't we lucky we got'em...' Oh shit! Cheeco starts to chase him down the street. Craig looks at the notice. "DELINQUENT! YOUR HOUSE WILL BE SEIZED AND</context>
      <utterance>Delinquent Property Tax Notice... I hope the Cracker Killers pay well 'cause if not, back to the ghetto you go. Wife stays here, of course.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes after Craig, who has to fight him off. UNCLE ELROY (cont'd) I like it rough now.</context>
      <utterance>Come on here, Suga...</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uncle Elroy grabs him in a bear hug and slams him on the bed. Craig finds himself caught between Suga and Uncle Elroy, but now everything is totally still and quiet. Uncle Elroy starts to snore again. He's asleep. The coast is clear now. Craig tries to make his escape. He crawls over Suga to get away. She grabs him and starts to kiss him.</context>
      <utterance>Naw, naw! Unc, wake up! It's me! Wake up!</utterance>
   <speaker>SUGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig breaks away and tries to hurry out the room. On his exit, he hangs himself on the "fuck swing" and hits the floor with a thud. He scrambles to his feet, then he's out of there. Uncle Elroy and Suga lay asleep as if nothing ever happened.</context>
      <utterance>Ohhh, baby!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>EZAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He finally stops at a pay phone. Ezal jumps off and grabs his ass. EZAL (cont'd) My God...gotta walk it out, walk it out. Man, it's gonna take us a week to ride out there.</context>
      <utterance>We gotta stop or something, man. My ass is hurting. This handlebar is hard. Debo keeps riding. EZAL  Debo! Debo! Now you stuck on stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up! He still eats here every day!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's the plan. You gonna call over there and say you have a very urgent message for Mr. William Jones.</utterance>
   <speaker>EZAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What urgent message?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you shut up I'll tell you. The urgent message is...Drop everything! Craig is in trouble. Come quick, don't call.</utterance>
   <speaker>EZAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Debo slaps him in the back of the head.</context>
      <utterance>That ain't gonna work.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>EZAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smack! Debo slaps him again.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know the number.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's on the outside of the building, now pick the phone up! Ezal picks up the phone. He starts to dial.</utterance>
   <speaker>EZAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello...Yeah, I got an urgent message for a nigga named Mr. Willie Jones. Debo slaps him again.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>William.</utterance>
   <speaker>EZAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I got a urgent message for a customer named William Jones. Drop everything, Craig is in trouble. Come quick. Don't try to call. Ezal hangs up the phone. EZAL  Man, you better stop hittin' on me for I do you like Craig did you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Debo and Ezal run across the street to the dog truck. Debo opens the back and lets all the dogs out. They run for it. DEBO (cont'd) After I get in, close the door. Debo is a hard fit. Ezal stuffs him in there.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>EZAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You too big.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finally he's in. Ezal gets in and slams the door shut. Just then, Mr. Jones comes running out the joint with a sandwich in hand.</context>
      <utterance>Keep pushing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets in and speeds off.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="34">
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tries to jump off the counter and land perfectly on his board. Wrong! Off the board and on his ass.</context>
      <utterance>Yo, Day-Day! Check me out.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Roach, I know you ain't never worked in a record shop before and you're a little excited. But if Pinky catches you doing that X-Games shit off his counter top, we both getting fired. You feel me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An unhappy CUSTOMER walks in holding a CD without the cover.</context>
      <utterance>I feel you. I've just been practicing that one move all week.  I thought that was it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUSTOMER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't get jiggy with this shit.  Where is the damn manager?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The customer throws the CD on the counter. Day-Day picks it up.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, the manager stepped out for a moment. I'm currently running the store. Can I see the CD?</utterance>
   <speaker>CUSTOMER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, give me my damn money back. Right now, and I don't have no damn receipt neither.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, sir...but where's the cover?</utterance>
   <speaker>CUSTOMER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig walks in with the notice in hand.</context>
      <utterance>I don't have no damn cover.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't give you your damn money back on this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUSTOMER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bullshit! I'll go postal in this mothafucka!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The customer KNOCKS over a counter display and then turns to get away. DAY-DAY (cont'd) Hey! Craig bumps him and he falls into the Rap cassette rack.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you gonna have to go postal then.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUSTOMER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He jumps up and slips on a few more cassettes on his scramble out the door.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry! Don't hit me! Don't hit me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roach can't believe what just happened.</context>
      <utterance>...and if you come back, it's gonna be worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you see that? That was a W.W.F. hit right there, huh, Day-Day?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it was. How you get up here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I walked.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You walked?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives it to Day-Day.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, ya'll got a notice today. It came certified mail.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Craig, this Roach. Roach, this is my cousin, Craig.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig nods his head.</context>
      <utterance>What up, bro?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day reads the notice.</context>
      <utterance>I tried to wake up Uncle Elroy but he thought I was Suga.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what this is?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that's why I walked down here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day ignores Roach.</context>
      <utterance>What it say?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can they do this?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Did ya'll forget to pay it or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What it say?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ever since my momma died the bills are always late.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day opens it. A PHONE starts to RING.</context>
      <utterance>See how much it is?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roach skateboards over to the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about it, man. Get the phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day reads on.</context>
      <utterance>Pinky's.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It says we owe $3,900...by tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day goes for his bank book. He flips a few pages.</context>
      <utterance>Damn...how much money ya'll got left from the lottery?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day is overwhelmed. Roach skates back over.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, plan B.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day looks at Craig. He runs over to the door.</context>
      <utterance>That was a girl on a cell phone. She said she's outside in the parking lot waiting for you to take her to lunch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="38">
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day locks the door and runs into the back. Craig and Roach follow.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God. That's D'Wana. And she got Baby'D with her.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>D'Wana brought Baby'D up here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That the big one, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The PHONE starts to RING again. D'Wana and Baby'D are at the door. D'Wana is on her phone. Baby'D starts to knock. DAY-DAY (cont'd) Craig, go out there and tell 'em I'm gone.</context>
      <utterance>You damn right that's the big one.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't trying to get in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The knocking gets louder.</context>
      <utterance>You already in.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No I'm not.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You can't handle a girl like D'Wana. It's got to be Craig.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'WANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That white boy said he was in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY'D</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Day-Day, don't make me break this window! Craig is peeking out. He hesitates.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig walks out the back. He steps over the door. Unlocks it, and cracks it open.</context>
      <utterance>Watch out for Baby'D.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They don't believe him.</context>
      <utterance>Day-Day ain't here.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'WANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm his cousin.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY'D</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You suppose to work here now or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I work here now.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'WANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We didn't come here for Day-Day.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'WANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No we didn't. We came to buy a CD.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY'D</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baby'D kicks the door. Craig has no choice but to let 'em in.</context>
      <utterance>Now move.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'WANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's that boy that told me Day-Day was here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know... I think he went out the back.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'WANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I look for myself? Suddenly Roach is pushed into the front area.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, ladies.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'WANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Day-Day?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Wana looks at Baby'D.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, he must've left.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought ya'll wanted to buy a CD?</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY'D</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig looks at Roach for directions. He nods over towards the front of the store.</context>
      <utterance>I do... can you help me find the jazz section?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baby'D checks out Craig as he leads the way. D'Wana looks around.</context>
      <utterance>Right this way. You know damn well you don't listen to no jazz.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'WANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If Day-Day comes back, tell him I came by and need to see him. Lamaze classes are Wednesday.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Wana starts to walk towards Craig and Baby'D.</context>
      <utterance>Will do.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'WANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But first she doubles back towards the storage room.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, 'D, let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'WANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't the rest room this way? I gotta pee.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'WANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she's walking in the back, Roach realizes his mistake.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day makes a run for it. She spots him ducking out the back door.</context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'WANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's in there!</utterance>
   <speaker>INSIDE STORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Baby'D knocks Craig out of the way.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY'D</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'WANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baby'D gives chase with D'Wana, Craig and Roach close behind.</context>
      <utterance>He ran out the door.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...and he is.</context>
      <utterance>Haul ass, dude. Don't stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You better stop running from that girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs back towards his BMW. The chase continues around his car. Baby'D is starting to tire. DAY-DAY (cont'd) I'mma shoot yo' big ass. D'Wana watches from a distance. Craig and Roach are close.</context>
      <utterance>Fuuuuuuck -- U!</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, remember me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell yeah, I remember you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry for what my brother did this morning. They're assholes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's cool. You ain't got to apologize for your brothers. They're big boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just wanted to give you this. She hands him a card with her number on it. KARLA  If my brothers wasn't so over-protective, I'd have you call the house. But for now just page me when you get a chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Most definitely.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She picks up her shopping bags and walks away. Over at the chase: Baby'D is winded. She bends over trying to catch her breath.</context>
      <utterance>Better sooner than later.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baby'D looks over at Craig.</context>
      <utterance>Baby'D, you're not going to catch me as usual. So what can we do to end it this time? What you want? Another Big Pun CD? 'Cause I gotta get back to work.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY'D</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, I know what I want this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything you need.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY'D</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo' cousin, Craig. Hook us up.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY'D</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just tell him to come over here and talk to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I can go free?</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY'D</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day carefully walks back over towards the store. D'Wana pouts and walks towards Baby'D. (If looks could kill.)</context>
      <utterance>Go, fo' I change my mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great moves, Day-Day.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happen?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig looks over at Baby'D. She's waiting.</context>
      <utterance>We worked out a deal. All you gotta do is go over there and talk to Baby'D.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you mean talk to her?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what he mean, dude.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig turns and sprints into the store. Baby'D looks concerned. Day-Day grabs Roach and they run into the store.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY'D</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Wana hands her a brick.</context>
      <utterance>I'mma get you, Day-Day! You gotta come out sometimes!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'WANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baby'D screams and throws the brick through Day-Day's</context>
      <utterance>I told you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="40">
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day is devastated.</context>
      <utterance>You don't wanna know.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks a lot, Craig.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know we cousins and all, but don't try an' hook me up with the big little sisters.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big bitches need love, too, Craig.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For sure. That's how I like 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are they still out there?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day starts to walk into the back storage area. ROACH (cont'd) Shouldn't we straighten up out here before Pinky gets back? Day-Day is like a zombie now. He doesn't answer, just keeps walking.</context>
      <utterance>Negative...they vamped.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Day-Day? No answer. Craig looks at Roach. They follow.</utterance>
   <speaker>BACK STORAGE AREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Day-Day sits with the notice in hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Today ain't my day.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bummer, huh? And Friday is suppose to be a kick-ass day.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah it is...the best day before the weekend.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roach pulls out a big, smashed brownie with green shit in it.</context>
      <utterance>That's fuckin' poetic, Craig. Day-Day is still sad. ROACH  I know how you feeling. And if I had my bong right now, I'd let you 'toke 'til you choke.' Dude, right here. All out. No lungs. All I got is this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the green stuff poking out?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wanna bite?</context>
      <utterance>That's cron-don, sir. My mom hates for me to smoke, so she made me bud-brownies.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naw, I already ate.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day shakes his head. Craig reaches into his fifth pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Day, try it. For moms.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has the joint from this morning.</context>
      <utterance>It ain't a bong but, wa-la!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roach snatches it.</context>
      <utterance>Wo!</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig snatches it back.</context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, bro, reflexes. How did you do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day snatches the joint and puts it in his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Black magic.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roach pulls out a mini-skateboard that's actually a lighter.</context>
      <utterance>Give me dat. I'm the one with the problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lights the joint. Day-Day takes a hit.</context>
      <utterance>Weed doesn't solve problems. It eases the mind, and the soul. Enjoy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't think you smoked bud that much.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn nigga, don't Jack the joint. I didn't even pass it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, dude.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You better open up a window or something before the smell gets out.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't no windows in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands the joint to Craig. Gets up and closes the door. Then he grabs the vacuum out of the corner. ROACH (cont'd) This is a little theory of mine... it should work. He plugs in the VACUUM and TURNS it ON. He puts the nozzle in Day-Day's face.</context>
      <utterance>I got an idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blow.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That ain't gonna work.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day hits the 'J and blows into the nozzle. It quickly sucks up the smoke.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It works.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still gonna smell it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roach hits the joint harder than anyone else. Smoke starts to come out of his ears. Craig and Day-Day get a kick out of that.</context>
      <utterance>No way. Watch this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roach, what are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A big cloud of smoke rolls out of his mouth and he falls and hits the deck. ROACH (cont'd) My spleen. Craig and Day-Day laugh at Roach. The VACUUM is still GOING but the room is very smoky. Craig jumps in.</context>
      <utterance>R-U-S-H Intensely.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This vacuum don't work. Where's the restroom?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out the door and to the left.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought the vacuum would work.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>PINKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'mma show you how I do 'em.</context>
      <utterance>Don't move or I'll blow your head smooth off. Craig throws his hands up. PINKY  Now back up slowly... and don't say a word. He obeys. Pinky backs Craig into the store. PINKY  Get on the floor. Craig gets down. PINKY  Little mothafucka trying to rob me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't trying to rob you...</utterance>
   <speaker>PINKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up! Fo' I pump this Glock in yo' ass! What did you do wit Day-Day and Roach?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, Day-Day is my people!</utterance>
   <speaker>PINKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said shut up! Now who sent you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody!</utterance>
   <speaker>PINKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pinky backs up and steps on Roach's skateboard. The gun goes flying and so does he. Pinky falls on his ass. The 9mm lands in front of Craig. There's a big scramble for the gun.</context>
      <utterance>If you say another word, it's over. I'm not playing! Pinky starts to pat down Craig's pockets. PINKY  You ain't got no gun, but where's the weed at? I smell it. Craig says nothing. PINKY  I'mma tie you ass up!</utterance>
   <speaker>BACK STORAGE AREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The mood is serious.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta think of a plan to get this money before tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could sell your Beamer. Day-Day gives Roach the evil-eye. ROACH  My bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I hope Craig got a good idea. We gotta ask him when he comes out. Let's go and clean up before Pinky gets here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you can ask him to loan you the money.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yoooo, that's it. You ain't as dumb as I think you are, Roach.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PINKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig is exhausted. He stands over Pinky with the gun.</context>
      <utterance>Don't kill me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up. I been trying to tell yo' ass that... Day-Day is my cousin. They're right there in the back.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, Day-Day and Roach come from the back.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever you say, man. I didn't see shit. The safe combination is 34-5-27. Just take it all.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Craig, what the hell are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Day-Day, is this your cousin?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. You fired...and, Roach, your fired too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why me?</utterance>
   <speaker>PINKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And you...you lucky. I was just about to get in yo' ass. Now give me my pistol back and get the hell out my store. Craig looks at Day-Day. Day-Day looks back at him. Nobody's high now.</context>
      <utterance>I smell weed. He looks up at Craig. PINKY</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just hold on, Craig. I'm on my way.</utterance>
   <speaker>EZAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Debo! Debo!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>EZAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't feel my legs no more.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me neither. How far is Rancho Cucamonga?</utterance>
   <speaker>EZAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah damn. Damn.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got fired too.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to beat Day-Day with a sex toy.</context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, sit down.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then the door opens and out walks MICHAEL JORDAN.</context>
      <utterance>Say, man, what the hell you doing in there? Open the door.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What we gonna do?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets on his skateboard.</context>
      <utterance>I know what I'mma do. Go home and face the music. My dad is gonna kick my ass for getting fired again.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, Roach, see you around.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry about today, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He attempts to jump off the porch with his board and lands dead on his ass once again. His board continues to roll.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, me too. Later.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His board continues to roll into the street. At this same time, Joker's low-rider rolls by and breaks his board in two. Roach runs to pick up the pieces.</context>
      <utterance>Man, sit down. I can't think with you falling everywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Joker Bros. back their low-rider into the driveway. They have no sympathy. Cheeco (the pitbull) is in the back yard. He's happy to see them. They stroll into the house with three Mexican girls with them. Joker spots our trio looking.</context>
      <utterance>My board!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck you looking at?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ran over my board!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They disappear into the house.</context>
      <utterance>So what? It shouldn't have been in the street.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the fuck is that, Day-Day?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let it go, Roach, trust me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not letting nothing go. They killed my board.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig is looking over at the Joker's house. Baby Joker walks out the front door. He walks over to the rider and POPS the</context>
      <utterance>Let it go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baby Joker pulls out a chrome hydraulic pump. He carries it towards the house. Cheeco starts to hump his leg.</context>
      <utterance>Wait. Check'em out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baby Joker drops the pump, something falls out. (We can't see what it is.) Baby Joker quickly puts it back.</context>
      <utterance>Get down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't see nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me neither.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's something in that hydraulic pump.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, air.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naw. I bet'cha it's something better than air.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you know? It could be anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But I just say we go take a look.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, and it could be anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I say we go over there and kick their asses. I can take the little one.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you out your mind? I'm not messing with them S.A.'s boy. You must be crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could be. Rather be crazy than homeless. Now all we need is a big pack of baloney. Day-Day and Roach look at each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOTH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Baloney??</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you were taking me to see Mama?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take you later.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When? After you get all drunk and loaded?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karla storms out the room. Baby Joker walks in carrying the chrome pump. JOKER (cont'd) Get up. The Pretty Girl moves off Joker's lap. JOKER (cont'd) Take it in the room. Baby Joker carries the pump in the bedroom. Joker is close behind. He SLAMS the DOOR. The Girl dancing with Li'l Joker gets too nosy.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! I said I'll take your fuckin' ass later. Now get out of here. You're scaring our company.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LI'L JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was what?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That silver thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>LI'L JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't see no silver thing, and neither did you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day tries to turn around. Craig grabs him.</context>
      <utterance>This ain't gonna work. I'm going back.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's about to work, just come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig slaps the baloney out of his hand.</context>
      <utterance>What about the dog?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All three kneel down next to a parked car. Day-Day looks sick.</context>
      <utterance>That's what the baloney's for!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, I don't think I can do this, Craig. I got the B-G's.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the B-G's?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The bubble guts. I'm so nervous it feels like I'mma shit on myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try an' hold it, man. Squeeze your ass cheeks together.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig grabs Day-Day again.</context>
      <utterance>Butterflies, my ass. I'm about to go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day realizes that Craig is right. He takes a deep breath. CRAIG (cont'd) Now all we gotta do is find out where the little one put that pump. Take it and see what's in it.</context>
      <utterance>Look, Day-Day. If we don't go over there and take a look, this might be the last night you got a home. Now trust me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You make it sound so easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is easy. You know why? 'Cause they're not expecting it. Now, Roach, you gotta occupy Cheeco. Long enough for me and Day-Day to take a good look.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Me and K-9's just don't get along.</context>
      <utterance>Dude, dogs hate me. I don't know why.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well get along with this one.  Go ahead of us. Don't get seen and don't let that mutt out of your sight.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck, what's his name?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roach crawls away on his hands and knees.</context>
      <utterance>Cheeco.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's pitch-black behind the fence, still no Cheeco.</context>
      <utterance>Here, Cheeco. Chee-co, here boy. That's a good boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKED CAR - SAME TIME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Craig makes a move.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day follows.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, he should have'em by now.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They sneak up to the side of the house. The MUSIC is BLEEDING THROUGH the walls.</context>
      <utterance>Hurry up. He didn't have that much baloney.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You go first.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naw, you go first.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You go first.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Day-Day, if you don't hop that fence I'mma throw you over.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day gets ready to fight.</context>
      <utterance>I ain't scared of you. We ain't little no more.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig jumps like he's going to hit him. Day-Day jumps back and almost falls.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope to God that dog is happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A LOT of BARKING. Nothing coming.</context>
      <utterance>Wait for what?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's still over by Roach.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BABY JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want me to take a look?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the mirror behind Joker, we see a stick slide through the curtain. The curtain cracks just enough to see Craig's eye looking in. Just then, Li'l Joker bursts through the door with his shirt off and two half-naked girls on his arms.</context>
      <utterance>No, keep working.</utterance>
   <speaker>LI'L JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's Friday, time to party, SA.</context>
      <utterance>Yo, man fuck that shit. Do it later.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Close the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>LI'L JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not until you come party with us, man. Baby Joker looks at the girls, then at Joker.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joker hands Baby Joker the money. He puts it away. They start to exit the room.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, put it in that drawer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you see?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That pump was full of money. I saw where they put it. Stay right here, I'mma climb in and go get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait here? So Cheeco can bite my ass off? Tell me where it is I'll do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig climbs in the window. Day-Day holds his stomach.</context>
      <utterance>No, man, just wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got the B-G's.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GIRL #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joker picks her up and carries her to the bedroom. She screams. He laughs. He goes for the door. It's locked. JOKER (cont'd) Who locked this door? Everybody looks confused. JOKER (cont'd) Who locked this fuckin' door?! Joker starts to kick the door.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joker walks in and hits the lights. He throws the girl on the bed.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want no doors locked around here. You hear me?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, poppy, I like it rough.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good, 'cause that's how you gonna get it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Think fast, Craig.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope you don't think I'm crazy, but I just had to come in here and show you I ain't scared of yo' punk ass brothers...and you wouldn't have be scared of 'em neither if you had a man like me in yo' life.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?? So you snuck in my room to tell me that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her door flies open. Smashing Craig behind it. It's Li'l Joker.</context>
      <utterance>Yes I did. Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LI'L JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig looks nervous.</context>
      <utterance>Who you talking to?</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody.</utterance>
   <speaker>LI'L JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard a voice.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karla pushes Li'l Joker out.</context>
      <utterance>No you didn't. Get out my room. Go back down to your little girlfriends.</utterance>
   <speaker>OUTSIDE JOKER'S BEDROOM WINDOW - CONTINUOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Day-Day is having a fit.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut the window.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She does.</context>
      <utterance>You shut the window.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day takes off. He hops the fence in record speed.</context>
      <utterance>Oh shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roach...Roach, come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Craig?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's inside the house?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did he go in the house?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's probably getting tied up now.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about it. We gotta figure out a way to get Craig out of there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did all this for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Most of it. I just hate to see you in this situation.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for noticing. It used ta be peaceful before they got out. Took over the house and caused my mother's nervous breakdown.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't she put'em out?</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easier said than done. We saved up to get away from them, but they followed us.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry to hear that. Craig walks over to the window. CRAIG  Can I get out this way? Karla walks up behind him, looking very sexy.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig turns around.</context>
      <utterance>I thought you came up here to see me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did. Is that door locked?</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's locked.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karla turns around to check the door.</context>
      <utterance>Make sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig drops a thick roll of money into her purse. She shakes the knob. KARLA (cont'd) See. All locked. She walks over to him. They're face-to-face. KARLA (cont'd) What's your hurry?</context>
      <utterance>You so nervous, I already locked this door.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got my cousin Day-Day waiting for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig looks AT the CAMERA.</context>
      <utterance>So what? Let's make'em wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I be damn.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna knock?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go for it. Day-Day knocks real soft. Too soft. ROACH  No one's gonna hear that. The music's playing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Scuse me, partner, but that's a ghetto knock.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roach starts to kick on the door with his foot. It's very loud.</context>
      <utterance>This is a knock.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You fuckin' lover boys hear that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The KNOCKING continues. Li'l Joker and Baby Joker push the girls aside and jump up. Li'l Joker grabs a big knife. Baby Joker grabs a 9mm. Joker looks at the girls.</context>
      <utterance>Hear what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They won't. The brothers run to the door.</context>
      <utterance>Don't fuckin' move.</utterance>
   <speaker>OUTSIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roach is still kicking.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The front door swings open and before we know it. Day-Day's got an AK pointed in his face, and Roach is looking at a 9 close up.</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with you, fool. Stop kicking their door. They might think we the police.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day's tongue doesn't work.</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh...um...I mean uh, can we borrow a cup of sugar?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?! This look like a 7-11 or something? Get the fuck outta here!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, no problem. We gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Immediately Day-Day and Roach are snatched inside the house, and the door is SLAMMED.</context>
      <utterance>Hold on. A man, you broke my fuckin' board and I don't appreciate it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got your message. Where's Craig?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, I didn't leave you no damn message!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't call the Sandwich Joint with a urgent message?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell naw, Willie. Them fleas and tics must be sucking on yo' brain!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody left me a message. Well where's Craig and Day-Day?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Suga, go ask Miss Ho Kym if she seen them.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Next time, page me first.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig climbs out the window. He loses his footing and free falls into some bushes.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs past a sleeping Cheeco and hops the fence. Free at last. He's about to run back across the street when he sees the dog truck. CRAIG (cont'd) What is he doing here? Craig ducks back.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'm cool. See you later.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, man, this is a big misunderstanding. All we wanted to do is borrow some sugar.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And some rolling papers.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They answer --</context>
      <utterance>...and some rolling papers, that's it. We didn't mean to mess up y'all get together or nothing.  How y'all doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's good. My name's Day-Day and this is my friend, Roach.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya'll live around here?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up! Both of you right now!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shhhh! Roach, shut the fuck up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joker thinks for a moment. Then he turns to Baby Joker. JOKER (cont'd) (in Spanish) Go check on the money. Baby Joker obeys the order.</context>
      <utterance>I don't believe this sugar shit. Something ain't right.</utterance>
   <speaker>LI'L JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here comes Karla, put the guns away.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karla walks back in.</context>
      <utterance>Keep your mouth shut.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, what's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing. What you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you going to take me to see Mom?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take your car.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Take your car?'</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karla doesn't believe it.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, and hurry up.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's out the door. Joker turns to Day-Day and Roach.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. She grabs the keys off the bar. KARLA  I'll be back in a bit. 'Bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If everything's alright. We might let you leave, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Jones pops up. So does Suga and Miss Ho Kym.</context>
      <utterance>Craig, where the hell you been?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold up, Elroy, that's my boy. Craig, what the hell wrong with you? Where you been?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you seen Day-Day?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Thought he was with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps in the house and closes the door behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Daddy, Uncle Elroy, I need your help.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BABY JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some of the money is missing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!?!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!  What that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Li'l Joker turns to the girls.</context>
      <utterance>It means you Miyateas are staying with us.  Get the duct tape.  You know what to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>LI'L JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The scared Girls start to dress.</context>
      <utterance>Put your clothes back on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw it.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me, too. You think they're in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yup.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS HO KYM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why for? Them boys are real player haters.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a long story. Right now we gotta do somethin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You come way out here to get into more trouble. You could've stayed at home.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Willie, shut up. Yo' old ass need to get in a little bit o' trouble sometimes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't get it twisted, Elroy. I ain't lost none of my street skills.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig, Uncle Elroy and Mr. Jones are about to go on a mission.</context>
      <utterance>If ya'll don't come back not in ten minutes, I'mma callin' the po'lice.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uncle Elroy runs upstairs.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute. I gotta go get my shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DAY-DAY &amp; ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Why can't we be friends?'...</context>
      <utterance>'Why can't we be friends? Why can't we be friends? Why can't we be friends?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut the fuck up! The singing stops. JOKER  If you don't tell me where my money is, I'mma show you how close we can get.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Money? Man, we came over here from some sugar and rolling papers. We was going to get high, and I was going to show this white boy how to make Kool-Aid. That's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joker walks over to Roach and kicks him in the mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, mister Joker, have a heart, bro. It's Friday.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm hearing a lot of talking, but I'm not hearing the right words.</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe the other guy took it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would he take it? He don't even know you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up! Where's that other miyatea?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a nice piece of heat right there.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. I only got two bullets in the mothafucka, but it's better than nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Back in the day, all I had was a stick.</context>
      <utterance>Two bullets? Yo' ass ain't changed.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They sneak over to the fence.</context>
      <utterance>Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about that ugly dog?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got my mase.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start to hop the fence.</context>
      <utterance>He's on the other side, sleep.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Need to lose some weight.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig &amp; Mr. Jones helps him up. They creep over to the window - the shades are pulled down.</context>
      <utterance>Shut yo' ass up. Uncle Elroy falls off the fence. UNCLE ELROY  Damn.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure, but I think they're in this room.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tape his mouth shut.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Joker, a man like yourself can do a lot for this community. By letting us go, you can improve black and brown relations.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day looks at Roach.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, brown and white relations, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Li'l Joker grabs Day-Day and tapes his mouth shut. He does the same to Roach.</context>
      <utterance>Boy, you gonna get us killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baby Joker hands him the AK and he's gone. Day-Day and Roach look terrified. Everything has turned serious.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sick and tired of bullshitting with you guys.  Baby brother, go get the chainsaw.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DEBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ezal! Ezal!</utterance>
   <speaker>EZAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We must be here 'cause we stopped.</utterance>
   <speaker>EZAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both try to get out. But it's no way to get out from the inside.</context>
      <utterance>Good, let's get out.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, how you get out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>EZAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both start to go nuts on the door.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>OUTSIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The dog truck is shaking like crazy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>BABY JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No Cheeco. He continues to a shed in the back yard. He goes inside and picks up a chainsaw. On his way out the shed, he's slapped in the face with a "Big Ass Stick." Mr. Jones is working the handle. Baby Joker is out cold. Mr. Jones stands over him.</context>
      <utterance>Cheeco! Cheeco! Here, boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nigga, you got knock the fuck out.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, pops!</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn, big bro. You swung that like Sammy Sosa.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The skills are still intact. Now tie his ass up, Elroy. He does.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day starts to cry. Roach tries to scream through the tape. Joker turns to Li'l Joker. JOKER (cont'd) Go see what's taking him so long. Li'l Joker obeys. We FOLLOW Li'l Joker THROUGH the house and OUT the back door.</context>
      <utterance>My little brother went out to get my chainsaw. I'mma show you what happens to fools who don't tell me what I wanna hear. You ever see Scarface, mothafucka?</utterance>
   <speaker>LI'L JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer. Suddenly he spots something over by the shed. It's Baby Joker all ties up. LI'L JOKER (cont'd) What the... He runs to the rescue. But right before he gets to him, Uncle Elroy jumps out the bushes and takes him. "Ronnie Lott Style." Mr. Jones steps in with the stick. Craig steps in with the rope, and it's over. Uncle Elroy's hurt. It's his back.</context>
      <utterance>Junior?! Junior?!</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig goes to assist Uncle Elroy.</context>
      <utterance>I slip my disc, again... Oh got damn.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stretch it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't move me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He storms out the room. Day-Day and Roach try to escape. They flap around on the ground like a fish out of water.</context>
      <utterance>Where are these fucking guys?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I lost something, nigga. What it look like?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Out of nowhere, Craig hits Joker from the back. He flies one way and the gun flies another. Now it's really on! Hand-to- hand combat. Craig vs. Joker. Right vs. wrong. Good vs. evil. You know how it go.</context>
      <utterance>Looks like a dead man.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go to the body, Craig! Go to the body!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get 'em, Craig!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bite his ear!</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joker takes a few more shots from Craig, then grabs Craig around the waist and slams him to the ground. Craig is hurt. UNCLE ELROY (cont'd) Get off yo' back, Craig! Craig struggles with Joker, who now has the devil in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>What 'em! Watch 'em!</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Day-Day and Roach look at each other. They rush to Craig's aide. Joker spots them coming, he also spots the AK. In SLOW MOTION, Day-Day and Roach dive on Joker...at the same time Joker dives for the AK. Day-Day and Roach land on top of Craig and our trio try to hurry to their feet. But as soon as they get up, they're looking down the barrel of an AK-</context>
      <utterance>Ya'll mothafuckas help me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finally you got a bitch, huh, Roach?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a boy, dude.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EZAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Jones don't wanna hear it. Craig runs into the house. Uncle, Day-Day, Roach and Cheeco look at the five on the ground...it's over, or is it?</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Jones, we was just playin'. He made me do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SHERIFFS are on our heroes, guns drawn.</context>
      <utterance>Freeze, Sheriff's Department!</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute! I live across the street!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Paid cash.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They the ones you want.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When my back gets better I'mma beat the black off you, Day-Day.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suga and Miss Ho Kym come running.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, my ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elroy, what happen?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I threw my back, again.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, no lovin' tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naw, baby, no lovin' tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, baby, let's go in the house.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone is sad.</context>
      <utterance>For what? We ain't gonna have no house after the auction tomorrow!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, bro, you, Suga, Day-Day and Craig can live with me and my parents. 'Til you get back on yo' feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Roach, but I can't accept that. We're moving back to Watts where it's safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Craig?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That boy just don't never learn.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks past the cops and crosses the street.</context>
      <utterance>I love Fridays.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There he go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is he carrying?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They greet Craig and all start to walk towards the house.</context>
      <utterance>Property taxes, and a new candy-apple paint job.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jump up and down on him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS HO KYM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's next.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suga is at the table counting money. She takes a few hundreds for herself.</context>
      <utterance>Don't listen to him. How much we got?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got forty-seven thousand, three hundred and fifteen dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good Lord.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS HO KYM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a whole lot of scrilla.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig is tending to his wounds.</context>
      <utterance>It's gonna feel good to pay my taxes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're welcome, Unc.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about me?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roach and Cheeco are about to leave. He has a handful of money.</context>
      <utterance>You didn't do nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, guys, I'm outta here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the help.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, man, the pleasure's all mine. Thanks for the dog, and the money. Maybe my dad won't kick my ass tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, later, bro. Hey, Craig, nice smokin' wit'cha.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You too.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smokin' what?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Later, Mr. Jones. Bye, Suga.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roach is gone. Day-Day shuts the door. Miss Ho Kym is finished. She steps off of Uncle Elroy.</context>
      <utterance>Bye, Roach.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS HO KYM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uncle Elroy gets up. He's better.</context>
      <utterance>All done. Stand up.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uncle Elroy walks over to the table and grabs a stack of hundred-dollar bills. He hands it to Miss Ho Kym.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, that George Jefferson shit works. Thanks, Miss Kym.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS HO KYM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't accept.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes the money.</context>
      <utterance>You better take this money.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS HO KYM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.  I can take a trip back to Korea now. Find a freak daddy, bring him back to America. Make 'em my bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uncle Elroy helps Miss Ho Kym out the door.</context>
      <utterance>You go, girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craig, get your stuff.</context>
      <utterance>Well, we better hit the road, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE ELROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suga hugs Craig.</context>
      <utterance>Well, Craig, you're welcome anytime.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUGA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the others have to agree.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, baby, it's a shame you leavin'. Aunt Suga gonna miss yo.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure you don't wanna stay?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naw, I'm got live ghetto fabulous. make sure you get that car fixed.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAY-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will. When can I come visit?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're out the door.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Probably next Friday.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
