<movie id="418" title="Notting Hill">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course, I've seen her films and always thought she was, well, fabulous -- but, you know, million miles from the world I live in. Which is here -- Notting Hill -- not a bad place to be...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's the market on weekdays, selling every fruit and vegetable known to man...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The tattoo parlour -- with a guy outside who got drunk and now can't remember why he chose 'I Love Ken'...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A frantic crowded Portobello market.</context>
      <utterance>Then suddenly it's the weekend, and from break of day, hundreds of stalls appears out of nowhere, filling Portobello Road right up to Notting Hill Gate...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The camera finally settles on a stall selling beautiful stained glass windows of various sizes, some featuring biblical scenes and saints.</context>
      <utterance>... and thousands of people buy millions of antiques, some genuine...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... and some not so genuine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Shot of Tony proudly setting out a board outside his restaurant, the sign still being painted. He receives and approves a huge fresh salmon.</context>
      <utterance>And what's great is that lots of friends have ended up in this part of London -- that's Tony, architect turned chef, who recently invested all the money he ever earned in a new restaurant...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... and where I now lead a strange half-life with a lodger called...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The house has far too many things in it. Definitely two- bachelor flat. Spike appears. An unusual looking fellow. He has unusual hair, unusual facial hair and an unusual Welsh accent: very white, as though his flesh has never seen the sun. He wears only shorts.</context>
      <utterance>Spike!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even he. Hey, you couldn't help me with an incredibly important decision, could you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is important in comparison to, let's say, whether they should cancel third world debt?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right -- I'm at last going out on a date with the great Janine and I just want to be sure I've picked the right t-shirt.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are the choices?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The t-shirt is white with a horrible looking plastic alien coming out of it, jaws open, blood everywhere. It says 'I Love Blood.'</context>
      <utterance>Well... wait for it...  First there's this one...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes -- might make it hard to strike a really romantic note.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He heads back up the stairs... talks as he changes...</context>
      <utterance>Point taken.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he re-enters in a white t-shirt, with a large arrow, pointing down to his flies, saying, 'Get It Here.'</context>
      <utterance>I suspect you'll prefer the next one.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cool, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes -- she might think you don't have true love on your mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He comes down wearing it. Lots of hearts, saying, 'You're the most beautiful woman in the world.'</context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't want that...  Okay -- just one more.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, yes, that's perfect. Well done.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. Great. Wish me luck.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spike turns and walks upstairs proudly. Revealing that on the back of the t-shirt, also printed in big letters, is written 'Fancy a fuck?'</context>
      <utterance>Good luck.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>William enters.</context>
      <utterance>... which, well, sells travel books -- and, to be frank with you, doesn't always sell many of those.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="56">
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shall I go get a cappuccino? Ease the pain.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, better get me a half. All I can afford.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He salutes and bolts out the door -- as he does, a woman walks in. We only just glimpse her. Cut to William working. He looks up casually. And sees something. His reaction is hard to read. After a pause...</context>
      <utterance>I get your logic. Demi-capu coming up.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is Anna Scott, the biggest movie star in the world -- here -- in his shop. The most divine, subtle, beautiful woman on earth. When she speaks she is very self-assured and self-contained.</context>
      <utterance>Can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, thanks. I'll just look around.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She wanders over to a shelf as he watches her -- and picks out a quite smart coffee table book.</context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That book's really not good -- just in case, you know, browsing turned to buying. You'd be wasting your money.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up a book on the counter.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. This one though is... very good.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think the man who wrote it has actually been to Turkey, which helps. There's also a very amusing incident with a kebab.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William suddenly spies something odd on the small TV monitor beside him.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks. I'll think about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes follow him as he moves toward the back of the shop and approaches a man in slightly ill-fitting clothes.</context>
      <utterance>If you could just give me a second.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>THIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bad news.</utterance>
   <speaker>THIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've got a security camera in this bit of the shop.</utterance>
   <speaker>THIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, I saw you put that book down your trousers.</utterance>
   <speaker>THIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What book?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The one down your trousers.</utterance>
   <speaker>THIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't got a book down my trousers.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right -- well, then we have something of an impasse. I tell you what -- I'll call the police -- and, what can I say? -- If I'm wrong about the whole book-down-the-trousers scenario, I really apologize.</utterance>
   <speaker>THIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay -- what if I did have a book down my trousers?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He returns to his desk. In the monitor we just glimpse, as does William, the book coming out of the trousers and put back on the shelves. The thief drifts out towards the door. Anna, who has observed all this, is looking at a blue book on the counter.</context>
      <utterance>Well, ideally, when I went back to the desk, you'd remove the Cadogan guide to Bali from your trousers, and either wipe it and put it back, or buy it. See you in a sec.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry about that...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, that's fine. I was going to steal one myself but now I've changed my mind. Signed by the author, I see.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles. Suddenly the thief is there.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, we couldn't stop him. If you can find an unsigned copy, it's worth an absolute fortune.</utterance>
   <speaker>THIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>THIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I have your autograph?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>THIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She signs his scruffy piece of paper. He tries to read it.</context>
      <utterance>Rufus.</utterance>
   <speaker>THIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does it say?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's the signature -- and above, it says 'Dear Rufus -- you belong in jail.'</utterance>
   <speaker>THIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice one. Would you like my phone number?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thief leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Tempting but... no, thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands William a note and the book he said was rubbish. He talks as he handles the transaction.</context>
      <utterance>I think I will try this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drops in one of the signed books.</context>
      <utterance>Oh -- right -- on second thoughts maybe it wasn't that bad. Actually -- it's a sort of masterpiece really. None of those childish kebab stories you get in so many travel books these days. And I'll throw in one of these for free.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him with a slight smile.</context>
      <utterance>Very useful for lighting fires, wrapping fish, that sort of things.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And leaves. She's out of his life forever. William is a little dazed. Seconds later Martin comes back in.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cappuccino as ordered.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. I don't think you'll believe who was just in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But William's innate natural English discretion takes over.</context>
      <utterance>Who? Someone famous?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They set about drinking their coffees.</context>
      <utterance>No. No-one -- no-one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would be exciting if someone famous did come into the shop though, wouldn't it? Do you know -- this is pretty incredible actually -- I once saw Ringo Starr. Or at least I think it was Ringo. It might have been that broke from 'Fiddler On The Roof,' Toppy.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Topol.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right -- Topol.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But Ringo Starr doesn't look anything like Topol.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, well... he was quite a long way away.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So it could have been neither of them?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose so.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. It's not a classic anecdotes, is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin shakes his head. William drains his cappuccino.</context>
      <utterance>Not classic, no.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right -- want another one?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. No, wait -- let's go crazy -- I'll have an orange juice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Jesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs some paper napkins and starts to clean it off -- getting far too near her breasts in the panic of it...</context>
      <utterance>Here, let me help.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He jumps back.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing, nothing... Look, I live just over the street -- you could get cleaned up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No thank you. I need to get my car back.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In his diffident way, he is confident, despite her being genuinely annoyed. She turns and looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>I also have a phone. I'm confident that in five minutes we can have you spick and span and back on the street again... in the non-prostitute sense obviously.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. So what does 'just over the street' mean -- give it to me in yards.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't lie -- it is eighteen yards away. She looks down. She looks up at him.</context>
      <utterance>Eighteen yards. That's my house there.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William runs in further -- it's a mess. He kicks some old shoes under the stairs, bins an unfinished pizza and hides a plate of breakfast in a cupboard. She enters the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Come on in. I'll just...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he guides her up the stairs, after taking the bag of books from her...</context>
      <utterance>It's not that tidy, I fear.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She heads upstairs.</context>
      <utterance>The bathroom is right at the top of the stairs and there's a phone on the desk up there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="36">
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like a cup of tea before you go?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves to his very empty fridge -- and offers its only contents.</context>
      <utterance>Orange juice -- probably not.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something else cold -- coke, water, some disgusting sugary drink pretending to have something to do with fruits of the forest?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really, no.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like something to nibble -- apricots, soaked in honey -- quite why, no one knows -- because it stops them tasting of apricots, and makes them taste like honey, and if you wanted honey, you'd just buy honey, instead of apricots, but nevertheless -- there we go -- yours if you want them.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. She looks at him deep.</context>
      <utterance>Do you always say 'no' to everything?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.  I better be going. Thanks for your help.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It has taken a lot to get this out loud. He is not a smooth- talking man.</context>
      <utterance>You're welcome and, may I also say... heavenly.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles. She's cool.</context>
      <utterance>Take my one chance to say it. After you've read that terrible book, you're certainly not going to be coming back to the shop.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He guides her towards the door.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Well. My pleasure.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In a slightly awkward moment, he shows her out the door. He closes the door and shakes his head in wonder. Then...</context>
      <utterance>Nice to meet you. Surreal but nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... He shakes his head again in horror and wanders back along the corridor in silence. There's a knock on the door. He moves back, casually...</context>
      <utterance>'Surreal but nice.' What was I thinking?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens the door. It's her.</context>
      <utterance>Coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh hi. Forget something?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I forgot my bag.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shoots into the kitchen and picks up the forgotten shopping bag. Then returns and hands it to her.</context>
      <utterance>Oh right.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here we go.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stand in that corridor -- in that small space. Second time saying goodbye. A strange feeling of intimacy. She leans forward and she kisses him. Total silence. A real sense of the strangeness of those lips, those famous lips on his. They part.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks. Well...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I apologize for the 'surreal but nice' comment. Disaster...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly there is a clicking of a key in the lock.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about it. I thought the apricot and honey business was the real lowpoint.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spike walks in.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God. My flatmate. I'm sorry -- there's no excuse for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spike walks past unsuspiciously and heads into the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And leaves them in the corridor.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just going to go into the kitchen to get some food -- and then I'm going to tell you a story that will make your balls shrink to the size of raisins.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably best not tell anyone about this.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. No one. I mean, I'll tell myself sometimes but... don't worry -- I won't believe it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she leaves, with just a touch of William's hand. Spike comes out of the kitchen, eating something white out of a styrofoam container with a spoon.</context>
      <utterance>Bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's something wrong with this yogurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not yogurt -- it's mayonnaise.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, there you go.  On for a video fest tonight? I've got some absolute classic.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smile.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smile.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got nothing to smile about.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And after a couple of seconds -- wow -- she smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Okay in about 7 seconds, I'm going to ask you to marry me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Imagine -- somewhere in the world there's a man who's allowed to kiss her.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, she is fairly fabulous.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have any books by Dickens?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, we're a travel bookshop. We only sell travel books.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh right. How about that new John Grisham thriller?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, that's a novel too.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>Oh right. Have you got a copy of 'Winnie the Pooh'?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Martin -- your customer.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William looks up. At that moment the entire window is suddenly taken up by the huge side of a bus, obscuring the light -- and entirely covered with a portrait of Anna -- from her new film, 'Helix.'</context>
      <utterance>Can I help you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just incidentally -- why are you wearing that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No clean clothes...</context>
      <utterance>Ahm -- combination of factors really.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There never will be, you know, unless you actually clean your clothes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kind of spacey.</context>
      <utterance>Right. Vicious circle. And then I was like rooting around in your things, and found this, and I thought -- cool.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's something wrong with the goggles though...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, they were prescription, so I could see all the fishes properly.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Groovy. You should do more of this stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So -- any messages?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh, I wrote a couple down.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two? That's it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William closes his eyes in exasperation.</context>
      <utterance>You want me to write down all your messages?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who were the ones you didn't write down from?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahm let's see -- ahm. No. Gone completely. Oh no, wait. There was -- one from your mum: she said don't forget lunch and her leg's hurting again.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. No one else?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spike leans back and relaxes.</context>
      <utterance>Absolutely not.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William freezes -- then looks at Spike.</context>
      <utterance>Though if we're going for this obsessive writing-down-all-messages thing -- some American girl called Anna called a few days ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did she say?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it was genuinely bizarre... she said, hi -- it's Anna -- and then she said, call me at the Ritz -- and then gave herself a completely different name.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which was?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely no idea. Remembering one name's bad enough...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>RITZ MAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I help you, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahm, look this is a very odd situation. I'm a friend of Anna Scott's -- and she rang me at home the day before yesterday -- and left a message saying she's staying with you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>RITZ MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, we don't have anyone of that name here, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, that's right -- I know that. She said she's using another name -- but the problem is she left the message with my flatmate, which was a serious mistake.</utterance>
   <speaker>RITZ MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir. I have him in my mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then double it -- and that is the -- what can I say -- git I'm living with and he cannot remember...</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try 'Flintstone.'</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think she said her name was 'Flintstone.'</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does 'Flintstone' mean anything to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>RITZ MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flintstone is indeed the magic word.</context>
      <utterance>I'll put you right through, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He practices how to sound.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello. Hi. Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We hear her voice -- don't see her.</context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh hi. It's William Thacker. We, ahm I work in a bookshop.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You played it pretty cool here, waiting for three days to call.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I've never played anything cool in my entire life. Spike, who I'll stab to death later, never gave me the message.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh -- Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps I could drop round for tea or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh -- unfortunately, things are going to be pretty busy, but... okay, let's give it a try. Four o'clock could be good.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Great.  Classic. Classic.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which floor?</utterance>
   <speaker>TARQUIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William pushes the button. They wait for the doors to close.</context>
      <utterance>Three.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure you...?</utterance>
   <speaker>TARQUIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He knocks. A bright, well-tailored American girl opens the door.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands them a very slick, expensively produced press kits, with the poster picture of Anna, for the film 'Helix.'</context>
      <utterance>Hello, I'm Karen. Sorry -- things are running a bit late. Here's the thing...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you think of the film?</utterance>
   <speaker>TARQUIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both turn to William for his opinion.</context>
      <utterance>Marvellous. 'Close Encounters' meets 'Jean De Florette.' Oscar- winning stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I agree.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I didn't get down what magazines you're from.</utterance>
   <speaker>TARQUIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Time Out.'</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great. And you...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Horse and Hound.' The name's William Whacker. I think she might be expecting me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They sit down as Karen goes off.</context>
      <utterance>Okay -- take a seat. I'll check.</utterance>
   <speaker>TARQUIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William goes for the cover-up.</context>
      <utterance>You've brought her flowers?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- they're... for my grandmother. She's in a hospital nearby. Thought I'd kill two birds with one stone.</utterance>
   <speaker>TARQUIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. He's in trouble.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. Which hospital?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you mind me not saying -- it's a rather distressing disease and the name of the hospital rather gives it away.</utterance>
   <speaker>TARQUIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh sure. Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Saved by the bell.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Thacker.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is shown in through big golden doors. Karen stays outside.</context>
      <utterance>You've got five minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There are lots of other flowers in the room.</context>
      <utterance>I brought these, but clearly...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A fair amount of tension. These two people hardly know each other -- and the first and last time they met, they kissed.</context>
      <utterance>Oh no, ho -- these are great.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry about not ringing back. The whole two-names concept was totally too much for my flatman's pea-sized intellect.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At which moment Jeremy, Karen's boss, comes in. A fairly grave, authoritative fifty-year-old PR man consulting a list.</context>
      <utterance>No, it's a stupid privacy thing. I always choose a cartoon character -- last time out, I was Mrs. Bambi.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEREMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEREMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William nods.</context>
      <utterance>And you are from 'Horse and Hound' magazine?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William shrugs his shoulders. Jeremy settles at a little desk in the corner and makes notes. A pause. William feels he has to act the part. They sit in chairs opposite each other.</context>
      <utterance>Is that so?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anna nods.</context>
      <utterance>So I'll just fire away, shall I?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>horses in it?</context>
      <utterance>Right. Ahm... the film's great... and I just wondered -- whether you ever thought of having more...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahm -- well -- we would have liked to -- but it was difficult, obviously, being set in space.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William puts his head in his hands. He was panic.</context>
      <utterance>Obviously. Very difficult. Jeremy leaves.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry -- I arrived outside -- they thrust this thing into my hand -- I didn't know what to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's my fault, I thought this would all be over by now. I just wanted to sort of apologize for the kissing thing. I seriously don't know what got in to me. I just wanted to make sure you were fine about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Re-enter Jeremy.</context>
      <utterance>Absolutely fine about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEREMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do remember that Miss Scott is also keen to talk about her next project, which is shooting later in the summer.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yes -- excellent. Ahm -- any horses in that one? Or hounds, of course. Our readers are equally intrigued by both species.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It takes place on a submarine.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeremy exits.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Right... But if there were horses, would you be riding them yourself or would you be getting a stunt horse person double sort of thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just a complete moron. Sorry. This is the sort of thing that happens in dreams -- not in real life. Good dreams, obviously -- it's a dream to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's a challenge.</context>
      <utterance>And what happens next in the dream?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. Then they move towards each other when... Jeremy enters.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I suppose in the dream dream scenario. I just... ahm, change my personality, because you can do that in dreams, and walk across and kiss the girl but you know it'll never happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEREMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Time's up, I'm afraid. Sorry it was so short. Did you get what you wanted?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very nearly.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEREMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe time for one last question?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeremy goes out -- it's their last seconds.</context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you busy tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at each other. Jeremy enters, with another journalists in tow. Anna and William stand and shake hands formally.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Surreal but nice.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it was nice to meet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. You are 'Horse and Hound's' favorite actress. You and Black Beauty. Tied.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TARQUIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How was she?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fabulous.</utterance>
   <speaker>TARQUIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William can't think his way out of this.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute -- she took your grandmother's flowers?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to go, but is accosted by Karen.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. That's right. Bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you'd like to come with me we can rush you through the others.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The others?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A forty-year-old actor with great presence warmly shakes William's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Thacker's from 'Horse and Hound.'</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE LEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pleased to meet you. Did you like the film?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah... yes, enormously.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE LEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, fire away.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right, right. Ahm -- did you enjoy making the film?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE LEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any bit in particular?</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE LEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you tell me which bit you liked most -- and I'll tell you if I enjoyed making it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahm right, right, I liked the bit in space very much. Did you enjoy making that bit?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you identify with the character you were playing?</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERPRETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Te identicaste con el personaje que interpretabas?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOREIGN ACTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERPRETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah. Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERPRETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Por que no?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOREIGN ACTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Porque es un robot carnivoro psicopata.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERPRETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because he is playing a psychopathic flesh-eating robot.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Classic.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this your first film?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- it's my 22nd.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course it is. Any favourite among the 22?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Working with Leonardo.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Da Vinci?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Di Caprio.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course. And is he your favourite Italian film director?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Thacker?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you got a moment?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>William enters. A certain nervousness. They are alone again.</context>
      <utterance>Come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahm. That thing I was doing tonight -- I'm not doing it any more. I told them I had to spend the evening with Britain's premier equestrian journalist.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh well, great. Perfect. Oh no -- shittity brickitty -- it's my sister's birthday -- shit -- we're meant to be having dinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay -- fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But no, I'm sure I can get out of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I mean, if it's fine with you, I'll, you know, be your date.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll be my date at my little sister's birthday party?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If that's all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure it's all right. My friend Max is cooking and he's acknowledged to be the worst cook in the world, but you know, you could hide the food in your handbag or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's bringing a girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miracles do happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does the girl have a name?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wouldn't say.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The oven seems to be smoking a little. Then the bell rings. MAX (cont'd) Oh God. It's bad timing. Max shoots out of the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Christ, what is going on in there?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William and Anna move along the corridor to the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Come on in. Vague food crisis.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hiya -- sorry -- the guinea fowl is proving more complicated than expected.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's cooking guinea fowl?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't even ask.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. Good Lord -- you're the spitting image of...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bella -- this is Anna.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(pause)</context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rises from his stove position.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Crisis over.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Max. This is Anna.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Anna ahm...  Scott -- have some wine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Door bell goes.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She does a little pose, having worn a real party dress.</context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They head back along the corridor.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Happy Birthday.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, your brother has brought this girl, and ahm...</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi guys.  Oh holy fuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hun -- this is Anna. Anna -- this is Honey -- she's my baby sitter.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hiya.</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God this is one of those key moments in life, when it's possible you can be really, genuinely cool -- and I'm going to fail a hundred percent. I absolutely and totally and utterly adore you and I think you're the most beautiful woman in the world and more importantly I genuinely believe and have believed for some time now that we can be best friends. What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands her a present.</context>
      <utterance>Ahm... I think that sounds -- you know -- lucky me. Happy Birthday.</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God. You gave me a present. We're best friends already. Marry Will -- he's a really nice guy and then we can be sisters.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The front door bell goes.</context>
      <utterance>I'll think about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He heads out into the corridor to the front door.</context>
      <utterance>That'll be Bernie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Bernie.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry I'm so late. Bollocksed up at work again, I fear. Millions down the drain.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bernie -- this is Anna.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doesn't recognize her -- turns to Honey.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Anna. Delighted to meet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey Bunny -- happy birthday to you.  It's a hat. You don't have to wear it or anything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You haven't slept with her, have you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is a cheap question and the answer is, of course, no comment.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'No comment' means 'yes.'</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it doesn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you ever masturbate?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Definitely no comment.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see -- it means 'yes.' Then on to Bernie's conversation.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So tell me Anna -- what do you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm an actress.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Splendid. I'm actually in the stock- market, so not really similar fields, though I have done some amateur stuff -- P.G. Wodehouse, you know -- farce, all that. 'Ooh -- careful there, vicar.' Always imagined it's a pretty tough job, though, acting. I mean the wages are a scandal, aren't they?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, they can be.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see friends from university -- clever chaps -- been in the business longer than you -- they're scraping by on seven, eight thousand a year. It's no life. What sort of acting do you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Films mainly.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh splendid. Well done. How's the pay in movies? I mean, last film you did, what did you get paid?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fifteen million dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Right. So that's... fairly good. On the high side... have you tried the nuts?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all move towards the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Right -- I think we're ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wonder if you could tell me where the...?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, it's just down the corridor on the right.</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A moment's silence as they leave -- then in a split second the others all turn to William.</context>
      <utterance>I'll show you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quickly, quickly -- talk very quickly what are you doing here with Anna Scott?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anna Scott?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The movie star?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yup.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The horror of his remembered conversation slowly unfolds. Honey re-enters.</context>
      <utterance>Oh God. Oh God. Oh Goddy God.</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She had to ask me to leave.</context>
      <utterance>I don't believe it. I walked into the loo with her. I was still talking when she started unbuttoning her jeans...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think of the guinea fowl?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a vegetarian.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="40">
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Having you here, Anna, firmly establishes what I've long suspected, that we really are the most desperate hot of under-achievers.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shame!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not saying it's a bad thing, in fact, I think it's something we should take pride in. I'm going to give the last brownie as a prize to the saddest act here. A little pause. Then William turns to Bernie.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bernie.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, obviously it's me, isn't it -- I work in the City in a job I don't understand and everyone keeps getting promoted above me. I haven't had a girlfriends since... puberty and, well, the long and short of it is, nobody fancies me, and if these cheeks get any chubbier, they never will.</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nonsense. I fancy you. Or I did before you got so far.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see -- and unless I'm much mistaken, your job still pays you rather a lot of money, while Honey here, she earns nothing flogging her guts out at London's seediest record store.</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. And I don't have hair -- I've got feathers, and I've got funny goggly eyes, and I'm attracted to cruel men and ... no one'll ever marry me because my boosies have actually started shrinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see -- incredibly sad.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On the other hand, her best friend is Anna Scott.</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's true, I can't deny it. She needs me, what can I say?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dead silence.</context>
      <utterance>And most of her limbs work. Whereas I'm stuck in its thing day and night, in a house full of ramps. And to add insult to serious injury -- I've totally given up smoking, my favourite thing, and the truth is... we can't have a baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bella shrugs her shoulders. Bernie is totally grief-struck.</context>
      <utterance>Bella.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Not true...</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William reaches for her hand. Max breaks the sombre mood.</context>
      <utterance>C'est la vie... We're lucky in lots of ways, but... Surely it's worth a brownie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all laugh. Anna smiles across at William.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't know. Look at William. Very unsuccessful professionally. Divorced. Used to be handsome, now kind of squidgy around the edges -- and absolutely certain never to hear from Anna again after she's heard that his nickname at school was Floppy.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I get the brownie?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you do, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute. What about me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry? You think you deserve the brownie?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... a shot at it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll have to prove it. This is a great brownie and I'm going to fight for it. State your claim.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I've been on a diet since I was nineteen, which means basically I've been hungry for a decade. I've had a sequence of not nice boyfriends -- one of whom hit me: and every time my heart gets broken it gets splashed across the newspapers as entertainment. Meantime, it cost millions to get me looking like this...</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>While she says this, quiet settles around the table. The thing is -- she sort of means it and is opening up to them.</context>
      <utterance>Really -- and one day, not long from now...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence... they all look at her... then.</context>
      <utterance>... my looks will go, they'll find out I can't act and I'll become a sad middle-aged woman who looks a bit like someone who was famous for a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah!!! Nice try, gorgeous -- but you don't fool anyone. The mood is instantly broken. They all laugh.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pathetic effort to hog the brownie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was such a great evening.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds out his hand to shake. She kisses him on the cheek. He stumbles back with joy.</context>
      <utterance>I'm delighted.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And may I say that's a gorgeous tie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you're lying.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Max loves this.</context>
      <utterance>You're right. I told you I was bad at acting.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lovely to meet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you. I'll wait till you've gone before I tell him you're a vegetarian.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Night, night, Honey.</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Honey gives her a huge hug.</context>
      <utterance>I'm so sorry about the loo thing. I meant to leave but I just... look, ring me if you need someone to go shopping with. I know lots of nice, cheap places... not that money necessarily...  nice to meet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anna and William head out... Bernie tries to save some dignity.</context>
      <utterance>You too -- from now on you are my style guru.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They move to the door and wave goodbye.</context>
      <utterance>Love your work.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="37">
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The house is in Lansdowne Road, on the edge of Notting Hill. They walk for a moment. A bit of silence.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry -- they always do that when I leave the house.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Floppy, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the hair! It's to do with the hair.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why is she in a wheelchair?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was an accident -- about eighteen months ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the pregnancy thing -- is that to do with the accident?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk in silence for a moment. Then...</context>
      <utterance>You know, I'm not sure. I don't think they'd tried for kids before, as fate would have it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles and shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>Would you like to come... my house is just...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too complicated.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Busy tomorrow?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you were leaving.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are now walking by a five foot railing, with foliage behind it.</context>
      <utterance>What's in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're like little villages.</context>
      <utterance>Gardens. All these streets round here have these mysterious communal gardens in the middle of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go in.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah no -- that's the point -- they're private villages -- only the people who live round the edges are allowed in.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You abide by rules like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her look makes it clear that she is waiting with interest on the answer to this.</context>
      <utterance>Ahm...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rattles the gate, then starts his climb -- but doesn't quite make it, and falls back onto the pavement...</context>
      <utterance>Heck no -- other people do -- but not me -- I just do what I want.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoopsidaisies.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said 'whoopsidaisies.' Tiny pause.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so. No one has said 'whoopsidaisies,' do they -- I mean unless they're...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no 'unless.' No one has said "whoopsidaisies" for fifty years and even then it was only little girls with blonde ringlets.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly. Here we go again. He fails, and unfortunately, spontaneously...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Whoopsidaisies.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a disease I've got -- it's a clinical thing. I'm taking pills and having injections -- it won't last long.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts to climb.</context>
      <utterance>Step aside.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But she's already almost over.</context>
      <utterance>Actually be careful Anna -- it's harder than it looks...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A few seconds later. Anna jumps down into the garden.</context>
      <utterance>Oh no it's not -- it's easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William clambers over with terrible difficulty, dusts himself off, and heads towards where she stands.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Flops.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leans forward -- and, for the firs time since the first time -- she kisses him. This time a proper kiss. A tiny pause.</context>
      <utterance>Now seriously -- what in the world in this garden could make that ordeal worthwhile?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice garden.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We cut in and see an inscription carved into the wood. She doesn't read the dates, carved below -- 'June Wetherby, 1917 - 1992.' She is slightly chocked by it.</context>
      <utterance>'For June, who loved this garden -- from Joseph who always sat beside her.'</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods. They are standing on either side of the bench, looking at each other. The camera glides away from them, up into the night sky, leaving them alone in the garden. Music plays.</context>
      <utterance>Some people do spend their whole lives together.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bollocks, bollocks, bollocks. Have you seen my glasses?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, 'fraid not.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bollocks.  This happens every time I go to the cinema. Average day, my glasses are everywhere -- everywhere I look, glasses. But the moment I need them they disappear. It's one of life's real cruelties.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's compared to, like, earthquakes in the Far East or testicular cancer?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh shit, is that the time? I have to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for your help on the glasses thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're welcome. Did you find them?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sort of.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="38">
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So who left who?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She left me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She saw through me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We've been aware of the conversation at a nearby table -- now we can hear it. Two slightly rowdy men.</context>
      <utterance>Uh-oh. That's not good.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWRENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William and Anna look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>No - No- No! Give me Anna Scott any day.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again -- Anna reacts.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't like that last film of hers. Fast asleep from the moment the lights went down.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWRENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't really care what the films are like. Any film with her in it -- fine by me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anna mouths 'Meg Ryan.'</context>
      <utterance>No -- not my type at all really. I prefer that other one -- blonde -- sweet looking -- has an orgasm every time you take her out for a cup of coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWRENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William and Anna smile -- they're enjoying it.</context>
      <utterance>Meg Ryan.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drug-induced, I hear -- I believe she's actually in rehab as we speak.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWRENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anna's twinkle fades.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever, she's so clearly up for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWRENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know -- some girls, they're all 'stay away chum' but Anna, she's absolutely gagging for it. Do you know that in over fifty percent of languages the word for "actress" is the same as the word for "prostitute." This is horrible.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWRENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Anna is your definitive actress -- someone really filthy you can just flip over...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets up and goes round the corner to the men. There are in fact four of them, the two meeker men, Gavin and Harry, hanging on the other guys' witty words.</context>
      <utterance>Right, that's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry to disturb you guys but --</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWRENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's not a very convincing or frightening figure.</context>
      <utterance>Well, yes, I wish I hadn't overheard your conversation -- but I did and I just think, you know...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...the person you're talking about is a real person and I think she probably deserves a little bit more consideration, rather than having jerks like you drooling over her...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWRENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anna suddenly appears at his side and whips him away without being recognized.</context>
      <utterance>Oh sod off, mate. What are you, her dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk on and then...</context>
      <utterance>No, that's fine. I love that you tried... time was I'd have done the same.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she walks straight back to their table.</context>
      <utterance>In fact -- give me a second.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWRENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry about my friend -- he's very sensitive.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWRENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, look, I'm sorry...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, please -- let's just leave it there. I'm sure you meant no harm, and I'm sure it was just friendly banter and I'm sure you dicks are all the size of peanuts. A perfect match for the size of your brains. Enjoy your meal. The tuna's really good. And she walks away. Gerald turns to Lawrence.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERALD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You prick.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I shouldn't have done that. I shouldn't have done that.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you were brilliant</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm rash and I'm stupid and what am I doing with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, I'm afraid.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They have arrived at the end of the arcade.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know either.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here we are.  Do you want to come up?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There seem to be lots of reasons why I shouldn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His look says yes.</context>
      <utterance>There are lots of reasons. Do you want to come up?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He watches her go -- and stands in the street. Music plays.</context>
      <utterance>Give me five minutes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="34">
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's something slightly awry. He doesn't notice.</context>
      <utterance>Hiya.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her gently on the cheek.</context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To be able to do that is such a wonderful thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because my boyfriend, who I thought was in America, is in fact in the next room.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is duly shocked. She's trying to be calm.</context>
      <utterance>Your boyfriend?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFF</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Jeff drifts into view behind. He is a very famous film star and looks the part -- well built, very handsome. Unshaven, he has magic charm, whatever he says. Over a t-shirt, he wears a shirt, which he unbuttons as he talks.</context>
      <utterance>Who is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahm... room service.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you doing? I thought you guys all wore those penguin coats.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, yes -- usually -- I'd just changed to go home -- but I thought I'd just deal with this final call.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh great. Could you do me a favour and try to get us some really cold water up here?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll see what I can do.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still, not sparkling.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely. Ice cold still water.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unless it's illegal in the UK to serve liquids below room temperature: I don't want you going to jail just to satisfy my whims...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm sure it'll be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And maybe you could just adios the dishes and empty the trash.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he does just that. Scoops up the two used plates and heads to the bin.</context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really -- don't do that -- I'm sure this is not his job.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. Is this a problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah -- no. It's fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeff slips him a fiver.</context>
      <utterance>Ahm... Bernie.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Bernie.  Hey -- nice surprise, or nasty surprise?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her.</context>
      <utterance>Nice surprise.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Liar.  She hates surprises. What are you ordering?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't decided.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, don't over-do it. I don't want people saying, 'There goes that famous actor with the big, fat girlfriend." He wanders off taking off his t-shirt.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anna just nods.</context>
      <utterance>I better leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- this is a fairly strange reality to be faced with. To be honest, I don't realize...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry... I don't know what to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think goodbye is traditional.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spike settles on the arm of a chair. William decides to open up a bit...</context>
      <utterance>Come on -- open up -- this is me -- Spikey -- I'm in contact with some quite important spiritual vibrations. What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, okay. There's this girl...</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Good. Speak on, dear friend.</context>
      <utterance>Aha! I'd been getting a female vibe.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spike nods thoughtfully.</context>
      <utterance>She's someone I just can't -- someone who... self-evidently can't be mine -- and it's as if I've taken love-heroin -- and now I can't even have it again. I've opened Pandora's box. And there's trouble inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He roars with laughter. William smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Yeh. Yeh... tricky... tricky... I knew a girl at school called Pandora ... never got to see her box though.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. Yes -- very helpful.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't know she had a boyfriend?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their looks make it obvious that everyone did.</context>
      <utterance>No -- did you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bloody hell, I can't believe it -- my whole life ruined because I don't read 'Hello' magazine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's face facts. This was always a no-go situation. Anna's a goddess and you know what happens to mortals who get involved with the gods.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buggered?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every time. But don't despair -- I think I have the solution to your problems.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all look to him for wise words.</context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her name is Tessa and she works in the contracts department. The hair, I admit, is unfashionable frizzy -- but she's as bright as a button and kisses like a nymphomaniac on death row. Apparently.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William nods. Max heads off to the door. We stay with William -- and just hear the door open and a voice come down the corridor.</context>
      <utterance>Now -- try.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESSA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>They reach the kitchen. Tessa is a lush girl with huge hair.</context>
      <utterance>I got completely lost -- it's real difficult, isn't it? Everything's got the word 'Kensington' in it -- Kensington Park Road, Kensington Gardens, Kensington bloody Park Gardens...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tessa -- this is Bella my wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh hello, you're in a wheelchair.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And this is William.</utterance>
   <speaker>TESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello William. Max has told me everything about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Has he?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wine?</utterance>
   <speaker>TESSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to take the wine and William has a split second to send a message of panic to Bella. She agrees -- it's bad.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yes please. Come on, Willie, let's get sloshed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keziah -- some woodcock?</utterance>
   <speaker>KEZIAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, thank you -- I'm a fruitarian.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is left to William, who has been set up here, to fill the pause.</context>
      <utterance>I don't realize that.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And ahm -- what's a fruitarian exactly?</utterance>
   <speaker>KEZIAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We believe that fruits and vegetables have feelings so we think cooking is cruel. We only eat things that have actually fallen from the tree or bush -- that are, in fact, dead already.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Right. Interesting stuff.  So these carrots...</utterance>
   <speaker>KEZIAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have been murdered, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Murdered? Poor carrots. How beastly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Delicious coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. I'm sorry about the lamb.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- I thought it was really, you know, interesting.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Interesting means inedible.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all laugh. It's going very well.</context>
      <utterance>Really inedible -- yes that's right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe we'll meet again some time.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses him gently on the cheek. He opens the door -- she walks out. He shuts the door quietly and heads back into the living room...</context>
      <utterance>Yes. That would be... great.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's perfect, perfect.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William makes a gentle, exasperated gesture, then...</context>
      <utterance>And?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you have forgotten...  what an unusual situation you have here -- to find someone you actually love, who'll love you -- the chances are... always miniscule. Look at me -- not counting the American -- I've only loved two girls in my whole life, both total disasters.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not fair.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No really, one of them marries me and then leaves me quicker than you can say Indiana Jones -- and the other, who seriously ought to have known better, casually marries my best friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still loves you though.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In a depressingly asexual way.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all roar with laughter.</context>
      <utterance>I never fancied you much actually...</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean I loved you -- you were terribly funny. But all that kissing my ears...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no -- this is just getting worse. I am going to find myself, 30 years from now, still on this couch.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want to stay?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Music starts to play to take us through these silent scenes.</context>
      <utterance>Why not -- all that awaits me at home is a masturbating Welshman.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. Can I come in?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves inside. Her hair is a mess -- her eyes are tired. Nothing idealized.</context>
      <utterance>Come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>They were taken years ago -- I know it was... well, I was poor and it happens a lot -- that's not an excuse -- but to make things worse, it now appears someone was filming me as well. So what was a stupid photo- shoot now looks like a porno film. And well... the pictures have been solid and they're everywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know where to go. The hotel is surrounded.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the place.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's very shaken.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you. I'm just in London for two days -- but, with your papers, it's the worse place to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are such horrible pictures. They're so grainy... they make me look like...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't think about it. We'll sort it out. Now what would you like -- tea ... bath...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A bath would be great.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He heads up the stairs. Opens the bathroom door, walks in.</context>
      <utterance>Christ alive... brilliant... fantastic .... magnificent...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's in the bath. Spike turns in shock -- and sidles out of the bathroom.</context>
      <utterance>You must be Spike.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just checking.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm really sorry about last time. He just flew in -- I had no idea -- in fact, I had no idea if he'd ever fly in again.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, that's fine. It's not often one has the opportunity to adios the plates of a major Hollywood star. It was a thrill for me.  How is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. It got to the point where I couldn't remember any of the reasons I loved him. And you... and love?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, there's a question -- without an interesting answer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have thought about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't think she has to talk about this.</context>
      <utterance>Oh no no -- no.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just anytime I've tried to keep things normal with anyone normal -- it's been a disaster.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I appreciate that absolutely.  Is that the film you're doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes -- start in L.A. on Tuesday.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like me to take you through your lines?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you? It's all talk, talk, talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hand it over. Basic plot?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a difficult but brilliant junior officer who in about twenty minutes will save the world from nuclear disaster.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well done you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Message from command. Would you like them to send in the HKs?'</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'No, turn over 4 TRS's and tell them we need radar feedback before the KFT's return at 19 hundred -- then inform the Pentagon that we'll be needing black star cover from ten hundred through 12.15' -- and don't you dare say one word about how many mistakes I made in that speech or I'll pelt you with olives.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Very well, captain -- I'll pass that on straightaway.'</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Thank you.' How many mistake did I make?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eleven.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn. 'And Wainwright...'</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cartwright.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Cartwright, Wainwright, whatever your name is, I promised little Jimmy I'd be home for his birthday -- could you get a message through that I may be a little late.'</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Certainly. And little Johnny?'</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My son's name is Johnny?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yup.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, get a message through to him too.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brilliant.  Word perfect I'd say.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gripping. It's not Jane Austen, it's not Henry James, but it's gripping.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I should do Henry James instead?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure you'd be great in Henry James. But, you know -- this writer's pretty damn good too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes -- I mean -- you never get anyone in 'Wings of a Dove' having the nerve to say 'inform the Pentagon that we need black star cover.'</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anna smiles her biggest smile of the day. He is helping.</context>
      <utterance>And I think the book is the poorer for it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is a poster of a Chagall painting of a floating wedding couple, with a goat as company.</context>
      <utterance>I can't believe you have that picture on your wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like Chagall?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do. It feels like how being in love should be. Floating through a dark blue sky.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With a goat playing a violin.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spike enters with three pizzas.</context>
      <utterance>Yes -- happiness wouldn't be happiness without a violin-playing goat.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Voila. Carnival Calypso, for the Queen of Notting Hill -- pepperoni, pineapple and a little more pepperoni.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fantastic.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't mention that Anna's a vegetarian, did I?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have some parsnip stew from last week. If I just peel the skin off, it'll be perfect.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got big feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Always have had.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what they say about men with big feet?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Big feet -- large shoes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The thing that's so irritating is that now I'm so totally fierce when it comes to nudity clauses.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You actually have clauses in your contact about nudity?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Definitely. 'You may show the dent at the top of the artist's buttocks -- but neither cheek. In the event of a stunt person being used, the artist must have full consultation.'</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have a stunt bottom?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could have a stunt bottom, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you be tempted to go for a slightly better bottom than your own?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Definitely. Ths is important stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's one hell of a job. What do you put on your passport? Profession -- Mel Gibson's bottom.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Why wouldn't he? It's delicious.</context>
      <utterance>Actually, Mel does his own ass work.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ice cream or Mel Gibson's bottom?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Both.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Today has ben a good day. Which under the circumstances is... unexpected.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>sofa-bed.</context>
      <utterance>Well, thank you.  Anyway -- time for bed. Or...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. She leans forward, kisses him gently, then steps into the bedroom and closes the door.</context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God...  Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drifts round the corner, half-naked.</context>
      <utterance>Hello. I wonder if I could have a little word.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spike.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to interfere, or anything ... but she's split up from her boy- friend, that's right isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And she's in your house.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you get on very well.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, isn't this perhaps a good opportunity to... slip her one?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spike. For God's sake -- she's in trouble -- get a grip.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Right. You think it's the wrong moment. Fair enough.  Do you mind if I have a go?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spike!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- you're right.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll talk to you in the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Back to William thinking again. Dreamy atmosphere. And then... more footsteps on the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Okay -- okay. Might be too late, but okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh please sod off.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The darkness of the living room. We see Anna in the shadow.</context>
      <utterance>No! No. Wait. I... thought you were someone else. I thought you were Spike. I'm delighted you're not.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then gets over it straight away.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And kisses her.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It still strikes me as, well, surreal, that I'm allowed to see you naked.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You and every person in this country.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God yes -- I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it about men and nudity? Particularly breasts -- how can you be so interested in them?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No seriously. I mean, they're just breasts. Every second person in the world has got them...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More than that actually, when you think about it. You know, Meatloaf has a very nice pair...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But... they're odd-looking. They're for milk. Your mum's got them. You must have seen a thousand of them -- what's the fuss about?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks under the sheet at her breasts.</context>
      <utterance>Actually, I can't think really -- let me just have a quick look...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She laughs...</context>
      <utterance>No, beats me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rita Hayworth used to say -- 'they go to bed with Gilda -- they wake up with me.' Do you feel that?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who was Gilda?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her most famous part -- men went to bed with the dream -- and they didn't like it when they woke up with the reality -- do you feel that way with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're lovelier this morning than you have ever been.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him carefully. Then leaps out of bed.</context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She heads across. She smiles and sits on the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Breakfast in bed. Or lunch, or brunch.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I stay a bit longer?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The doorbell goes.</context>
      <utterance>Damn, I forgot the jam.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You get the door, I'll get the jam.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He comes back inside, snapping the door behind him. Anna is in the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She heads back the corridor, with no suspicion.</context>
      <utterance>Don't ask.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She thinks he's fooling around. She opens the door, the same explosion. In a split second she's inside.</context>
      <utterance>You're up to something...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God. And they got a photo of you dressed like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Undressed like this, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He does a thumbs up to William -- very excited about what he knows was a 'result.'</context>
      <utterance>Morning, daring ones.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She heads upstairs.</context>
      <utterance>It's Anna. The press are here. No, there are hundreds of them. My brilliant plan was not so brilliant after all. Yeh, I know, I know. Just get me out then.  Damnit.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't go outside.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The moment William goes upstairs, Spike heads for the front door.</context>
      <utterance>Just take my work for it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inspects himself.</context>
      <utterance>How did I look?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mmmmm. Nice firm buttocks.</context>
      <utterance>Not bad. No bad at all. Well-chosen briefs, I'd say. Chicks love grey.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you think I'm doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's packing.</context>
      <utterance>I do. Your furry friend thought he'd make a buck or two telling the papers where I was.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not true.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? The entire British press just woke up this morning and thought 'Hey -- I know where Anna Scott is. She's in that house with the blue door in Notting Hill.' And then you go out in your goddamn underwear.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I went out in my goddamn underwear too.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get out, Spike.  I'm so sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is such a mess. I come to you to protect myself against more crappy gossip and now I'm landed in it all over again. For God's sake, I've got a boyfriend.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's a difficult moment -- defining where they stand.</context>
      <utterance>You do?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As far as they're concerned I do. And now tomorrow there'll be pictures of you in every newspapers from here to Timbuktu.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, I know -- but... just -- let's stay calm...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can stay calm -- it's the perfect situation for you -- minimum input, maximum publicity. Everyone you ever bump into will know. 'Well done you -- you slept with that actress -- we've seen the pictures.'</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's spectacularly unfair.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She heads out.</context>
      <utterance>Who knows, it may even help business. Buy a boring book about Egypt from the guy who screwed Anna Scott.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Have a cup of tea.</context>
      <utterance>Now stop. Stop. I beg you -- calm down.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The doorbell goes.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want a goddamn cup of tea. I want to go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spike leans merrily out of the window.</context>
      <utterance>Spike, check who that is... and for God's sake put some clothes on.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like a chauffeur to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And remember -- Spike owes you an expensive dinner. Or holiday -- depending if he's got the brains to get the going rate on betrayal.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not true. And wait a minute... this is crazy behavior. Can't we just laugh about this? Seriously -- in the huge sweep of things, this stuff doesn't matter.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What he's going to say next is -- there are people starving in the Sudan.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, there are. And we don't need to go anywhere near that far. My best friend slipped -- she slipped down- stairs, cracked her back and she's in a wheelchair for the rest of her life. All I'm asking for is a normal amount of perspective.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right: of course, you're right. It's just that I've dealt with this garbage for ten years now -- you've had it for ten minutes. Our perspectives are different.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean -- today's newspapers will be lining tomorrow's waste paper bins.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you know -- it's just one day. Today's papers will all have been thrown away tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes this in. That's the end.</context>
      <utterance>You really don't get it. This story gets filed. Every time anyone writes anything about me -- they'll dig up these photos. Newspapers last forever. I'll regret this forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him. The doorbell goes again. She opens the door. Massive noise and photos. Outside are her people, including Karen, a chauffeur, two bodyguards. And then the door is shut and they're all gone. Silence.</context>
      <utterance>Right. Fine. I will do the opposite, if it's all right by you -- and always be glad you came. But you're right -- you probably better go.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was it you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose I might have told one or two people down the pub.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. He puts his head in his hands. It's over now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have we got something for you. Something which will make you love me so much you'll want to hug me every single day for the rest of my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blimey. What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The phone number of Anna Scott's agent in London and her agent in New York. You can ring her. You think about her all the time -- now you can ring her!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, thanks, that's great.</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she rushes out. William looks at the piece of paper, folds it and then places it gently in the garbage bin.</context>
      <utterance>It is great, isn't it. See you tonight. Hey, Marty-- sexy cardy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>BELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a little speech to make -- I won't stand up because I can't... be bothered. Exactly a year ago today, this man here started the finest restaurant in London.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unfortunately -- no one ever came to eat here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A tiny hiccough.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tony's brave face breaks. The dream is over.</context>
      <utterance>And so we must face the fact that from next week, we have to find somewhere near to eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just want to say to Tony -- don't take it personally. The more I think about things, the more I see no rhyme or reason in life -- no one knows why some things work out, and some things don't -- why some of us get lucky -- and some of us...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... get fired.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're all rather stunned.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, they're shifting the whole outfit much more towards the trading side -- and of course...  I was total crap.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They toast him.</context>
      <utterance>So we go down together! A toast to Bernie -- the worst stockbroker in the whole world!</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Total bewilderment from the others.</context>
      <utterance>Since it's an evening of announcements ... I've also got one, Ahm... I've decided to get engaged.</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Special cut to Bernie -- the shot shows he had special feelings for Honey.</context>
      <utterance>I've found myself a nice, slightly odd looking bloke who I know is going to make me happy for the rest of my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute -- I'm your brother and I don't know anything about this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it someone we know?</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she sits down, Honey leans towards Spike and whispers.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. I will keep you informed.</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By the way -- it's you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me?</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, yes. Groovy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any more announcements?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes -- I feel I must apologize to everyone for my behavior for the last six months. I have, as you know, been slightly down in the mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's an understatement. There are dead people on better form.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I wish to make it clear I've turned a corner and henceforward intend to be impressively happy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elsewhere, Max an William are relaxed together.</context>
      <utterance>I'm really horribly drunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So -- you've laid the ghost.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I believe I have.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't give a damn about the famous girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, don't think I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts down a copy of the 'Evening Standard' with a picture of Anna on its cover.</context>
      <utterance>Which means you won't be distracted by the fact that she's back in London, grasping her Oscar, and to be found filming most days on Hampstead Heath.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God no.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So not over her, in fact.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>SECURITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes -- I was looking for Anna Scott...</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does she know you're coming?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no. She doesn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid I can't really let you through then, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh right. I mean, I am a friend -- I'm not a lunatic but -- no, you basically...</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment -- thirty yards away, William sees trailer door open. Out of it comes Anna -- looking extraordinary -- in a velvet dress; full, beautiful make-up; rich, extravagant hair. She has a necessary cluster of people about her. Hair, make-up, costume and the third assistant who has collected her. She walks a few yards, and then casually turns her head. And sees him. Her face registers not jut surprise, certainly not a simple smile. His being there is a complicated thing. Cut back to him. He does a small wave. She pauses as the whole paraphernalia of the upcoming scene passes between them. The movie divides them. But then she begins to walk through it, and followed by her cluster, she makes her way towards him. When she reaches him, the security guard stands back a pace, and her people hold back. She doesn't really know what to say...</context>
      <utterance>... can't let you through.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is certainly... ah...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I only found out you were here yesterday.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The third assistant is under pressure.</context>
      <utterance>I was going to ring... but... I didn't think you'd want to...</utterance>
   <speaker>THIRD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks around. The poor third is nervous -- and the first is approaching.</context>
      <utterance>Anna.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not going very well -- and it's our last day.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely -- you're clearly very busy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But... wait... there are things to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is swept away, four people touching her hair and costume.</context>
      <utterance>Drink tea -- there's lots of tea.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come and have a look...</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you a fan of Henry James?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Henry James film?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry the sound man is a pleasant, fifty-year-old balding fellow. He hands him the headphones.</context>
      <utterance>This is Harry -- he'll give you a pair of headphones so you can hear the dialogue.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here we go. The volume control is on the side.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William, the headphones on, surveys the scene -- the cluster is a full 100 yards from the action, to allow a gracious sweeping wide-shot. He watches Anna. She is with her co-star in the Henry James film -- let's call him James.</context>
      <utterance>That's great.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are living in cloudcuckooland -- we'll never get this done today.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to. I've got to be in New York on Thursday.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He studies an actress a few yards to the left.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, stop showing off.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, that's an enormous arse.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not listening.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, but seriously -- it's not fair -- so many tragic young teenagers with anorexia -- and that girl has an arse she could perfectly well share round with at least ten other women -- and still be beg-bottomed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Back by the desk, William is listening and laughs. That's his girl. Anna prepares.</context>
      <utterance>I said I'm not listening -- and I think, looking at something that firm, you and your droopy little excuse for an 'arse' would be well-advised to keep quiet.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I ask you when you're going to tell everyone, and you say...?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Tomorrow will be soon enough.'</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then I... right.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who was that rather difficult chap you were talking to on the way up?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh... no one... no one. Just some... guy from the past. I don't know what he's doing here. Bit of an awkward situation.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes off the headphones and puts them gently down.</context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William walks away. The moment of hope is gone. He couldn't have had a clear reminder.</context>
      <utterance>Anytime.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to throw out these old videos.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You can't bin these. They're classics. I'm not allowing this.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right -- let's talk about rent...</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me help. We don't want all this shit cluttering up our lives.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to disturb you when you're cooking the books, but there's a delivery.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Martin, can't you just deal with this yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it's not for the shop. It's for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They head out, Martin behind him, incomprehensively rubbing his hands -- he's in a very good mood.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Tell me, would I have to pay a wet rag as much as I pay you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You disappeared.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes -- I'm sorry -- I had to leave... I didn't want to disturb you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... how have you been?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I've watched in wonder. Awards, glory</context>
      <utterance>Fine. Everything much the same. When they change the law Spike and I will marry immediately. Whereas you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's quite a big wrapped parcel, flat -- 3 foot by 4 foot, leaning against a bookshelf.</context>
      <utterance>Oh no. It's all nonsense, believe me. I had no idea how much nonsense it all was -- but nonsense it all is...  Well, yesterday was our last day filming and so I'm just off -- but I brought you this from home, and...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought I'd give it to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Shall I...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, don't open it yet -- I'll be embarrassed.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay -- well, thank you. I don't know what it's for. But thank you anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I actually had it in my apartment in New York and just thought you'd... but, when it came to it, I didn't know how to call you... having behaved so... badly, twice. So it's been just sitting in the hotel. But then... you came, so I figured... the thing is... the thing is</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then the door pings. In walks the annoying customer, Mr. Smith.</context>
      <utterance>What's the thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Smith is taken aback and therefore completely obedient.</context>
      <utterance>Don't even think about it. Go away immediately.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Right. Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were saying...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause as William takes this in.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. The thing is... I have to go away today but I wondered, if I didn't, whether you might let me see you a bit... or, a lot maybe... see if you could... like me again.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But yesterday... that actor asked you who I was... and you just dismissed me out of hand... I heard -- you had a microphone... I had headphones.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You expect me to tell the truth about my life to the most indiscreet man in England? Martin edges up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me -- it's your mother on the phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you tell her I'll ring her back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I actually tried that tack -- but she said you said that before and it's been twenty-four hours, and her foot that was purple is now a sort of blackish color...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin is left with Anna.</context>
      <utterance>Okay -- perfect timing as ever -- hold the fort for a second will you, Martin?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I just say, I thought 'Ghost' was a wonderful film.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... I've always wondered what Patrick Swayze is like in real life.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't say I know Patrick all that well.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh dear. He wasn't friendly during the filming?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, no -- I'm sure he was friendly -- to Demi Moore -- who acted with him in 'Ghost.' She's kind in here, not sarcastic.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William returns a little uneasy.</context>
      <utterance>Oh right. Right. Sorry. Always been a bit of an ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Martin leaves them.</context>
      <utterance>Anyway... it's lovely to meet you. I'm a great fan of yours. And Demi's, of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's awaiting an answer.</context>
      <utterance>That's fine. There's always a pause when the jury goes out to consider its verdict.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He can't really express what he feels.</context>
      <utterance>Anna. Look -- I'm a fairly level- headed bloke. Not often in and out of love. But...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... can I just say 'no' to your kind request and leave it at that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Yes, that's fine. Of course. I... you know... of course... I'll just... be getting along then... nice to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He feels he must explain.</context>
      <utterance>The truth is...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>well, buggered, basically.</context>
      <utterance>... with you, I'm in real danger. It took like a perfect situation, apart from that foul temper of yours -- but my relatively inexperienced heart would, I fear, not recover if I was once again ... cast aside, which I would absolutely expect to be. There are too many pictures of you everywhere, too many films. You'd go and I'd be...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see.  That reality is a real 'no,' isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I live in Notting Hill. You live in Beverly Hills. Everyone in the world knows who you are. My mother has trouble remembering my name.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Fine. Fine. Good decision.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. She kisses him on the cheek.</context>
      <utterance>The fame thing isn't really real, you know. Don't forget -- I'm also just a girl. Standing in front of a boy. Asking him to love her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then turns and leaves. Leaving him.</context>
      <utterance>Bye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think? Good move?</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good move: when all is said and done, she's nothing special. I saw her taking her pants off and I definitely glimpsed some cellulite down there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good decision. All actresses are mad as snakes.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tony -- what do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never met her, never want to.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brilliant. Max?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely. Never trust a vegetarian.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spike enters.</context>
      <utterance>Great. Excellent. Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was called and I came. What's up?</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>William has just turned down Anna Scott.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bella is casually looking at the painting that sits beside William. It is the original of the Chagall, the poster of which was on his wall.</context>
      <utterance>You daft prick!</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This painting isn't the original, is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I think that one may be.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But she said she wanted to go out with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes -- sort of...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you know, anybody saying they want to go out with you is... pretty great... isn't it...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They take in the line. It totally reverses their attitudes. A pause.</context>
      <utterance>It was sort of sweet actually -- I mean, I know she's an actress and all that, so she can deliver a line -- but she said that she might be as famous as can be -- but also... that she was just a girl, standing in front of a boy, asking him to love her.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at him. Spike does a big nod.</context>
      <utterance>Oh sod a dog. I've made the wrong decision, haven't I?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Max, how fast is your car?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If anyone gets in our way -- we have small nuclear devices.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And we intend to use them!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Bella?</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's not coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shoots out of his door, rushes round and grabs Bella out of the chair.</context>
      <utterance>Sod that. Bernie -- in the back!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, babe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Down Kensington Church Street, then Knightsbridge, then Hyde Park Corner.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crazy. Go along Bayswater...</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right -- then Park Lane.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or you could go right down to Cromwell Road, and left.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly the car slams to a halt.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop right there! I will decide the route. All right?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>James Bond never has to put up with this sort of shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is the same man.</context>
      <utterance>Is Miss Scott staying here?</utterance>
   <speaker>RITZ MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about Miss Flintstone?</utterance>
   <speaker>RITZ MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Man shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Or Bambi... or, I don't know, Beavis or Butthead?</utterance>
   <speaker>RITZ MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns despondent and takes two steps when the Ritz Man stops him in his tracks.</context>
      <utterance>Right. Right. Fair enough. Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>RITZ MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William is very grateful. He kisses the Ritz Man. Bernie's also gratuful. He kisses him too.</context>
      <utterance>There was a Miss Pocahontas in room 126 -- but she checked out an hour ago. I believe she's holding a press conference at The Savoy before flying to America.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A Japanese guest assumes this is the way to behave and the Ritz Man gets kissed a third time.</context>
      <utterance>We have lift off!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets out of the car and boldly stops the traffic coming in the opposite direction. Our car shoots past him.</context>
      <utterance>Bugger this for a bunch of bananas.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They leave him behind. Honey leans out the window and shouts...</context>
      <utterance>Go!</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spike waves wildly -- he loses concentration and is very nearly hit by a car.</context>
      <utterance>You're my hero.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, where's the press conference?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN AT SAVOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you an accredited member of the press?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He flashes a card.</context>
      <utterance>Yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN AT SAVOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a Blockbuster video membership card, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right... I work for their in- house magazine.  'Movies are our business.'</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN AT SAVOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Honey shoots into shot, pushing Bella's chair.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN AT SAVOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you are?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Writing an article about how London hotels treat people in wheelchairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN AT SAVOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course, madam. It's in the Lancaster Room. I'm afraid you're very late.</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Run!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JEREMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... You -- Dominic.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUESTIONER 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much longer are you staying in the UK then?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's in a slightly melancholic and therefore honest mood.</context>
      <utterance>No time at all. I fly out tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEREMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which is why we have to round it up now. Final questions. He points at a journalist he knows.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUESTIONER  2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is your decision to take a year off anything to do with the rumours about Jeff and his present leading lady?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely not.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUESTIONER 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you believe the rumours?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They love that answer, and all scribble in their note books. Next question comes from someone straight right next to William.</context>
      <utterance>It's really not my business any more. Though I will say, from my experience, that rumours about Jeff... do tend to be true.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was just a friend -- I think we're still friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEREMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is pointing straight at William, who has his hand up.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, the gentleman in the pink shirt.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anna sees who it is asking.</context>
      <utterance>Yes -- Miss Scott -- are there any circumstances in which you two might be more than just friends?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hoped there might be -- but no, I'm assured there aren't.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what would you say...</utterance>
   <speaker>JEREMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's just one question per person.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, let him... ask away. You were saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I just wondered whether if it turned out that this... person...</utterance>
   <speaker>OTHER JOURNALIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His name is Thacker.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We cut to Max, Bella, Bernie and Honey, all watching. Then back to Anna.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks. I just wondered if Mr. Thacker realized he'd been a daft prick and got down on his knees and begged you to reconsider, whether you would... reconsider.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I'm pretty sure I would.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anna whispers something to Jeremy.</context>
      <utterance>That's very good news. The readers of 'Horse and Hound' will be absolutely delighted.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEREMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dominic -- if you'd like to ask your question again?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUESTIONER 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. Anna looks up at William. He nods.</context>
      <utterance>Yes -- Anna -- how long are you intending to stay here in Britain?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both smile -- suddenly the press gets what's going on -- music -- noise -- they all turn and flash, flash, flash photos of William. Max and Bella kiss. Bernie kisses a total stranger. Spike finally makes it -- he's bright red from running.</context>
      <utterance>Indefinitely.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Honey hugs him. It's a new experience for Spike. Cut to William's face -- flash after flash -- still looking at Anna. They are both smiling.</context>
      <utterance>It was good.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
