<movie id="423" title="Out of Sight">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>TELLER/LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can I help you, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley takes out a ZIPPO LIGHTER and casually, yet expertly, begins to fiddle with it as the teller looks across the bank.</context>
      <utterance>Loretta, you see that guy talking to your manager, has his case open?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Mr. Guindon, one of our assistant managers. Our manager is Mr. Schoen, but he's not in today.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you see the guy with the attache case?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loretta goes stiff, swallows, stares back at Foley.</context>
      <utterance>That's my partner. He has a gun in there. And if you don't do exactly what I tell you, or you give me any kind of a problem, I'll look over at my partner and he'll shoot your Mr. Guindon between the eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>We hear a bit of thunder and Foley cuts a fast look out the front door. When he turns back, he sees that Loretta's having some trouble fitting all the bills into the envelope.</context>
      <utterance>Now take one of those big envelopes and put as many hundreds, fifties and twenties as you can pack into it. Nothing with bank straps or rubber bands. I don't want any dye packs. I don't want any bait money. Start with the second drawer and then the one over there, under the computer. Come on, Loretta, the key's right there next to you. No bills off the bottom of the drawer.  First time being robbed?  You're doing great. Just smile, Loretta, so you won't look like you're being held up.  That's the way, you're doing fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here, give me the twenties. I'll put 'em in my pocket. Okay, I haven't had to give my partner a sign; that's good. Now, he's gonna wait thirty seconds till after I'm out the door, make sure you haven't set off the alarm. If you have, he's gonna shoot Mr. Guindon between the eyes. Okay? I think that'll do it. Thank you, Loretta, and have a nice day.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley heads for the door. He pauses by Mr. Guindon's desk, looks back at Loretta. Foley smiles at her, then turns to the Man sitting with Mr. Guindon, indicates Loretta...</context>
      <utterance>You, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man looks across the bank at Loretta.</context>
      <utterance>She's cute, isn't she?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley winks at Loretta and walks out.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, yeah, I guess so.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who was that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the car won't start. Foley bangs on the wheel...</context>
      <utterance>Come on...</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Foley then stiffens as a cop sticks his gun through the open window into Foley's ear...</context>
      <utterance>Fuck!</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley looks to the passenger window, where ANOTER COP, smiling, now has his gun pointing at him.</context>
      <utterance>I think you flooded it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get out've the car, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wanna hear a funny story?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And as Foley obliges, we then...</context>
      <utterance>Shut up and get out've the car.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley keeps his eyes fixed on the basketball game.</context>
      <utterance>You want something, Foley?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What if I told you where and when?</context>
      <utterance>Some people are going out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I expect you to look out for me, Pup, let me run off work details.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. How many going out?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hear six.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know who they are?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do, but I won't tell you just yet. Meet me in the chapel at eight-thirty, right before lock-down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context>Chino looks over, watches Foley approach, lets his arm slip down so he can hook his thumb into Lulu's belt... the next thing to having him on a leash.</context>
      <utterance>Today's the day, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You excited?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you, man, Super Bowl Sunday.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but I see you moved it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why you think is today?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chino and Lulu exchange looks.</context>
      <utterance>You were out running this morning, sticking to your routine, anybody happened to notice. But you only did a couple of miles instead of your usual five. Saving yourself for the main event. Then I see you inside eating ten pounds of macaroni. Carbohydrates for endurance.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You all right, Foley. I like you.</context>
      <utterance>You want, I tole you you can come.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You told me I can come 'cause I caught you digging the fuckin' tunnel, saw you and Lulu coming out of the bushes, thought maybe you two were making out. Foley smiles at Lulu, who glares back at him.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Chino looks towards the fence along the front of the yard.</context>
      <utterance>So what, you finish ahead of schedule?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see what they doing, those posts out there? Putting up another fence, five metres on the other side of the one that's there. We wait until Super Bowl Sunday, they could have the second fence built and we have to dig another nine, ten days. So we going soon as it's dark. You want -- I mean it -- you can still come.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley looks off towards the visitors' parking area, the fence not twenty yards away.</context>
      <utterance>I appreciate the offer. And it's tempting.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, man, it's a long run to civilization. A hundred miles to Miami? I'm too old to start acting crazy, try a stunt like that. You make it out, send me a postcard.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?  Yeah, I accept.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Adele, how you doing?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Next time, leave the engine running.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Bank Robber, want some advice?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's funny, Adele. How many more times you gonna gimme that one?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Till it's not funny any more. What do you want, Jack?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know that Super Bowl party? They changed the date. It's on</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said not as a rule.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So why don't you come right out and tell me what you're talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to Miss Smarty Mouth. Out there in the free world.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's free about it? I'm looking for work.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to Mandrake the Magician?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Emil the Amazing. The bastard fired me and hired another girl, a redhead. I'm working on a new business card, pass out to the cafes. How's this sound--</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Adele, the reason I called, that party is today instead of Sunday. About eight-thirty, like only a few hours from now. So you'll have to get hold of Buddy, whatever he might be doing...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the one driving the other car?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, seeing as you have so much luck with cars, Buddy thought it might be better to bring two. He got this guy he says you know from Lompoc, Glenn something.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Glenn Michaels.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that's him. Buddy says Glenn thinks you guys are real cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He did, huh. Well, tell Buddy I see Glenn wearing his sunglasses I'll step on 'em. I might not even take 'em off first.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="30">
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...to where KAREN SISCO -- twenty-eight, black suit, long hair, a knockout -- sits. She picks up the box and shakes it.</context>
      <utterance>Happy birthday.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You fit another Chanel suit in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karen starts to carefully unwrap the present. Marshall watches, takes a sip of his drink, looks around the bar, sees how everyone's looking at the two of them...</context>
      <utterance>Something better. Open it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls a gleaming automatic pistol from the box...</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God...</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a --</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leans across the table and kisses him.</context>
      <utterance>--Sig-Sauer .38. I love it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Happy birthday, kid.  You want another Coke?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't. I gotta drive out to Glades, then I'm meeting Ray Nicolet at ten.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which one is that? The ATF guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was. Ray's with the F.B.I. now, he switched over.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's still married though, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Technically. They're separated.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, he's moved out?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's about to.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then they're not separated, are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we change the subject?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you doing at Glades?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Serving process, a Summons and Complaint. Some con doing mandatory life doesn't like macaroni and cheese. He files suit, says he has no choice in what they serve and it violates his civil rights.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know you can always step in, work with me full-time as one of my investigators.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You used to like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd meet doctors, lawyers -- nothing wrong with them necessarily if they're divorced. Why settle for some cowboy cop who drinks too much and cheats on his wife? That's the way those hotshots are, all of 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I really gotta go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't get to talk much any more.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How 'bout I come next Sunday and watch the Super Bowl with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets up, kisses him again.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the gun, Dad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LOMPOC FEDERAL PENITENTIARY.  LOMPOC, CALIFORNIA.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then...</utterance>
   <speaker>TWO YEARS AGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley watches a MAN -- fifties, out of place, not as hard-looking as those around him. The guy looks nervous, can feel the other cons' eyes on him as he tries to find a seat. The BELL SOUNDS and the white boxer staggers to his feet. Maurice steps in and resumes the bloody pummelling. Foley turns and watches the fight now...</context>
      <utterance>Ref don't call it pretty soon, Snoopy's gonna send this guy out in a body bag.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buddy shakes his head. Maurice dances around the other guy now. Teases him.</context>
      <utterance>Anyone ever tell you why they call him Snoopy?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The white guy throws a tired, loping roundhouse that barely glances off Maurice's jaw. Sure enough, Maurice makes a big show out of snapping his head back, staggering, before he finally goes down.</context>
      <utterance>He was Maurice "Mad Dog" Miller back when he was pro. Now you pet him, he goes down.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley watches the new inmate as fights erupt all around him and, anxious now, he tries to get out of there.</context>
      <utterance>I don't believe it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley looks at the other side of the yard where Maurice now stands at the far side of the yard coldly watching the guy, one hand thrust into his pocket. Foley watches as Maurice stops the NEW INMATE -- the older guy who looked out of place at the fights -- as he comes out into the yard.</context>
      <utterance>Guy's braggin' he won a thrown fight. Fuckin' pathetic.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Richard Ripley.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley watches as Ripley now makes a note in a BLACK BOOK.</context>
      <utterance>Dick the Ripper they called him, on account of all the people he ripped off.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he doin' here?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context>They look to where Glenn Michaels, the blond guy in dark shades we saw in Maurice's corner, works out on the bench press a few feet away. He's shirtless, tan, in shape.</context>
      <utterance>Three years.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He got three years and fined fifty million dollars and wrote 'em a fucking check. Like that, fifty mil, signed his name.  Whoa-- little help here!</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who you talkin' to, Studs? Me, or Buddy. I can't tell, you got those shades on.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys-- come on-- this is too heavy!</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess the bright glare out here made it hard to see the numbers on the weights.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley helps him get the bar up. Glenn sits up.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take the shades off. Just get this fuckin' thing off me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know he wrote a check?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He told me. He works the laundry with me. The guy loves to talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He watches Snoopy talking to Ripley, one eye always on the swaggering boxer across the yard, one hand in his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, to the U.S. Attorney. I hear he rolled over on all the snitches he was doing business with and got 'em all brought up.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, anybody that can write a check for fifty mil, he says</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Detroit. Snoopy Miller told me uncut diamonds are as easy to move as cash.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look like plain old rocks.</context>
      <utterance>Ever seen an uncut diamond, Studs?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So. What's your point?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My point is, that's probably what you're gonna end up with.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think he's lying?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A BELL SOUNDS. Everyone starts walking for the gate. Foley watches as the Boxer and his crew head for the gate, Maurice still standing there with his hand in his pocket. SLOW MOTION AS the boxer gets to the gate, sees Maurice who moves to him now, smiling like he's so glad to see him... his left hand clapping the guy on the back, saying something like congratulations as now his right hand comes out of his pocket and we see the long metal shiv--</context>
      <utterance>Use your head. The guys got five million lying around his house, you really think he's gonna tell some motormouth he just met in prison about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice wraps his left arm around the boxer's shoulder and hugs him tight for a moment, then quickly moves away. The Boxer stands there like a statue, doesn't move until he's at last jostled from behind and his legs fold and he drops to the cement.</context>
      <utterance>Here it comes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>We hear a WHISTLE BLOW as a GUARD spots the body. And now everyone moves like hell for the gate... except for... Richard Ripley who stands there frozen, staring down at the body. Foley glances back at the approaching guards, casually takes Ripley by the arm as he passes, leads him away from there, talks to him as they walk into the block...</context>
      <utterance>I guess the Snoop doesn't like to lose, even if it's on purpose.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't wanna be standing there, the hacks start asking questions you don't wanna answer.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley then moves away. He sees Maurice looking back at him, giving him a hard stare just before he melts into the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, uh, right, thanks...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She doesn't seem too sure about it, but lets him load the groceries in the trunk and take the key out of the lock.</context>
      <utterance>Here, lemme help you with those, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buddy smiles, waves her off.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't ask for your help, so don't expect a tip.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stands there stupidly as he gets in and drives off.</context>
      <utterance>That's okay, ma'am. I'll just take your car.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley watches Pup creep up the aisle towards the front of the chapel, eyes on the floor, listening...</context>
      <utterance>They're right underneath you, Pup. They dug a tunnel.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pup turns his back, walks up the aisle and across the front of the pews to a window.</context>
      <utterance>I don't hear 'em. Where's the tunnel come out?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Pup stares out the window...</context>
      <utterance>Second fence post from the tower out there. Go on, take a look.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley reaches down into a pew where's stashed a FOUR-FOOT CRUCIFIX. He picks it up, starts up the aisle...</context>
      <utterance>I don't see nothing there.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will directly. Keep watching.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now he pulls his radio from his belt, says into it...</context>
      <utterance>There some car headlights out there...  Jesus Christ...</utterance>
   <speaker>PUP</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Okay-- now Foley raises the metal cross, steps in and lays it smack against the side of Pup's head. Drops him clean with one swing, bouncing him off the window frame and down without a sound coming from him.</context>
      <utterance>Man outside the fence! By tower six!  This is Officer Pupko...  I'm looking at him, for Christ's sake!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He watches her duck her head in the trunk and come out with a holstered pistol.</context>
      <utterance>What's she doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>But then she throws the pistol in the trunk, ducks in there again and comes out this time racking a shotgun.</context>
      <utterance>Uh-oh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buddy watches the two cons, both Latins, make up their minds, start edging away -- shit, they've come this far. They look out at the spotlight sweeping around in the dark, then look the other way, along the fence towards the main gate, to see armed hacks coming out on the run, and that decides it for the cons. They take off running... Now Buddy watches as Karen puts her pump gun on them, but doesn't fire... The hacks running from the gate with rifles beat her to it, open up all at once and keep firing until the two convicts are cut down as they run. The hacks glance at Karen, but don't bother with her, more interested in the hole the convicts had come out of. Now they're standing by it peering in, edging closer with their weapons ready, then they all step back at once, bump into each other as... A head appears wearing a guard's baseball cap, the guy now saying something to the guards, his face smeared with muck, excited, pointing towards the orange grove. They run off, pausing briefly to kick the convicts they shot to see if they're alive, then keep going. The man in the hole, Foley, climbs out. He takes his time, puts on a show, standing with his hands on his hips like an honest-to-God hack, that serious cap down on his eyes. Buddy waves to Foley to come on and Karen turns and puts the shotgun on Buddy. Buddy raises the palm of his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Get your hands in the air!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay, honey, we're good guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not so much asking, but putting it to him the way cops do when they're already pretty sure what you're doing. She glances around to include Foley, now coming at her like some creature out of the swamp, giving Buddy time to take her around the neck. She fights him, jabs him in the gut with the butt end of the shotgun before Foley wrenches it from her grip. They drag her to the rear end of her car, the trunk lid still up, and crouch there as some hacks come running along the fence, past the dark gun tower and cross the road towards the orange grove. A moment later, they hear bursts of gunfire, then silence.</context>
      <utterance>What're you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bet that's all the hacks they send out. Otherwise nobody's left to mind the store.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to see Foley and Karen staring at each other in the headlights from Buddy's car; Karen not at all afraid.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't we talk about it later?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why you're just a girl. What do you do for a living you pack a shotgun?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley keeps staring at her like he's giving the situation serious thought, but what he says is...</context>
      <utterance>I'm a federal marshal and you're under arrest, both of you guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Listen, you hop in the trunk and we'll get out of here. Karen looks at him, then gets up, climbs into the trunk. She's reaching around, trying to find her pistol, when... Foley gives her a shove and gets in with her, wedging her against the wall of the trunk, pressing against her back like they're cuddled up in bed. He holds her to him, giving her no room to turn and stick the gun in his face. Buddy reaches for the trunk lid and then everything goes...</context>
      <utterance>I bet I smell, don't I?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You comfy?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I could have a little more room.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There isn't any. All this shit you got in here. What is all this stuff anyway? Handcuffs, chains... what's this can?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>Squirt some in your mouth.</context>
      <utterance>For your breath. You could use it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>A BEAM OF LIGHT appears as he finds a flashlight and turns it on. He plays the beam along Karen's leg, calms down some as he looks at all of her now and finally says...</context>
      <utterance>You devil, it's mace, huh? What've you got here, a billy? Use it on poor unfortunate offenders.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's your gun, your pistol?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They go over some bumps. We hear men's voices from somewhere far off, outside.</context>
      <utterance>In my bag, in the car.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He runs his hand down her thigh, looking for her gun, but also, just, well, looking.</context>
      <utterance>You know you don't have a chance of making it. Guards are out here already, they'll stop the car.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're off in the cane by now chasing Cubans. I timed it to slip between the cracks, you might say.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, it stunk in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I believe it. You've ruined a nine- hundred-dollar suit my dad gave me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, went real nice with that twelve gauge, too.  Tell me, why in the world would someone like you ever become a federal marshall?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The idea of going after guys like you appealed to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guys like me, huh. Well, listen, even though I've been celibate lately, I'm not gonna force myself on you. I've never done that in my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wouldn't have time anyway. We come to a roadblock, they'll run the car, find out in five seconds who it belongs to.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If they get set up in time, which I doubt. And even if they do they'll be looking for a buncha little Latin fellas, not a big black guy driving a Ford.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More bumps. Then picking up speed as the road smooths out.</context>
      <utterance>Must be quite a pal, risk his own ass like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who, Buddy? Yeah. He's a good guy. Back when we jailed together, he'd call his sister every week without fail. She's a born-again Christian, does bookkeeping for a televangelist. Buddy calls her up, confesses his sins, tells her about whatever bank he happened to rob.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buddy. That's his given name?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One I gave him, yeah.  Fuck...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, what's</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, are you famous?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Time I was convicted in California? FBI told me I'd robbed more banks than anyone in the computer.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All three of us ended up in Angola.</context>
      <utterance>Tell you the truth, I don't know. I started when I was eighteen, driving for my Uncle Cully and his partner, Gus. They go into a bank this one time in Slidell, Gus jumps the counter to get the tellers and breaks his leg.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought so, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was me, I woulda left ol' Gus on the floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I believe you would have. Another fall, I did seven years at Lompoc. And I don't mean the place next door where some of Nixon's people went.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know the difference. You were in Lompoc USP, the federal penitentiary. I've delivered people there. So basically you've spent half your life in prison.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Can you imagine looking at that?</context>
      <utterance>Basically. Yeah. If I go back now, I do a full thirty years, no time off.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her, then looks away as we...</context>
      <utterance>I don't have to. I don't rob banks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't seem all that scared.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't act like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want me to do? Scream? I don't think it would help much.  I'm just gonna sit back, take it easy, and wait for you to screw up.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, you sound like my ex-wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were married? All those falls, I'm surprised you had time.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was just a year, give or take a few days. I mean, it's not like we didn't get along or anything. We had fun, we just didn't have that... that thing, you know? That spark, you know what I mean? You gotta have that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We still talk, though.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, this isn't gonna end well, these things never do.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, if it turns out I get shot like a dog, it'll be in the street, not off a goddamn fence.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And for a few moments, all we hear is the sound of the car on the road. Then...</context>
      <utterance>You must see yourself as some kind of Clyde Barrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you mean of Bonnie and Clyde? Hm. You ever see pictures of him, the way he wore his hat? You could tell he had that don't-give-a-shit air about him.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't recall his hat, but I've seen pictures of him lying dead, shot by Texas Rangers. Did you know he didn't have his shoes on?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that right?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They put a hundred and eighty-seven bullet holes in Clyde, Bonnie Parker and the car they were driving. Bonnie was eating a sandwich.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're full of interesting facts, aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was May, 1934, near Gibsland, Louisiana.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That part in the movie where they get shot? Warren Beatty and... I can't think of her name.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Faye Dunaway.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I liked her in that movie about</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peter Finch.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, right. Anyway, that scene where Warren Beatty and Faye Dunaway get shot? I remember thinking at the time it wouldn't be a bad way to go, if you have to.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bleeding on a country road.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We HEAR FAINT SIRENS OS...</context>
      <utterance>It wasn't pretty after, no, but if you were in that car -- eating a sandwich -- you wouldn't have known what hit you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="36">
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're sure easy to talk to. I wonder -- say we met under different circumstances and got to talking, say you were in a bar and I came up to you -- I wonder what would happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean if you didn't know who I was.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd probably tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just saying I think if we met under different circumstances...</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. Foley tries to get back to where it was working...</context>
      <utterance>You have to be kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Another one Faye Dunaway was in I liked,</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They lie there a moment, think about that as we hear THE CAR SLOWING DOWN, coasting, then bumping along the shoulder of the road to a stop.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah...</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never thought it made sense, though, the way they got together so quick.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, romantically.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The trunk goes dark again as the car's turned off.</context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.  Well, but if --</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context>And the trunk lid raises so that we see Karen and Foley lying in the back. Foley gets out. Karen doesn't move.</context>
      <utterance>You still alive in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where in the hell are we?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the turnpike up there. Glenn's waiting with the other car.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karen pushes off, rolls from her right side to her left, brings up her Sig Sauer in both hands to put it on them, both standing in the opening, in the dark, but right there.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, honey, come on out of there.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get your hands up and turn around.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We may as well leave her, we're leaving the car and we gotta leave her some place anyway, what's the difference where?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley walks to the passenger seat, reaches in the window.</context>
      <utterance>She's coming with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ, what were you doing in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley takes her wallet, looks at her driver's licence photo.</context>
      <utterance>Get the shotgun. And her purse. I'd like to know who she is.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A sheriff's green-and-white goes screaming past and they keep to the narrow space between the car and the concrete abutment of the overpass. When the road quiets down, Foley moves to the trunk and bangs on it once with his fist.</context>
      <utterance>I already looked. Her name is Karen Sisco. Like the Cisco Kid only spelled different, S-i-s-c-o.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Karen? Be a good girl now, you hear? Now, I'm gonna open the-- Foley jumps at the sound of a pistol shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He looks up to see Buddy holding her shotgun, staring at him. He settles down, then...</context>
      <utterance>You're putting holes in your car!</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Foley puts his hand out and Buddy, still looking at him funny, gives him the keys.</context>
      <utterance>We're not leaving you. I'm gonna open the trunk enough for you to throw the gun out. Okay? You shoot -- Buddy's got your shotgun, says he'll shoot back if you do and I can't stop him. So it's up to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Coming from somewhere above them.</context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Foley steps out into the open, Buddy close behind him. They look up to see a figure, head and shoulders against the evening sky, leaning on the concrete overpass rail. We can see his long blond hair falling beside his face, now half-concealed behind dark sunglasses.</context>
      <utterance>It's me, Glenn.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley looks at Buddy.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Jack, good to see you, man. The fuck're you guys shooting at?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do we need him?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley thinks about it, then looks up at the overpass again.</context>
      <utterance>The green-and-whites saw us. One of 'em starts thinking, what's that car doing there? Ties it to the break and turns around...</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, hey, Studs? We thought you were somebody else.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Studs. Man, I haven't heard that since Lompoc. What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley shakes his head, then walks back to the Ford and bangs on the trunk.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, nuthin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Foley sticks the key in the lock as Buddy steps up to the trunk and racks the pump on the shotgun. Foley leans close to the metal.</context>
      <utterance>You coming out?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He turns the key and raises the lid. Karen, bunched in there, extends her arm, her hand holding the Sig Sauer by the barrel.</context>
      <utterance>You hear that?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>"Jack." Buddy gives him another funny look.</context>
      <utterance>You win, Jack.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Glenn looks over as the three of them reach the top of the grade, move through the scrub. Glenn leans against the car, flashers blinking.</context>
      <utterance>Have your clothes cleaned and send me the bill.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll send it to you at Glades.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, what'd you crawl through, a sewer?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take your sunglasses off.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see better with them on.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Glenn shrugs, takes them off and sticks them in his jeans.</context>
      <utterance>You don't take 'em off, I'm gonna throw 'em off the overpass while they're still on your head.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait in the car.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're in civilization now, man, ease up.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like you to go wait in the car. How's that? Take her with you and put her in back.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the trunk?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley stares at him, waiting. Glenn motions to Karen...</context>
      <utterance>The backseat.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks past Foley without looking at him.</context>
      <utterance>Come on. I have to do what I'm told.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute. Let me have your raincoat.  Somebody forgot to bring me clean clothes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I brought 'em, they're back at Glades in the Cadillac. You wanted to take her car.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't say anything as Glenn takes off the raincoat, folds it up, then throws it at Foley's feet.</context>
      <utterance>You can blame me if you want. I don't mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley watches as Glenn gets his sunglasses out, puts them back on and takes Karen by the arm.</context>
      <utterance>Here you are, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karen looks over at Foley, then ducks her head and gets in the backseat.</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why you brought Glenn into this, I'll never know.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How 'bout the score was his idea to begin with?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buddy watches Foley struggle with the buttons on the uniform, all of them caked with muck.</context>
      <utterance>His idea? Gimme a break. Fuckin' guy's got a vacant lot for a head. Was you and me figured the whole thing out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lays the shotgun in the grass and comes up, takes the guard shirt in his two hands and rips it open, popping buttons and tearing the shirt.</context>
      <utterance>You're pulling at it. Here...</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know why, but every time he opens his mouth I want to punch him out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>He ain't the problem, Jack.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna pull your head outta your ass and tell me why we're bringing</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karen leans forward to have a look, sees Foley and Buddy against the dark foliage.</context>
      <utterance>...if he thinks he can talk to me like this. Shit, I don't even know what I need them for.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got a big score lined up up north. They wouldn't even know about it, it wasn't for me. I could do it right now myself, except it's so fucking cold up there in January--</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His head turns so that we can see his designer shades.</context>
      <utterance>Glenn?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't remember me, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It couldn't have been out at Glades, if that's what you're thinking. I was never out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He raises his hand, strokes his hair away from his face.</context>
      <utterance>No, that's not what I'm thinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you're sure we've met, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't move or say a word, staring at her now like he's been turned to stone.</context>
      <utterance>Last fall, I drove you from the Palm Beach county jail to the federal courthouse, twice. You're Glenn Michaels.  I never forget anyone I've cuffed and shackled.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He turns away, all the way around to look straight ahead...</context>
      <utterance>Let's think for a minute, Glenn, see if we can work this out...</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do we have a gun in the car?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I remember you now. Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She touches his shoulder and he jumps.</context>
      <utterance>Foley's not going to make it. And if he goes down, Glenn, you go with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I can understand if you and Foley are close.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not. I'm helping him, yeah--</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to take her to my place and get cleaned up? You come out of the bathroom with your after-shave on and she goes, "Oh, I had you all wrong"?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to talk to her again, that's all. See what would happen under, you know, normal circumstances.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley doesn't say anything. Just takes a deep breath as we HEAR THE CAR START and they both look over...</context>
      <utterance>You're too late, Jack.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>They start towards the car. Then stop and watch as it takes off, tires squealing as the rubber hits pavement. Their backs to us, they stand there watching the tailights until they're out of sight down the turnpike, neither of them saying a word. We hear SQUEAKY FOOTSTEPS OVER...</context>
      <utterance>He wants to get out of here and I don't blame him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ripley looks up as Maurice and Himey come strolling into the library, sit down on either side of a now very anxious Ripley.</context>
      <utterance>Dick. My man.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He sets a small Ziploc with two tiny fish inside down on the table.</context>
      <utterance>I got your fishies for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not so fast, Dick.  Starting now, there's gonna be an across the board cost a living increase.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Year ago, I come in here on credit card fraud, but after I shanked that loudmouth pussy on the yard the other day, my Dunn &amp; Broadstreet, has gone way the fuck up.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it's Dunn </utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's start with the fish. They was two grand, but now they's three. Ripley looks at the two tiny fish in the bag.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That Bausch &amp; Lomb Saline shit you asked for is gonna be eighty bucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I need that...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and that extra pillow's gonna be an even three c's.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all look to where...</context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sign says "Shut the fuck up." Or can't you guys read?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There a problem, Foley?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley shuts the big book -- CHILTON'S AUTO REPAIR.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I got a problem. This is the dumbest fucking shakedown in the history of dump shakedowns. Three hundred bucks for a pillow?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds high, doesn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Must be a real soft pillow.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Faux goose down.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still...</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much for your company at chow?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Company, shit. I watch the man's back.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bet. How much?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley shakes his head, turns to Ripley.</context>
      <utterance>Another C.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're smart, Ripley, you'll tell this guy to fuck off.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? Well, I uhhh...</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ripley looks at Maurice: Good point.</context>
      <utterance>First of all, if he kills you, he's not gonna get any more money out of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ripley turns back to Foley now: Also a good point.</context>
      <utterance>Man doesn't have to get killed. He could accidentally fall on something sharp, like a shiv. Or my dick.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You stick</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't smoke.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Himey here's a pro-toh-jay of mine. He's ranked number thirty-two in the federal prison system.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you know, reading's funnamental an' shit, we just excited.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guard exits. Maurice and Foley are still staring at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Clear outta here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me. Snoopy? Did we settle the fish thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pours the water out of the bag and drops the fish into Ripley's open hand. Maurice then squeezes Ripley's hand into a fist, crushing the fish. He taps his fist to Ripley's.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Sure. It's all settled.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice gives Foley a last look, starts out of the room with Himey. Ripley looks at the crushed fish in his hand, then at Foley.</context>
      <utterance>That's how you do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for your help.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear a PHONE RING and then...</context>
      <utterance>Any time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stick and jab, fool. Stick and jab.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tuffy. C'mere, boy...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gonna answer the phone?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice watches as Moselle now tries to throw the frisbee to a little wire-haired terrier, but it just bounces off the dog's head.</context>
      <utterance>What for? It's not for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSELLE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bad dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lovingly nuzzles the dog like it's his child.</context>
      <utterance>Moselle, the fuck are you doing to my little Tuffy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>I'm trainin' Tuffy, so he can be on a Kal Kan commercial, make us some extra money.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She comes over, picks up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>That's the dumbest thing I heard in my life. Everybody knows Kal Kan doesn't pay for shit. You gonna get a gig, it's gotta be for one of the big three: Science Diet, Iams or that Cycle shit for the fat dogs. Now answer the fuckin phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?  For you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Glenn watches as some guy in a suit gets out of a black Lincoln Town Car and jogs to the john.</context>
      <utterance>Studs. Hey, son, you must be one a them psychic friends. I was just thinkin' about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Snoopy, I'm on my way up to Detroit and need a place to crash.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You crazy, come up</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'll just tell you it's someone big.</context>
      <utterance>I can't really go into it right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gimme another hint.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice doesn't say a word.</context>
      <utterance>It's Richard Ripley.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You there?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Question is, why aren't</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm here, all right. I'm very here.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just saying she wasn't scared.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buddy opens the door, looks at Foley.</context>
      <utterance>Cause she had her hand on her gun the whole time, waiting to make her move.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're just jealous it was me in the trunk with her and not you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley starts for the bathroom.</context>
      <utterance>First thing I'm gonna do is get all this mud off me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been dreaming about a hot bath for the last six months. Soak the prison off me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's some lilac oil, you want some, a vanilla candle under the sink.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's something about a nice hot bath, transforms a person. It's not just about opening up your pores, know what I mean? There's just something about the heat and the wet that's calming you know? Settles me in a way that I really can't articulate.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know exactly what you mean. It's just a feeling.  You know, I could go for some wine tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a store around the corner, I'll be right back.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley goes into the bathroom. A moment later WE HEAR THE BATH</context>
      <utterance>Sounds great.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at each other a moment. He then pulls her down to him and kisses her. She kisses him back. He then pulls her into the tub with him as we now hear...</context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL SISCO</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Karen...?</utterance>
   <speaker>CUT TO: KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As she opens her eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were talking in your sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd I say?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Hey, yourself."</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear A KNOCK at the door. They look to where Special Agent DANIEL BURDON -- black, forties, expensive suit -- stands in the doorway, file in one hand.</context>
      <utterance>Huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Daniel.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Daniel Burdon, FBI.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marshall Sisco. Karen's dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marshall looks at him a moment. Then, to Karen...</context>
      <utterance>You mind please waiting outside. We have some business to do here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burdon waits for Marshall to walk out, then sits down.</context>
      <utterance>I need to go to the john anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanna be on the task force, Daniel.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's nice of you to offer, Karen, but I got all the help I can use right now. Instead, let's talk about how you got the bump on your head.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't that my report you're holding onto?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, but I want to hear you tell it. Starting with when you tried to grab the wheel -- where was this?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now we see it...</context>
      <utterance>Coming to the Okeechobee exit...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="35">
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take the next exit.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What am I supposed to do</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches over and grabs the wheel.</context>
      <utterance>No way, man, no fuckin' way am I gonna turn myself in.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He hits the brakes. The car goes off the road, down the grade, the abutment coming right at us as we go back to...</context>
      <utterance>The fuck are you doing?!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE HOSPITAL ROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As Burdon sets the file down, sits back now.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burdon looks at Karen a moment, then...</context>
      <utterance>The next thing I knew, the paramedics were taking me out the car.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a couple of points I keep wondering about have to do with the two guys that grabbed you. Buddy is it? And this fella Jack Foley. I swear the man must've robbed two hundred banks in his time.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? Huh. He told me he didn't remember how many he robbed.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You talked to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the trunk, yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd you talk about?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh... different things, prison, movies.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This fella holds you hostage, you talk about movies?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was an unusual experience.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Foley made me think of that fella Carl Tillman, the one you were seeing, it turns out the same time he was doing banks. You recall that?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I was seeing Carl Tillman, I didn't know he robbed banks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but I had enough reason to believe he did, and I told you. So you had to at least suspect him.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what happened to Carl?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The time came, you shot him. But you didn't shoot Foley or the guy with him. They're unarmed, you had a shotgun and you let them throw you in the trunk. Okay, now you got your Sig in your hand. You say in the report you couldn't turn around, he had you pinned down. But when the trunk opened, how come you didn't cap the two guys then?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that what you would've done?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You say in the report Glenn didn't have a gun, but you let him get away, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Daniel, what do you work on most of the time, fraud? Go after crooked bookkeepers.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Karen, I've been with the Bureau fifteen years, on all kinds of investigations.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you ever shot a man? How many times have you been primary through the door?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to qualify, is that it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear CHUCKLING OS. Burdon glances at the doorway where we see Marshall now standing, enjoying this.</context>
      <utterance>You have to know what you're talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll talk another time, Karen. All right? I'd like to know why Foley put you in that second car when he didn't need you any more.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll have to ask him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sisco.</context>
      <utterance>Sounds to me like he liked having you around. I'll see you, Karen. Mr.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marshall waits for him to walk out...</context>
      <utterance>Agent Burdon.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She's not listening. He sits down, takes her hand...</context>
      <utterance>The white man's Burdon. That's what everybody calls him in Miami. The Metro-Dade guys. He's got a knack for pissing people off.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you thinking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Sig Sauer you got me for my birthday.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Tell you what, you're a good girl, you might get another one for Christmas.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll get it back when I get Foley.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh-- Are you delivering the oxygen?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, no, ma'am. Sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up the newspaper so that Foley can see his picture on the front page: an unflattering mug shot that doesn't look all that much like him.</context>
      <utterance>You made the front page.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They pass this picture around you can go anywhere you want, nobody'll know you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'd just drawn thirty to life.</context>
      <utterance>I wasn't feeling my best that day.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buddy reaches into the bag, tosses Foley a NEW ZIPPO.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe this'll make you feel better.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley catches the lighter, immediately begins playing with it. He looks at the paper on the coffee table as Buddy sits down, pulls some groceries and a sixpack from the bag.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paper says there's ten grand each on you, Chino and Lulu.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say anything in there about Karen Sisco?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just that she got away.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but what happened after she drove off with Glenn?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley walks back out on to the balcony, looks at the contents of Karen's bag spread out on the table.</context>
      <utterance>You'll have to ask Glenn. And most likely, he's on his way to Detroit, where we should be.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You realize what you're doing? Worrying about a person that works in law enforcement. You want to sit down and have cocktails with a girl that tried to shoot you. You hear what I'm saying? Foley holds up the picture of Marshall Sisco.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's the only picture she carries.</context>
      <utterance>Think this old guy is her boyfriend?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley picks up her drivers licence photo.</context>
      <utterance>Am I going to Detroit by myself?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Longer we hang around down here, Jack, better chance there is either Glenn's gonna fuck up the whole score, or we gonna get busted, or both.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll leave first thing in the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He doesn't even look like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She realizes Marshall's watching her.</context>
      <utterance>No, he looks a lot...</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The doorbell RINGS. She ignores his look, gets up. Walks to the door and opens it to reveal RAY NICOLET, boots, leather jacket, etc. Cowboy Cop.</context>
      <utterance>Different.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Ray.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look great. Your dad taking good care of you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marshall gets up, shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>He took the week off so we'd have time together. So far he's worked on his boat every day. Dad? Ray Nicolet.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've heard a lot about you, Mr. Sisco.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Likewise.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ray's with the F.B.I. Task Force, working on the prison break.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray turns to Karen, holding his jacket open to show the task force inscription on his T-shirt in red, the guy's .357 tucked into his waistband.</context>
      <utterance>I see that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In case no one knows what he does. Tell me, Ray, you ever wear one says, "Undercover"?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Course not.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's it going?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karen looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Great. We got one of 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was it Foley?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Off a tip?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, someone spotted two of 'em in this hobo camp out by the airport, called the number--</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grabs Nicolet by the arm.</context>
      <utterance>I knew it, soon as I saw they were offering a reward.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We went out there, full SWAT, two choppers, the whole bit, but Linares started shooting anyway. We put him down, but somehow Chirino got away.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you pay the guy the reward?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, as soon as we got back.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her father gives her a look.</context>
      <utterance>Foley hadn't been there?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE PHONE RINGS. Marshall moves to it.</context>
      <utterance>This place was strictly Cuban. If Foley had a ride he must have his own agenda. He seems to be the only one knows what he's doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?  Yeah, she is. Just a minute.  For you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know who this is?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks out to her father's balcony now.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just wanted to see if you're okay, make sure Glenn didn't hurt you or, you know, anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marshall picks up the newspaper...</context>
      <utterance>Something I've been wondering, Ray...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She closes the glass door, so that they won't hear her.</context>
      <utterance>It says in the headline, "I slept with a murderer, says shaken Miami woman." She lives in Little Havana, her husband's out of town working when one of the escapees shows up at her door...</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd you get this number?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who was it answered the phone?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>None of your business.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just worried maybe I'm not old enough for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's my dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really. He has a cop's face.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know? Wait-- you have my wallet.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And your gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think I could have them back?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do we do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's see. You could come on by my dad's place, drop 'em off.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley stops flipping through the magazine, stares at what he's been looking for: an ad for</context>
      <utterance>Sure. I'll just leave 'em with the S.W.A.T. guy answers the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You won't do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She doesn't know what to say to that. Foley smells the ad.</context>
      <utterance>Because you're having too much fun.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...She fixes him pork chops and rice, the next thing you know they're making love on the sofa. She says he was very gentle.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I spoke to her. The guy told her he missed his little girl and she felt sorry for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's how you score now?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My dad's retired. He was a Private Investigator. Forty years. I used to work for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can just picture that, a cute girl like you following slip-and-fall and whiplash cheaters.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something I've been wondering, what ever happened to your Uncle Cully?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? You think he might tell you where I am?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unless you wanna tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's dead. He did twenty-seven years before he came out and died not too long after in Charity Hospital, I think trying to make up for all the good times he'd missed.  That's not gonna be me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One last score, that the idea? Move to some island.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm partial to mountains myself. But if you like islands, we'll make it an island.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatta you mean</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who you talking to?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley's caught off guard, hangs up the phone. He looks at Buddy.</context>
      <utterance>Is that Buddy?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You better come see this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The woman also said he stole her husband's gun, a twenty-two pistol, and some of his clothes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So the woman's married. She goes to bed with this prison escapee because he misses his little girl and then tells the world about it. But you don't reveal her name, you protect her. It sounds like you're saying it's okay as long as her husband doesn't find out about it. Like the guy who cheats on his wife, saying what she doesn't know won't hurt her.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks over at her now. Gives her an innocent look.</context>
      <utterance>Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chino's gonna wanna talk to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's running for his life, he doesn't give a shit about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's gotta know by now that I gave him up back at Glades. He does, he's gonna try to find me. Maybe go see Adele, see what she knows.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley doesn't answer. Buddy mutes the set. Turns to Foley.</context>
      <utterance>He knows where she lives?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were talking one time, drinking rum. I may've mentioned Adele, how she worked for a magician. Chino got interested. He's like, Yeah? How does he saw the woman in half? He wanted to meet her. Or get a look at her if she ever came to visit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So call her up. Tell her don't talk to any Cubans.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her phone's probably tapped.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you know they're gonna have some people watching the hotel.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember, pay attention to how she talks about Foley, her tone. Do it right, she'll tell you things she wouldn't tell Burdon. Tell her you think he's a nice guy. No, first tell her about being in the trunk with him, in the dark for half an hour, and see how she takes it. If she's in on it, what does she get for all the aggravation; cops breathing on her? I bet nothing. So she still likes him enough to stick her neck out. You think that's possible? What kind of guy is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's pretty laid back, confident.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He remind you of that guy, Tillman?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you know he's dirty and you still wanna see him again.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to bust his ass, put him in shackles.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe. But you're also curious about the man. Twice last night you asked your married boyfriend Nicolet about him. You were concerned, but you didn't want to show it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My married boyfriend - setting him up with that news story so you could talk about infidelity. I couldn't believe it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like the wild ones, don't you? Tillman, Nicolet and now Foley. You know, I've always said there's a thin line between the cowboy cops and the armed robbers, all those guys that love to pack.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Foley</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, is this Adele?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up, glances about, then checks the little .22 stuck in one of his pockets. As he then starts off down the street, we can see the name "COLOR MY WORLD HOUSEPAINTING" on the back of the jumpsuit.</context>
      <utterance>Uh-- sorry. Wrong number.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice disguise.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a tourist.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You at least bring the gun?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There. You see the guy sitting on the porch? The old ladies and one guy? You know they'll have a couple more in a car somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buddy follows Foley's gaze to...</context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley watches, her hair in her face as she tries to reach under the car and grab it.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, my.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>They watch as she walks to the Normandie and shows the YOUNG AGENT her ID...</context>
      <utterance>Okay, you saw her. That's all you get.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess Adele's in good hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure looks that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go to Detroit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you're talkin'.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The FBI didn't tell you I was with them?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They didn't</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She thinks a moment. The door closes and opens again, all the way. Adele stands there in a robe, hanging partly open, panties, but no bra.</context>
      <utterance>I know a Glenn.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm getting ready to go out. You can come in if you want, sit down for a minute. Would you like a Diet Coke?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="98">
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She comes in, checks out the place. She turns a chair from the glasstop table and sits down as Adele comes out of the kitchenette with a Diet Coke and packet of cigarettes.</context>
      <utterance>No, thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks away, comes back with an ashtray.</context>
      <utterance>Those are cute shoes. The kind of jobs I get, I have to wear these killer spikes, they ruin your feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When you were in the trunk with Jack... Karen waits, watches her light her cigarette.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He didn't hurt you or anything, did he?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean, did he try to jump me? No, but he was kind of talkative.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele sits down at the other end of the table.</context>
      <utterance>He gets that way when he's nervous sometimes.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't visit him in prison.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He didn't want me to.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. He was different after he was sentenced, looking at thirty years. Said it depressed him every time the younger cons called him an old timer.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you spoke to him on the phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'd call every once in a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He called the day he escaped.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He did? I don't remember. Did he say about me? In the trunk?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said he wished the two of you could start over, live a normal life.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh. Problem is, Jack's idea of a normal life is robbing banks. It's all he's ever done.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you know that when you married him?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele looks out the window. Karen waits, looks to an end table where she sees a photograph of Jack and Adele on a boat somewhere ten years back.</context>
      <utterance>He said he was a card player. I could live with that. I never knew he robbed banks till he got busted with that car that caught fire -- if you can imagine something like that happening, comes out of the bank and the car's on fire. I did go see him in jail to tell him I was filing for divorce. He said, "Okay." Jack's so easy going.  He was fun, but never what you'd call a real husband.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll say one thing for Jack, he was never ugly or mean, or drank too much. He was very considerate, lights on or off, if you know what I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She realizes Adele is looking at her.</context>
      <utterance>Really.  Hm.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Adele, sooner or later, he's gonna get caught. I'd like to get him before he does something else, makes it worse on himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karen shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>Buddy'll take care of him. Keep him out've trouble. He's Jack's conscience. Always has been.  He tell you how they met?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack came out of a bank he just robbed in Pasadena, couldn't get his stolen car to start. Battery was dead. He looks over, sees Buddy sitting in a burgundy Bonneville, goes up, offers him a thousand dollars for a jump. Turns out, Buddy was casing the same bank and saw the whole thing. Buddy says, I'll take the thousand, but we're leaving in my car, not that piece of shit you come in.  They musta robbed fifty banks together.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Till they got busted.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That wasn't Jack's fault. No, that was on account of Buddy, for some reason, decided to call his sister and confess to a job</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Adele? You in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to speak with you, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I talk to the guy you work for, Emil. He tole me your number and where you live. See, I'm looking for an assistant and would like to speak to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did work for Emil, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I was Emil's box-jumper for almost four years.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were his what, his box?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karen looks at the door. Something's wrong... through the glass bricks that line one side of the door, we see blurred movement on the other side, someone doing</context>
      <utterance>His assistant.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now Karen and Adele look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, around here. I was a mayishan in Cuba before I come here. Manuel the Mayishan was my name.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Karen shakes her head "no."</context>
      <utterance>Can you open the door?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not dressed.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Boom. Karen gets to her feet, brings her bag to the edge of the table, sees Adele staring at her.</context>
      <utterance>Listen to me.  I'm a good friend of Jack Foley.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ask him his name.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karen brings her Beretta out of the bag.</context>
      <utterance>Jose Chirino.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Karen moves along the table to Adele...</context>
      <utterance>Or maybe you hear Jack Foley call me Chino. I'm the same person.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Adele speaks, Karen racks the slide on her 9mm.</context>
      <utterance>Tell him to wait in the hall, you have to get dressed. Say it loud.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait in the hall! I have to get dressed!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karen motions for Adele to keep talking as she takes a position beside the door, where we now see Chino's silhouette in one of the three glass panels in the centre of the door.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me where is Jack Foley, I don't bother you no more.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know where he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, I'm the one help Jack escape from prison. He tole me, I can't find him to see you. So why don't you open this fucking door. Okay? So we can speak.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go away, or I'll call the police.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele says nothing. Then...</context>
      <utterance>Why you want to do that, to a frien'?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, you don't want to help me, I'm leaving.  I'm going now. I see you maybe some time, okay? Bye bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave it where it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait. You not Adele?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a federal marshal and you're under arrest. Put the gun on the table. I mean, now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He now aims the gun point-blank at Adele.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Then this must be Adele...</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put it down or I'll shoot.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wouldn't shoot me, would you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want to bet?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could walk out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chino doesn't move. Keeps his gun on Adele. Karen starts walking towards him...</context>
      <utterance>If you move, if you look at her again, you're dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can live or die, it's up to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, is that right? You going to shoot me? Nice girl like you?  I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that, she kicks him in the knee. Chino buckles over and she hits him on the side of the head with her gun...</context>
      <utterance>You don't, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He does as he's told. Karen raises his jacket, feels around his waist from behind.</context>
      <utterance>On your knees.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lie face down on the floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kicks him over onto his stomach and stays there. She puts her foot to his back as she reaches for the phone, dials. She sees Adele staring at her.</context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Karen looks at Adele a moment, then says into the phone...</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me...</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Daniel Burdon, please. Karen Sisco.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, Adele?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do the sawing of the box in half trick with you inside?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adele looks at Karen, who shoves Chino's head to the floor with her foot.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me, how do you do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Karen. Where are you? I been trying to get a hold of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Daniel. Listen --</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you? I been trying to reach you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm at Adele Delisi's.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What-- we already talked to her. That's a dead end.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Why were you trying to reach me?</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I know. I was just leaving.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was a Buddy Bragg at Lompoc around the same time Foley was there. We got an address for him at the Adams Hotel in Hallandale. I want you to go there, see if you can get the manager to i.d. him as the other guy. If he does, you call me right away...</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But don't you</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now. What is it you wanted to tell me?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I was just wondering, if I were to bring in Chirino, would you put me on the task force?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Is that what you're calling me about?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes or no, Daniel. If I get him, will you let me go after Foley?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, sure, Karen. You bring in Chirino, you can be on the task force.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all I wanted to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE</mode>
      <context>Karen hangs up, looks at Adele. Adele nods.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Now forget about the ex-wife and get over to the Adams Hotel.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're good.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First thing we do, we get to Detroit, we find Glenn, then we find a window to throw him out of.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I been thinkin', if I was Glenn, I was up there to take down the Ripper, where would I go?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, first off, if you were Glenn, you wouldn't be thinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember Snoopy Miller, his old pal from Lompoc?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Snoopy. Christ, I thought he'd be brain dead by now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He isn't fighting no more. Glenn told me the Snoop's been managing some guys up there now, works out at the Kronk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You get the key?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands it to him as they wait for the elevator.</context>
      <utterance>They're in 7D.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burdon, Karen and the remaining four SWAT team agents. Burden looks at them one at a time.</context>
      <utterance>I want two men outside, front and back. Conway and Jessup go on up to seven, cover both ends of the hall.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're primary, you're secondary, you're point man.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gonna use a ram?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, why?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all look at her.</context>
      <utterance>The manager's door is metal.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Burdon looks at her, not all that happy she spoke up. The fourth man raises the shotgun, a three-inch strip of metal taped to the muzzle.</context>
      <utterance>You know what I mean? They might all be. And a ram on a metal door makes an awful lot of noise for what good it does.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOURTH MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got a shock-lock round in my shotgun oughta do the trick.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sees the elevator still hasn't come down.</context>
      <utterance>Fine. Whatever.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Burdon pauses, looks at Karen, hands her a radio.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck it. Let's take the stairs. Karen...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take the radio, stay down here in the lobby, watch the elevator.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Daniel, I wanna go upstairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She doesn't say anything.</context>
      <utterance>You can go wait out in the car, you want to.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you see Foley and this guy Bragg come in behind us, whatta you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call and tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before she can answer, an old woman steps in, asks Burdon...</context>
      <utterance>And you let them come up. You don't try to make the bust yourself. You understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burdon looks at her, then nods for his men to start up the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Are you delivering the oxygen?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this your floor, mother?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Yes, it is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OLD GENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like to play some gin?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He creeps off towards the elevator.</context>
      <utterance>No, thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode>RADIO</mode>
      <context>Karen looks off towards the street entrance, then back at the elevator where the man is still waiting, leaning on his cane. The elevator door opens to reveal Buddy and Foley.</context>
      <utterance>Karen. They're not up here. Keep your eyes open.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD GENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buddy and Foley don't answer. The old man starts to get on, feeling with his cane, taking forever. Karen and Foley are staring at each other. He doesn't move. Not until the elevator door begins to close. Buddy sees Karen, helps the old man aboard as... Karen picks up her radio, is about to speak into it when... Foley raises his hand. And</context>
      <utterance>Going up?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD GENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit, I wanted to go up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's just hope there's no one in the garage.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She looked right at me. She didn't yell or get excited. She didn't move.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They know where I live, I guess they know what I drive, so maybe we should pick up another car on the way.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buddy gives him a look, shakes his head and then burns rubber out of the garage as we...</context>
      <utterance>She just sat there, looking right at me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURDON</speaker>
      <mode>ON THE RADIO</mode>
      <context>Karen? You there? Karen...?</context>
      <utterance>Karen. Report. You see anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He waved to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I couldn't swear to it, but I'm pretty sure he did.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wave back?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't have time.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>I imagine you would've though.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buddy's sister Regina Mary Bragg got two calls from Buddy up in Detroit this morning, called Burdon. She's also the one gave Burdon Buddy's address.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what I want to know is why Buddy still calls his sister every week even after she turned him in.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He doesn't seem to hold a grudge.  What</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll call soon as I get in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Glenn just nods, stares out the window.</context>
      <utterance>I've diversified since the last time you saw me. I've vertically integrated and now I'm into home invasions and the occasional grand larceny.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Maurice indicates WHITE BOY BOB, a fucking huge, depraved- looking white guy now squeezed in behind the wheel.</context>
      <utterance>White Boy Bob's my all-around man, my bodyguard when I feel I need one, and my driver.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watch the road, boy.  I like this Town Car. We can cruise the man's neighbourhood without getting the police or private security people on our ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, right, they see Bigfoot driving around a black guy wearing shades and a lavender fucking bandanna, no, they won't think anything of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The car creeps past a huge Tudor-style country house.</context>
      <utterance>It's lilac, man, the color, and the style's made known by Deion and other defensive backs in the pros. I could be one of them living out here with doctors of my race and basketball players. Okay, here comes Mr. Ripley's house up on the left. Yeah. The brick wall. There's his drive, right there.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure Foley and his pal aren't coming up here, do this themself?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If they're not busted now, they're gonna be.  It's wide open.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="49">
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you still haven't said, how you wanna do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll show you, soon as I get one more guy I'm gonna need, Moselle's brother, Kenneth. Along with White Boy there.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The car pulls to the kerb and KENNETH -- a wiry black man in a bright yellow T-shirt and red baseball cap backward, always seems to be high on some chemical or another - gets in.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kenneth tosses a gym bag into the back seat. Glenn stares at it. Something about the bag makes him uneasy. Maybe it's the HACKSAW that sticks partially out of the opening.</context>
      <utterance>You get everything?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cool. Kenneth, this is the man I told you about, Glenn.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The one gonna help us rip off the rich guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Help</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thing I'm worried about is you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. If you can step up and actually do it. Understand? 'Stead of just talking the talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I do what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Walk in a house with me, do this cross- dressin' nigga named Eddie Solomon I used to sell to been dealin' on his own.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What-- when?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right now, son.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Ripley job is</context>
      <utterance>I don't have to prove shit to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you're forgetting, this is my car. I drove it up here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, shit, come on. I say I want this car, man, it's mine. You go get yourself another one. I say I'm in on Ripley? I'm in, with or without</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Glenn hesitates, then slowly gets out of the car as we hear...</context>
      <utterance>Let's go see Eddie.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Must take balls, do what you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me something. What's it like, walk in a bank with a gun, stick it up?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I never used a gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd be surprised what all you can get, you ask for it the right way.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the reason, Jack, I don't keep all my money in banks.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No? Where do you keep it, Dick?  I'm talking about all those uncut diamonds you told Glenn about.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know what you're talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the one with balls, Dick, say something like that to someone like Glenn. Or maybe you just forgot where you were for a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I mean, do</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but who's gonna believe Glenn?</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Plus, even it was true, he'd still have to figure out where I keep 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't have to figure out shit. You</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me something, Jack, how much longer you in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty-two months, three days, two hours. Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley looks at Ripley.</context>
      <utterance>I was just thinking that I could use a guy like you, someone knows how to ask for things the right way. I'm talkin' about when you're outta here. I mean, you can't rob banks for ever.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a little late for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Jack? Bullshit. I didn't make my first million until I was forty- two. Forty-two. You really</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is? But then you gotta look at a job as more than just work. You gotta look at it as peace of mind. As</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No need to decide now. Be like the fish. Let whatever happens happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The fish?</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They just do it. They accept.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, fish live in the present. They don't dwell on yesterday and they don't worry about tomorrow. Even when a big fish attacks a little fish, there's no neurosis involved. No guilt afterward. No whining on some fish-shrink's couch.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't say that I've paid that much attention to 'em before.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The fish saved my life. Two years ago, I found out I had high blood pressure. So my doctor, he tells me to go get an aquarium, look at the fish every time I felt myself stressing out.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the guy sent you a bill for this?</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It works. You should try it sometime.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ripley shakes his head, then gets up...</context>
      <utterance>The next time I walk into a bank.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley watches him go.</context>
      <utterance>Think about my offer, Jack.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Jack...</utterance>
   <speaker>CUT TO: CLOSE UP OF FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As he turns to us.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buddy reads from a newspaper while Foley watches the gym.</context>
      <utterance>You see this one...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Fight over tuna casserole may have spurred slaying." Seems this woman's live-in boyfriend, seventy years old, complained about her tuna noodle casserole and she shot him in the face with a twelve-gauge. Police found noodles in the woman's hair and think the guy dumped the casserole dish on her before she shot him. They'd been together ten years.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buddy looks at him. Notices something over Foley's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Love is funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now Foley turns and looks over as the black Town Car pulls into the Kronk parking lot.</context>
      <utterance>Hey--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice looks at Glenn now and grins.</context>
      <utterance>Was a time you see a gold Mercedes over in the parking lot has a license plate on it say HITMAN? You know Tommy Hearns is inside. Seeing the car would get our juices flowing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Glenn just looks at Maurice.</context>
      <utterance>You already got your juices flowing, huh? Pissed your pants back there at Eddie's house, didn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was some shit, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why'd he have to do that to that girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Kenneth, why you have to do that to that poor girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Glenn says nothing, just looks at Kenneth.</context>
      <utterance>Do what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he and Whiteboy start laughing as they get out of the car.</context>
      <utterance>Just wait till we get inside Ripley's house.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all right with you, I'll just hang in the car.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You gonna stay close to me from now on. So you don't disappear on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice looks at him, starts laughing. White Boy Bob and Kenneth join in. Maurice leans over... Glenn flinches as Maurice opens Glenn's jacket so that we can see the BLOOD splattered on his T- shirt.</context>
      <utterance>Why would I do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was worse than you imagined, wasn't it?  Baby, you with the bad boys now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatta you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think Glenn opened his big mouth and now we got us another partner.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or two.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="36">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stick and jab!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up, sees Buddy and Foley coming this way.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Studs, how you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They sit down on either side of him, close.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ, what're you guys doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Weren't you expecting us?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now he turns to Buddy as Buddy stands up, takes off his overcoat and sits down again.</context>
      <utterance>That broad you picked up -- did you know she was a US Marshal, for Christ sake?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to your shades? Someone finally step on 'em?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley notices the blood on Glenn's shirt.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know...</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whose blood you got all over you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley follows his gaze, sees Maurice coming this way, White Boy Bob beside him, carrying his shirts.</context>
      <utterance>These guys, man, they're crazy.  Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that Snoopy? In the purple doo rag?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice stands at the edge of the ring apron, looks from Foley to Buddy and back again, pretty serious about it.</context>
      <utterance>What's he do now, tell fortunes?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE BOY BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have a problem here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack Foley, famous bank robber.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Snoopy Miller, famous fight thrower.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It seems to me I been reading about you in the newspaper. Busted out of some joint in Florida, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Low class of people there, Snoop.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE BOY BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You call him that again I'll put your head through the wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? You mean Snoop?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody calls me Snoop no more or Snoopy, is what White Boy's trying to say. He's a little crude, you understand. No, I left that Snoopy shit behind me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you call this bozo White Boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>White Boy Bob.  White Boy used to be a fighter.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White Boy Bob stares down Buddy who couldn't give a shit.</context>
      <utterance>What's he do now outside of shoot his mouth off?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like being back in the yard, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just like it. Nobody backing down. You back down, you pussy. Tell me what you and Buddy doing up here in the cold?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Glenn didn't tell you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you guys were busted.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley looks at Glenn. Glenn shrugs, laughs nervously. Foley smiles, laughs with him, maybe a little too hard. Now Maurice starts laughing. Buddy, too. White Boy's lost, looking from one guy to the next as Foley gets up, faces Maurice, his smile going away as he says...</context>
      <utterance>Why? Just because you left us standing on the side of the road?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Snoop, I don't know what Glenn promised you or what you think you're gonna get, but the deal is me and Buddy get half of whatever we take from Ripley, understand? How you and Glenn cut up the rest is up to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go outside and talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's nice and warm.</context>
      <utterance>What's the matter with right here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley nods then looks at Glenn as Buddy gets up.</context>
      <utterance>Warm? Man, it's ninety-five degrees in here, sometimes a hundred -- the way Emanuel always kep' it so his boys'd sweat, get lean and mean like Tommy Hearns. No, I ain't talking any business in here. To me this is holy ground, man. You understand? I got to be someplace anyway. Y'all want to talk, come to the fights tomorrow night, we'll sit down and look at it good. The State Theater.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice then watches as they walk out.</context>
      <utterance>We'll see you tomorrow then.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>White Boy, how much is the reward on the man again?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE BOY BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten gees.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.  You recall, did it say dead or alive?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm looking for Ray Cruz.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karen ducks under the tape and starts up the walk. She pauses to watch as two CORONER'S ASSISTANTS cover with a sheet a DEAD BLACK WOMAN who lies just below a broken upstairs window.</context>
      <utterance>He's inside.  With everybody else.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karen looks over as RAYMOND CRUZ, a stocky, genial-looking detective comes out of the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Called themselves the Youngboys.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ironic, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you, Raymond?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her on the cheek. She indicates the body by the door.</context>
      <utterance>Freezing. But I'm getting warmer.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quite a mess.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. And I thought everyone liked Eddie.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dude in the dress is Eddie Solomon, used to buy scag off a corner till he kicked it and found his happiness with crack and then started dealing himself. Word on the street was he was saving up for an operation.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it with crack and transsexuals?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Eddie was a real character. Had these girls cooked the rocks he called the Rockettes.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I saw one of 'em outside.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This shuts them both up. Cruz indicates the door.</context>
      <utterance>Yonelle. Looks like someone raped her, shot her, then threw her out the window.  Fuckin' animals.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She starts to follow him out, pauses as she sees something on the ground...</context>
      <utterance>Let's get some air.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Other than we had so much fun the last time we worked together. You gonna tell me why you're comin' to me instead of the FBI?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I report to the FBI, first thing they're gonna do is ask me to go get some coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I'm not in homicide any more.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I didn't know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'm crimes against persons and property now, also sex crimes and child abuse.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Detroit, you must be pretty busy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, and, as you can see, home invasions are big, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Raymond, a year ago, DEA had this guy Glenn Michaels on possession with intent but couldn't make it stick. In his statement, Glenn said he went up to Detroit to visit a friend and look into job opportunities -- if you can believe that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who was the friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guy named Maurice Miller, also known as Snoopy, a former prizefighter.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ, I know Snoopy Miller. He's a fuckin' wackjob thinks he's Sugar Ray Leonard. Hangs out with a couple other Grade-A nutcases over on the West side.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll need a last known address.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's fine, but I don't want you to talk to Miller alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Raymond, I'm a federal officer, I'm armed. He turns and looks at her.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he gets into his car, we then:</context>
      <utterance>Yes, you are. I'll call you tomorrow with the address.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a terrific shot of her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Outside of that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't say what she's doing up here, but I don't think it has anything to do with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley reaches in one of the bags from the Jewish Recycling Center and pulls out a tie.</context>
      <utterance>She came up here on her vacation, 'cause she likes shitty weather.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think she's after Glenn. The girl still with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't stay the night, Jack, 'less you pay for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You tell your sister about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just hung up.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long you talk to her?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long were you with the girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forty-five minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't tell your sister about Ripley, did you? 'Cause I don't wanna go through that again.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget about my sister. If Karen Sisco's tailing Glenn, we're fucked. Tomorrow night at the fights we all get picked up.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley hangs up. He faces the mirror, starts to tie his tie.</context>
      <utterance>Let's drive by where we're meeting and have a look. Maybe take a look at Ripley's place while we're at it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess next time I see you, you'll be wearing a suit and tie...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still haven't made up my mind yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's to think about?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You goin' right back to work?</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tears a picture off the wall...</context>
      <utterance>First, I'm goin' to Israel for a year, study the Talmud, work on a Kibbutz... then come back, maybe take some tennis lessons.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Foley stares at the photograph of sea life.</context>
      <utterance>Here...  Something to remember me by.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Foley looks at Ripley, who extends his hand.</context>
      <utterance>It's not the real thing, but it's still nice to look at.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See you on the outside, Jack.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Atheneum Hotel.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Karen Sisco, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, but there's no one by that name registered.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He dials the next number...</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Best Western...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="52">
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Moselle Miller?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm looking for Maurice.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You find him, tell him the dog got run over and I'm out of grocery money.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Moselle. Who you talking to?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lady looking for Maurice.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's she want?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hasn't said.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not Maurice?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Kenneth, my brother. He's talking on the phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ask what she want with him?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ask her. Maurice's business is none of</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karen walks into the living room, where Moselle sits on the sofa lighting a cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>The State, huh. Who's fighting?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like to sit down?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karen takes a chair and looks around the room: dismal, gray daylight in the windows, dark wood and white stucco, the fireplace full of trash, plastic cups, wrappers, a pizza box.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm looking for a friend of mine I think Maurice knows.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You not with probation, one of those?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You a lawyer?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Moselle draws on her cigarette, blows out a stream of smoke.</context>
      <utterance>No, I'm not. Maybe you know him. Glenn Michaels?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Glenn? No, I don't know any Glenn.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said he stayed here last November.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here? In this house?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said he stayed with Maurice.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well,</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got run over by a car.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Moselle looks at the couch, where a MANGLED FRISBEE sits.</context>
      <utterance>What did you call it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was a she, name Tuffy.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do you think I might find Maurice?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I</context>
      <utterance>I don't know -- the gym, the fights.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karen turns, sees Kenneth standing in the arched entrance from the foyer.</context>
      <utterance>What you want with Maurice?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She looking for a man name of Glenn.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He waits until Moselle gets up, not saying a word, walks away from them through the dining room. Karen watches him come toward her now in kind of an easy strut. She indicates the scar over his eye...</context>
      <utterance>Did I ask you? Go on out of here. Do something with yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a fighter?</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can tell.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd you fight, middleweight?</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Light to super-middleweight, as my body developed. You go about what, bantam?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Flyweight.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know your divisions. You like the fights? Like the rough stuff? Yeah, I bet you do.  Like to get down and tussle a little bit? Like me and Tuffy, before she got run over, we use to get down on the floor and tussle. I say to her, "You a good dog, Tuffy, here's a treat for you." And I give Tuffy what every dog love best. You know what that is? A bone.  I can give you a bone, too, girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not my type.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't matter. I let the monster out, you gonna do what it wants.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a minute. Her hand goes into her bag next to the chair.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her hand comes out of the bag holding what looks like the grip on a golf club. Kenneth grins at her...</context>
      <utterance>Bring your own rubbers with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNETHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Karen pushes out of the chair to stand with him face-to-face.</context>
      <utterance>What else you have in there, mace? Have a whistle, different kinds of female-protection shit?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives him a friendly poke with the black vinyl baton that's like a golf club grip.</context>
      <utterance>I have to go, Kenneth.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She steps aside and brushes past him. He grabs her left wrist...</context>
      <utterance>Maybe we'll see each other again, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karen flicks the baton and sixteen inches of chrome steel shoots out of the grip. She pulls an arm's length away from him and chops the rigid shaft at his head, Kenneth hunching, ducking away...</context>
      <utterance>We gonna tussle first.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she walks out. She sees Moselle standing there in the foyer. Karen looks at her a moment, puts the baton in her purse and comes out with a business card.</context>
      <utterance>You wanted to tussle, we tussled.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Moselle slips the card into the pocket of her robe. Karen smiles at her and walks out the door.</context>
      <utterance>I wrote my hotel number on there -- in case you run into Glenn.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now that's a really big house.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, look at that wall. Place almost looks like a prison.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No doubt the man's got some big-ass security system.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Go in the easy way.</context>
      <utterance>Time comes, we knock on the door. See if he wants to talk about old times.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? You think he'll let us in, we got Snoopy and the muscle-bound asshole with us?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who says anybody's gonna be with us? I say we go to the fights tomorrow, find out what the Snoop's big plan is, then go in ahead of those guys --</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me something, Buddy. You know anyone who's actually done one last big score and gone to live the good life? Cause it occurred to me that everyone</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, they don't know for sure he's dead.  Look, there's always a chance we'll walk out've there with nothing. I say let fate decide.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let fate decide? What're you, the fuckin' Dali Lama now?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My sister believes in fate, but not hell. That's why she stopped praying for the lost souls since you don't hear that much about purgatory anymore. But every day she asks her boss to pray I don't fuck up. Whatta you think, you think there's a hell, Jack?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it's called Glades Correctional Institution and I'm sure as shit not going back there or any place like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>You might not have a choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They put a gun on you, you'll go back.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley turns back to the house. And now we hear...</context>
      <utterance>They put a gun on you, you still have a choice, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. HEARN</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you're gonna fit right in...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>MR. HEARN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now Mr Ripley and I have had a long discussion about your role in the company and it was his feeling that you would be happiest working down here in Miami. How's that sound to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Hearn pauses, looks down at Foley...</context>
      <utterance>Great.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. HEARN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're about a 42 long, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Mr. Hearn walks out without answering. Foley looks at the desktop, where a spoon sticks out of a half-eaten fruit-on-the- bottom yogurt, which in turn sits beside a half-eaten Powerbar. Foley shakes his head, takes out his zippo, starts to play with it.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. HEARN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley turns as Mr. Hearn bounces back into the room with what looks like a UNIFORM draped over one arm.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Let's see how she fits.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. HEARN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your uniform.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Hearn shows him the yellow patch that reads SECURITY on one arm. Foley smiles... amused... angry... hurt...</context>
      <utterance>My what?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding me?</utterance>
   <speaker>RICHARD RIPLEY'S OFFICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>View. Wet bar. Huge fucking aquarium.</utterance>
   <speaker>RECEPTIONIST</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context>Ripley looks up from his desk as Foley steps in, the receptionist right behind him now.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, you can't go in there...</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meanwhile, Ripley pushes a PANIC BUTTON beneath his desk...</context>
      <utterance>Jack? Whoa-- what's the problem? Take it easy, let's talk...</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ripley considers Foley a moment, then...</context>
      <utterance>A security guard? Are you fucking kidding me?</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley says nothing.</context>
      <utterance>You know, I wasn't sure you'd show up. But I was pretty sure that, if you did, you'd throw the job in my face.  Understand something, Jack. Up to this point, everything you've done with your life means absolutely nothing in the real world. Less than nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a bank robber. This is not a marketable skill. There are no old bank robbers out in the world living on pensions. You know this. That's why you're here right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still Foley says nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Today, I'm offering you a lousy job at a lousy wage. You think you're better than that? Fine. Show me. Show me that you're really willing to change and we'll talk about something better. A lot better. But first, Jack, you gotta earn it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How, Dick? The way</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, what job he promise</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? What are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen. I think we've calmed down now. Haven't we, Jack?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that he picks up a paperweight (A LEAD FISH) and wings it at the aquarium, shattering the glass.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah, I'm calm. In fact, I'm totally "relaxed..."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, I gotta get some better shoes, few other things before tomorrow. Why don't you drop me off at the Ren Cen, we'll hook up later?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, and I better call my sister.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="49">
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns, sees her reflection in the glass against the overcast sky, snow swirling, blowing in gusts, seven hundred feet above the city, down there somewhere.</context>
      <utterance>Jack Daniel's, please, water on the side.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE GUY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to see them raising snifter glasses to her, smiling, pleasant-looking guys in dark suits.</context>
      <utterance>Celeste, do us again, please, and put the lady's drink on our bill.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They want to buy you a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She then watches the three guys looking at the waitress delivering the message. Then they look at Karen. She gives them a shrug, turns to watch the snow. Her drink arrives. She takes a sip, looks up as one of the guys comes over...</context>
      <utterance>I get that. Tell them I'd rather pay for my own.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances at the table, the other two watching.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me. My associates and I made a bet on what you do for a living.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE GUY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I won. Hi, I'm Philip.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it's okay with you, Philip, I'd like to just have a quiet drink and leave. Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>How I know what you do for a living?</context>
      <utterance>Don't you want to know what I guessed?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns back to the snowstorm. She sees his reflection turn and leave. A moment later, the next one appears at the table.</context>
      <utterance>Tell you the truth, I'm not even mildly curious. Really, I don't want to be rude, Philip, I'd just like to be left alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE GUY #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She just looks at him. So sure of himself.</context>
      <utterance>I think I know why you're depressed -- if I may offer an observation.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXECUTIVE GUY #2</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She says nothing to him.</context>
      <utterance>I have a hunch you're the new sales rep and your customer isn't exactly knocked out by the idea of a young lady, even one as stunning as you, handling the account. Am I close? Hi, I'm Andy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're ad guys. We flew in from New York this morning to pitch Hiram Walker Distillery, present this test-market campaign for their new margarita mix. What we do, we show this guy who looks like a Mexican bandido, you know, with the big Chihuahua hat, the bullet belts--</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives her a sympathetic expression.</context>
      <utterance>Andy? Really. Who gives a shit?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want to tell me what happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares at the guy until he turns away. She sips her drink, stares once more out at the blizzard. After a few moments, another dark suit appears, reflected in the window.</context>
      <utterance>Beat it, will you?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Boom. Not one of the executive guys. She stares at the reflection for a moment, then slowly turns, looks up at JACK FOLEY now standing there in his new navy blue suit.</context>
      <utterance>Can I buy you a drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls the chair out, looking at her. The three guys at the other table now staring as he sits down. Foley offers his hand...</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'd love one.  Would you like to sit down?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hesitates, then shakes his hand...</context>
      <utterance>I'm Gary.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles with him. When she lowers her hand to the table, his hand comes down to cover hers. She watches his expression as she brings her hand out slowly, his eyes not leaving hers, and lays her hand on his. The tips of her fingers brush his knuckles, lightly back and forth.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Celeste.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It takes hours to get a drink around here. There's only one waitress.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can go to the bar.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't leave me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those guys bother you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She picks up her drink and places it in front of him.</context>
      <utterance>No, they're all right. I meant, you just got here.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She watches him take a sip, smack his lips.</context>
      <utterance>Help yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like bourbon?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Love it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we got that out of the way.  Tell me, Celeste. What do you do for a living?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a sales rep. I came here to call on a customer and they gave me a hard time because I'm a girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that how you think of yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, as a sales rep?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have a problem with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like your hair. And that suit.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had one just like it -- well, it was the same idea, but I had to get rid of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It smelled.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Having it cleaned didn't help, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.  What do you do for a living, Gary?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This stops her, throws her off balance.</context>
      <utterance>How far do we go with this?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet. Don't say anything yet. Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think it works if we're somebody else. You know what I mean? Gary and Celeste, Jesus, what do they know about anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's your game. I've never played this before.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not a game. Something you play.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, does it make sense to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't have to, it's something that happens. It's like seeing a person you never saw before -- you could be passing on the street -- you look at each other and for a few seconds, there's a kind of recognition. Like you both know something. But then the next moment the person's gone, and it's too late to do anything about it, but you remember it because it was right there and you let it go, and you think, "What if I had stopped and said something?" It might happen only a few times in your life.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at each other a moment, then...</context>
      <utterance>Or once.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both get up. The ad guys at the table watch as she follows Foley to the elevator. Karen winks at them.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't we get out of here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="39">
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He comes over to her, takes out the newspaper clipping with her picture and shows it to her.</context>
      <utterance>How'd you find me?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, God...</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I called your room from downstairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I had answered, what were you gonna say?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'd say who I was and do you remember me and ask if you'd like to meet for a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I remembered you. I came looking for you. I would've said sure, let's do it. But for all you knew I could show up with a SWAT team. Why would you trust me?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him, touches his face with her hand...</context>
      <utterance>It would be worth the risk.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like taking risks.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her now, puts his arms around her.</context>
      <utterance>So do you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands him his drink. They both drink, then...</context>
      <utterance>What's the hurry, Jack? You have to be somewhere?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She stops and he looks at her over the rim of her glass.</context>
      <utterance>Sooner or later...</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really wear that suit.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shrugs, lets it go. He puts down his drink, kisses her. She lets him, then moves to the couch.</context>
      <utterance>That's not what you were about to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember how talkative you were? In the trunk? Adele said you do that when you're nervous.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She did, huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You kept touching me, feeling my thigh.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sits down and they kiss again. This time she peels his jacket off. He does the same with hers. He's starting to unbutton her blouse when--</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but in a nice way.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I might've smelled like a sewer, but you could tell I was a gentleman. They say John Dillinger was a pretty nice guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops. Looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>He killed a police officer.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hear he didn't mean to. The cop fell as Dillinger was aiming at his leg and got him through the heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You believe that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him, decides to get off this subject. Anyway he's finished unbuttoning her blouse and is now putting his hands inside her shirt. She closes her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he kisses her on the neck.</context>
      <utterance>You know that Sig .380 you took was my favourite. My father gave it to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What were you gonna do with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I hadn't worked that part out yet. All I knew was that I liked you, and I didn't want to leave you there, never see you again.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's loosening his tie, unbuttoning his shirt.</context>
      <utterance>You waved to me in the elevator.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wasn't sure you caught that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I couldn't believe it. I was thinking of you by then, a lot, wondering what it would be like if we did meet. Like if we could take a time-out...</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at each other a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Really? I was thinking the same thing. If we could call time and get together for a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know I saw you on the street.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to kiss her again, but--</context>
      <utterance>Outside Adele's.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were going to see her?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To warn her about Chino.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So she did help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think we should get into that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you're right. Or Buddy. I won't ask if he's with you or what you're doing here in Detroit. Or if you've run into Glenn Michaels yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he moves to kiss her, but she stands up, holds out her hand.</context>
      <utterance>Don't talk like that, okay? You scare me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets up and she leads him across the room...</context>
      <utterance>Come on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her, down to her bra and panties, watches as she gets out of the rest of her clothes and comes over to him, standing close to help him with the tie...</context>
      <utterance>Are you gonna leave your tie on?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When her clothes are off, she loops the tie around his neck again and then as she turns off the light... She kisses him. He sits down on the bed, drawing her back with him, the only light now coming from the sitting room.</context>
      <utterance>My God, look at you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She smiles and then they start to make love as we then...</context>
      <utterance>You having fun?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You coming back?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets up and crosses the room to the bathroom and closes the door. Foley picks up his Zippo off the night table.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just going to the bathroom.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to know something. I wasn't looking for just a fuck, if that's what you're thinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you mad?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or I did it for some kind of kinky thrill. Score with a bank robber the way some women go for rough trade.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know of a guy he goes in the bank holding a bottle he says is nitroglycerin. He scores some cash off a teller, he's on his way out when he drops the bottle. It shatters on the tile floor, he slips in the stuff, cracks his head and they've got him. The nitro was canola oil. I know more fucked-up bank robbers than ones that know what they're doing. I doubt one in ten can tell a dye pack when he sees one. Most bank robbers are fucking morons. To go to bed with a bank robber for kinky thrills, as you say, you'd have to be as dumb as they are. I know you're not dumb, so why would I think that? Why would</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They lie there for a few moments, Karen watching him. He senses this, looks at her...</context>
      <utterance>I don't know about that. You can't do three falls and think you have much of a brain.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You getting serious on me now?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm trying not to. I just wanna know what's gonna happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he kisses her.</context>
      <utterance>You know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It took you, what, seven hours to buy a pair of shoes?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buddy turns to him.</context>
      <utterance>I saw Karen Sisco.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And she saw you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, she did.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how's that work, a wanted felon socializing with a U.S. Marshal?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know how I felt about her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you give her a jump? If you did I might begin to understand where your head's at.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wasn't about getting laid. I just wanted to know what might've happened if things were different.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You find out?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buddy watches Foley pour a shot of Jim Beam in his coffee.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's that mean? That you're disappointed by what you found or you're sorry you robbed all those banks?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White Boy Bob throws down a beer and gives Glenn's shoulder a jab.</context>
      <utterance>Stick and jab, stick and jab!</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE BOY BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White Boy looks around to see if there are any other morons sitting nearby who think it's funny. Kenneth comes through for his pal and laughs.</context>
      <utterance>You drink like a girl.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hesitates, sees the car keys on the table in front of White Boy Bob. But before he can grab them...</context>
      <utterance>I got to go take a piss.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE BOY BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Glenn gets up, sees his coat on the back of the chair, but knows he can't take it with him. He walks away from the table.</context>
      <utterance>What're you telling us for? You want somebody to hold your little pecker?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Glenn, are you trying to steal this car?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, I don't believe it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He raises his empty hands.</context>
      <utterance>Another one of those days, huh, nothing seems to go right?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have the keys.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see that.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean I'm not stealing the fucking car.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I already stole it. Last week or whenever it was, in West Palm. I can't be stealing it again, can I?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The two guys you were with -- that one, that isn't Maurice Miller, is it? I've seen Snoopy's mug shot and that didn't look like him.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karen looks at him, shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus. How'd you know about Snoopy?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Glenn, I know your life history, who your friends are, where you've been and now, it looks like, where you're going. Put your hands on the wheel.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gonna bust me for picking up a car?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For the car, for aiding and abetting a prison escape, and conspiring to do whatever you came here for.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're fucking animals.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, these guys, they're gonna be out here any minute looking for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on, Glenn?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing. I just wanna get the fuck outta here.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I thought the whole thing was your idea?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rippin' off Ripley was my idea, but these guys, man, they're into shit I can't handle.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ripley? You mean the wall street guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, the plan was to pick him up at his office tomorrow, take him out to his house in Bloomfield Hills. Now, I don't give a shit what they do.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And is Foley a part of this?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's supposed to be, but he hasn't shown up yet, which is a good thing for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maurice is gonna kill him, try and collect the reward.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you say he hasn't shown up, you think he backed out?</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know-- he doesn't exactly confide in me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gee, I wonder why not.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm freezing my ass off.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to get out of here, run, it'll warm you up.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But listen, Glenn. If you're lying to me...</utterance>
   <speaker>GLENN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, you'll find me. Jesus, I believe it. I keep thinking if you hadn't driven me to federal court last summer, you wouldn't even know who I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he takes off. She sits there another moment, then flicks her cigarette out the door, gets out the car.</context>
      <utterance>If I didn't know you, Glenn, by tomorrow you'd be in jail or dead. Look at it that way. Go on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley and Buddy remain standing.</context>
      <utterance>Where you been? You miss the big boys, come in time for the walkout fights. Well, shit, you may as well pull up a chair.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Foley nods to the raincoat draped over the back of a chair.</context>
      <utterance>Kenneth, this is Mr. Jack Foley and this is Mr. Buddy, famous bank robbers.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's sitting here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley gives Buddy a look. White Boy Bob grins at them.</context>
      <utterance>Your homie, Glenn. Only thing, he went to the men's about a while ago and never came back.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE BOY BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think he must've fell in.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I sent these two looking for him, they come back shaking their heads.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if he left his coat and he's been gone a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE BOY BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The car's still there. I looked.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reggie, push off and hit, man. Push him off.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're leaving.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The fuck you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice takes Foley by the arm, moves him away from the table.</context>
      <utterance>Snoop, if you don't know where Glenn is...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, what you worried about Glenn for? What's he know?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley watches the fighters: one of them patient, moving in while the other one takes wild swings and misses...</context>
      <utterance>I thought everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Glenn knows everything we suppose to do</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me a minute, talk to Buddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got two minutes, that's all. Make up your mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley walks up to the bar with Buddy.</context>
      <utterance>I wasn't asking permission.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They want to go tonight, before Glenn gets in any trouble, opens his big mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley takes out his lighter, begins playing with it.</context>
      <utterance>Whatta you wanna do?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know they gonna set us up.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I get that feeling, yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley looks at him a moment, then...</context>
      <utterance>But you still think you can get the diamonds fore they do?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll make you a deal. Get out of here. Right now. I'll do the job with the Snoop, meet you wherever you want and give you half.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Half for doing what?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Getting me out of Glades for starters.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And who watches your back?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That what they're wearing these days to break and enter?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Break and enter, shit. Take it and git, how it's done. Don't waste any time. That's how you do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you've done this before, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit, yeah. White Boy even got busted for it.  White Boy, tell these boys the reason you went down on that burglary that time.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE BOY BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guy grins at them. Foley can't believe it.</context>
      <utterance>I left my wallet in the house I robbed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Takes the TV, the VCR, some other shit and leaves his wallet on the floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a wonderful story, Snoop. I'm very excited about tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley and Buddy exchange looks. Maurice turns around, a Beretta in his hand. Foley looks at him. Buddy tenses.</context>
      <utterance>Hey. You learn from doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know how to use one a these?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice hands Foley the Beretta. Then reaches into a bag, comes up with a .38 he hands to Buddy.</context>
      <utterance>I've seen 'em used on TV.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kenneth grins in the mirror, punches it more. Buddy gets out the .38 and touches it to the back of Kenneth's head.</context>
      <utterance>Slow down.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Kenneth, his eyes freaked with speed, glares at Buddy in the mirror.</context>
      <utterance>Get ready to grab the wheel when I shoot this asshole.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do like he says, man. Slow down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"An army .45 will stop all jive." Huey P. said that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice looks at Buddy. Buddy holds his gaze. Then the coach lights on either side of the front entrance come on.</context>
      <utterance>You think he was talking about walking into people's houses when he said it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now the front door opens...</context>
      <utterance>Get ready to go skiing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>We catch a glimpse of a WOMAN in the doorway, arms folded over her bathrobe as White Boy gives her a push and steps inside the house with her. Maurice is out of the truck and Kenneth, with a shotgun, is scrambling to be next. Buddy catches him by his jacket collar and holds him squirming until Foley is out. The minute Kenneth's feet hit the driveway he turns the 12-gauge on Buddy, still in the truck. Foley takes the barrel in one hand and shoves it straight up in Kenneth's face.</context>
      <utterance>Here we go.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kenneth puts his face up close to Foley's and stares at him good before going inside. Foley turns to Buddy...</context>
      <utterance>Go on in the house before you get hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's still time, take me up on my offer.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not leaving you alone with these assholes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kenneth reaches out, opens her robe and we get a flash of flimsy bra and low-cut panties before she slaps him away.</context>
      <utterance>I work here. I'm the maid.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN/MAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck off.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, shit, we're gonna have a party.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet. Where's Mr. Ripley?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you, he isn't here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out for the evening?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's in Florida. Palm Beach.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When's he due back?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ, what difference does it make? You want to wait for him?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christmas to Easter.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Ripley's down for the season.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You here all by yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley catches the hesitation, glances at Buddy.</context>
      <utterance>That's right, just me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Ripley's safe at, he keep his valuables in.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have any idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go upstairs, have a look at the man's bedroom. All right now, you and Mr. Buddy check the rooms down here. Look at the wall behind any pictures hanging on it. Look at the walls in the closets. The man has a safe, it's gonna be up there somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice gives him a look, pulls the maid up the stairs. Kenneth and White Boy Bob follow...</context>
      <utterance>How about his place in Florida? If you'd called, we could've checked his walls down there before we left. That is, if you'd checked to see where he was. You follow me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You set off any kind of alarm and you're a dead Hazel. Understand? Kenneth puts his arm around the maid.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hooks a finger in the waist of her panties, pulls on the elastic, is about to look in there when Maurice backhands him across the face.</context>
      <utterance>What's you name, mama?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alone with Buddy now, Foley rolls his mask up on his head.</context>
      <utterance>First money, then pussy.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever wear one of these?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't ski.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay with the maid. I'm gonna have a look around.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RAYMOND CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll send a unit over there, see if there's anything going on.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me where Ripley's house is. I'll meet them there.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Karen, you gonna promise me you're not gonna go in, do anything stupid till I get there...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WHITE BOY BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey-- Maurice and Kenneth look over expectantly.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE BOY BOB</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I found a rubber.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice looks out the door, sees Buddy in the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>White Boy, the man's not gonna hide no diamonds under the fuckin' mattress.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Foley?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Checkin' the other rooms, like you said.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>White Boy Bob slips out of the room. Maurice turns to Kenneth, who's still playing with the stereo.</context>
      <utterance>Go keep an eye on him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kenneth, fuck the radio, put on a CD.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't recognize none of these bands.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just pick one, put it on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WHITE BOY BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes in the huge room, the massive sub-zero refrigerator. He moves to the freezer, opens it, takes in the FROZEN STEAKS.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, Foley?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE BOY BOB</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cool.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. The door opens and we see a terrified Richard Ripley sitting on top of a toilet, the phone in his lap.</context>
      <utterance>They cut the lines, Richard.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Foley? That you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you, Richard?</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ, what the hell are you doing here? What's going on? Who's upstairs?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maurice Miller, couple of his friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ripley moves to the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>Maurice? From Lompoc? Good God.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have they got Midge up there?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kinda man lets a woman answer the door, this time a night?</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We thought it might be her husband. Sometimes he comes and checks up on her. She told him I was down in Florida.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ripley looks at him. Foley pats the back of a chair.</context>
      <utterance>A minute or two, you're gonna wish you were.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you come on over here, sit down, Richard, have a look at your fish.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do I look, mama?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice smiles at her, goes back into the closet. Kenneth stares at the maid, nodding slowly.</context>
      <utterance>Like a fag.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks to the doorway, where Buddy now starts to take a step into the room, when Maurice comes out of the closet...</context>
      <utterance>I think she like to tussle with me. Get boned a way she gonna remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context>He sticks his head out of the closet.</context>
      <utterance>Motherfucker!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Buddy backs out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>I found the safe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want from me, Jack? Name it. You want money?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gonna write me a check?</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley just looks at him. Buddy sticks his head in the room.</context>
      <utterance>We'll go to my bank. I'll make a withdrawal.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They found the safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You remember Buddy, don't you, Richard?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, hi. Nice house.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice and his boys open fire on the safe. The maid covers up as bullets begin ricocheting all over the room.</context>
      <utterance>We gonna open up this fucker...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus...!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good God... they're shooting Midge!</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Siddown, Dick. They're trying to open the safe, not your maid.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A'ight, this time we gotta get the motherfuckin' trajectory right...  Okay, on three: One... Two...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all turn to look at her, guns still pointing at the safe.</context>
      <utterance>The combination is three-ten-forty-four.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAID</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Richard's birthday.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...the fuck is this...</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE BOY BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at White Boy Bob...</context>
      <utterance>Are they dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go find Foley. NOW!</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe you're still angry with me, Jack, after all this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ripley sags, closes his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not angry, Richard.  In fact, I'm completely relaxed. Thing is, I can't tell if it's the fish that're cooling me out or all those uncut diamonds on the bottom of the tank there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now Buddy takes a closer look and now we, too, see that strewn about the bottom of the aquarium are dozens of uncut diamonds of various sizes.</context>
      <utterance>Damn--</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dumbfuck Glenn was right, there's about five million worth in there, wouldn't you say, Richard?</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five point two.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They look like plain old rocks.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets up, looks at Buddy.</context>
      <utterance>They sure do.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Foley turns to Richard as Buddy comes back into the room with a plastic bag, starts reaching into the tank.</context>
      <utterance>Go get a bag.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I were you, I'd get up and run.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not leaving Midge.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be an asshole, Richard. They're gonna kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley looks at Buddy. Now what?</context>
      <utterance>If that's my fate, so be it. I'm not leaving.  I love her, Jack.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon. Foley just looks at Ripley, who doesn't move.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good luck, Richard.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context>Buddy and Foley slip out the other door, down the hall, just as Maurice walks in, some of Ripley's clothes over his arm.</context>
      <utterance>Someone down here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if it isn't the Ripper hisself.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are those</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buddy straightens up, looks at Foley.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're gonna rape the maid, aren't they.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From the looks of those boys, the Ripper too.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then they'll kill 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley looks at the diamonds in the bag.</context>
      <utterance>At least.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We made it, didn't we?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again Foley looks at the diamonds, then...</context>
      <utterance>All you gotta do is get in.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going back inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley finally hands him the bag with the diamonds in it...</context>
      <utterance>I'll go with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'll take one of Ripley's cars.</context>
      <utterance>No, you dump the van, meet me at the airport.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack --</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buddy just looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, Buddy, the shit that's about to go down, you'll be on the phone with your sister for a month. Let me do this part alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Foley turns to go.</context>
      <utterance>I'm saying this isn't your problem. Far as I'm concerned, we're square.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buddy hands him his gun. Foley takes it, stuffs it in the back of his pants, and then turns back to the house.</context>
      <utterance>Hey...</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now get outta here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Midge.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget about her. Tell me where the money's at.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Foley's got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where the fuck is Foley?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maurice grabs him by the collar, spins him around and whips him across the face with his gun. He and White Boy Bob then both hit Ripley on the head until he goes down and stays down.</context>
      <utterance>Midge!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You take the front stairs, I'll take the back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Dick?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Downstairs.  But wait here. There's two more.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WHITE BOY BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley sees White Boy Bob at the bottom of the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Hold it, asshole!</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE BOY BOB</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Nowhere to go, Foley has to comply.</context>
      <utterance>Drop the gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE BOY BOB</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>White Boy Bob starts to jog up the stairs two at a time, all the while keeping his eyes fixed on Foley.</context>
      <utterance>Now stay right there. Don't move.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE BOY BOB</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maurice! I got Foley!</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITE BOY BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...and a moment later, Karen comes out of the kitchen into the downstairs hallway -- just missing each other.</context>
      <utterance>Maurice! Up here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack, you don't use a gun, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not until recently.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nervous?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAURICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This kind of setup, you don't have any idea what the fuck you're doing -- do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley pulls the trigger. CLICK. Maurice hesitates, surprised that Foley would pull the trigger, then the two of them at the same time rush each other, begin a messy</context>
      <utterance>You're right. So why take a chance--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode>PHONE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're a few minutes away. Just sit tight, stay outta the house till we get there, understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh-kay...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MIDGE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Foley looks to where Midge stands -- now back in her bathrobe, but more importantly, clutching the shotgun. Foley crosses and takes it from her, begins to stride out of the room, when --</context>
      <utterance>This what you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIDGE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Foley just looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>It's empty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context>He sees Midge looking at him, closes his eyes, sags against the wall.</context>
      <utterance>Jack?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode>OS - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you're up there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Jack -- don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretend I'm somebody else.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley brings up the pistol and the shotgun. AND NOW WE HEAR</context>
      <utterance>You think I'd shoot you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you don't, one of those guys will.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you now, a desperado? Put the guns down.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He raises the guns hip-high and we hear sounds behind Karen, but she's quick to raise her hand, though she doesn't turn or look around.</context>
      <utterance>I told you, I'm not going back.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stand there staring at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Don't do this. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He raises the guns. She sadly shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>No more time outs.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She fires and he falls to the staircase, dropping the guns, grabbing hold of his right thigh. And now Cruz and several other cops enter... Karen motions them to stop...</context>
      <utterance>You win, Jack.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Karen, I told you not to--</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes up the staircase to where Foley is lying and gently lifts the ski mask and looks at his sad eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Wait, I know him --okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Jack, but I can't shoot you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just did, for Christ sake.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances about, makes sure no one can hear, then leans closer to him.</context>
      <utterance>You know what I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Foley looks like he's in pain. He watches as she walks back down the stairs. As a couple of uniform cops rush past her and pick up Foley, a shaky Ripley staggers into the foyer.</context>
      <utterance>I wish things were different. I'm sorry, Jack.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She comes running down the stairs into his arms. They embrace. He looks at Foley over her shoulder...</context>
      <utterance>Richard!</utterance>
   <speaker>RIPLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley just looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, Jack...  What'd you do with my diamonds?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't know yet if they want to bring him up on the homicides.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I doubt if they will. The Bureau's put a detainer on him, so when they're through with him here he'll go back to Florida.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gonna go get him?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's possible. Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then throw him in the can.</context>
      <utterance>I was just thinking... you could have a nice time with him on the plane -- like picking up where your interlude, or whatever you call it, left off.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He knew what he was doing. Nobody forced him to rob banks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karen hangs up, stares thoughtfully out the window.</context>
      <utterance>My little girl, the tough babe.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Foley turns around and faces a FEDERAL MARSHAL in the doorway, we see that Foley's hands and feet are shackled.</context>
      <utterance>Foley.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context>He looks to where Karen looks at him through a steel grate that separates the front from the back.</context>
      <utterance>Jack?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pushes A ZIPPO THROUGH the grate.</context>
      <utterance>I got you a present, something for the road.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Before Foley can say anything, the back door is opened once more and the Marshal helps ANOTHER PRISONER -- a black man with a shaved head -- into the back of the van.</context>
      <utterance>I have to take it away, though, soon as the ride's over.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEDERAL MARSHAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An annoyed Foley stares at the guy as the marshal shuts the door then gets in up front with Karen.</context>
      <utterance>Jack Foley meet Hejira Henry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's it mean, "No Hair"?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEJIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Hejira was the flight of Mohammed from Mecca in 622.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The flight?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEJIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The brothers in Leavenworth gave me the name.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were at Leavenworth, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEJIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For a time.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meaning?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEJIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meaning time came, I left.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You busted out?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEJIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I prefer to call it an exodus from an undesirable place.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And how long was it before they caught up with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEJIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That time?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There were others.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEJIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. That was the ninth.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must be some kinda walker, Henry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEJIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hejira.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And so now you're off to Glades.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEJIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Apparently, yeah. I was supposed to leave last night with the lady marshal, but for some reason she wanted to wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She did, huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEJIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cheaper I guess, take us both down in one van.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, could be. Or maybe she thought we'd have a lot to talk about.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEJIRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foley glances at her, then turns back to Heiira Henry and considers the guy; a smile on Foley's face, his spirits a little higher than when he first sat down, as we then...</context>
      <utterance>I don't know.  It's a long way down to Florida.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
