<movie id="428" title="Peeping Tom">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SMALL MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of a Young Man (MARK) sighting a cine-camera. He lowers the camera - and turns politely to his interrogator. He seems to have slight difficulty informing his words.</context>
      <utterance>What paper are you from? The finder is lowered.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I beg your pardon?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMALL MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark smiles at him pleasantly.</context>
      <utterance>What paper are you from?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Ambulance Men come out of the house carrying the stretcher... there is a body on it covered by a sheet. Mark raises his cine-camera and photographs them. He photographs the ambulance as it drives off. He photographs the Policemen dispersing the crowd. He photographs his Interrogator, who gladly poses for him. Then he slings his camera over his shoulder, and strolls away.</context>
      <utterance>The Observer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="37">
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're late!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns towards a small door at the end of the shop.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Peters hesitates, drumming his fingers on the counter. CLOSE SHOT of Mark. He starts to drum his fingers on a shelf.</context>
      <utterance>Hold on, Mark. Mark turns round.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops drumming his fingers. So, at that moment, does Mark.</context>
      <utterance>Mark... I've a question for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which magazines sell the most copies?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those with girls on the front covers - and no front covers on the girls.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Overlaid is the sound of the door opening.</context>
      <utterance>Exactly!... And it's just the same with the work you do for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An ELDERLY GENTLEMAN is standing there.</context>
      <utterance>Look busy. Mark busies himself sorting some newspapers. A whole row of Doras smile up at him. CAMERA PANS to doorway of the shop.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDERLY GENTLEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Times, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Certainly, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDERLY GENTLEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And The Telegraph.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Elderly Gentleman hesitates - glancing at Mark's back. Then:</context>
      <utterance>Certainly, sir - anything else?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDERLY GENTLEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... er... have been told by a friend that you... er... have some views for sale?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What sort of views, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDERLY GENTLEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, er...</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From under the counter he produces a thick book. Mark turns round. From his POV WE SEE the Elderly Gentleman open the book. He - er- seems - er - more than a little interested.</context>
      <utterance>This sort, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDERLY GENTLEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I, er... how much each?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five shillings, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDERLY GENTLEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take this one... and, er... this one... and, er... how much would the lot be?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Elderly Gentleman hesitates. Mr. Peters turns over a page... and the Elderly Gentleman almost turns over with it.</context>
      <utterance>To you - five pounds, sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell you what, sir. Four pounds ten - and I'll throw in The Times and Telegraph... how's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDERLY GENTLEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, er... thank you very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts it in a wrapper which says 'Educational Books'.</context>
      <utterance>Let me wrap it for you, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shall I put you on our mailing list?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELDERLY GENTLEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no! But I'll look in again...</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds open the door for the Elderly Gentleman, and watches him leave.</context>
      <utterance>By all means, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns triumphantly to Mark.</context>
      <utterance>He won't be doing the crossword tonight!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark.</context>
      <utterance>Those pictures he chose... were all yours!  This is yours! Mark pockets them without counting them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up a postcard - holds it towards Mark.</context>
      <utterance>And this is yours too...</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark looks at the postcard in silence.</context>
      <utterance>And that's what I want to talk to you about. It's a clever picture - because you're a clever lad... but, Mark...  It's all face.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to hurt your feelings, son - but if people want the Mona Lisa they go to the National Gallery.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Louvre.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pats Mark's arm.</context>
      <utterance>Well, wherever they go, they don't come here... so no more of this fancy stuff...</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... now get upstairs - the girls are waiting... and so is a bonus if you give me what I want.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you do with all your money?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens a door at the far end of the room. We catch a glimpse of a winding staircase. He starts to climb it.</context>
      <utterance>Buy cameras.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From REVERSE ANGLE WE SEE Mark venture a shy smile at Milly. Milly opens the door impatiently.</context>
      <utterance>Well look who's here! Cecil Beaton!</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Through the half-open door we catch a glimpse of a second Girl (LORRAINE). She is staring out of a window, her back to camera. She is naked except for a shawl draped round her shoulders. Mark enters the room... the door begins to close. CAMERA TRACKS towards the door. On the threshold of the room, a hood is thrown over our faces. THE SCREEN BLACKS OUT. In the darkness WE HEAR Milly's voice.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, sonny... make us famous.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you read about that girl who was murdered last night?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>MILLY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>We hear Lorraine's voice - muffled, and very far away.</context>
      <utterance>The same thing nearly happened to me!</utterance>
   <speaker>LORRAINE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The SMALL INVERTED IMAGE of Milly peers anxiously into the camera.</context>
      <utterance>Last night! I went out with my boyfriend... We're getting married next month... trouble was my fiance saw us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ground-glass camera begins travelling slowly down Milly's back. CLOSE SHOT of Milly. She is on a couch, lying on her stomach at a slightly oblique angle. All that WE CAN SEE are her face and naked shoulders. From Milly's POV WE SEE Mark under the hood of an antiquated camera.</context>
      <utterance>can you fix it so the bruises don't show?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark's voice is MUFFLED under the hood.</context>
      <utterance>Well, can you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...think so, Milly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of her naked toes. They start to wriggle. CLOSE SHOT of Mark's toes - in sandals, next to the tripod of the camera. They start to wriggle. CLOSE SHOT of Lorraine. We watch her in profile as she stares out of the window - clutching her shawl. She has outstandingly beautiful features. CLOSE SHOT of Mark. He is standing by the side of the camera, studying us thoughtfully. He is holding a remote- control switch panel in his hand. He clicks off several lights and then switches several others on... then he ducks back under the hood.</context>
      <utterance>Then be quick about it, sonny! I'm freezing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WE SEE a small INVERTED IMAGE of Milly on the ground-glass. Her shoulders are now white and glistening, her spine caressed by shadows. She is staring into the camera.</context>
      <utterance>There he goes again! What have you got under there? A girlfriend? We join Mark under the hood.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He adjusts the focus. We can see more clearly the contempt on Milly's face.</context>
      <utterance>I suppose you have a girlfriend?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Milly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From Milly's POV WE SEE Mark come round to the front of the camera, and insert a dark slide.</context>
      <utterance>Hear that, Lorraine? He's available.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Raise your head, please - and look at the sea.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Mark presses a rubber bulb - the shutter clicks.</context>
      <utterance>What sea?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark inserts another dark slide.</context>
      <utterance>What sea?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just wanted that puzzled look.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, did you? Well if you want it again, I'll think of you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="30">
   <speaker>MILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark presses the rubber bulb - the shutters click.</context>
      <utterance>You're a puzzle and a half.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a spare time job for you, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He inserts another slide.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Milly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what do you do for a living?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He presses the bulb - the shutters click.</context>
      <utterance>Take pictures.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This sort?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He inserts another slide.</context>
      <utterance>No, Milly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you like this sort?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He presses the bulb - the shutters click.</context>
      <utterance>No, Milly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark looks at her thoughtfully for a long moment.</context>
      <utterance>Well what sort do you like?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I may show you - one day.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark smiles at her shyly.</context>
      <utterance>That'll be a treat, I'm sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all, Milly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark inserts another slide.</context>
      <utterance>Oh no, sonny! Now take one I can show my mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a gentle KNOCK at the door, and Mr. Peters enters. He carries a tray of coffee. He keeps his eyes modestly lowered.</context>
      <utterance>Think of her then.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lays the tray on a table, still keeping his eyes lowered, and goes out.</context>
      <utterance>On the house.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances over her shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Some house! Hope it falls on his ruddy earhole!</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Lorraine staring out of the window. She stiffens. Milly's voice is overlaid.</context>
      <utterance>It's your turn now, love...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Lorraine clutches her shawl tightly.</context>
      <utterance>... it's her first time.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The left side of her face is classical in its beauty. She has a hare lip, which twists and distorts the whole of the right side. Her eyes are large - and beautiful - and defiant. CLOSE SHOT of Mark looking at her. CLOSE SHOT of Lorraine.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, love. Don't be shy. Lorraine turns round.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORRAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark.</context>
      <utterance>He said... you needn't photograph my face!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to. CLOSE SHOT of Lorraine. Beautiful in profile.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORRAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose you'll fix my bruises too?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of the shawl round Lorraine's shoulders. CLOSE SHOT of Mark.</context>
      <utterance>What about the customers?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Lorraine's eyes - puzzled.</context>
      <utterance>You needn't be shy... of me... it's my first time too.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORRAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tries to go on - but words are a foreign language to him.</context>
      <utterance>In front of eyes... like...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In a sudden rush:</context>
      <utterance>...eyes... as full of...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Lorraine standing very still — looking at him in silence. Milly shrugs and reaches for the coffee pot. Overlaid is the gentle purring of a cine-camera. CAMERA LINGERS on the dark liquid being poured into a cup.</context>
      <utterance>Lorraine - let my camera tell you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>YOUNG PEOPLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of TONY HUNTER, a well-built youngster in his middle twenties.</context>
      <utterance>Happy birthday to you, Happy birthday to you, CAMERA TRACKS towards them.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Happy birthday... dear Helen He obviously means it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of 'dear HELEN'. A sensitive, intelligent, and extremely attractive girl, who — as the encircling youngsters now inform us in song - is:</context>
      <utterance>happy birthday to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG PEOPLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of the glass by Mrs. Stephens' side. It is half empty. An elderly lady leans across to her. She is Mrs. Partridge, slightly high on a glass of sherry.</context>
      <utterance>Twenty-one today, She's twenty-one today, She's got the key of the door, She's never been twenty-one before.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PARTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Stephens grunts. Someone switches on a gramophone and the young couples start dancing at once. Tony hurries up to Helen.</context>
      <utterance>You must be very proud of your daughter, Mrs. Stephens.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helen goes towards him. A YOUNG MAN calls out sharply:</context>
      <utterance>May I?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is pointing at something out of camera. All heads - except Mrs. Stephens' - follow the direction of his gaze. Mrs. Stephens continues to sit motionless in the high-backed chair. CAMERA PANS to the window. Mark is standing there. CLOSE SHOT of Helen looking at Mark. We watch him over her shoulder - Tony's arm encircling it.</context>
      <utterance>Look!</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's that chap from upstairs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Helen - smiling at him.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me! Mark hesitates, then turns round.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark looks at her as if he does.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know how many times we've passed each other on the stairs?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her directness is natural, consistent and very hard to resist. CLOSE SHOT of Mark - smiling.</context>
      <utterance>... but tonight I'm determined at least to say hello to you! So hello!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances with unconcealed interest at the camera over his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Helen Stephens.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm having a party - and the other tenants are there... And a few friends. We'd like you to join us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pardon?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Mark...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hallo, Mark. She holds out her hand... he takes it gently.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please come in... you'll meet the others who live here, and...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, but... work.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances again at his camera.</context>
      <utterance>Oh...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She realizes that this is not the happiest of phrases.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I hope to keep it going for hours yet... so when you've finished why not look in?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA PANS to Helen's door. Tony stands there.</context>
      <utterance>...Mark? He hesitates.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark - looking at her.</context>
      <utterance>Darling, your cake - everyone's waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns away.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Helen. She stares after him for a moment. Then returns thoughtfully to her party.</context>
      <utterance>Happy Birthday. He hurries up the stairs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark - shaking his head, smiling shyly. CLOSE SHOT of Helen.</context>
      <utterance>I hope I'm not disturbing you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds out a plate on which is a piece of birthday cake.</context>
      <utterance>I knew you wouldn't come down... so I've brought you this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes the plate.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... very much...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mustn't keep you from your work She turns to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns round.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like to offer you a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Mark.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't one.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I'd adore some water.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>a hostess can't drink water at her own party, it looks like a hint to the guests.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you... would you... like to come in?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She steps over the threshold. The door closes behind her.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Mark...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's milk... if you'd like some?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very much... if you can spare it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Helen glances towards the inner room. He holds out a glass of milk to her.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She drinks it with relish. He watches her in silence.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Mark...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a pleasant room... and you've another inside?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long have you lived here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him in surprise.</context>
      <utterance>All my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark.</context>
      <utterance>I was born in this house Oh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's my father's.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you mean I've at last found out who our landlord is? Your father?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>Well - no... he's dead!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him in astonishment.</context>
      <utterance>I'm the landlord.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="32">
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you walk about as if you haven't paid the rent.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I meant...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark.</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her anxiously.</context>
      <utterance>It's his house - and I'll never sell it... but I can't afford the upkeep, so I let rooms.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... if I charge too much, tell me and I'll tell the agents.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The rent's very reasonable, but don't say anything to the others or you'll have no peace.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Helen.</context>
      <utterance>Peace...?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark, what do you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Most of the time, I work in a film studio.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On the photographic side, I'll bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope to be a film director... very soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How exciting.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have some spare time jobs... as well.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To do with photography?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More milk?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No thank you... to do with photography?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... to do with photography...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I came in were you looking at some films?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her in silence.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like to see them...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Know I'm being rude... but I really would like to see them...  ...it would be a birthday present... from you to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Mark.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts down the glass, turns to the door.</context>
      <utterance>But I suppose you're too busy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns round. He is standing by the entrance to the inner room.</context>
      <utterance>Will you... would you... like to see them now?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leads the way - she follows. For a moment the screen is in darkness. A dark-room darkness.</context>
      <utterance>I'll... go first.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes a final look round.</context>
      <utterance>This is so... well - so many things... but above all - it's so...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him searchingly.</context>
      <utterance>...completely unexpected!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is all of it yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark.</context>
      <utterance>I mean... is it designed by you? Furnished by you? Tell me about this room.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It belonged to my father</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was he?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scientist...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then this equipment was his?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sold his to buy it...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him with renewed interest.</context>
      <utterance>But it seems to be so... technical.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark - in difficulties.</context>
      <utterance>If this is where you work, I can't wait to see what you work at.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't know what to show you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her thoughtfully.</context>
      <utterance>Well... what were you looking at when I interrupted you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He crosses to the corner cupboard - opens the door. CLOSE SHOT of the cupboard. WE SEE Mark's hand reach for a spool of film... then hesitate, poised above another spool. CLOSE SHOT of Helen - watching with interest. REVERSE ANGLE SHOT of Mark. He closes the cupboard, and turns round... there is a spool of film in his hand. He walks slowly towards his projector... he seems — for the moment — to have forgotten she is there. CLOSE SHOT of Helen - watching him thread the film into the projector.</context>
      <utterance>All right!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the first... twenty-first birthday present... I'll ever have given.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He places a chair a few feet away from the screen - and, with an oddly courteous bow, beckons her into it. She sits down. CLOSE SHOT of Mark. He looks at her intently for a moment - then turns off the lights. Over Helen's shoulder We can just make out the empty screen. Mark switches on the projector. CLOSE SHOT of Helen - the light flickering on her face. CLOSE SHOT of Mark staring at Helen's face. CLOSE SHOT of Helen. WE SEE her expression of surprise. Over Mark's shoulder WE SEE the surprise growing. Over Helen's shoulder we see the screen. We are looking at a small boy. He is lying in his bed asleep. Although the print is old, we can see that he is a remarkably handsome boy.</context>
      <utterance>It's the first I've ever asked for...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy turns restlessly in his sleep... one of his pillows falls to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Mark, what a beautiful child.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course it is! Then who took this film?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A light - as if from a small torch — starts to shine on the child's eyes. He moves restlessly.</context>
      <utterance>My Father.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The light plays on the child's left eye, then on his right. It is growing brighter.</context>
      <utterance>What a wonderful idea...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The child wakes up suddenly. He stares at something... then starts to scream.</context>
      <utterance>You'll be able to show it to your own chi...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark watching her in silence.</context>
      <utterance>You must have had a bad dream...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark does not answer. The small screen is filled with the face of the screaming, terrified child. (Mark's father now tries a not altogether successful dissolve:) WE NOW SEE the little boy standing in front of a garden wall. He tries hard to climb to the top of the wall, but falls over. Helen laughs. Mark watches her in silence. Small Mark tries again - and again - to scale the wall... At last he succeeds.</context>
      <utterance>...but what was that light? ...The camera, I suppose?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WE SEE the little boy lying flat on the wall staring at something... rapt, motionless. The cine-camera which is taking this picture now tracks rather clumsily towards the wall. HIGH ANGLE SHOT over the wall of what is fascinating young Mark - A man and woman are lying on the ground, kissing. The CINE-CAMERA PANS - again rather clumsily - to young Mark... staring intently.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever are you after?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Helen. It suddenly occurs to her.</context>
      <utterance>Naughty boy I hope you were spanked!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... but, Mark... what a strange thing for your father to photograph.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Switch off?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares again at that lonely figure perched on the wall.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The small screen begins to dissolve ...so does the large one.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns round.</context>
      <utterance>Tony!</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tony advances reluctantly towards her. REVERSE ANGLE SHOT of Mrs. Stephens. Over Tony's shoulder WE SEE a powerfully built and once lovely woman. She is so perpetually drunk as almost to be sober. The few movements she makes are slow - deliberate - and give nothing away. The voice articulates so carefully that the slur scarcely shows. The fact that she is blind almost helps to conceal the fact that she is drunk. Her sightless eyes stare out the camera as Tony reaches her.</context>
      <utterance>Me, Mrs. Stephens? The head nods.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want a word with you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="43">
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy moves restlessly, then turns over onto his face, pulling the bedclothes round him. His right hand is limp on the pillow. The light shines for a moment on this hand, then goes out. Helen half turns towards Mark.</context>
      <utterance>Again? Mark looks at her in silence.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her attention is suddenly riveted on the screen.</context>
      <utterance>Mark, this isn't some kind of jo...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Over Helen's shoulder WE SEE something drop onto the child's bed... something which stays quite still for a moment, then starts crawling towards the counterpane. It is a small lizard.</context>
      <utterance>No, Helen.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her voice trails away. She stares - repelled and fascinated - at the screen. WE SEE Mark reach for his cine-camera. Over Helen's shoulder WE SEE the lizard reach the counterpane. It stretches itself out on the floral design - its body is pointed towards the child's hand. WE HEAR a click - and suddenly a spotlight falls onto Helen's face. OVERLAID is the GENTLE PURRING of Mark's cine-camera. She wheels towards him - blotting out the small screen.</context>
      <utterance>Mark, whatever is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>wanted to photograph you... watching...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera purrs on.</context>
      <utterance>No, Mark!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He switches off the spot... the purring of the camera dies away. She turns towards the small screen.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The small boy is sitting upright... screaming with terror... there is no sign of the lizard. A handkerchief is thrown onto the boy's bed. He continues crying - looking up into someone's face. CLOSE SHOT of Mark watching the screen. We hear a man's deep voice overlaid.</context>
      <utterance>help me to understand this... this nightmare...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN'S DEEP VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Small Mark reaches for the handkerchief and wipes his eyes... his hands are trembling. The small screen trembles with them into a clumsy dissolve. Helen turns to Mark.</context>
      <utterance>That'll do Mark... dry your eyes and stop being silly.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her helplessly.</context>
      <utterance>All right... now look... Mark - what was all that about?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... that was a lizard, wasn't it? Or a...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Liz...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well how did it get there?... How did it get there Mark?... Was it a pet?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not mine...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark staring at the screen.</context>
      <utterance>Won't you try to explain?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd better go!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to the screen.</context>
      <utterance>I like to understand what I'm shown!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her voice trails away.</context>
      <utterance>What was your father trying to do?... Photographing you at nigh...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From Helen's POV WE SEE the screen. Small Mark is wearing a dark suit and a black tie. He is standing at the foot of a four-poster bed, staring at something in horror and disbelief... his hands clasp the bedrail tightly. Slowly - very slowly - he walks towards the head of the bed, staring. His lips begin to quiver. He bends forward over the bed. WE CAN SEE the back of his bowed head.</context>
      <utterance>better go...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark... what is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We catch a glimpse of a woman's hands folded in front of her. CLOSE SHOT of Helen.</context>
      <utterance>I am saying... goodbye... my mother...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark.</context>
      <utterance>He... photographed... that...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly - and healthily - his temper snaps.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pushes a lever on his projector as far forward as it will go. The film is now shown at tremendous speed - We catch a glimpse of a long line of cars.</context>
      <utterance>...and this!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It speeds by.</context>
      <utterance>...her funeral!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A confused picture of earth and flowers.</context>
      <utterance>...and this!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The briefest glimpse of a little boy with a spade.</context>
      <utterance>...her burial!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WE SEE a girl in a bikini by sand-dunes. Mark offers no comment.</context>
      <utterance>...and this!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark, who is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Helen.</context>
      <utterance>Her successor.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Suc-?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls back the lever of his projector... the film returns to its normal speed. WE SEE the same attractive young woman standing in a garden. She is holding a bewildered and defiant Mark by the hand. Suddenly the girl runs towards camera - leaving Mark standing alone.</context>
      <utterance>He married her... six weeks after... the previous sequence.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Helen watching intently. It's out of focus! From Helen's POV WE SEE a tall man in a black coat walking away from camera. He hurries towards small Mark - who watches him anxiously.</context>
      <utterance>She filmed... what comes now.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that your father?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The back of Mark's father suddenly obscures our view of small Mark... all we can see is that tall figure looking downwards standing very still. Camera wobbles - as if the person holding it is laughing.</context>
      <utterance>The morning that he left for his honeymoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is he doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Giving me a present...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark stares at the blurred screen, perspiration trickling down his forehead.</context>
      <utterance>What was it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The small screen comes back into focus - and suddenly our camera rushes towards it. WE SEE a CLOSE SHOT of a CLOSE SHOT - and at the moment we see it, Mark's Voice is overlaid... A whisper which echoes round the room.</context>
      <utterance>Can't you guess?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>We are looking at a close shot of a camera in a small boy's hands. There is a single shrill chord of music on the sound track. CLOSE SHOT of the shelf which encircles Mark's room. We are looking at the very same camera which the small boy is holding. CLOSE SHOT of the camera in small Mark's hands. His father's finger points lo the view-finder. Small Mark stares into it. Small Mark begins to smile. CLOSE SHOT of Mark watching himself being born. CLOSE SHOT of Helen watching Mark.</context>
      <utterance>A camera...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He continues to stare at the screen.</context>
      <utterance>Switch it off!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to the projector - touches the wrong switch. Small Mark and his father go rapidly backwards. Mark turns off the projector abruptly. The room is in darkness. WE CAN HEAR both of them breathing quickly. The light goes on. Mark is standing by the exit - he keeps his face averted. Helen walks slowly towards the exit. She glances round once, over her shoulder, then goes into the other room. Mark stares after her.</context>
      <utterance>Switch it off, Mark!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He keeps his face averted.</context>
      <utterance>So he was a scientist?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of scientist, Mark?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Biologist.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't answer.</context>
      <utterance>What was he trying to do to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns round slowly. From his POV WE SEE the willingness to understand on her face.</context>
      <utterance>Mark!...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was he trying to do to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks towards him... takes his handkerchief from his jacket pocket and wipes his forehead.</context>
      <utterance>Watch me... grow up...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark.</context>
      <utterance>He wanted a record of a growing child... complete in every detail - if such a thing were possible - and he tried to make it possible by training a camera on me... at all times...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never knew... the whole of my childhood... one moment's privacy...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And those lights in your eyes?... and that - thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was interested ... in the reactions of the nervous system... to fear... Fear?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fear?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of the word 'fear'.</context>
      <utterance>Fear.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think he learned a lot... from me... I'd wake up... screaming... sometimes... and he'd be there... taking notes... and pictures... and I'm sure good came of it... for some people... He was brilliant.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A scientist drops a lizard onto a child's bed - and good comes of it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know... if he did... but if he did... he'll have learned something of value...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If only about lizards! Mark - it sounds to me as if your father was...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He founded clinics.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He sounds completely...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was famous! Professor A. N. Lewis... three clinics.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you still live in his house... and watch his films?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They helped make me... what I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her in silence.</context>
      <utterance>A photographer? It's no wonder, is it? But you still haven't shown me anything you've photographed!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a knock on the door.</context>
      <utterance>Will you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tony is standing there.</context>
      <utterance>One day... He hurries to the door, and opens it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From Tony's POV WE SEE Helen looking at the door of the dark room.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns towards him.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, there you are, Helen.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The party looks like breaking up, and we were wondering if...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to Mark.</context>
      <utterance>I'm coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>I wish you'd join us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks... work.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is suddenly aware of Tony watching her. She glances at the birthday cake on the table.</context>
      <utterance>I hope that you...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles at him.</context>
      <utterance>... have a sweet tooth!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes into the passage.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you... for my present.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts his arm round Helen, and closes the door. Mark stares after them, motionless. The CAMERA LINGERS on the birthday cake. As the light fades, a voice yells: Cut!</context>
      <utterance>Good night, old boy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BADEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances at the CHIEF CAMERAMAN (PHILIP TALE), who nods his head in agreement. CLOSE SHOT of Mark standing at the back of the camera crew. He shakes his head in disagreement. The Chief Cameraman spots Mark's small mutiny and wags his finger at him. As the Chief Cameraman turns away, Mark's finger automatically wags back. CLOSE SHOT of Baden looking at his watch. He sighs, then nods to the Assistant Director who stands beside him.</context>
      <utterance>OK. Print that one!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baden walks out without a word to anyone. A hubbub of chatter breaks out. The unit downs tools and begins to disperse. CLOSE SHOT of one of the extras (VIVIAN) - a small, vivacious, brunette with delicate, attractive features. She edges towards the camera crew. CLOSE SHOT of Mark watching her. Over his shoulder WE SEE Vivian glance towards him. He nods almost imperceptibly. Vivian hurries towards the exit. Mark turns to a shelf behind him - picks up his cine-camera and a little full string bag containing his lunch.</context>
      <utterance>All right, everyone! Back at two!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="71">
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hallo...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were you spotted?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark.</context>
      <utterance>Is it tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Vivian.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're sure we won't be caught?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not if you do as I tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will, I promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You haven't... said anything... to anyone?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course not.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good... like some cake?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see him break off a piece of birthday cake, and pass it over to her.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark staring at his cake.</context>
      <utterance>Mark... I want to be quite clear about this...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tonight, when the studio's empty... I'm to come back-and you're going to give me a film test... right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll then print the film - so I can show it to my agent and anyone else who matters - right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>Mark...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been offered film tests before... but I haven't liked the terms.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There aren't any.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why are you doing this? Risking your job and...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not just for you... Viv... I have an agent too - and I want to show him what I can do... I want to direct...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark lies motionless behind the wall. A young male EXTRA comes towards Vivian.</context>
      <utterance>There's someone coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hallo - lousy morning's work, wasn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thought I saw you talking to somebody...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was learning my lines.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances at his watch.</context>
      <utterance>Didn't know you had any...</utterance>
   <speaker>EXTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want a drink? Dutch?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Later... perhaps.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be seeing you He wanders off.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't mind me asking?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, more cake?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark is silent, staring at the sky.</context>
      <utterance>No... you want to direct... more badly than anything don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you, Mark?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want... to photograph... the impossible...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is impossible?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something... that has never been photographed before.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really want to know...?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very much, especially if there's a part for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want... to photograph a murder... while it's being committed.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No part for me then.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But that... isn't enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this a new script?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want... to frighten... someone... to death... and photograph... their expression of fear...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark! What's this story called?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is something... he never photographed...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark is silent.</context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is he, Mark?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one could... they'd be caught!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't care... if I had my picture.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Besides, how would you frighten anyone to death?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a way.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a way.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A hooter.</context>
      <utterance>You'd better not tell me! I'll be scared to death tonight as it is!</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Back on the set - shall I go first?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rises to her feet. From behind the wall comes a gentle whirring purring sound.</context>
      <utterance>Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles down at him.</context>
      <utterance>Getting into practice.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See you tonight!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks away. And the gentle purring continues. CAMERA PANS to the sun beating down on the lot.</context>
      <utterance>See you tonight!</utterance>
   <speaker>BADEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A cry goes up,</context>
      <utterance>Would you enquire if our leading lady is ready to start leading.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Baden turning towards the entrance. CLOSE SHOT of Mark turning towards the entrance. CLOSE SHOT of entrance.</context>
      <utterance>Miss Diane Ashley, please!... Miss Diane Ashley, please!...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>DIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you, Sparks? Chippy? Bob?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hallo, Diane...</utterance>
   <speaker>DIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you, Tom? Roger?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And so on, until:</context>
      <utterance>Hallo, Diane...</utterance>
   <speaker>DIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark.</context>
      <utterance>How are you, Phil?... Mark?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hallo, Miss Ashley.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you, Pete...?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches Baden - and completely ignores him.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Di!</utterance>
   <speaker>BADEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She ignores this.</context>
      <utterance>Darling, you've only been playing this part for three weeks, so in case you haven't yet had a chance to read the script...</utterance>
   <speaker>BADEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him - then at her hand - and nods.</context>
      <utterance>... may I remind you that you're a girl with an irresistible impulse!</utterance>
   <speaker>BADEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>a kleptomaniac! Who cannot help stealing... Get inside her, Diane!... What - in all the world - do you most want to steal?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baden sighs.</context>
      <utterance>The limelight!</utterance>
   <speaker>BADEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vivian steps forward.</context>
      <utterance>We'll run the scene where you catch sight of the store detective and faint... Where's the girl who plays the bystander?</utterance>
   <speaker>BADEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hallo, Diane...</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Vivian taking her position in front of the lift. She glances at her watch. CLOSE SHOT of Mark standing by the side of the studio camera. He glances at his watch. CAMERA TRACKS towards the lift. From Mark's POV WE SEE Diane catch sight of the Store Detective - and crumple in a faint.</context>
      <utterance>Positions, everyone!</utterance>
   <speaker>BADEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of door marked: DON JARVIS - MANAGING DIRECTOR.</context>
      <utterance>Hit that floor with a thud!</utterance>
   <speaker>BADEN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>A timid knock is overlaid before we dare enter.</context>
      <utterance>D.J. insists on realism!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S. FILTERED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...it's a wonderful subject, D.J.... Paramount wants it, M.G.M. wants it, Columbia wants it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JARVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But is it commercial?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S. FILTERED</mode>
      <context>Still reading the script, Mr. Jarvis lays the receiver on his desk and picks up another.</context>
      <utterance>Danny Angel wants it!</utterance>
   <speaker>JARVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He replaces this receiver and picks up the original. The voice is still talking - something about 'a wonderful part for Kenny or Alec'...</context>
      <utterance>Are those budgets ready? Well bring 'em in.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S. FILTERED</mode>
      <context>He replaces the receiver. MISS SIMPSON enters. She hands him some folders... her smile curtsies. CLOSE SHOT of Mr. Jarvis opening a folder. Over his shoulder WE SEE a page covered with row upon row of figures. The great man's finger skims along the figures like a tailor feeling cloth.</context>
      <utterance>Send me a memo - we'll discuss it next week.</utterance>
   <speaker>JARVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's an error! The total should be a hundred and fifty thousand pounds fourteen shillings and sixpence - not thirteen and ninepence... That could mean the difference between profit and loss on a first feature!</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS SIMPSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glowers at her - but his day is made.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, D.J.</utterance>
   <speaker>JARVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any units working late tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS SIMPSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only one, sir. Night exteriors on the lot. The Elephant with two...</utterance>
   <speaker>JARVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Jarvis.</context>
      <utterance>That animal needs a stick of dynamite!</utterance>
   <speaker>JARVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remind me to pay them a visit tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS SIMPSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She makes a note in her little book.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, D.J.</utterance>
   <speaker>JARVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Over his shoulder WE SEE an open window. CAMERA TRACKS towards it.</context>
      <utterance>Now, Miss Simpson... take a memo to all department heads...</utterance>
   <speaker>JARVIS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In light of the new economy drive...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BADEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to Diane, who is wearily picking herself up off the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Again, please... and, darling...</utterance>
   <speaker>BADEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... just this once... will you please make an effort to forget that you're stunning, and try to look as if you're stunned...?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say one kind word - and I would be!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Positions, everyone!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I have to faint once more I shall faint!</utterance>
   <speaker>BADEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark nods perfunctorily.</context>
      <utterance>Cut! How was that?...  Mark?</utterance>
   <speaker>BADEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances at his watch - then nods to the Assistant Director.</context>
      <utterance>Print it!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it, boys and girls . . . wrap it up! Night-night everyone! Baden puts his arm round Diane's shoulder.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Vivian hurrying towards the exit carrying her little recorder. In a burst of chatter, the unit starts to disperse. CLOSE SHOT of Mark picking up his cine-camera and his lunch bag. The CLAPPER BOY comes up to him.</context>
      <utterance>How are you, darling? She makes a hobbling exit.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAPPER BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Catching the bus?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not tonight... meeting someone... for a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAPPER BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wanted to discuss the film at the Everyman... Tomorrow then?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope so.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAPPER BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good night, Mark.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>EXTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Greetings... lousy afternoon's work, wasn't it? Who wants a lift to town?</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In what?</utterance>
   <speaker>EXTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>colleague's car... there's room for two on my lap - three at a pinch.</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which is what we'd get.</utterance>
   <speaker>2ND GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You, Viv?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, thanks... I've a date... at the Local.</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Us two then?</utterance>
   <speaker>2ND GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm game... might as well get pinched in a car as squeezed in a tube.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS SIMPSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grunts.</context>
      <utterance>I'm to remind you to pay a surprise visit tonight to The Elephant with...</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS SIMPSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jarvis goes on reading...</context>
      <utterance>Good night, D.J.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>IS ON'.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vivian looks round - there is no one in sight. Vivian slips in quietly, and closes the door behind her.</context>
      <utterance>The light is out.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No reply. Vivian hesitates... then edges slowly forward. Ahead of her are shadowy counters full of merchandise. Beyond them is the door of the lift. CLOSE SHOT of the studio camera and the Director's empty chair beside it. CLOSE SHOT of Vivian edging forward.</context>
      <utterance>Mark...?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches one of the counters - and leans against it, looking around. REVERSE ANGLE shot of Vivian. She is leaning against the counter of the trunk department. Trunks and suitcases at 'greatly reduced prices' are piled behind her. CLOSE SHOT of Vivian. She starts whistling nervously under her breath. Very faintly overlaid is the sound of Mark whistling under his. Vivian stops whistling - and so does Mark. She listens intently for a moment - then peers at her watch. CLOSE SHOT of the watch on Mark's wrist. CLOSE SHOT of Vivian. She shivers suddenly... then looks at her watch again. She hesitates... then turns towards the exit, and starts to edge back. She trips over a cable and almost falls. Suddenly she is bathed in light. She wheels round. One of the big spots is beating down on her.</context>
      <utterance>Mark...?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No sign of him. Overlaid is a gentle purring sound. Where are another light comes on, shining through her hair.</context>
      <utterance>Mark...?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sound of his steps is overlaid.</context>
      <utterance>Mark!</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His footsteps stop... she looks round.</context>
      <utterance>Listen... we must...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His voice is quietly overlaid.</context>
      <utterance>Where are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark sitting in the Director's chair. He is holding in his lap his cine-camera, and a black bag. CLOSE SHOT of Vivian breathing quickly.</context>
      <utterance>Here, Viv... She wheels round.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her in silence.</context>
      <utterance>You frightened me!</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now listen... they're working late on the lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods, staring at her intently.</context>
      <utterance>I know. They're branched off this stage - I'm using their juice.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We must call it off... someone's bound to see us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They might...  ... but they won't interrupt us while we're filming... I've put the red light on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've what?...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put the...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then they'll know someone's here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They won't come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll wait outside... what's the difference?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Over his shoulder WE SEE the studio camera.</context>
      <utterance>The difference is... a perfect film...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances round at the brazenly burning lights; shakes her head despairingly.</context>
      <utterance>... have waited... a long time... for this... and so have you ... no one... must interrupt it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll be caught.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does that matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Matter!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him in silence.</context>
      <utterance>You stand to lose... a job as an extra... I stand to lose... nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark.</context>
      <utterance>...the results must be so perfect... that the risks don't count...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So perfect... that even he ...  ... even he... would say...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her, then nods.</context>
      <utterance>Who Don Jarvis!?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh! He'd say:  Sign on the dotted line, kiddies! You can use my pen, but bring your own ink!  Mark... if you're sure it's worth it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks slowly towards the studio camera. She prepares for the test by switching on music and warming up with dance movements.</context>
      <utterance>It's time to find out, Viv...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark puts the cine-camera and the black cloth bag on the dolly, slowly mounts the platform, closes the blimp - and swings the camera. We watch him from the top of the studio, from the door of the studio, from the Director's chair. And finally WE WATCH HIM from Vivian's POV. She stops dancing but the music continues.</context>
      <utterance>Come on! Get hot!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares ahead of him, his mind far, far away... then bends and looks into the finder. There is a single harsh chord of music - and the screen goes dark. It remains dark for a moment. Suddenly the darkness parts like curtains - and in the centre WE SEE Vivian's face in the finder of the studio camera. (Unlike the ground-glass of the newsagent's camera, we see everything the right way up and in perfect perspective.) Mark hooks a filler-light below the camera and switches it on. He adjusts the finder until he has made of Vivian's delicate features a radiant miniature. The miniature smiles shyly at him. She has stopped dancing and is looking directly at the camera. Music continues.</context>
      <utterance>You belong there...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do feel alone in front of it...  I suppose stars never do?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Through the film, we can see only her eyes - large and wistful.</context>
      <utterance>They feel alone without it...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She becomes the uninhibited Vivian again.</context>
      <utterance>... and the great ones... feel alone... all the time...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up from the camera; she smiles and starts keeping time to the rhythm again.</context>
      <utterance>Then I'm great, boy! What is it you want me to act?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Being frightened to death?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You remembered?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear his quick breathing.</context>
      <utterance>Yes - and I'll have a go!</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark. He looks down - a little sadly - and peers into the finder. (The camera dolly is on tracks - he tracks forward.) Music continues - piano. In the finder WE SEE a large trunk - 'at greatly reduced prices' — on the shelf behind Vivian. From Vivian's POV WE SEE Mark leave the studio camera — and hurry towards the trunks. She watches him wide-eyed.</context>
      <utterance>I've been wondering all the afternoon how you'd do it! I'll bet you've thought of a wonderful twist!</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches for the largest trunk.</context>
      <utterance>Building us a set.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not pull the studio down while you're about it? They can only hang you once.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He carries the trunk towards the studio camera, and lays it carefully on the floor. Music continues. Vivian peers into the front-glass of the studio camera — as if it were a mirror. The rhythm of the music changes.</context>
      <utterance>Exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She jumps onto the trunk and taps.</context>
      <utterance>If only Don Jarvis could see me now!</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She giggles again.</context>
      <utterance>If only I could see Don Jarvis now!</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens the trunk. she jumps into it. Her laughter echoes round the deserted studio.</context>
      <utterance>I warn you, Mark - I'm hysterical... I'd rather act dying of laughter, if it's all the same to you... She jumps off the trunk onto the floor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>1ST ELECTRICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA PANS to a dial on the wall... one of the needles flickers slightly.</context>
      <utterance>So he did it again! Now you tell one.</utterance>
   <speaker>2ND ELECTRICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Half a mo...</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST ELECTRICIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One lump or two?</utterance>
   <speaker>2ND ELECTRICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns away from the dials, and grasps at the outstretched mug.</context>
      <utterance>As the starlet said to the casting director...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of the studio camera. In front of it - fixed on a small hook - is a tape measure. Mark reaches for it... then carefully measures the distance between the trunk and the camera... then he takes apiece of chalk from his pocket and makes a small cross on the floor. The music continues.</context>
      <utterance>Be patient, Viv... it's going to be worth it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh well! I've stood alone in front of a studio camera! That's more than most have.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances at a nearby dial - only a few feet away from the one which is flickering.</context>
      <utterance>Ever stood... behind one?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes around the camera out of sight - and he is out of hers. He glances into the trunk - it is deep, and very empty.</context>
      <utterance>Help yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can see you, Mark... perfectly!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark hurries to the side of the studio camera and picks up his cine-camera.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir! I'll bet I'm the best camerawoman in the business! . . .</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've lost you!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Mark's face appears in the finder.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be back.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see Mark raise his cine-camera. He seems to be pointing it straight at us. We hear a gentle purring.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome, stranger!</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>High angle shot of Mark standing in front of the studio camera - photographing her photographing him.</context>
      <utterance>Photographing you photographing me...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks slowly towards her, holding his cine-camera to his eyes. In the finder of Mark's cine-camera WE SEE Vivian at the studio camera. She comes closer and closer.</context>
      <utterance>Mark, you're brilliant...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lost you again!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>We see him standing almost on top of her - his cine-camera trained on her.</context>
      <utterance>Never mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks up slowly - and a little hesitantly. Music, all drums.</context>
      <utterance>I'm ready now, Viv...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go and stand on that cross, will you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark is watching her over the top of the studio camera.</context>
      <utterance>Am I supposed to imagine someone is going to put me in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He peers into the viewfinder. In the finder we see Vivian looking rather pathetically into camera.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Viv...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark - I hope I won't let you down... I know you're trying to create atmosphere for me - but... I just don't feel frightened! Wouldn't it be better if I just did my number?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Later.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From her POV WE SEE see him raise his head slightly.</context>
      <utterance>Oh all right! I could do anything - I feel so relaxed - and that's due to you... You're so at home with that camera you make me feel at home too... you have it in you, boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ready, Viv?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well-I'll try - In the finder we see her wrinkling her brow.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what... would... frighten me to death?  Set the mood for me, Mark...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes and switches off the recorder. The sudden silence is startling.</context>
      <utterance>Well...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Imagine someone... coming towards you... who's going to kill you - regardless of consequences...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A madman?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes - but he knows it... and you don't... and just to kill you... isn't enough for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares into focusing screen - intrigued, but not frightened, not even by the silence and shadowy vastness around her.</context>
      <utterance>But how would he frighten me to?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stands motionless - staring into camera.</context>
      <utterance>Stay there, Viv... you're... just right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JARVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Fireman opens his mouth to explain — and smoke exudes.</context>
      <utterance>Smoking on duty!</utterance>
   <speaker>JARVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Fireman follows him meekly.</context>
      <utterance>Come with me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That..?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... that would be frightening!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We can hear his heart pounding as if it will burst - and gradually Vivian, too, becomes aware of it.</context>
      <utterance>But... there's something else...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just for a moment Mark's arm moves. His back hides what he is doing. Suddenly WE SEE Vivian turn her head sharply - she is looking at something out of camera.</context>
      <utterance>Well? What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The spike is very close to her throat - but Vivian ignores it, staring out of camera. Over Mark's shoulder we concentrate on Vivian's face.</context>
      <utterance>That...?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The fear on her face is rapidly growing...</context>
      <utterance>Mark... take it...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tries to move back - but the trunk prevents her.</context>
      <utterance>... away!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="51">
   <speaker>HELEN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mrs. Stephens, a large glass of whisky - and the bottle - beside her. It is night.</context>
      <utterance>And that, darling, is the end of the news! Unless you want the football results?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Helen. 'She's Got the Key of the Door' is overlaid.</context>
      <utterance>No thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What else can I read you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The label on this whisky bottle! Are you sure it says seventy per cent proof?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Certain.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From Helen's POV WE SEE her reach for her glass with a steady hand.</context>
      <utterance>They're bigger liars than the press!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that your last tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I doubt it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your last but one?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't haggle.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Toss me double or nothing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helen spins the coin on the table Mrs. Stephens listens intently... the coin stops spinning.</context>
      <utterance>Done!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her fingers shoot out and feel the surface of the coin.</context>
      <utterance>Heads.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bad luck, darling.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns the coin over and carefully feels the other side. Helen watches her with a smile - then looks thoughtfully at the ceiling.</context>
      <utterance>Huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you looking at?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ceiling!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wondering if that young man is home?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From Helen's POV WE SEE the sightless eyes staring at her.</context>
      <utterance>Well he is... I heard him come in... four paragraphs ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Helen.</context>
      <utterance>Do you like him?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, darling.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He has a quality...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wish this had.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... and I think he could help me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With your photographs?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mrs. Stephens.</context>
      <utterance>Yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Helen...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Stephens hesitates - which is rare.</context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't matter.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mummy, what's worrying you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The price of whisky.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What else?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What else matters?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you like Mark?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Haven't met him.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mrs. Stephens. Again she hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>You don't like him! Now why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I distrust a man who walks quietly.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's shy!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His footsteps aren't! They're stealthy...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now darling.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you going up to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We both have the key of the door... Mine needs oiling - and yours needs exercise... Off you go.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses her - and glances at the whisky glass.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks to the door.</context>
      <utterance>remember that you lost the toss.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Helen...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, darling?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're back in five minutes... I won't even finish this.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hurries out. Mrs. Stephens instantly refills her glass. CLOSE SHOT of her hand. It has begun to tremble.</context>
      <utterance>Done!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark. Faintly overlaid is 'She's Got the Key of the Door'. He looks down at the clock.</context>
      <utterance>Helen...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come in, Helen!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="72">
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No reply from the inner room.</context>
      <utterance>Mother heard you come in - so I guessed you wouldn't be in bed ...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure this is conven...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Helen glances at her watch... then looks curiously round the room. CLOSE SHOT of Vivian's recorder, placed on a chair. CLOSE SHOT of Helen. She picks it up and looks at it, curiously, fingering the stops.</context>
      <utterance>Won't be long!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Helen turns round. Mark is standing on the threshold of the dark-room.</context>
      <utterance>Hallo.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks towards her... he stops suddenly. He is staring at the recorder in her hand.</context>
      <utterance>Hallo, Mark...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope you don't mind - is it a tape-recorder?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gently he takes it from her - as if it is a cup with which she has finished - and replaces it on the shelf. CLOSE SHOT of Helen.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark. He is holding out a small package.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sure I'm being a nuisance... but, Mark, I very much want to... Her voice trails away.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Happy birthday.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark! That's very sweet of you - but really.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It isn't much... I don't know anything about... presents for twenty-one... but I saw it this morning... so... please.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes the package, and unwraps it. Inside is a slender brooch</context>
      <utterance>Thank you...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's beautiful...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like the design... More milk?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He watches her hold it against her dress.</context>
      <utterance>More?... No, thank you, Mark... and I really appreciate this... I'm going to put it on now.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There?... Or there?...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The first place...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Helen pinning it on. CLOSE SHOT of Mark touching his lapel. CLOSE SHOT of Helen glancing at her watch. CLOSE SHOT of Mark glancing at his. He thinks of the ticking clock in the dark-room. Helen looks up, and sees him.</context>
      <utterance>I think so too!...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am keeping you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... I promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark, I'm here for some advice.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks as if he has just been voted the best cameraman of the year (unanimously) - and the two films he directed have both won Oscars (though Don Jarvis understood them). His delighted astonishment is such that she has to smile.</context>
      <utterance>From me? Please...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes a deep breath.</context>
      <utterance>... I work in a public library - in the children's section... I'm telling you that to postpone admitting what always embarrasses me...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In my spare time... I write.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's embar...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I write stories for children... but so did Grimm... Hans Andersen... Lewis Carroll...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Had any published?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some short stories.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to read...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I learned today... that my first book... has been accepted! ... For publication in the spring...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But that's wonderful... what's it about?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark.</context>
      <utterance>A magic camera - and what it photographs...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever made you... think of that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you one day - I promise...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well what does it photograph?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you that too - but, Mark... this is the problem... The children who read the book will want to see the pictures the camera takes - but the publishers say they're impossible to photograph, and suggest drawings... but I don't agree.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No - nothing's impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>was hoping you'd say that! There must be photographs - however difficult to take - and I was wondering, Mark - if you'd...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>discuss it with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>take them.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They have cancelled his Oscar.</context>
      <utterance>Mark - I can't ask you to do that...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean... the publisher's mightn't agree.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd take them... for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes but... the money.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are some things... which I photograph... for nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean to offend you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark.</context>
      <utterance>Offend?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Helen looking at him...</context>
      <utterance>Helen... if you knew what it meant... for something to happen to me... that I don't have to make happen... it's like... you've given me a twenty-first birthday...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does your camera photograph?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark - I must go... I just wanted to know... if you'd talk it over with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When please?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's up to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Helen ... I don't know much about... dinner out... but would you come with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It had better be soon...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you going away?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Almost for certain! ...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh... well you suggest when.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you free... tomorrow night?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope I am!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll understand if you're not.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll try to be - I'll try my hardest to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you for listening... and for my present.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at each other in silence.</context>
      <utterance>and for mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good night, Mark...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He watches her leave, standing very still. Offstage, the time clock explodes. CLOSE SHOT - the excited clock. Mark's hand silences it.</context>
      <utterance>Good night... Helen...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DIANE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>From Diane's POV WE WATCH the screen. We see the Tall Man (SHOP ASSISTANT) reaching for a trunk and laying it on the counter. He opens it with a flourish. Vivian passes across the screen - glances casually at the trunk - and wanders off.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like to see that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Assistant Director nods.</context>
      <utterance>No - no - no - we must get some comedy into this...!</utterance>
   <speaker>BADEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA LINGERS for a moment on the screen as Diane (on- screen) smiles at the Assistant.</context>
      <utterance>We'll retake it this morning...</utterance>
   <speaker>DIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Assistant bows and closes the trunk. We dissolve to the set itself -</context>
      <utterance>I'll take it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>BADEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Instead of taking the first trunk you see, I want you, darling... to ask for a blue trunk - and when he brings it to you, to ask for a red one - and when he brings that, to ask for a white one...  And you, Michael... get the trunks one by one - growing more and more fed up - and we'll end on a gag which I'll think of in a minute - all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't feel it!</utterance>
   <speaker>BADEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't feel it! Do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Over Mark's shoulder - behind the camera - WE WATCH the Unit taking up positions.</context>
      <utterance>Positions, everyone!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyone seen Vivian?</utterance>
   <speaker>BADEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The red-headed bystander - Viv.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never mind - I'm cutting her out of this scene... Let's run it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From Mark's POV WE WATCH the scene being rehearsed. Diane approaches the trunk counter and the Assistant smiles at her.</context>
      <utterance>Quiet, everyone!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I interest you in a trunk?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you...  I'd like to see that one...</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns away. She pockets a small item from the counter. He heaves a trunk forward.</context>
      <utterance>Certainly, madam...</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's beautifully fitted -  She takes a perfunctory glance -</utterance>
   <speaker>DIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to see one in red.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pockets another item. He turns and wrestles with another trunk... brings it forward and opens it</context>
      <utterance>Certainly, madam.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... do you have one in white?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark walks away quietly from the back of the Camera Crew. He hurries to the shelf where he keeps his cine-camera and a lunch basket. He reaches for his camera. Diane's voice is overlaid.</context>
      <utterance>Certainly, madam.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIANE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have one in blue?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Mark turns towards the rehearsal and raises his cine-camera. WE SEE the Assistant try to lift a blue trunk - and half collapse with the weight of it. CLOSE SHOT of Baden - beaming. The Assistant manages to drag the trunk forward. He leans over it - exhausted - then starts to open it. Mark moves round until Diane's face is in the finder. As the lid of the trunk is opened we can see only her eyes above the rim of the lid... WE HEAR her scream. CLOSE SHOT of Baden - freezing. There is the sound of a body falling to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Certainly, madam...</utterance>
   <speaker>BADEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The silly bitch! She's fainted in the wrong scene...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SERGEANT MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, Chief.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mm?</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We pass my house when we reach the bypass. Would you mind if I drop off for a minute?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To collect your kid's autograph book?</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Chief!... If the nipper hears where I've been...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Over his shoulder WE SEE what he is looking at - it is a photograph of Dora in her furs and finery.</context>
      <utterance>All right, Dawson - anything to help the Sergeant...  ... and it's about time the Sergeant helped me - we're getting nowhere with this.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about that man the landlady passed?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She couldn't describe him - except to say that he was carrying something that she couldn't see.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of the Inspector staring at the folder.</context>
      <utterance>That's a help.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sergeant, I've been on the force thirty odd years... and I have never seen such fear on anyone's face as on this girl's...  What was it she saw?</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Surely, Chief... a man coming at her - with a sharp weapon.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Sergeant glances at Dora's photograph.</context>
      <utterance>I'm familiar with that kind of terror. This is something new to me... but what?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to turn the page</context>
      <utterance>...now take a look at how we found her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much longer must we wait in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark glances at a group in the comer. The Trunk Assistant is encircled by eager listeners.</context>
      <utterance>Till the police arrive... D.J.'s orders.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>and when she opened that trunk... and I saw what was inside... my dears - I nearly fainted with her -  and do you know what horrified me most?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>D.J. says not to discuss it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From his POV WE SEE a police car driving across the courtyard. Mark watches with great interest - then reaches for his cine-camera. He photographs the police, then puts his cine-camera on to the table and sits back... waiting. CAMERA LINGERS for a moment on the folded tripod.</context>
      <utterance>Any more sauce from D.J. and I shall refuse to sign for seven years! My dears... that poor girl's expression. Mark glances out of the window.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chief, it's exactly the...</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know...  ... don't say anything.  Well, sir... we shall probably have to interview everyone at the studio, so we'd better plan a campaign that won't interfere too much with your productions.</utterance>
   <speaker>JARVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Chief Inspector... if you knew what even a single day's delay could cost.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, we do sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JARVIS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>A hand tugs at Mark's elbow. He turns round. The Clapper Boy looks at him waringly. From Mark's POV WE SEE Don Jarvis standing in the doorway - facing a suddenly hushed room. The great man's hands are folded in front of him -</context>
      <utterance>If I may have your attention, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>JARVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From D.J.'s POV WE SEE the upturned faces - the light from the window falls upon Mark, listening to him with rapt attention. Mark's hands are folded in front of him.</context>
      <utterance>The police wish to interview each of you individually... after which you will be at liberty to leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>JARVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Don Jarvis.</context>
      <utterance>There will, of course, be no shooting today... but work will be resumed, as usual, tomorrow... with, I hope, all of you present.</utterance>
   <speaker>JARVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I look to you to give the police your fullest cooperation.  Sergeant Miller enters with a smile.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark reaches for his cine-camera...</context>
      <utterance>Well now... let's get ourselves organized...  We don't want to keep you cooped up in here, so we've worked out a timetable... We'll talk to the artists first, then the technicians in this order...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>EXTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...she said she didn't want a lift - because she had a call to make locally.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did she say where?</utterance>
   <speaker>EXTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir... and when I left, she was still in the dressing room.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see... let's have a look at this dressing room, shall we?</utterance>
   <speaker>EXTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hallo, Mark...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The girl walks out of picture. THE CAMERA (and Mark) TRACK after the Policemen.</context>
      <utterance>Hallo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I don't think you ought to do that!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hurries down the passage.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Extra's voice is overlaid - a hint of hysteria in it.</context>
      <utterance>Make me famous. Some chap was giving me a screen test</utterance>
   <speaker>EXTRA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The Inspector turns away, and the Sergeant closes the door.</context>
      <utterance>That's where she sat. Inspector.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And whoever did it must be...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF CAMERAMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Crew-member hurries into the office, and closes the door. The Chief Cameraman wanders off thoughtfully. Mark and the Clapper Boy are left sitting side by side.</context>
      <utterance>You're next.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAPPER BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been watching you...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAPPER BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you been filming those policemen?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I've a few quite interesting shots of them - it's a chance I never expected!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAPPER BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A chance for what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To photograph... an investigation... or as much of it as I can.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAPPER BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What on earth for?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It will complete a documentary I'm making.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAPPER BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark nods.</context>
      <utterance>documentary?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAPPER BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's it about?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd rather not tell you till it's finished. And it soon will be ...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAPPER BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But suppose they catch you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh they will - they look very efficient.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAPPER BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you mind?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAPPER BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But they might confiscate your camera.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid they will! But by then... I'll have finished with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAPPER BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door of the small room opens, and the Crew-member comes out.</context>
      <utterance>I don't...</utterance>
   <speaker>CREW-MEMBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You, Mark?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rises slowly... the cine-camera is over his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAPPER BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark, hadn't you better leave that with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, John.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAPPER BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd look after it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Clapper Boy looks at him in amazement.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sure of that - but I'd like to photograph them while they're questioning me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't suppose they'll let me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAPPER BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark, are you potty?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Clapper Boy laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, do you think they'll notice?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAPPER BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't get into any trouble for heaven's sake — I want to discuss that film at the Everyman...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Clapper Boy takes out a copy of Sight and Sound and starts to read it.</context>
      <utterance>Yes... I'd like that... He walks slowly towards the door.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="40">
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Inspector nods.</context>
      <utterance>Mark Lewis - focus-puller... Whatever that may be?</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts a tick on the list. There is the sound of a door opening. The Inspector looks up... From his POV WE SEE a young man with a camera over his shoulder advancing shyly towards him.</context>
      <utterance>Come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Lewis?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Sergeant glances up.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Chief Inspector Gregg and this is Sergeant Miller. Grab a chair.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah! My photographer.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds out his camera. The Sergeant glances enquiringly at the Inspector.</context>
      <utterance>I've brought the camera in case you want to take the film away.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark smiles.</context>
      <utterance>That's all right, Mr. Lewis - as long as we don't appear at the Odeon next week in place of the cartoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well now; have you anything to tell us?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't think so, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you know the girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How well?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mainly by sight.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up a pencil — taps it idly on the desk.</context>
      <utterance>When did you see her last?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yesterday afternoon - when we broke...</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Speak to her?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark's fingers... tapping on his knee in time to the pencil.</context>
      <utterance>Called out good night - don't know if she heard?</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you do then?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Took sqme shots, sir - for a film I'm making.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh... where?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All over the place, sir... it's a documentary.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyone with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir. Just my camera.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What time did you arrive home, Mr. Lewis?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About ten... ten-thirty...</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyone see you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... the people downstairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The telephone rings. The Sergeant promptly answers it.</context>
      <utterance>I see.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He replaces the receiver, turns to the Inspector.</context>
      <utterance>Sergeant Miller - Right, I'll tell him...</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Inspector rises at once.</context>
      <utterance>The doctor's finished his examin...</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...wants to see you -</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.  That'll be all for the moment, Mr. Lewis - thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, sir ...</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark stands very still.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>direct me to that set of yours, will you? I'd probably end on location.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he opens the door)</context>
      <utterance>I'll take you there, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.  Carry on with the interviews, Sergeant.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the Sergeant's POV WE SEE Mark turn to go into the passage. The Sergeant stares at the camera on his shoulder... then the door closes. The Sergeant makes a note on a piece of paper.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I think I can find my way now...</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Inspector hurries towards the door of the set. The Constable opens it - and the Inspector goes inside. The Constable closes the door - and stands in front of it. Mark turns away quickly.</context>
      <utterance>...thanks for the escort</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Mark changes lens (and alters the finder to a 75mm lens). The Doctor's face - thin and impersonal - appears in the finder over the lid of the trunk.</context>
      <utterance>No doubt at all... wounds were caused by the same instrument...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... both women... subjected to the most violent shock...</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What sort of shock?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to something in the trunk - out of the camera's eye-line. CLOSE SHOT of Mark. He balances carefully - then raises the camera above his head. As he leans forward, the pencils fall. WE SEE them shooting like small torpedoes into the darkness below. They make three separate landings. CLOSE SHOT of the Inspector. Looking up. From his POV WE SEE tiers of scaffolding deep in shadow...</context>
      <utterance>...still cannot determine - but look!</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Detectives make as much noise to become quiet as the normal occupants of the studio - and then there is complete silence. Complete, except for the Doctor's asthmatic breathing... And then - so gently that it might almost be in our own minds - WE HEAR a purring sound from the shadows above. The Inspector listens intently.</context>
      <utterance>Quiet, everyone. Please...</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a burst of laughter - the Inspector frowns.</context>
      <utterance>I thought I heard a putty cat!</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to spoil anyone's fun, but we do have a maniac on our hands, and if we don't get him quickly there'll be a third unsolved murder to report to the Commissioner. So let's hurry things up, shall we?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The 'putty cat' Detective raises his flashlamp towards the trunk counter. In the brilliant flash of light that ensues, we glimpse a shadowy figure moving towards a ladder high in the scaffolding... But then we are looking for it - no one else is. The flashlight dies away. The scene fades with it. CLOSE SHOT of a knitting-needle held upwards. Another knitting-needle scales down it like a fireman descending a ladder.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Chief!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mrs. Stephens listening intently.</context>
      <utterance>she was appearing in Arthur Baden's new film The Walls Are Closing In, starring Diane Ashley.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Stephens sips from her glass. The Prime Minister to visit Athens.</context>
      <utterance>a spokesman at the studio said that her performance in the film showed such promise, that her role was to have been built up... All work at the studio ceased today as a tribute to her memory!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark is in films, isn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, darling... It is reliably...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Helen looking up.</context>
      <utterance>I wonder if he knew her?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll ask him tonight...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he taking you out?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If he's free.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's very chivalrous of him. Where's he taking you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've no idea - and I don't suppose he has...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which studio does he work at?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll ask him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind her back we see that her fingers are crossed.</context>
      <utterance>If he's free.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll bring him in and introduce you if...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel I know him.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Stephens stiffens suddenly.</context>
      <utterance>Now how can you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark is standing outside - looking in.</context>
      <utterance>He's here. CLOSE SHOT of the window.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helen beckons to Mark to come in. We see him nod eagerly - and leave the window.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't we make him a present of the window? He practically lives there!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you know where he was standing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helen hurries to the door of the sitting room.</context>
      <utterance>The back of my neck told me... the part that I talk out of!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hallo...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Free?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good! So am I...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like you to come in for a moment - and meet my mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds open the door. He goes inside. The screen suddenly greys out into the veiled images of Mrs. Stephens' world. We hear Helen's voice.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, please...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>WE HEAR the sound of footsteps shuffling shyly forward - and then Mark's voice, every intake of breath magnified.</context>
      <utterance>Darling, this is Mark... Mark, my mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>WE HEAR the pounding of someone's heart - and then Mrs. Stephens' voice.</context>
      <utterance>How do you do... Mrs. Stephens...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>As her voice dies away.</context>
      <utterance>Hallo, Mark.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you been running, young man?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes...  ... didn't want to be late for Helen.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Mark - You deserve a drink for that! What would you like?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Stephens grunts, and reaches for her glass.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing - thank you... very much...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Darling, I've left your supper in the...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The screen greys out. WE HEAR Mark's tiny intake of breath.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me young man... Which studio do you work at?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chipperfield Studio . . .</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Someone's heart is pounding fast.</context>
      <utterance>And that poor girl... where did she work?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At Brookwood.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were wondering if you knew her?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No - No, I didn't...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear Mark's small attempt at a laugh.</context>
      <utterance>A pity. I do like first-hand information.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again that little intake of breath.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, well - I mustn't keep you gossiping after you've run all the way from - Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The station.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Darling, may I tell you about your supper?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... go and be told about yours!  Goodbye, Mark... I expect we shall meet again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Helen kissing her mother and whispering into her ear.</context>
      <utterance>I hope so - Goodbye...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Stephens grunts.</context>
      <utterance>Darling, we forgot to toss.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Supper's laid out in the kitchen.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're not back early, you'll find me laid out with it!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll be early! Good night, darling.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark holds the door open for Helen and she goes into the passage. Mark turns and takes a long look at Mrs. Stephens. She is in the middle of raising her glass. She stops suddenly, the glass poised mid-air. He goes out - closing the door. She finishes her drink as if it is her last.</context>
      <utterance>Good night...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Helen?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her anxiously.</context>
      <utterance>I want to ask you something rather personal...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long is it since you've gone out without that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Without what?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your camera...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark.</context>
      <utterance>Oh...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... don't think I know?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her in silence.</context>
      <utterance>Exactly. I've never seen you without it... but are you going to need it tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well are you? And if so... shall I bring some work with me too?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not going to need it tonight!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds out her hand. He looks at her, appalled.</context>
      <utterance>Good - then give it to me!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...It'll be quite safe - I'll put it away for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark.</context>
      <utterance>Then take it upstairs - if you can't trust me with it...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I trust you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens the door of her bedroom - and turns on the light.</context>
      <utterance>Then look...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...let's put it in here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks slowly round the room, stares for a moment at the bed in the comer, but he won't cross the threshold. He stays outside.</context>
      <utterance>Come in - and see for yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll put it in here - and lock it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This... was my mother's room.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again he stares at the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Was it, Mark?...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes off his camera - and holds it out to her.</context>
      <utterance>I am being tactless, aren't I? ... It's just that... I thought it was growing into an extra limb, and - but you bring it with you if you want to.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes it from him, puts it into the cupboard, and locks it. Then offers him the key.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't describe it! Could only photograph it - She laughs.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shall I tell you what I feel?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Famished!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hurry towards the door.</context>
      <utterance>Good!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a small place round the corner... It's awfully good on Christmas Day.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... there aren't too many open then.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No - it sounds fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark and Helen walking along by the side of the house.</context>
      <utterance>This way.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Mark stands motionless. He is staring at something off camera. Especially when - Her voice trails away... she is staring at Mark staring at something. In the shadows, at the mouth of an alley, a young couple are kissing. Mark stands motionless, staring at them. Automatically his hand reaches for his camera. Helen starts to speak - then looks at him in silence. The man glances round. Mark hurries away and Helen stares after him. CLOSE SHOT of Mark. He turns back - waiting for Helen. From his POV WE SEE Helen come slowly towards him. She looks at him searchingly for a long moment. He manages - but only just - to meet her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I adore new restaurants...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is this restaurant?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Round the corner...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Know much about films?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark.</context>
      <utterance>Come on then...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk slowly down the street.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, young man, Helen's out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With Mark - from upstairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can stay and talk to me - if you like?</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Know much about films?</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or film studios?</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Chipperfield Studios?</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chipperfield, I suppose...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a phone book outside... Look up the number, will you? And see if you can get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Certainly... and then I must go to my room.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lifts her glass, and sits, waiting as he crosses the room.</context>
      <utterance>Granted.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="40">
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has again won the Academy Award.</context>
      <utterance>I like this place! And this dinner! CLOSE SHOT of Mark.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...thank you, Mark...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you ready to talk about your book?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His face falls.</context>
      <utterance>I'm ready to talk about you...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark looks.</context>
      <utterance>It won't take a second - and it's best to have it said.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Helen.</context>
      <utterance>Carrying a camera is only one of your habits, isn't it, Mark? He looks at her in silence.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>... when you stared at that couple, you were like the little boy on that film you showed me... looking over the wall at something he shouldn't see. But Mark - you're strong enough now to lift that child off the wall... aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll try to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you, Mark?... Will you really?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause.</context>
      <utterance>Lecture finished...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When your book's published - will you go on working in a library?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Mark... in case, one day, a child comes in and asks for it!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Helen.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not popular with my customers! They ask me for horror comics - and I take their sticky hands and drag them to where there are books!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... and do you know, Mark, waiting for them to come in next time and ask for books... is as exciting... as a horror comic...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does your magic camera photograph?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark listening, engrossed.</context>
      <utterance>It's owned by a little boy who is terrified of grown-ups... but when he looks in his magic camera he sees grown-ups as they were when they were children... and he isn't frightened any longer.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The little boy opposite her shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>... and one day he gives his camera away to a little boy who is even more frightened of grown-ups than he was - and do you know what he finds?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A moment's pause. She drinks her wine - shy, awaiting his reaction.</context>
      <utterance>... that when he looks at grown- ups without his camera he can still see them as they were when they were children! And that means that he's grown up himself...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What made you think of this story?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark.</context>
      <utterance>You did!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... I looked out of my window - and saw you going off to work carrying that camera like a little boy with a satchel... and an idea came... so thank you...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to think... I was responsible... in some way...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now what do I do about the photographs?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slams the table so violently that a lady nearby looks around... then reaches for his camera.</context>
      <utterance>Take 'em!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helen smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Oh!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns around excitedly and sees her watching him.</context>
      <utterance>There isn't a single face that doesn't look like a child's - not a single one - if you catch it at the right moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It would be a challenge!... Unlike anything I've photographed!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What have you photographed, Mark?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him curiously.</context>
      <utterance>Everything. But nothing I'd want children to see.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But this would belong to them - and they'd know if it wasn't right... Oh, Helen... I would like to find those faces for you... with you...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs excitedly... She looks regretfully at her watch. At once he looks at his.</context>
      <utterance>Very well! Let's try!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You made a promise to your mother -</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Mark...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd better keep it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He signals to the head waiter... and pays his first bill for two.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mother must have gone to bed.  Mark, it was a wonderful evening...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I was going to say... a wonderful evening...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A shadow passes over his face.</context>
      <utterance>And you made it wonderful... without your camera.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(she looks at herself in the lens)</context>
      <utterance>wonder how this sees grown-ups?  ...me, for instance... now that I am one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not you!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It never will... see you!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever I photograph -</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I always - lose...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door at the end of the passage opens and Tony emerges in his dressing-gown, carrying a towel. He avoids looking at them - goes into the bathroom opposite, and slams the door.</context>
      <utterance>I don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is the sound of running water.</context>
      <utterance>He'll wake Mother!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... thank you, again, for my evening.  Will you go to bed now - and not stop up watching those films?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks down at the face which he has found for himself. She raises her head slowly.</context>
      <utterance>Well... I've a little work to do... then I'll go to bed... and think of how to find faces for you...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses him very gently on the mouth. The bathroom begins to sound like a small waterfall.</context>
      <utterance>...faces which - are faces which...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He watches her as she goes into the room, and doses the door. A light goes on beneath the door. He stands very still for a moment... then turns the camera round and points the lens towards his lips. Then he turns abruptly, and hurries up the stairs. The waterfall cascades on. The screen grows dark - and the dark-room grows out of it.</context>
      <utterance>Good night, Mark...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good evening, Mark...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...how did you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands motionless, staring at her standing motionless. Above her head an ancient, half-blind camera also stares at her. The only movement in the room is her smile.</context>
      <utterance>The young man bathing himself brought me to your door... I managed the rest of the adventure alone...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is one room I expected to find locked.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Stephens' sightless eyes stare at him.</context>
      <utterance>I was never allowed a key..., can't get used to them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of her hand - tightening on the heavy stick.</context>
      <utterance>I brought her home early.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there something you...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... a talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Next door would be more...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm at home here... I visit this room every night.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Visit?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark nods.</context>
      <utterance>The blind always live in the rooms they live under...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every night you pace for hours above my head! Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Stephens nods. Her hand touches the black cloth loading bag, lying on the table.</context>
      <utterance>I've no one to talk to... in the rooms I live over...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of her hand - touching the black cloth bag. CLOSE SHOT of Mark - walking slowly towards her. At once she raises the heavy stick - pointing it towards him. CLOSE SHOT of the stick. It is a shooting stick - with a sharp spike on the end of it, similar to the tripod on Mark's camera. Mark stares at the stick, fascinated. CLOSE SHOT of Mrs. Stephens - exploring the inside of the black cloth bag with her free hand.</context>
      <utterance>I'm told that you stare too much... so do I.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cloth... with something hard inside it...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a changing bag... we put films in it - so that the light won't spoil them...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In Mrs. Stephens' own dark-room we hear the hum of Mark's projector - and the pounding of Mark's heart - and, very faintly, the sounds of Tony bathing himself.</context>
      <utterance>How odd - that the light can spoil anything... The screen greys out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear his tiny intake of breath.</context>
      <utterance>Every night you switch on that film machine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sound of his footsteps softly approaching. Like a chair?</context>
      <utterance>What are these films you can't wait to look at?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like a chair?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Very faintly we hear Tony singing in his bath.</context>
      <utterance>What is the film you're showing now?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you lie to me? I'd never know...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Stephens smiles - then turns her head towards the 16mm screen.</context>
      <utterance>You'd know at once -</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take me to your cinema.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes her arm gently and guides her towards us. Both of them stare at the 16mm screen... She leans forward - her face only inches from the screen - the light from the projector flickering on to her. REVERSE ANGLE SHOT of Mrs. Stephens. Slowly she stretches out her hands and touches the screen.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her head and shoulders blot out most of the screen - but between her outspread fingers WE CATCH A GLIMPSE of a girl's terrified eyes.</context>
      <utterance>What am I seeing, Mark?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark and Mrs. Stephens.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you answer?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's no good - I was afraid it wouldn't be.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The lights failed too soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They always do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hurries to his cine-camera.</context>
      <utterance>I'll have to try again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark slips a new spool of film into his cine-camera.</context>
      <utterance>I've yet to meet an artist who could judge his own work...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think you've spoiled?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her thoughtfully, then presses a light switch. A spotlight falls blindingly on to her eyes. He presses another switch, and then another, until the whole of her face is shining with light.</context>
      <utterance>An opportunity... now I must find another.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks towards her. She starts to back away. The shadow of Mark's head appears on the 16mm screen. WE SEE him raise his camera - then pull down the tripod. Black out into the grey darkness of Mrs. Stephens' world. WE HEAR the purring of Mark's camera - more clearly than we have yet heard it. (There is the faint rasp of a cog which needs oiling.) The sound of footsteps approaching... the purring changes direction.</context>
      <utterance>Why are you putting those lights on my face?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The purring is on top of her. There is a sudden thud.</context>
      <utterance>It's almost over...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She edges towards her stick. He hurries forward and picks it up. He looks at the spike on the end of it - then carefully gives it to her by the handle. She grasps it tightly.</context>
      <utterance>Please let me finish! It's for Helen!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean? It's for Helen?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He returns excitedly to his camera.</context>
      <utterance>She wants to see something I've photographed!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On Mark's focusing screen WE SEE the fear on her face. Her hand trembles as she wipes away the perspiration.</context>
      <utterance>My daughter sees enough of my face without photographs...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please... don't be frightened.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But it is fear that we are looking at.</context>
      <utterance>Not frightened! Hot!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the focusing screen we see her moisten her lips nervously.</context>
      <utterance>So put that camera away...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He switches off the camera abruptly, and folds up the tripod. He turns away without looking at her - and hurries to the door. CLOSE SHOT of Mrs. Stephens listening to his movements - puzzled.</context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From his POV WE SEE the fear in her eyes. He looks away at once, staring into the darkened room.</context>
      <utterance>In rather a hurry, aren't you? He glances towards her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From her POV (shooting over her shoulder with a large CLOSE SHOT of her ear in the foreground) WE SEE Mark standing in the doorway - and hear, very clearly, his quick, uneasy breathing.</context>
      <utterance>It's late.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must be tired...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear his quick intake of breath.</context>
      <utterance>You're anxious to get rid of me all of a sudden.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't be selfish... You can take some more pictures - if you want to...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not, Mark?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Run out of film.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances towards her - then hurries into the next room.</context>
      <utterance>Can't you find some - to please Helen?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't trust yourself to take any more, do you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Over her shoulder we follow the stick towards him.</context>
      <utterance>Instinct's a wonderful thing, isn't it Mark? A pity it can't be photographed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His face is averted... his eyes are closed.</context>
      <utterance>if I'd listened to it years ago, I might have kept my sight.  I wouldn't have let a man operate I had no faith in... so I'm listening to it now...  It says all this filming isn't healthy - and that you need help...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... get it, Mark... get it quickly... and until you've got it... I don't want you and Helen to see each...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll never photograph her... I promise you that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns towards her - a small boy who suddenly understands what contagious means...</context>
      <utterance>I'd rather you don't have the chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean it, Mark. And if you don't listen to me... one of us will move from this house - which would be a pity, because we'd never find a cheaper...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll never have to move... because of me... I promise you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They go into the passage.</context>
      <utterance>Good boy.  The stairs are the difficult part...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares at Helen's room - then looks quickly away. Suddenly she raises her hands - and runs them gently over his face...</context>
      <utterance>Far enough, Mark...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>taking my picture?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We can see his eyes through her outstretched fingers.</context>
      <utterance>Yes ...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's been a long time... since anyone did...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark... what's troubling you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns away abruptly and hurries up the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Good night, Mrs. Stephens.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. STEPHENS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks towards Helen's room - then turns slowly towards her own. HIGH ANGLE SHOT of Mrs. Stephens opening the door of her room - and Mark opening the door of his.</context>
      <utterance>...you'll have to!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>JARVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you any suspicions, Chief Inspector?</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It could be any of them...</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He catches a glare from the great man.</context>
      <utterance>That's the trouble with film people - they're all peculiar...  ... present company excepted.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUBLICITY MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Inspector turns round.</context>
      <utterance>Speaking of peculiar people.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUBLICITY MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've a psychiatrist coming down today. Dr Rosen -</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know him.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUBLICITY MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's pure publicity - and I promise he won't do any work.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What will he do?</utterance>
   <speaker>PUBLICITY MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get himself photographed... We're telling the press he's here to help the case - and to see if he can spot the murderer.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the best of luck!</utterance>
   <speaker>JARVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you object. Chief Inspector?</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Publicity Man sighs with relief.</context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he shrugs')</context>
      <utterance>I'll be frank. I'd welcome anyone's help... I don't know how this maniac kills - or why he kills - or who he'll kill next, but if he isn't caught quickly...</utterance>
   <speaker>BADEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Inspector, have you convinced yourself he's a member of my unit?</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir ... but a few things seem to point to it... No one outside your unit admits to knowing the girl... There was a trunk all ready for her... and with the risks he was running, I think he'd have to use surroundings he was familiar with... Where is your unit now?</utterance>
   <speaker>BADEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Waiting for me on the set.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to watch them at their jobs, sir. It may tell me more than a hundred interviews.</utterance>
   <speaker>BADEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, Inspector, the strain on them is already...</utterance>
   <speaker>JARVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come now, Arthur, if that's what the Inspector wants.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid it is, sir... now where could I get the best view?</utterance>
   <speaker>BADEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On the dolly... the camera... You can watch everyone and everything from there... including me!</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very well, sir ... I'll become a member of your camera crew...</utterance>
   <speaker>BADEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... if the unions don't object!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VOICE 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hear they're making an arrest today.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark turns round and walks towards the small group of people assembled round the studio camera -</context>
      <utterance>hope it's D.J. It's about time they caught up with him!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're there, Doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He continues reading. The car enters the studio.</context>
      <utterance>Dr Rosen! What a pity.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="46">
   <speaker>BADEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pats her arm reassuringly. The Chief Cameraman nods to Mark. From the Inspector's POV WE SEE Mark pull a tape measure from the front of the camera and hold it to Diane's forehead. From Mark's POV WE SEE the Inspector watching him over the top of the studio camera. A man with a shock of white hair is also watching him... and the Sergeant stares at him from the other side of the set. The tape measure in Mark's hand remains steady. From the Inspector's POV WE SEE Mark replace the tape measure and take up his position on a small stool by the side of the camera.</context>
      <utterance>Try it, darling... We'll all be with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the nervous laughter that follows, the Assistant Cameraman whispers to the Chief Cameraman.</context>
      <utterance>Terribly sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT CAMERAMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark turning round to look at the Doctor - a hint of hope in his face. CLOSE SHOT of the Inspector following Mark's glance.</context>
      <utterance>That sneezer geezer's a psychiatrist!... Heard it on the grapevine.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Assistant hands her a hat. Diane tries it on.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like to see... that one...</utterance>
   <speaker>DIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... have you it... in red...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Certainly, madam.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She bursts into tears and runs off the set. From the Inspector's POV WE SEE Baden whisper to the Assistant Director - then hurry after Diane.</context>
      <utterance>... in... red  I can't! I can't, Arthur!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The unit dissolves into small, chattering groups. The Assistant Director hurries up to the Doctor.</context>
      <utterance>Ten minutes break, everyone!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you suggest anything, Doctor?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. It looked jolly interesting to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean to help her psychologically...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Give the girl a proper rest... Ten minutes is useless!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bustles off and the Doctor is left alone. He glances round thoughtfully. From the Doctor's POV WE SEE the small, chattering groups. Then we see Mark standing a few yards away, watching him. The Doctor smiles at him pleasantly.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your job?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a focus-puller...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh... so am I, in a way.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was wondering if you knew my father - Professor Lewis...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at Mark with renewed interest. So does the Inspector. From his POV WE SEE Mark and the Doctor talking. The Doctor is fidgeting with his watch chain. Mark fidgets with his jacket button. The Inspector then glances towards the Hat Salesman, who is holding court in the comer. We return to Mark and the Doctor.</context>
      <utterance>Professor... but of course I knew him. He lectured to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was an extraordinary man - quite brilliant!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what he was interested in before he died?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark puts his hands behind his back.</context>
      <utterance>No? Tell me...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't remember what he called it... It was something to do with what causes people to be... peeping Toms...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scoptophilia!... That would interest him! A most fertile mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scopto...?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>philia... The morbid urge to gaze... Coined since his day... Have you any manuscripts of his which I could...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He thought... it could be cured...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Usually. Now about his manuscripts -</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quickly?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark - his last hope gone.</context>
      <utterance>The cure? Very quick... A couple of years analysis - three times a week - an hour a time - and it's soon up-rooted...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... if you've any of his papers on the subject?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Doctor...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the Sergeant's POV WE SEE the Doctor hand Mark a card, and pat him jovially on the shoulder. The Sergeant edges up to the Inspector.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like to see them - I'll give you my address, young man.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wonder what all that's about?</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll find out afterwards... Now, listen... I want you to watch who brings their own lunches... Someone ate homemade cakes and sandwiches by the side of those bushes - and we may get a lead.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA PANS to a shelf in the comer. A lunch basket stands next to a cine-camera.</context>
      <utterance>Right, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Overlaid is the noise of the unit dispersing. Mark picks up his camera - then reaches for the lunch basket. An urgent voice whispers behind him.</context>
      <utterance>We're stopping at four today - so have a quick lunch, everyone! Back at two sharp! FADE IN on the lunch basket.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns round. The Clapper Boy is standing there. The Clapper Boy glances round carefully. The Inspector and Sergeant are wandering casually towards the door.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Mark!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAPPER BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of the postcard. We see Milly's face and naked shoulders framed between Mark's hands.</context>
      <utterance>Can't wait to show you this!  I ought to charge you! He winks at Mark, gives him the postcard.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAPPER BOY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Mark hands it back.</context>
      <utterance>You don't get that in Sight and Sound - Isn't she terrific? Got some more - if you're interested?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've given me... an idea...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAPPER BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark turns towards the exit.</context>
      <utterance>I'll bet I have!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAPPER BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Phone - may be my last chance - and... thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAPPER BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But your lunch?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hurries excitedly towards the exit... CLOSE SHOT of the Clapper Boy staring at his photograph.</context>
      <utterance>You have it!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLAPPER BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches for the lunch basket, then walks towards the exit where the Sergeant is waiting casually.</context>
      <utterance>... some photograph! Well lit too!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... be here at six o'clock. Milly'll be waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six o'clock...</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On the dot, Mark, or she'll go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be there, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd better be!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE SET - DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>CLOSE SHOT of Dr. Rosen smiling.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR ROSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He asked if I knew his father... which I did... a brilliant man!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that all he wanted?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>think so... we had a little chat about scoptophilia - and he's going to show me...</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About what?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Voyeurism.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What makes people into Peeping Toms, one of his father's subjects, apparently.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peeping Toms...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An interesting boy... he has his father's eyes... you don't suspect him, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suspect 'em all - what about you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm interested in that chap with the bald head and hatchet face... there's something on his mind!</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns away thoughtfully.</context>
      <utterance>No wonder... he's the director!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ASSISTANT DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA PANS to a comer of the studio. The Inspector and Sergeant stand in the shadows.</context>
      <utterance>All right, everyone. This is the last shot... Make it a good one!</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got your list, Sergeant?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to see how some of them spend their spare time...</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which ones, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly, Sergeant...  ... which ones?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't make a habit of this!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Milly's upstairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to the door.</context>
      <utterance>Right, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got to go out... If you finish before I'm back, lock up and put this through the letter-box...  CLOSE SHOT of Mark staring at the key.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark takes the key. He starts to smile.</context>
      <utterance>What's the matter? Haven't you ever seen a key before?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark turns to the door.</context>
      <utterance>The till will be empty - if that's what you're smiling about.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark goes into the inner room; he is still smiling.</context>
      <utterance>You know what I want now! No fancy stuff...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've spoiled my whole evening, you have!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Milly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the idea?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I shan't be here tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to draw the curtains - and stops suddenly. Over his shoulder WE SEE the man in the raincoat standing on the opposite side of the street.</context>
      <utterance>Why? Going on manoeuvres with the boy scouts?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark raises his cine-camera and carefully photographs the Detective through a chink in the curtains.</context>
      <utterance>I thought so!</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you gone absolutely...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just... completing a documentary.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He draws the curtains - and turns round.</context>
      <utterance>You're a document and a half, you are. Is it safe to be alone with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns round and walks slowly - and a little sadly - towards her BLACK OUT: The screen remains dark for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>... might be more fun if it wasn't...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes her mother's shoulders. Mrs. Stephens snores on.</context>
      <utterance>Darling...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes her again — but it is hopeless. Helen pulls the bedclothes round her mother, then turns away. She picks up a large envelope and her handbag, and hurries to the door.</context>
      <utterance>Darling.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hallo.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hallo, Tony...</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To leave something for Mark...</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You haven't much time for me these days.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tony...</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all right - I'll be here - if you want me.  ... by the way... your mother was yelling out something before you came in... about Mark photographing her.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Photographing Mother? You must be mistaken!</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes into his room, closing the door. She stares after him for a moment, then hurries up the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Of course. See you sometime.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer. She knocks again, then opens the door and goes inside.</context>
      <utterance>Mark...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MR. PETERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of the Chief Inspector.</context>
      <utterance>went up to look around - found her.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF INSPECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slams down the receiver, and jumps to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, yes... What's the address? ... Newsagent's shop? ... Did you say news...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="47">
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't let me see you... frightened...  Leave!  Hurry, Helen!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not...  ... till I know...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stands with her back to him. From REVERSE ANGLE we see her struggling for breath. Over her shoulder WE SEE him staring at the 16mm screen.</context>
      <utterance>Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Over her shoulder we see him hurry towards the projector.</context>
      <utterance>That film...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sound of him switching it off.</context>
      <utterance>That film...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She wheels round towards him.</context>
      <utterance>... is ... just a film...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... isn't it? From REVERSE ANGLE we see her looking at him.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark.</context>
      <utterance>... horrible ... horrible... but... just a film... isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Helen — not enough breath to scream... hardly enough to breathe.</context>
      <utterance>No...  I killed them...  And now that you know... I want you with me... a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stands motionless.</context>
      <utterance>You'll be safe - as long as I can't see you frightened - so stand in the shadows, Helen... please...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From her POV WE SEE him standing in front of the door, looking ahead of him. She backs slowly away into the shadows at the back of the room.</context>
      <utterance>... please...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Helen standing in the shadows where her mother stood.</context>
      <utterance>She's right... your mother... must tell someone everything... sorry... has to be you!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The room is suddenly filled with the terrified screaming of a small boy. Helen wheels round. The screaming seems to be coming from the walls. Mark's hand is on a switch - one of a number on a panel.</context>
      <utterance>This was his laboratory... and you know some of what he did... but not all.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He presses another switch. There is a click, and the screaming stops, to be replaced by a low sobbing.</context>
      <utterance>... aged five...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He presses another switch. There is a moment's silence.</context>
      <utterance>... aged seven...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WE SUDDENLY HEAR the ticking of a clock.</context>
      <utterance>All the rooms were wired for sound... and... still are.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Helen - listening.</context>
      <utterance>Your room.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The click of a switch - and we hear a loud snoring.</context>
      <utterance>Your mother's .</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The click of a switch - and we hear Tony's voice.</context>
      <utterance>Tony's.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one will come in... honestly, darling...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care!</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But darling...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Mark listens with interest.</context>
      <utterance>Stop it, Tony!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He does so - at once. She walks towards him. He turns away from her.</context>
      <utterance>Turn it off!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at me, Mark!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not if you're frightened...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slowly he faces her.</context>
      <utterance>Look at me!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you do... to those girls?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tries to turn away - but she follows him.</context>
      <utterance>What did you do, Mark...?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark - his eyes closed.</context>
      <utterance>If you want to torment me... for the rest of my life... then make me imagine!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you do ... to those girls?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Show me, Mark...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But if you're frightened...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to his cine-camera, and picks it up. He releases the tripod. CAMERA HOLDS on Helen. She stands very still against the wall. Mark's voice is overlaid.</context>
      <utterance>Show me - or I'll remain frightened... for the rest of my life. Show me!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She is looking at something, puzzled.</context>
      <utterance>Do you know... what the most frightening thing in the world is?...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sound of his footsteps approaching...</context>
      <utterance>It's fear.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WE SEE a look of fear spring into her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>So I did something... very simple...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WE SEE the spike approaching her throat... but she is looking at something else.</context>
      <utterance>Very simple.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The spike is touching her throat.</context>
      <utterance>When they felt the spike... touching their throats... and knew I was going to kill them...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Helen's face several times its natural size. She is looking at herself in a large circular magnifying mirror which has been fitted over the camera's face. The mirror entirely obscures both Mark and the camera. There is a small hole in the mirror through which the lens of the camera winks. As Helen looks at her terrified distorted face this small hole gives her an extra eye in the middle of her forehead.</context>
      <utterance>... I made them - watch their own deaths!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE SHOT of Mark - crouching behind the mirror, sweat pouring down his forehead... his finger on the trigger of the camera.</context>
      <utterance>Made them see their own terror as the spike went in... and if death has a face, they saw that too!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helen's eyes are closed. The spike is still touching her throat. CLOSE SHOT of Mark — his face turned away from the viewfinder.</context>
      <utterance>Not you! Not you! I'll never photograph you! I promised - I promised - Not you!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's the sound of a car pulling up. He hurries to the other room.</context>
      <utterance>... frightened ... for you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark! Mark! Give yourself up!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rapidly he fixes his camera on to a hook on the wall. Then he adjusts the tripod so that the spikes protrude towards him...</context>
      <utterance>I've been ready for this... for such a long time...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He makes chalk marks on the floor in front of the camera, then switches on all the floodlights. WE CAN HEAR the Policemen pounding on the door.</context>
      <utterance>It'll be all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He crosses to a switch - presses it. The room is filled with a small boy's screaming.</context>
      <utterance>I can beat that!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands next to her, and looks at his long array of cameras. WE SEE that each one of them has been fitted with a small metal disc (a delayed release), and that some of the older cameras have flashlights attached.</context>
      <utterance>Give yourself up... Mark!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slowly he walks past his cameras. As he does, the metallic disc on each one explodes with a little plop - and the eye of each camera winks once as if in salute. Some go off with flashlights on either side of the room. The sound of footsteps hurrying up the stairs. Ahead of Mark - coming steadily closer — are the spikes of the tripod. The mirror on the cine-camera reflects the approach - and Helen's terrified face.</context>
      <utterance>Watch them, Helen... Watch them say goodbye - one by one -  I've timed this... so often...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The child's screaming reaches its peak as Mark approaches the spikes... Ahead of him, on the small table where his projector stands, is Helen's book The Magic Camera.</context>
      <utterance>No - No!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Policemen are now rattling on the dark-room door.</context>
      <utterance>I wish... I could have found your faces for you...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see his face, terrified, in the magnifying mirror. The spikes are against his throat. The eye of the camera is winking rapidly.</context>
      <utterance>Helen - I'm afraid!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Heavy shoulders are pressing against the dark-room door... as it breaks in, Mark lunges forward against the spikes. The cine-camera is wrenched away from the wall as he falls back. He crashes against the small table, which falls over. He is not parted from his camera - it is fixed to him by the tripod, and falls back with him, covering his face like a canopy. WE SEE his face in the lens of the cine- camera. and WE SEE his hand - lying limp on the cover of The Magic Camera. The Policemen hurry into the room. They stare motionless at what they see. CLOSE SHOT of Helen - her face buried in her hands. The child's screaming stops suddenly... and in the absolute silence which follows WE HEAR the voice of Mark's father:</context>
      <utterance>I'm glad I'm afraid!</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>And a small voice answers.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be a silly boy... there's nothing to be afraid of...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHILD'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The spotlights begin to dim... The dazzling white of the 16mm screen fades slowly into greyness... The room is filled with the gentle breathing of a small child.</context>
      <utterance>Good night, Daddy...</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
