<movie id="429" title="Perfect Creature">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GENETIC DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Strange isn't? Apprentice DOCTOR Strange?</utterance>
   <speaker>GENETIC DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That God would choose such humble vehicle for a miracle. The mothers invariably come from the slums, we don't know why.  This is your 7th isn't it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GENETIC DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woman now looks up. And tentatively speaks.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, her first was successful, a Brother was born. Thereafter variously malformed offspring. We can only hope this one will be different.  You'll have to try harder this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN IN THE SURGURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please...</utterance>
   <speaker>GENETIC DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN IN THE SURGURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They always take my babies away.</context>
      <utterance>Please... I want to keep my baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENETIC DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woman drops her eyes. We see the Apprentice Doctor, almost pitying the poor woman. Apprentice DOCTOR (to woman) You won't have to worry. The Brotherhood will take him... We are closer on the woman now. Tears begin to glisten in her eyes as we drift closer to her. Apprentice DOCTOR (continuing; off) ...raise him in the church, teach him. He's special. You should be proud. It's a blessing really, he'll want for nothing. Not like the rest of us? We track in closer, closer, to the woman, then continue, right into her eye, through the fluid, to see the room reflected upside down at the back of the retina. This dissolves to an upside view of...</context>
      <utterance>Don't be stupid woman!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The little boy then shares a glance with the woman who has just given birth. She seems to recognize the boy.</context>
      <utterance>This is your brother Silus. You will teach him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS AS A BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that my mother?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Augustus then leans forward and gently opens the baby's mouth. We see the baby close. In the otherwise baby-like mouth we see something strange. There are two tiny fangs protruding from the otherwise smooth gums. We see Augustus smile. In his mouth too, we see two perfectly pointed teeth.</context>
      <utterance>No, not any more.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome to the world little Brother. Cut to We end close on the baby; its piercing eyes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is taken care of.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is good.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Augustus. We failed this girl. We asked her to help us catch him, and then we failed her.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Augustus lifts a beautifully designed glass and silver pipe from the onyx table at which they sit, then settles back into a fine hardwood chair. The chair's swirling, delicate back creeks as he takes a puff on the pipe.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. But her death served a greater good. Every trap needs bait.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silus shakes his head, no. The opium in the pipe crackles.</context>
      <utterance>Are you sure you won't join me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Augustus places the pipe down, blows a smoke ring as a Chinese woman, dressed in a sarong, brings over two finely cut crystal glasses and sets them before the men, then leaves. Silus now lifts the glass and we see what it contains. Blood; dark and red and viscous. Silus takes a sip, then looks over to the bar. There is a young woman there, sitting at the bar, being treated with great care by several of the elegantly dressed patrons; the young woman laughs, enjoying the attention. Tubes run from the young woman's arms. These tubes carry her blood into a conch shaped glass bowl. We see the Chinese waitress fill another glass from the bowl. Silus watches, blood slightly present on his ashen lips. And we see two perfectly pointed fangs hanging in his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps this is beyond us. Perhaps we should inform the authorities. The human beings.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For now the Brothers feel we should deal with this ourselves.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If they find out we are covering up these deaths...</utterance>
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silus now turns to Augustus, still looking unconvinced.</context>
      <utterance>Which is why you must find him. Silus.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For centuries we Brothers have served mankind and them us. The great union. But remember your history. 300 years ago when our kind were first born into this world they burnt our children as monsters. They had no notion of evolution. In another world we might all have been slaughtered, only to be remembered in myth, monsters to frighten the young or a puzzle for anthropologists. We must refuse to let one aberrant individual destroy the balance between the two races. The old prejudices are still there. Human beings are paranoid creatures by nature.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps they have good reason.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cut to</context>
      <utterance>Silus. Simply concern yourself with finding Edgar. Find your Brother so that we can help him. Before he kills again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone's ready Lilly.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both move to one of the tall buildings; a four story, ancient tenement that looks empty, almost derelict. They quietly move up the steps of the place and then pause. There is the bleep from a strange looking valve powered Walkie Talkie; hereafter called an RT.</context>
      <utterance>About time.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On three gents. One, two...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see a gun in Jones' hand as he moves towards the woman, who has her hands up and is getting down on her knees. The camera then pans wildly, left and right. Then Lilly's foot kicks in a door to our right, revealing a dank office and a man, half naked, reaching for a gun. A woman is lying on a cot and she's screaming. She is instantly recognizable as a prostitute.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you move!</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From this POV we see Lilly's hand pointing a gun at the SLUM LANDLORD, who is now slowly easing back into the scummy office.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you dare.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jones!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SLUM LANDLORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know nothing about it. I give 'em out. Make sure everyone gets 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another man now approaches Lilly.</context>
      <utterance>That's a lie! We know you've been trading influenza vaccine in the workhouses!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lil'. I think you should see this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WOMAN IN THE BASEMENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woman extends her arm. It is covered in sweat; grimy. The glands at the side of the woman's neck are distended and swollen, her eyes bloodshot.</context>
      <utterance>Help me. Please help.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN IN THE BASEMENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The room is a version of hell. Lilly's eyes glisten. Cut to</context>
      <utterance>Please. I'm sick. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a fucking liar!</utterance>
   <speaker>SLUM LANDLORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lilly stares at the Slum Landlord; shock in her face, and anger.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, I swear it, I gave 'em their boosters, both of 'em. I'm a responsible landlord, I swear to god. There must've been something wrong with them vaccines.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see the woman who was screaming before, the prostitute; she makes an obscene gesture at Jones. As this is going on Frank and the other man we've seen are tearing the place apart, looking for something. They don't find it and Frank's look tells Lilly so. Lilly's face is a mask. She is watching the Slum Landlord very carefully. He keeps looking down; strangely, nervously.</context>
      <utterance>This is a civil health violation! You're going to the hell house for this. You can forget lovely Doris here where you're going.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SLUM LANDLORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lilly lets her eyes drift down, all the way down to the chair legs, which rock unevenly on the floor. Lilly is staring at the scratched, worn floor boards which MOVE. Cut to Frank, prizing back the floor boards. Jones restrains the Slum Landlord. Lilly watches. Frank pulls the floor boards away easily. We see that hidden in the floor cavity are packets of something. Frank pulls them out. Rips one of the plastic bags open. In it are packets with the words "Jamestown Borough - Civilian Influenza Vaccination." Frank holds it up for Lilly to see. The Slum Landlord is now looking three ways at once. Lilly slowly begins to approach the Slum Landlord.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you're on about. I've done nothing, I swear to god, I've done nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is my pleasure to inform you that you are under arrest for trafficking influenza vaccine.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLUM LANDLORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want my lawyer.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a violation of the 12/10 health act, whereby you have withheld borough sponsored vaccines from your tenants.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLUM LANDLORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want a lawyer!</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Slum Landlord just stares at her.</context>
      <utterance>Anything you say will be held against you as evidence and, by endangering the public good, you are not entitled to a lawyer.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLUM LANDLORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lilly smiles grimly.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you then.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lilly gives the Slum Landlord one almighty slap across the face that stuns him. Then Jones grabs the Slum Landlord and drags him off, but we stay on Lilly. Her face. She stoops and lifts something from the landlords desk. A public health flier saying "Fight Influenza. Ask your landlord for your free vaccine now." Then from the corner of the room, the prostitute pipes up, impatiently waving a cigarette at Lilly.</context>
      <utterance>There's only one other thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROSTITUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cut to</context>
      <utterance>Oi! How about me? He promised me some of that. I earned it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones is eating some kind of pie that is an affront to culinary art.</context>
      <utterance>Come one!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ensconced in the back Lilly shakes her head, no.</context>
      <utterance>Lil', you want some?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is watching the patterns of street lights that play and flow over the wet windows of the car. Jones shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Smells terrible.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not letting that scum put me off my food. That'd be like a moral victory.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll get out here.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones watches Lilly move off; something like compassion crosses his features.</context>
      <utterance>What's up with her?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jones? Is she alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Lilly's kid. It died of the influenza, didn't it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's never said anything about a kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones stares after Lilly, then starts chomping into his food.</context>
      <utterance>No. She never says anything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MAN IN THE STREET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kid struggles and the Man now sees the shape of the woman in the alleyway, slumped to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Where are you going in such a hurry my little ruffian? Pilfering by the look of you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN THE STREET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on here? What'd you do to her?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man moves forward, dragging the kid. And he sees the woman there, deathly white in the alley. Dead eyes staring.</context>
      <utterance>Don't, I didn't do nothing. It was a Brother. It was a Brother did it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN THE STREET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cut to</context>
      <utterance>Oh dear god...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see the faces of the children, rapt.</context>
      <utterance>He deciphered that the Brothers were a new race of beings, sent by god, to serve and protect you.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>De Angelo formed the church of the Brotherhood. He was a great great man, but there were others, bad men, who took what De Angelo had discovered and experimented without concern for the results. The science of genetics and all its power has been banned ever since. Who can tell me what came from these bad experiments? One child puts his hand up. Behind the child, in the distance, Augustus now sees Silus approaching; Silus obviously wants to talk to Augustus. Augustus points to the child while looking at Silus.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHILD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Augustus nods, watching Silus' ominous expression.</context>
      <utterance>All the bad things. Like bad germs and flu.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Augustus looks at the child and tries to smile.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All the bad things.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lilly and Jones move towards the police cordon. Immediately a reporter accosts them.</context>
      <utterance>Someone should flatten this cesspool and start again.</utterance>
   <speaker>STREET REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marm? The Tribune. Do you have any comments on the death?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>STREET REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lilly stares at the reporter, pauses for thought. She whistles to one of the cops nearby, who then approaches.</context>
      <utterance>They're saying it was a Brother, is that true?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones and Lilly push past as the reporter protests at being manhandled.</context>
      <utterance>Arrest her.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones nods and moves over to a policeman guarding the alley. Lilly ducks under the crime scene tape, moving into the alley.</context>
      <utterance>Find any witnesses and shut them up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I step in?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORENSIC GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With the traffic. What's it matter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DOMINIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lil'.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello Dominic.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMINIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dominic bends down and moves the dead woman's head, displaying the side of her neck. A bite has torn the skin on the side of her neck. The wound extends down, the carotid artery sliced in two.</context>
      <utterance>Have you seen it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMINIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a bite. If you know what I mean? Lilly nods, then looks down at the woman's dead, cockeyed stare. Lilly closes the woman's eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is passed a bloody ID. Lilly stares at it.</context>
      <utterance>Any identification?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones now arrives.</context>
      <utterance>Tanya Garfield.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No one answers. Jones shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Where do you get a cup of tea around here?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a kid who saw it, down there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lilly nods.</context>
      <utterance>Says it was a Brother. And they've got another fellow, that's all who saw it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All the police officers stare at her; they know what she means alright.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, we'll close this down gents. None of you are to say a word, not even to your old mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones shrugs and nods. Lilly gets up and moves towards the street kid who is being talked to by two burly, grumpy policemen. The boy is shaking.</context>
      <utterance>Jones. Make sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He saw what happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lilly looks at the boy. So young.</context>
      <utterance>Now he wont talk. Didn't see anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kid doesn't answer and gets a whack around the ears from one of the policemen.</context>
      <utterance>What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lilly stares at the kid, as if the way he looks has keyed a memory in her. She squats and looks him straight in the eye.</context>
      <utterance>Stop that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your name then?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Albert.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kid looks nervous. Lilly moves some of the bedraggled hair out of the kid's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>You live around here?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I grew up 3 streets from here. Matheson Lane. The Skrummers Workhouse.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kid smiles. Lilly focuses on him now.</context>
      <utterance>Or should I say, I crawled out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kid stares at her; she's a magician and he's a believer.</context>
      <utterance>No one else will do anything about this, you know? They just think this is a slum. No one really cares what happens to the people here. Except for you. And me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you see?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A man.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of man?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A Brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're sure it was a Brother?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He had teeth and everything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kid turns and points to the shear wall of the alley.</context>
      <utterance>Where did he go?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lilly stares at the wall.</context>
      <utterance>He went straight up there.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rises.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, you go with these men, they'll look after you. I promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Policemen grunt and begin to lead the kid off.</context>
      <utterance>Get him to describe it all. And keep him away from everyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones, now standing next to Lilly, moans.</context>
      <utterance>And get him some food.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lilly looks at Jones's callous face; she's not amused. Cut to</context>
      <utterance>Now they'll all want feeding.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As far as anyone knows we have a new influenza outbreak.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the telephonic companies?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anderson nods.</context>
      <utterance>They're cooperating, closing all phone lines in and out except directly to us.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She does.</context>
      <utterance>Sit, sit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've done well Lilly. The reporter is more of a problem. We have 2 days by law before we have to release her. Then it's out. Anderson lays down the medi kit and stares at it as he motions for her to sit. She does.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate these things. I'm like a pin cushion.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's better than the alternative, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>26</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anderson stares at her; a moment of tension.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lilly acknowledges the compliment.</context>
      <utterance>I need you to stay with this, Lilly. You know Jamestown better than anyone, how to handle the people.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Brothers have requested to be involved with the investigation.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's nice for them.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have a problem with it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not particularly.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. I think they can help. And I don't want someone working on this whose got something against the Church.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know I don't?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cut to</context>
      <utterance>Lilly, you're the least prejudiced person I know. In fact, you're the only one I know. That's important. The church is powerful, but more than that, people's faith in the Brotherhood is about all they've got these days. And the government knows it. Even the Queen herself is involved. This is political.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>STEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know who he is? That's Brother Silus. They say one day he will lead the Brotherhood. He's a great man.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Steph flashes Jones a resentful look.</context>
      <utterance>I think I hear choir music.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you respect anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cut to</context>
      <utterance>Hey. My old mum goes to church four times a week and gives blood. She's happy as a lark. Just don't expect me to kiss him, that's all I'm telling you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silus opposite Lilly, his perfect, serene appearance an anathema in the grunge of the Jamestown police station. He watches her very carefully, listens to the way her finger taps the sheet in front of her, the sound of her chair swiveling, all the sounds very acute to him; she has a physical ease about her.</context>
      <utterance>Senior Brother Edgar... How long have you known about this?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lilly smiles.</context>
      <utterance>A matter of weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lilly stops smiling. For the first time she is still.</context>
      <utterance>Is there something wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silus nods.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Withholding evidence. Covering up two murders. And no one's worried. If me or one of the people in Jamestown did that they'd be in the hell house with the key thrown away. It seems the church is able to do whatever it wants.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lilly becomes more interested at this; at the bald honesty of the statement.</context>
      <utterance>You're right to not like it. It is political.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The greatest danger is if this were to become public knowledge.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't want anyone criticizing the church I suppose.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's more than that Captain. This is about prejudice, or rather the nature of it. As a female surely you would understand.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many other Captains in this borough are female?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>None?</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lilly stares at Silus; he is an incredible being.</context>
      <utterance>How are your actions judged, the same or differently from the men.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Differently.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lilly nods, acknowledging the truth of it.</context>
      <utterance>Exactly. If a white man kills, then he is just a killer. If a black man kills, then all black men are suspect. That is the nature of prejudice. Those who are different are grouped together. If only one Brother does a bad thing then all Brothers are suspect, because we are different. And then what would this world be like, if there was no hope?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright then. So what do you suggest?</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cut to</context>
      <utterance>First, there is something you should hear.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone nods and shuts up as Lilly stands in front of the men.</context>
      <utterance>Ok, ok, quiet down.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There are guffaws from most of the policemen.</context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen, there's no other way to put it. We have only 2 days to find the suspect.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no chance. Not a hope in hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's right. We don't even know where to begin.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lilly is angry. There is silence in the room. Lilly seems more angry than she should be.</context>
      <utterance>Quiet!</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>What you are about to hear will not leave this room. Everyone understand? Jones?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No one moves. They all stare at Lilly.</context>
      <utterance>I would suggest anyone with a weak stomach leave now.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She motions to Silus, who rises, watching the glares from the cops who eye him like a suspect.</context>
      <utterance>This is Brother Silus.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you Captain. Could we have the plate?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Senior Brother Edgar. Until 3 weeks ago, he was a trusted and talented theologian and scientist.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMINIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd he do?</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>3 photos come up. The victims.</context>
      <utterance>He was personally responsible for developing the most recent influenza antivirals. It is because of him that most of you are alive today. His behavior appeared normal. Next.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A Map.</context>
      <utterance>The victims. John Anderson. Julie Danes. Tanya Garfield. All in their early 20's, but beyond that no obvious connection. Next.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is no precedent for Brother Edgar's behavior. No Brother has ever taken a human life, not in the 300 years since we began. Not one. Our role has been to preserve and maintain the human life. Not take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silus stares directly at Jones now. Their eyes lock. Silus continues, perfectly calm.</context>
      <utterance>Next he'll be wanting an fucking medal.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I am saying to you is that Brother Edgar's behavior is aberrant. We</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>don't understand it. And therefore it's difficult to predict. The only thing we know is where he will strike next.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMINIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silus moves to the desk next to him. He passes something to another cop who now sits at the desk. We see Lilly now. The look on her face tells us that she knows what is coming and she's not looking forward to it. We see what Silus gave the cop. An audio tape. The cop places the tape in a tape deck. He then switches it on. He then turns the volume knob on an amplifier which now directs static hiss to two big speakers. We see the faces of the cops, all listening in the dim light coming from the slide projector. Above the level of the hissing tape there is another noise. It is a wet sound. Like a cat would make if it were lapping up milk. An another sound. Like an animal, moaning with pleasure. We see the cops; some of them are beginning to twig. And there is another noise. It is a man; moaning.</context>
      <utterance>How do you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quiet.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN ON THE TAPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please...</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then we hear a punch and then noises which can only be described as sounding like a dog killing something. Jones springs out of his seat.</context>
      <utterance>I said shut up!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck!</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jones, sit down.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are we listening to this?!</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones stands there enraged. Dominic pulls him down back into his chair. All the cops are appalled by what they have heard. And then a voice.</context>
      <utterance>Quiet!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We can hear Edgar moving around.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Now you're quiet.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see Silus, listening as intently as everyone else.</context>
      <utterance>Did you hear that Silus? I hope so.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More moving around, then the sound on the tape cuts out. We are left with only tape hiss. Everyone stares at Silus.</context>
      <utterance>The next one will be tomorrow. There is a square, Bridge Square it's called. I will take the next one from there. You should try harder this time. Please try harder...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He sent this to you. Specifically.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cops all stare at Silus' emotionless response.</context>
      <utterance>We share the same mother. There is a bond.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank nods.</context>
      <utterance>There will be two teams. Frank, I want you and Abernathy up in the buildings around Bridge Square.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll lead the other team with Dominic, Jones and Queen's Imperial Guard in support. No guns, batons only.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You heard me. He's to be taken alive.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silus surveys the scene. He can see an Imperial Guard sniper over the square on the roof of a building. Below, in the street, we can see the silhouettes of several Brothers; unmoving, watchful sentinels.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's getting late.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He will come.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lilly closes the com. Jones is staring at her.</context>
      <utterance>Ok. We'll sit tight.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lilly ignores Jones and talks into the RT again.</context>
      <utterance>This is a dud.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cut to</context>
      <utterance>Frank?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah Lil'.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not a thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank motions to Abernathy, who is already sighing.</context>
      <utterance>Check each floor again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's on the sixth floor! He's on the sixth floor!</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone fires into action and begins to exit the van.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then another crash on the door. Edgar drops Lilly. He propels himself towards a ventilation grill on the wall. Cut to Jones and the cops kicking the door in. It swings open to show Lilly on the floor. Jones stoops down.</context>
      <utterance>You're so strong.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones gets close to Lilly, starts squeezing the side of her neck, trying to stop the arterial blood from squirting her life away.</context>
      <utterance>Lilly!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dominic enters and sees the scene. He yells into his RT.</context>
      <utterance>Oh shit shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMINIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other cops are now scanning the room. Meanwhile Dominic has found the ventilation shaft, blood smeared around the opening.</context>
      <utterance>Lilly's hurt. She's hurt!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMINIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's in the ventilation shaft!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment SILUS appears at the door. Silus stares at Lilly, bleeding to death in Jones' arms. Silus immediately bends to her. With his free hand Jones pulls out a vicious knife which he points at Silus.</context>
      <utterance>She's dying! She's fucking dying!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Silus ignores the knife and moves closer to Lilly.</context>
      <utterance>Get away from her!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get away or I'll stick you!</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones wavers.</context>
      <utterance>Do you want me to save her?</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones backs the knife away. Silus whips his hand to the blade of the knife, slashing his wrist, blood immediately issuing from the wound. He presses his bleeding wrist to Lilly's mouth. At first resistant, Lilly begins to suck at the wrist. Jones is appalled. Silus then leans close to Lilly and whispers in her ear. All the other noises in the soundtrack drop out.</context>
      <utterance>She is dying.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DOMINIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's getting away!!</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quiet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get out of my way.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones stares at Silus and contemplates firing.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silus doesn't move. He stares calmly at Jones. Jones points the gun in Silus' face. Beat.</context>
      <utterance>He killed Lilly.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bang.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silus nods. He slowly sits on the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Antibiotics. They say it's like an animal bite.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We all caught Edgar.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't mean that. The blood, they say it saved my life. Is it true that people who go to church are given your blood?</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes the rituals call for it. Some say they have visions from it. That it restores their health.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns over his hand to reveal the wrist; the scars are almost gone from where Silus cut himself.</context>
      <utterance>So smooth.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Healed already.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She releases his hand.</context>
      <utterance>In some ways my body is like a human embryo. The cells regenerate quickly. It is why we live so long. Will someone come for you? Your family?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have one. Not any more.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Influenza. My husband was quick. But my daughter, Mary, her little body fought it for a long time. So I just waited. Hoped. But then you realize how cruel hope is. And you just want it to end. Not to stop her suffering, but to stop my own.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do we seem pathetic to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But you fight back.</context>
      <utterance>No. Fragile. Worn down by nature.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lilly stares up into Silus' serene face. Silus smiles. Then stands.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. We're good at that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lilly tries to smile as Silus turns and walks off down the ward. Close on Lilly who looks grim. Then she turns to the window. Rain again, blowing hard against the pane.</context>
      <utterance>I think yours will be a good life to watch, Lilly. Goodbye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silus shakes the Professor's hand. We see the hands touching, then slide apart with a wisping sound that makes the Professor wince a little.</context>
      <utterance>Silus. You know Professor Liepsky.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR LIEPSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He taps one of the men at the console on the shoulder. The man hits a button and we see that in front of the console there is a huge glass window and beyond it a room which is now lit. Edgar is in there. And Edgar is not pleased. Even from here his glowering stare penetrates everyone in the room. From this distance we can't make out much, beyond the fact that Edgar is seated in a chair, in an otherwise plain white room. Around his chair is a strange "brace" of sorts, that seems to be holding Edgar in place.</context>
      <utterance>See for yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is the brace necessary?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He decapitated a guard as they brought him in. Even though he was sedated. He said he will drink us all dry.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Insane then.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PROFESSOR LIEPSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silus now turns to the Professor.</context>
      <utterance>Not quite.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR LIEPSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's become infected.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Professor looks to Augustus, as if worried he's said to much.</context>
      <utterance>With what?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cut to</context>
      <utterance>Go on, Brother Silus will soon be part of the inner circle of the Brotherhood. He should know this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PROFESSOR LIEPSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silus quietly turns to the Professor.</context>
      <utterance>If she wasn't restrained she would try to kill you. Don't worry, it's only transmissible through their blood. We designed it that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Designed?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PROFESSOR LIEPSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Genetically designed. Edgar was experimenting with the virus that created you. It was sanctioned by the government.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since when do they sanction such things?</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR LIEPSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since not one Brother has been born in 70 years. And never a female of your kind from which we could breed. And we need to breed more Brothers. You give the world hope. To the people you're like gods walking the earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silus is now turns back to the poor creature on the bed.</context>
      <utterance>This is what Edgar was doing Silus. Trying to genetically control the birth of Brothers.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR LIEPSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silus places his hand on the poor creature's head, blessing her.</context>
      <utterance>And Edgar was successful. Each of these women carried a Brother, for a time. But, the virus... changed. Most of them have died and these will die soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR LIEPSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Edgar may be the first Brother to ever die.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The police officer. Lilly. Did he infect her with this?</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR LIEPSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. She was lucky. But it is in Edgar's blood. It always will be. ...and another door in front of Silus clicks, then slides open to reveal...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves again, as if enjoying it.</context>
      <utterance>Do you like what they've done for me Silus?</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are sick. We will help you if we can.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edgar leans closer to Silus.</context>
      <utterance>Help me? I am being what I was meant to be. How can you help me from that? Or do you want to tame me? Brainwash me? Animal or vegetable, are those the two choices, Silus?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to share the feeling with you. To feel their blood flow until every last drop is yours, until that weak, pointless little pump finally stops. They are staring at each other very intently now. Edgar smiles gently.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edgar moves.</context>
      <utterance>The one I had, the police woman. She was so strong. I found it hard to leave her.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is she dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She survived.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For perhaps the first time, we see a real hint of anger on Silus' face.</context>
      <utterance>Good. I will have her again.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You won't touch her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silus' control has returned now.</context>
      <utterance>You've chosen to watch over her. You want her don't you? I can see it in your eyes. You are like me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silus then turns and leaves.</context>
      <utterance>I will pray for your cure, Brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves violently, blood seeping from his wounds now.</context>
      <utterance>I wont be able to forgive you for this you know? Not ever. In fact, when I get out of here...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CONSOLE OPERATOR 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't like it when he does that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSOLE OPERATOR 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You stop that or we'll use the gas!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones nods as Lilly walks off.</context>
      <utterance>Take them away from here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Lilly doesn't respond, she just walks off. Jones watches her leave. Then he stares at the round faces of the children in front of him, something approaching compassion there.</context>
      <utterance>You don't feel like a drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now my girls, anyone hungry?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lilly turns to Jones.</context>
      <utterance>I knocked.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Steph now emerges from the kitchen, dressed in a t-shirt and shorts and carrying some food. Jones looks at her coldly.</context>
      <utterance>You nearly gave me a heart attack.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lilly and Steph smile at the inference Jones is beginning to draw.</context>
      <utterance>What's this then?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meanwhile Lilly shushes them and turns back to the murky gray images emitting from the television.</context>
      <utterance>My apartment was condemned, keep your hair on, what's left of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TV PRESENTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones and Lilly watch as Silus is seen on the television in an interview. Steph stares at the screen with awe, she involuntarily kisses the symbol that hangs from a chain around her neck; it resembles a Brother's ring.</context>
      <utterance>...the ascension through the ranks of the Church has been fast for Brother Silus. He will now be the highest ranking cardinal outside the ruling council of the Brotherhood. This is largely seen as a reward for his handling of the last influenza pandemic.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones sneers under his breath.</context>
      <utterance>Isn't he amazing?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A saint.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We move over their shoulders to track closer to the black and white TV screen.</context>
      <utterance>Quiet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TV PRESENTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have been an opponent of those who want an easing in the ban on genetic research.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>TV PRESENTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They would say you're denying legitimate research into a science that would change the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The church does not deny the potential. Only the motivations of those who want to exploit it. And the fact that we understand so little of its power.</utterance>
   <speaker>TV PRESENTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she is saying this we are now close on the TV's speaker. We then begin tracking out. We reveal the speaker is not part of the TV, but the speaker in Edgar's cell. Edgar, smiling coldly as he listens. As he listens he is gently gliding his finger nails against a sharp edge of the chair; sharpening them.</context>
      <utterance>With the elimination of influenza, are we approaching a new era where disease might be a thing of the past?</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Close on Edgar.</context>
      <utterance>Disease is part of nature, it will always be a part of our lives.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How true.</utterance>
   <speaker>TV PRESENTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edgar listens, smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Brother Silus' confirmation ceremony will be held today in the sacred Chapel of St. Augustine where all the Brotherhood will gather.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silus raises his head. We see his face. He takes the bowl, drinks and then stands, holding it up to the other Brothers.</context>
      <utterance>The blood flows, through them, to us and we preserve them, preserve the blood we are bound to protect.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cut to</context>
      <utterance>Let the blood be one and the two races join, as the Perfect Creature.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Today my brother enters the history books, Professor.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR LIEPSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a moment, Edgar slowly walks backward in perfectly smooth movements.</context>
      <utterance>Move back!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the far wall Edgar begins to glide forward, first in slow motion then ramping up to full speed, launching himself at the glass window. He bounces off it, leaving blood and saliva there. The Professor and the console operator share an unsettled glance. Edgar slowly stands. He stares very intently at the glass window in front of him. We zoom in on the glass. The small hair line fracture we saw previously now begins to lengthen before our eyes. Edgar's face. A smile. Then he is forward at high velocity before anything else can happen, smashing once more into the glass window, this time shattering it into a thousand tiny pieces.</context>
      <utterance>Tonight all the Brothers will be with him. A perfect day for me to celebrate.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We are left with Silus' beautiful, reflective eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Now he carries this thing out into the world. Can you imagine what will happen if he infects others? Or if the experiments were known.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cut to</context>
      <utterance>The question becomes what will he do next? He said he would kill us all. But especially the police officer. Lilly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PROSTITUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on governor, you going to pay me or not?</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sucks on something that looks like a ventaline inhaler, then pockets it, licks his lips and begins heading off down the street, the drunk Prostitute dragged along. Cut to Again, Lilly from a distance, walking along the street which is more deserted, now carrying a bag full of groceries. As she walks we begin to hear voices; violent, arguing. Lilly approaches an alleyway, the raised voices becoming louder. She slowly places her bag on the ground and then pulls out a revolver. She edges into the alleyway.</context>
      <utterance>Soon enough my cherub. I've not finished with you yet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've been ripping me off! I should blow your dirty little brains out!</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's ok. I'm complying officer, see.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put the gun on the ground and step away!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Freddy puts the gun down. The Prostitute on the ground now scrambles to her feet and heads towards Steph.</context>
      <utterance>I'm doing it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROSTITUTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives Freddy the finger then heads off.</context>
      <utterance>He's crazy! Fucking crazy!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Freddy gets down.</context>
      <utterance>Wait!  Down! Right now, down on the ground!</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Low Angle on Steph approaching. Behind her a FIGURE is descending the wall behind him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm getting wet now.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Steph is over Freddy now. He's staring up at her. He can see that a shape has appeared behind Steph. EDGAR, his eyes gleaming. Steph pulls out some handcuffs.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put your hands behind your back.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But before Steph can move forward, Edgar has her gun hand in a vice-like grip. She cries out in pain as her wrist disintegrates. As a reflex she stamps on Edgar's foot and kicks him in the groin with her other. He does not flinch. He smashes Steph into a down pipe on the wall of the alley so that wet grit is ground into her face. We then see Edgar's face at her shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Sure. Anything you say.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edgar pulls back the jacket at Steph's neck to find no scars. He pulls Steph's face towards him brutally, staring at her profile.</context>
      <utterance>Nice to meet you again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You brought me the wrong one.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edgar's stare makes Freddy shut up and avert his eyes. Edgar then turns on the tube on his arm so that blood drips into the unconscious Steph's mouth; making her gag.</context>
      <utterance>Does it matter, one's as good as the next?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For a moment Edgar strokes Freddy's hair, then rips the tube away.</context>
      <utterance>What do you see Freddy. Visions? Can you see your future?</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Freddy moves forward, but is pushed back by Edgar.</context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Close on Edgar, his repellent features under the hood. He looks up. Far above, through the falling rain, past the high- rise slum around them; we see the moon hanging like a pearly crescent in the sky. The moon is slowly obscured by clouds.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be a greedy little pig Freddy. You have to earn more.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cut to</context>
      <utterance>We have more to do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PARISHONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lilly grabs Silus' shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Holy brother, please...</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shows Silus the pamphlet.</context>
      <utterance>Let him go.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARISHONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then Silus reaches out and places his hand on the man's head.</context>
      <utterance>Forgive me. I've offended you... We see Silus' dark stare. A beat.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silus rises, the Parishioner just lays there in awe. Silus now turns to Lilly who is on his shoulder. And now Lilly realizes for the first time that it is Silus.</context>
      <utterance>No. You are divine. It is the world that offends me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We then hear a police siren and a car pulls up through the rain. The door opens and Jones emerges, taking in both Lilly and Silus. A grim smile of realization comes to Jones' face. He pulls something from his jacket. Cut to</context>
      <utterance>Brother Silus. What's going on?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A shopkeeper heard yelling. Went to see, found this. One witness. A prostitute. Jones tosses down a photo. It is Freddy, looking suitably scummy in a police identikit photo.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silus stands by the window; lights make patterns on his face.</context>
      <utterance>She identified this lovely citizen. We thought maybe he had a grudge or was crazy. I guess we were wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is Edgar.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And now he's got Steph. Why does he want her?</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see Lilly slowly getting it.</context>
      <utterance>She is not what he was after.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silus now turns, slowly moves towards her, coming out of the shadows. Lilly finds it hard to return his gaze, involuntarily touches her neck where it is scarred from Edgar's attack. Jones is watching all this very carefully.</context>
      <utterance>Steph was staying with me. She was wearing my coat. It was me he was after. Wasn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. He will come for you Lilly.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right, then we put you somewhere safe and set up this place. Shooters on the roofs. And when he comes we blow his fucking brains out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He will know. He will see and hear it.</utterance>
   <speaker>72</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lilly is staring at Steph's ID.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It has to be me. That's what he wants. It's the only chance Steph's got.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about, she's probably dead already...</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones is shaking his head. Silus just stares at Lilly.</context>
      <utterance>Jones! And we can't make it too hard. He has to be able to get in. He can't suspect anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Close on Silus.</context>
      <utterance>That's the way it will be. I'm the bait.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STEPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches for Freddy, but he pulls away. Freddy's not looking too hot either.</context>
      <utterance>Help me. Please, I'm sick. Help me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up the half filled cup and leaves. Steph stares after him. Tears welling in her eyes, beginning to shake now, moving against the chains that bind her. But they stay fast.</context>
      <utterance>Don't fucking touch me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His voice echoes through the empty space.</context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where've you gone now?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edgar's nose is bleeding. He dabs some on his fingers, then raises his hand to Silus.</context>
      <utterance>When will you admit it. You're just like me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lilly then moves into the adjacent alleyway to search for Edgar.</context>
      <utterance>Get him down.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns and gives him a final quick look.</context>
      <utterance>Lilly, wait! Damn you. Lilly!</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cut to</context>
      <utterance>If he escapes then Steph is dead. Just follow me when you can, hurry!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The little policewoman.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edgar purposely raises his hand so that she fires; the bullet going through the flesh of Edgar's arm; his arm now smoking.</context>
      <utterance>Don't move!</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edgar can only smile.</context>
      <utterance>I said don't move. Where is she, where's the girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then he moves, she fires, but he's too fast, spinning, diving, in an instant he has the gun, twisting it and Lilly's arm behind her back. She fires, once, twice, the bullets and smoke rising up from Edgar's side. He twists harder, the gun then falling to the ground. Edgar is now behind her. He moves his face close to hers.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I've killed her already. Essentially.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lilly tries to twist out of his grasp.</context>
      <utterance>Has he tasted you yet, little policewoman?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's just the same as me, you know it, you can feel it too.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edgar's face twists into a smile.</context>
      <utterance>He's nothing like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We will see. You will be my tool.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>80</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cut to Silus and Jones entering the alleyway, the cat tearing away from them in fright. Jones moves forward and we tilt down to see Lilly's gun lying on the wet cobblestones, smoke wisping from the barrel. Jones stoops down and picks up the gun, then turns to Silus. After a beat, Jones throws the gun at Silus' head. Silus dodges it easily and it clacks onto the cobblestones.</context>
      <utterance>A cat, hissing, screeching.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cut to</context>
      <utterance>You happy now?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edgar approaches, still silhouetted.</context>
      <utterance>You scared the shit out of me. Hey, the police woman. She's real sick. To tell the truth I don't feel so hot myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to take her and put her where they'll find her.</utterance>
   <speaker>FREDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edgar moves incredibly fast, we can't quite see what he has done but we suspect he has just buried his hand in Freddy's chest. We see Freddy's face, stunned, deathly white.</context>
      <utterance>But I'm sick. She's given me something...</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Freddy falls, leaving Edgar's hand in mid air; we can't see clearly, but it likes frighteningly like he has one of Freddy's internal organs in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>What have I said to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cut to</context>
      <utterance>I hate arguments.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then a scream. Blood curdling; the sound of someone insane, screaming their lungs out, hurling abuse. We see the faces of the cops and the terrified nurse in front of them who points down the hall where the noise is coming from. The Cops move off. The nurse then sees someone else arrive. She raises the pendant that hangs around her neck and kisses it.</context>
      <utterance>Stephanie Richards, you just brought her in.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see who has entered. It is Silus. Near him there are several people sick. They look sick; like Steph and Freddy looked. Cut to</context>
      <utterance>Thank god you're here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Doctor turns to Jones; the Doctor looks puzzled.</context>
      <utterance>Will she recover?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones turns to Silus.</context>
      <utterance>No. Containment is the issue now. She is... insane. And we've had more cases, 10 in the last hour. The Doctor leaves.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this? What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It comes from Edgar. He has shared his blood with them.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones gets close to Silus, intimidating.</context>
      <utterance>You're telling me that he's out there spreading this around?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dominic gets in between.</context>
      <utterance>He'll give it to Lilly!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMINIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dominic pushes Jones back and then stares at Silus.</context>
      <utterance>Jones! Back off.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMINIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silus doesn't speak, just stares at Steph.</context>
      <utterance>This is spreading.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMINIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brother Silus?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it, Lilly's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. He will keep her alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMINIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dominic pulls an envelope from his jacket and passes it to Silus, who opens it to discover a beautifully handwritten letter.</context>
      <utterance>So that I will come for him. That's what he wants.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMINIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silus stares at the two men. Then turns to Steph, her eyes, creepy, still locked on Silus.</context>
      <utterance>It says, "Everything flows from me. My blood will change the world." What does that mean?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It almost sounds like children playing, don't you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lilly's features tense.</context>
      <utterance>I looked at your body. You have borne a child.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you abandon it? Your kind are good at that. Even though her position is impossible, Lilly won't show Edgar fear.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edgar just smiles. Lilly spits in his face and screams at him.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you just kill me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edgar grabs her by the throat, for a moment anger boils out of Edgar, but he restrains himself.</context>
      <utterance>Kill me!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Join me.</context>
      <utterance>I can see why he likes you. But I have a better use for you. To save you, Silus will take my blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're insane.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then Edgar's face changes; he stares at her with pity, for a moment we see a hint of the noble creature he used to be.</context>
      <utterance>The world is insane. I am better than you. But they force me to serve you. Does that happen in a sane world? Forced to watch you waste the most precious thing you have. Life.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lilly senses an opening.</context>
      <utterance>Do you know what they do to us when we are born? They take us from our mothers. Force us into a life of loneliness, and denial. Can you imagine a life like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edgar places his head in his hands, he seems to be weeping.</context>
      <utterance>You don't have to do this. You can change things.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When he looks back up at her, he is terrifying to behold.</context>
      <utterance>You have reminded me of something.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I must search out my mother, if she still lives. And kill her for what she did.</utterance>
   <speaker>86</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We are left with Lilly bound to the rusty pipes. She strains, tries to pull her hands from the chains, but they won't move. Above her on the pipe there is a old rusty bracket. Lilly blinks through the sweat running into her eyes. She moves the chains that bind her hands closer to the bracket and begins rubbing the chains against the bracket in the vain hope that she may be able to cut her way through the chains. She strains harder and harder, fighting back the tears, the fear, she just grinds at the chain repetitively. Cut to</context>
      <utterance>Edgar smiles quietly, rises and exits.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Augustus turns to Silus. Augustus moves closer to him, stares into Silus' strange, pale eyes.</context>
      <utterance>He is somewhere in the quarantine zone. I will find him.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Augustus moves off to his desk. Silus is shocked.</context>
      <utterance>Clear. So very clear your eyes. The way they were when you were born. There will be no search.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No search?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Queen has instructed the government to evacuate the city around the quarantine zone. In another day they will take action.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of action?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Including Edgar.</context>
      <utterance>Eradication. Of everything within the area. They will burn it all.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the innocents there, who are not infected?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is a necessary step. We cannot let this escape.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Augustus looks up at Silus; this is perhaps the first time Silus has refused anything that Augustus has decreed.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it the policewoman? Is this affecting your thinking? There is no love for our kind Silus. Only service.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have done this. Released this thing into the world. We have betrayed their trust in us, more than once. I won't do it again.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silus shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>There is no debate. They will be sacrificed, so the rest will be pure.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silus watches Augustus very carefully.</context>
      <utterance>This policeman, Jones. He talked to the press. Told them this came from Edgar.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Augustus moves close to Silus now. Gently touches his face.</context>
      <utterance>There are members of the inner circle who question the way you have handled this. Blame you for this man's actions. I have made it clear that you will fix this. That you will silence him.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUGUSTUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are hard things we do. But you must think of the greater good. And of your own future. Cut to A light bulb flickering.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones begins to stomp down the hall, towards the part of the hall that is lit. Then pop, that light goes out as well. Jones stops. He pulls out his big gun from his armpit holster. He checks over his shoulder, and then with the gun extended he moves slowly forward. He approaches an area that opens up a little. He pauses, then under his breath.</context>
      <utterance>Great.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He launches himself around the corner and fires his gun. He's lucky that his misses his target. A small, dirty, cowering boy with his fingers on the bank of light switches. The wall next to the boy's head has exploded; dust and wall board now drift down like snow. Jones can only stare at the quivering child whose dirty face blank with fright. Then Jones turns. He can make out a figure in the dark hall. A patient, quiet sentinel.</context>
      <utterance>Come on then...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to help you. They know you talked to the press.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones takes a slurp on his drink.</context>
      <utterance>They can fuck off. For that matter, so can you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd be the last person I'd trust.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silus doesn't answer now. Jones moves forward.</context>
      <utterance>I saw you. Remember. Watching Lilly, when she was asleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones prods Silus' shoulder with the gun.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe you're just like your Brother. Maybe you're helping him. Now there's a thought.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones prods again and finds Silus' elegant steel fingers around his wrist. The two men face off.</context>
      <utterance>Do you know where she is?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cut to</context>
      <utterance>Coffee's ready.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's the quarantine zone. It's a pit. Slums.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones searches and then pin points an area in the center of the quarantine zone.</context>
      <utterance>The water supply. Where is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men stare at each other, both reaching the same conclusion.</context>
      <utterance>There, all the old suburbs are supplied by their own artesian wells. Mineral springs. That's why it hasn't broken out of Jamestown, it's the water. Jamestown's water.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see the Map.</context>
      <utterance>He is there, with Lilly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silus turns to Jones.</context>
      <utterance>You'll never get in, they've circled the whole borough.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will get in. You must go to the press. Tell them about the water. Tell them what the government will do.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silus smiles.</context>
      <utterance>You're dead after this. You know that? Whatever happens.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watch for me, Officer Jones.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PRIEST 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who has done this, Brother?</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have. To our shame.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PRIEST 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silus watches the baby carefully.</context>
      <utterance>It is a miracle my Brother. She is a female, the first of our kind.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He then turns to the Priest.</context>
      <utterance>She must be protected.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would ask for your help Brother. The Church can no longer be trusted...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EDGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edgar takes one more blinking look at Lilly and then leaves, slamming the large iron door behind him. Lilly pulls at the chains, hoping against hope that they'll break. They don't.</context>
      <utterance>He's coming little one. He's coming for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She now looks above. The pipe her chains are connected to runs up towards the roof, then takes a bend to disappear into the wall near the door. She bangs on the pipe. There is a little movement where it goes into the wall. Just enough to give her some hope. Lilly struggles now to her feet. She slides the chains up. To get the chains over the bend she'll have to jump. She does, sliding the chain over the bend. Now she hangs from the pipe, the chains cutting into her wrists viciously, making her groan. She then gets her hands on the pipe and begins sliding along the pipe until she is near the door. She then reaches up with her feet and kicks at the wall, pushing, trying to dislodge the pipe. It moves, water leaks from it. But it does not give way. A desperate beat. Then she reaches down to the door with her foot. She tries to force down the door handle, her foot wet and slippery. Finally she gets the handle down, opens the door so that it clangs against the wall.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silus is pointing to a fallen down building through the haze and the rain.</context>
      <utterance>In there.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there something wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gently touches her mud smeared face.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don't let them touch it.</context>
      <utterance>There is something very precious. You must take it, keep it secret.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PRIEST 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lilly moves forward. Emotional music rises in the soundtrack; evoking memory, the circle completing. Lilly reaches out, letting the baby girl grip her hand. Lilly reaches into the crate, drawing the baby into her arms, staring down into the baby's face; a face somehow already wise, already serene. Broken tears run down Lilly's cheek as she presses the baby to herself, all the pain of the past flooding over her, the baby's tiny hands reaching out, clasping onto her.</context>
      <utterance>The first female of her kind. The first daughter given to us.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cut to</context>
      <utterance>Come. Before they find her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PRIEST 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a final pause Lilly moves off with the Priest, carrying the tiny bundle with her.</context>
      <utterance>We must go.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For me, everything has changed now. Because of Silus I see the world through new eyes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>He can see the lounge. Jones is there with Lilly. Lilly is dressed to go out; to leave. Jones and Lilly hug. Then Jones picks up two suitcases and moves towards the door. Silus watches as Lilly moves into the bedroom and reaches down for the tiny baby, its tiny arms clasping onto her as she lifts it.</context>
      <utterance>Now I see hope, and I see a child, the first female of her kind. Silus scans the apartment.</utterance>
   <speaker>LILLY</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps Edgar got what he wanted after all, because it time this child will truly change our world.</utterance>
   <speaker>107</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lilly, pausing, moving to the window of her apartment, staring out into the night, almost directly toward Silus. She raises her hand, as if in a gesture of goodbye and then she leaves. Cut to Silus, close, nodding.</context>
      <utterance>We see Silus, closer, watching. Cut to</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
