<movie id="436" title="Pirates of the Caribbean">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JOSHAMEE GIBBS, who was born old, skin a dark leather, clutches her shoulder, startling her.</context>
      <utterance>...drink up me hearties, yo, ho...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth stares wide-eyed at him.</context>
      <utterance>Quiet, missy! Cursed pirates sail these waters. You want to call 'em down on us?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>NORRINGTON, a dashing young man, Royal Navy to the core, glares sternly at Gibbs. Standing besides him is GOVERNOR WEATHERBY SWAN, a man of obvious high station, brass buttons on his thick blue jacket. He is Elizabeth's father.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Gibbs.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That will do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was singing about pirates. Bad luck to sing about pirates, with us mired in this unnatural fog-- mark my words.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Consider them marked. On your way.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He returns to his deck-swabbing duties, surreptitiously takes a quick swig from flask.</context>
      <utterance>'Aye, Captain.  Bad luck to have a woman on board, too. Even a mini'ture one.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it would be rather exciting to meet a pirate.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth doesn't know what 'a short drop and a sudden stop' means. Gibbs helpfully mimes: a man being hung.</context>
      <utterance>Think again, Miss Swan. Vile and dissolute creatures, the lot of them. I intend to see to it that any man who sails under a pirate flag, or wears a pirates brand, gets what he deserves: a short drop and a sudden stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain Norrington... I appreciate your fervor, but I am concerned about the effect this subject will have on my daughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My apologies, Governor.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, I find it all fascinating.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chastised, she turns away, to look out over the bow rail.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, father.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Norrington and Swann spot him --</context>
      <utterance>Look! A boy! In the water!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man overboard!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy overboard!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quick movement and activity on the deck. Sailors use a boathook to snag the boy he the passes. Norrington and Swann haul him aboard, and lay him on the deck. Elizabeth sidles in for a closer look.</context>
      <utterance>Fetch a hook! Haul him out of there!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's still breathing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Attention is turned away from the boy -- The sea is no longer empty. WRECKAGE from a ship litters the water... along with the bodies of its crew. What is left of the ship's hull BURNS, a ragged British flag hanging limply from the stern. The H.M.S. Dauntless slips silently through it all. The scene calls for hushed voices.</context>
      <utterance>Mary mother of God ...</utterance>
   <speaker>SWAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened here?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merchant vessels run heavily armed.</context>
      <utterance>An explosion in the powder magazine.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lot of good it did them...  Everyone's thinking it! I'm just saying it! Pirates!</utterance>
   <speaker>SWAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is no proof of that. It could have been an accident. Captain, these men were protection. If there is even the slightest chance one of those poor devils is still alive, we cannot abandon them!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course not, Governor.  Come about and strike the sails! Unlash the boats! Gunnery crew... jackets off the cannons!  Hope for the best...prepare for the worst.  Move the boy aft. We'll need the deck clear.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SWAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth nods gravely. Swann hurries away to help unstow the longboat. The sailors lay the boy gently on the poop deck, behind the wheel, then hurry off. Elizabeth kneels down besides the boy. His good looks are not lost on her. She reaches out, gently brushes the blond hair from his eyes -- Suddenly, he grabs her wrist, awake now. Elizabeth is startled, but their eyes lock. She takes his hand in hers.</context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth, I want you to accompany the boy. He's in your charge now. You'll watch over him?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name is Elizabeth Swann.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will Turner.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He clutches her hands, then slips back into unconsciousness. His movement has opened the collar of his shirt; Elizabeth sees he wears a chain around his neck. She tugs it free, revealing-- A GOLD MEDALLION. One side is blank. She turns it over -- A SKULL gazes up at her. Vaguely Aztec in design, but to her eyes, it means one thing only:</context>
      <utterance>I'm watching over you, Will.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She glances back at the crew. Sees Norrington, giving orders, moving toward her. She looks back at Will -- comes to a quick decision. Takes the medallion from around his neck. Hides it under her coat.</context>
      <utterance>You're a pirate.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Norrington arrives.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did he speak?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His name is Will Turner -- that's all I found out.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norrington hurries off. Elizabeth steals away to the stern of the ship. Examines her prize -- the gold medallion. A wisp of wind, and she looks up -- Out over the sea, moving through the fog, silent as a ghost, is a large sailing ship, a schooner -- It has BLACK SAILS. Elizabeth stares, too frightened to move, or cry out. The ship is obscured by the fog it as it passes -- but not the mizzen-top ... and there hangs the frightening skull and crossbones of the Jolly Roger. Elizabeth looks from it to the medallion -- the skull on the flag is the same as the one on the medallion. Fog surrounds and closes in on the black ship -- except for the black flag. As Elizabeth watches, the skull appears to TURN and GRIN at her -- Elizabeth shuts her eyes tight --</context>
      <utterance>Very good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SWANN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth? Is everything all right? Are you decent?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts the medallion on, throws on a dressing gown as Swann enters, carrying a large box. A uniformed maid, ESTRELLA, follows.</context>
      <utterance>Yes -- yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Estrella pulls back the heavy curtains, revealing: Beneath a blue sky lies the bucolic town of PORT ROYAL, built on a natural harbor. On a bluff at the mouth of the harbor stands FORT CHARLES, its stone parapets lined with cannon.</context>
      <utterance>Still abed at this hour? It's a beautiful day!</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He opens the boxes, and displays for her a gorgeous velvet dress. She lets out an admiring gasp.</context>
      <utterance>I have a gift for you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SWANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth happily takes it, disappears behind a screened- off dressing area. Estrella follows, carrying the box.</context>
      <utterance>Is an occasion necessary for a father to dote upon his daughter with gifts?</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Although...I did think you could wear it to the ceremony today.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ceremony?</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth peeks around the screen.</context>
      <utterance>Captain Norrington's promotion ceremony.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind the screen, Elizabeth GASPS.</context>
      <utterance>Or, rather, Commodore Norrington...a fine gentleman, don't you think?  He fancies you, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>ON ELIZABETH -- She holds her hair and the medallion (still around her neck) out of the way as the maid cinches her into a corset over her slip. Estrella has her foot in Elizabeth's back as she pulls the laces tight.</context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth? How's it coming?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Difficult ... to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm told that dress is the very latest fashion in London.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SWANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The caller turns -- it is WILL TURNER. Handsome, with a watchful demeanor that gives him weight beyond his years.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, Mr. Turner! It's good to see you again!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Swann hurries to him, opens the case. Inside is a beautiful dress sword and scabbard. Swann takes it out reverently.</context>
      <utterance>Good day, sir.  I have your order.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He takes the sword from Swann, and balances it on one finger at the point where the blade meets the guard.</context>
      <utterance>The blade is folded steel. That's gold filigree laid into the handle. If I may -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SWANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will's face falls. Clearly, the work is his, and he is proud of it. With practiced ease, he flips the sword around, catches it by the hilt and returns it to the case.</context>
      <utterance>Impressive. .. very impressive. Commodore Norrington will be pleased, I'm sure. Do pass my compliments on to your master.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will tries to speak, but can't. He gives up, smiles to himself, and simply nods emphatically.</context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth! You look stunning!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her hand goes to the chain around her throat (the medallion is hidden in the bodice of her dress).</context>
      <utterance>Will! It's so good to see you!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dreamt about you last night. Will reacts with surprise: "Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth, this is hardly appropriate -</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About the day we met. Do you remember?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could never forget it, Miss Swann.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will, how many times must I ask you to call me 'Elizabeth'?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth is disappointed and a little hurt by his response.</context>
      <utterance>At least once more, Miss Swann. As always.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>understands propriety. Now, we must be going. Swann takes the case from Will, opens the door for Elizabeth. Elizabeth straightens her back, gathers her skirts and strides past Will.</context>
      <utterance>Well said! There's a boy who</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good day, Mr. Turner.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He watches as she is helped aboard a carriage by the driver.</context>
      <utterance>Good day.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>IN THE CARRIAGE: Swann glowers at his daughter.</context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dear, I do hope you demonstrate a bit more decorum in front of Commodore Norrington. After all, it is only</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>through his efforts that Port Royal has become at all civilized.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts up the dock, strapping on his sword belt; besides the scabbard, it also carries a compass, pistol and small powder horn. The Harbormaster cuts him off.</context>
      <utterance>It's remarkable how often those two traits coincide.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARBORMASTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a shilling for the dock space, and you're going to have to give me your name.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tosses three shillings onto the ledger. The Harbormaster considers, then shuts the ledger on the coins, steps aside.</context>
      <utterance>What do you say to three shillings, and we forget the name?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARBORMASTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack gives him a half-salute as he goes past. Looks across the water toward the Interceptor -- and smiles. Above the Interceptor, among the parapets of Fort Charles, a ceremony is underway -</context>
      <utterance>Welcome to Port Royal, Mr. Smith.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MURTOGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This dock is off-limits to civilians.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Music drifts down from Fort Charles. Jack looks up, shields his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, I didn't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>You two weren't invited?</context>
      <utterance>Some sort of to-do up at the fort, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MURTOGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No ... someone has to make sure this dock stays off-limits to civilians.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This must be some important boat.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURTOGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain Norrington's made it his flagship. He'll use it to hunt down the last dregs of piracy on the Spanish Lake.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Commodore.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MURTOGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Commodore Norrington.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a fine goal, I'm sure ... But it seems to me a ship like that --  -- makes this one here just a wee superfluous.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURTOGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, the Dauntless is the power in these waters, true enough -- but there's no ship that can match the Interceptor for speed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mullroy scoffs at the name.</context>
      <utterance>That so? I've heard of one, supposed to be fast, nigh uncatchable ... the Black Pearl?</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLR0Y</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no real ship as can match the Interceptor.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURTOGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Black Pearl is a real ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's not.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURTOGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes it is. I've seen it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLR0Y</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've seen it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MURTOGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've seen the Black Pearl?</utterance>
   <speaker>MURTOGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MURTOGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I have.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLR0Y</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've seen a ship with black sails that's crewed by the damned and captained by a man so evil that hell itself spat him back out?</utterance>
   <speaker>MURTOGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... No .</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURTOGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I've seen a ship with black sails.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLR0Y</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, and no ship that's not crewed by the damned and captained by a man so evil hell itself spat him back out could possibly have black sails and therefore couldn't possibly be any ship other than the Black Pearl. Is that what you're saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>MURTOGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... no.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLR0Y</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Jack's not there. Murtogg and Mullroy look around, spot</context>
      <utterance>Like I said, there's no real ship as can match -- Hey!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>MULLROY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jack looks over in exaggeratedly innocent surprise. The sailors hurry toward the gangplank.</context>
      <utterance>You!</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLROY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jack spreads his hands in apology.</context>
      <utterance>Get away from there! You don't have permission to be aboard there!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sailors study him suspiciously.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. It's just such a pretty boat. Ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURTOGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smith.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLR0Y</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your business in Port Royal, 'Mr. Smith' ?</utterance>
   <speaker>MURTOGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And no lies!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>None? Very well. You've rumbled me. I confess: I intend to commandeer one of these ships, pick up a crew in Tortuga, and go out on the account, do a little honest pirating.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURTOGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said, no lies.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLR0Y</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think he's telling the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURTOGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not telling the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He may be.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURTOGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If he were telling the truth he wouldn't have told us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He extends his arm. She takes it. He walks her away from the party, toward the parapet. A rather too long of a silence as Norrington works up his courage.</context>
      <utterance>May I have a moment?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth frowns, unable to focus. Norrington mistakes her expression as disapproval.</context>
      <utterance>You look lovely. Elizabeth.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I apologize if I seem forward -- but I must speak my mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This promotion confirms that I have accomplished the goals I set for myself in my career. But it also casts into sharp relief that which I have not achieved. The thing all men most require: a marriage to a fine woman.  You have become a fine woman, Elizabeth.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't breathe.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth loses her balance, stumbles away from Norrington. She reaches a hand out to the parapet to steady herself, but it slides off - -- and then she vanishes over the wall. Gone.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a bit nervous, myself --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth! .</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't you going to save her?</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLR0Y</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Murtogg shakes his head -- neither does he.</context>
      <utterance>I can't swim.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Above where Elizabeth struggles in the water. Norrington and several other men pick their way down the cliffs. They are too far away to get to her in time. Jack scowls. He has no choice -- and it pisses him off.</context>
      <utterance>Sailors.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He pulls a pistol from his sword belt, hands it to Murtogg; then hands the belt to Mullroy.</context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>And then he dives into the water, swims toward Elizabeth. Elizabeth struggles to keep above water, gasping for air '- then a swell rolls over her, and she is submerged - UNDERWATER, Elizabeth drifts down, unconscious. The current turns her, and the MEDALLION slips loose from her bodice. The MEDALLION turns slowly, until the SKULL is fully visible. A shaft of filtered sunlight hits it, and it</context>
      <utterance>Don't lose these.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MULLROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never would have thought of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack flips the knife and hands it hilt-first to Murtogg - and that's when he spots - The MEDALLION. Jack catches it up in his "hand.</context>
      <utterance>Clearly, you've never been to Singapore.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Before Elizabeth can answer, the BLADE of a SWORD is at Jack's THROAT -- Norrington's new ceremonial sword, in fact, looking bright and sharp.</context>
      <utterance>Where did you get this?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It looks bad -- Jack standing over Elizabeth, most of her clothes gone. He gets to his feet. The rest of Elizabeth's erstwhile rescuers reach the scene, including Swann.</context>
      <utterance>On your feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He strips off his jacket, drapes it around her.</context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth! Are you all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes -- yes, I'm fine -- Commodore Norrington, do you intend to kill my rescuer?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack takes Norrington's hand gingerly. They shake - -- and Norrington tightens his grip, yanks Jack's arm toward him, then tears back the sleeve of Jack's shirt - -- exposing a BRAND on Jack's inner wrist: a large 'P.'</context>
      <utterance>I believe thanks are in order.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The others react in shock, but the sailors are well-trained --in an instant, half a dozen pistols are aimed at Jack. He stands there, still holding the corset.</context>
      <utterance>Had a brush-up with the East India Trading Company, did you ... pirate?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Norrington notices something else -- below the 'P' brand is a tattoo: a small bird in flight across water.</context>
      <utterance>Keep your guns on him, men. Gillette, fetch some irons.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, well... Jack Sparrow, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norrington looks out at the bay.</context>
      <utterance>Captain Jack Sparrow. If you please.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't see your ship -- Captain.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURTOGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said he'd come to commandeer one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you he was telling the truth.  These are his, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jack looks away, a bit embarrassed. Norrington returns the compass to the belt. Draws the sword half from the scabbard.</context>
      <utterance>It doesn't bear true.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He slides it back into the scabbard, hands it to Mullroy.</context>
      <utterance>I half-expected it to be made of wood.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Taking stock: you've got a pistol with only one shot, a compass that doesn't point north ... and no ship. You are without a doubt the worst pirate I have ever heard of.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gillette returns with shackles, approaches Jack.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, but you have heard of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth steps forward. Swann's jacket slips off her. She is unconcerned, but he is intent on putting it back on her.</context>
      <utterance>Carefully, lieutenant.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Commodore, I must protest. Pirate or not, this man saved my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One good deed is not enough to redeem a man of a lifetime of wickedness.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it seems to be enough to condemn him.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now that Jack is safely chained, Norrington nods to his men. All but one stow their weapons, and two step forward -</context>
      <utterance>Indeed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lightning-quick, he snaps the corset around the hand and wrist of the man holding the pistol and yanks. The pistol sails into the water. Before anyone can react to that, Jack has the manacle chain wrapped around Elizabeth's throat. Pistols are drawn again, but now Elizabeth serves as a shield. Norrington raises a cautioning hand to his men.</context>
      <utterance>Finally.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Norrington hesitates, balls his fists in frustration.</context>
      <utterance>Commodore Norrington ... my pistol and belt, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Mullroy hands the pistol and belt to Norrington. Norrington holds them out to Jack.</context>
      <utterance>Commodore!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>ELIZABETH Miss Swann.</context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth -- it is Elizabeth? Elizabeth is more angry than frightened.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miss Swann, if you'll be so kind?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She figures out what he wants: put the belt on him.</context>
      <utterance>Now, if you'll be very kind?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are despicable.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Done. He turns her again, and then backs up until he bumps against the cargo gantry.</context>
      <utterance>I saved your life; now you've saved mine. We're square.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He shoves Elizabeth away, grabs a rope and pulls free a belaying pin -- a counterweight drops and Jack is lifted up to the middle of the gantry, where he grabs a second rope - Pistols fire -- and miss. Jack swings out, out, out, away and around from the gantry. Norrington has held his shot. With careful aim, he tracks Jack's trajectory- Jack drops from the rope even as Norrington FIRES. His shot tears the rope - -- as Jack plummets past one of the gantry's guy lines, he snaps the length of manacle chain over the line and grabs hold of the far loop -- slides down the line - -- drops to the deck of a ship. He runs, leaping to another ship, then out of sight -</context>
      <utterance>Gentleman. .. m' lady. .. you will always remember this as the day you almost caught Captain Jack Sparrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On his heels! Gillette, bring a squad down from the fort!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth, are you -</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norrington's taken aback by her ire, and wisely hurries away. Swann drapes his coat around Elizabeth.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I'm all right, I'm fine! Go capture him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth shivers, finding suddenly that she is cold. Glances out at the bay - -- where a THICK FOG moves across the top of the water. She takes the jacket.</context>
      <utterance>Here, dear ... you should wear this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But she accepts his comforting embrace.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Father ... and let that be the last of your fashion advice, please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Something catches his eye: an empty peg on the wall. The sledge lying beside the anvil.</context>
      <utterance>Right where I left you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He moves casually toward the sledge. Then grabs for it -- but the flat of a sword blade slaps his hand. Will jumps back. Jack stands there, sword leveled at Will. He backs Will up, toward the door. Will glares at him.</context>
      <utterance>Not where I left you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT' D</mode>
      <context>The pirate.</context>
      <utterance>You're the one they're hunting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look familiar ... Have I ever threatened you before?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've made a point of avoiding familiarity with pirates.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beside the door is a grindstone, a sword resting in the honing guide. Before Jack can react, Will has it in hand.</context>
      <utterance>Ah. Then it would be a shame to put a black mark on your record. So if you'll excuse me ...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Crossing blades with a pirate?</context>
      <utterance>Do you think this is wise, boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You threatened Miss Swann.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In response, Will assumes an en garde position. Jack appraises him, unhappy to see Will knows what he's doing. Jack attacks. The two men stand in one place, trading feints, thrusts and parries with lightning speed, almost impossible to follow. Will has no trouble matching Jack.</context>
      <utterance>Only a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He takes a step around an imaginary circle. Will steps the other way, maintaining his relationship to Jack.</context>
      <utterance>You know what you're doing, I'll give you that ... Excellent form ... But how's your footwork? If I step here -</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very good! And if I step again, you step again. . .</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are now exactly opposite their initial positions.</context>
      <utterance>And so we circle, circle, like dogs we circle. . .</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jack turns and heads for the door, now directly behind him. Will registers angry surprise -- and then with a vicious overhand motion, he throws his sword - -- the sword buries itself into the door, just above the latch, barely missing Jack. Jack registers it, then pulls on the latch, but it won't move up -- the sword is in the way. Jack rattles the latch. Tugs on the sword a few times -- it is really stuck in there. Jack mouths a curse, but when he turns back to Will, he's smiling.</context>
      <utterance>Ta!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT' D</mode>
      <context>Eyes on Jack, Will simply picks up a new sword from an anvil. Jack slumps in dismay -- but then leaps forward. Will and Jack duel. Their blades flash and ring. Suddenly, Jack swings the chain still manacled to his left hand at Will's head. Will ducks it, comes up wide-eyed. Then Jack's chain smashes across Will's sword, disarming him. Will quickly picks up another sword. Jack becomes aware that the entire room is filled with bladed weapons: swords, knives, boarding axes in various stages of completion.</context>
      <utterance>That's a good trick. Except, once again, you are between me and the way out.  And now you have no weapon.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who makes all these?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do. And I practice with them. At least three hours a day.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A direct hit -- and Will coils even more tightly with anger.</context>
      <utterance>You need to find yourself a girl.  Or maybe the reason you practice three hours a day is you've found one -- but can't get her?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He explodes: kicks a rack, causing a sword to fall into his hand; uses his foot to bring his dropped sword into the air, catches it -- and attacks Jack, both blades flashing. Jack parries with sword and chain. Jack's chain wraps around Will's sword; Will twists the handle of his guard through a link, and stabs the sword up into the ceiling - So Jack's manacled left arm is now suspended from the ceiling. Not good. He parries using one hand, twisting and dodging around the furnace - Jack compresses the bellows, blowing a SHOWER OF SPARKS into Will's face. Jack grabs the chain, hoists himself up, kicks with his feet, knocking Will back. Jack uses his full weight, yanks the sword from the ceiling. Hurls a wooden mallet at Will, then a second, hitting Will on the wrist. Will drops his sword, falls down, gets up - Jack's pistol is aimed directly between Will's eyes. Will steps back, directly in front of the back exit. Glares, rubs his wrist gingerly.</context>
      <utterance>No. I practice three hours a day so that when I meet a pirate ... I can kill him.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You cheated.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Move away.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Move!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack cocks the pistol. Will stares back. The stand-off lasts for a long moment.</context>
      <utterance>No. I can not just step aside and let you escape.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack uncocks the pistol. Will is surprised, reassesses Jack</context>
      <utterance>You're lucky, boy -- this shot's not meant for you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excellent work, Mister Brown. You've aided in the capture of a dangerous fugitive.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack groans. Norrington stands over him, smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Just doing my civic duty.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I believe you will always remember this as the day Captain Jack Sparrow almost escaped.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PRISONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In an adjoining cell, Jack lies on a pile of straw.</context>
      <utterance>Come here, boy... Want a nice, juicy bone?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can keep doing that forever, that dog's never going to move.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRISONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse us if we ain't resigned ourselves to the gallows just yet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SWANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Has my daughter given you an answer yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. She hasn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ghastly weather tonight.</context>
      <utterance>Well, she had a taxing day...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the distance, there is a BOOM -</context>
      <utterance>Bleak. Very bleak.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- and then the WHISTLE of an incoming ball --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tackles Swann as the wall of the parapet EXPLODES --</context>
      <utterance>Cannon fire!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He peers out through the bars of the window. The other prisoners crowd around their window as well.</context>
      <utterance>I know those guns!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the Black Pearl.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRISONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Black Pearl? I've heard stories ... she's been preying on ships and settlements for near ten years ... and never leaves any survivors.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are a lot of stories about the Black Pearl.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Swann turns to go -- but finds himself face-to-face with a pirate -- KOEHLER, a handsome blond man with gold earrings. Beyond Koehler, more pirates come up over the far wall. Koehler grins and raises a cutlass - -- Norrington's sword blocks Koehler's slash.</context>
      <utterance>Governor! Barricade yourself in my office!  That's an order!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>INT. GOVERNOR'S MANSION - ELIZABETH f S BEDROOM - NIGHT Elizabeth looks out a window at the scene below: even through the fog, multiple fires are visible, and ships burn in the harbor. Shouts and cries of pain. Cannon fire</context>
      <utterance>They've flanked us! Men! Swords and pistols! The battle is joined --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ESTRELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth jumps. Estrella is right behind her, terrified. They whisper:</context>
      <utterance>Miss Elizabeth?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTRELLA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth realizes she's right. There is the SLAM of a body against the door.</context>
      <utterance>Are they come to kidnap you, miss? The daughter of the governor would be very valuable.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Estrella nods. Another SLAM at the door -- it gives a bit -</context>
      <utterance>Listen, Estrella -- they haven't seen you. Hide, and first chance, run for the fort .</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PINTEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smoldering pirate gives him look -- he wants to hurt her plenty. Pintel shakes his head: 'Don't worry, I'm lying.'</context>
      <utterance>We know you're here, poppet. Come out and we promise we won't hurt you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINTEL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We will find you, poppet ... You've got something of ours, and it calls to us!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth touches the chain of the medallion ... and a desperate idea occurs to her. The pirates burst through the door. Elizabeth backs away, holds the bread knife out to ward them off. They come around either side of the table, stalking her -</context>
      <utterance>Please, no ...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Par. .. Parlay!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pintel can't believe his ears.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINTEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Parlay! I invoke the right of parlay! According to" the Code of the Brethren, set down by the pirates Morgan and Bartholomew, you must take me to your Captain!</utterance>
   <speaker>PINTEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know the code.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If an adversary demands parley, you can do them no harm until the parlay is complete.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINTEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It would appear, so do you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMOLDERING PIRATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps forward, dirk drawn -- Pintel stops him.</context>
      <utterance>To blazes with the code!</utterance>
   <speaker>PINTEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks to Elizabeth: 'right?' Elizabeth nods.</context>
      <utterance>She wants to be taken to the Captain, and she'll go without a fuss.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINTEL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Smoldering Pirate concedes the point, sheaths his dirk. He grabs Elizabeth roughly by the arm -</context>
      <utterance>We must honor the code.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PRISIONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He and the other two scramble through.</context>
      <utterance>Praise be!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>To his surprise, the dog crawls out from under the bench. Jack continues to coax him closer.</context>
      <utterance>It's all right, doggie ... come here, boy. Come here, Spot. Rover. Fido?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The dog bolts, through the bars, into the cell, then out through the breached wall -- taking the keys with him. The door to the cell block bursts open. A pair of pirates step in: KOEHLER and TWIGG.</context>
      <utterance>What's the matter, boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't the armory. He turns to go, but Koehler has spotted Jack.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOEHLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, well... Look what we have here, Twigg. It's. Captain Sparrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh. Last time I saw you, you were all alone on a God-forsaken island, shrinking into the distance. I'd heard you'd gotten off, but I didn't believe it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOEHLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you sprout little wings and flyaway?</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two laugh. Jack doesn't. He steps forward, close to the bars. This puts him in a spill of moonlight. He is tight with fury.</context>
      <utterance>His fortunes aren't improved much.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Worry about your own fortunes. The lowest circle of hell is reserved for betrayers ... and mutineers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT' D</mode>
      <context>Koehler sneers, shoves Jack backwards, hard. Now out of the moonlight, his hand is normal. Jack stares, realizing -</context>
      <utterance>You are cursed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Koehler ushers Twigg toward the door. Looks back.</context>
      <utterance>The stories are true.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOEHLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then they're gone.</context>
      <utterance>You know nothing of hell.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BOSUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know we was taking captives.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINTEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>parlay... with Captain Barbossa. ON THE POOP DECK -- an imposing FIGURE in silhouette stands by the wheel, too far away to have heard Pintel's words. But his head turns at the mention of his name. The silhouetted figure moves toward the stairs. A cloud of SMOKE obscures him -- and then, as if he skipped the stairs, he strides out of the SMOKE on the main deck- This is BARBOSSA. Despite the bright colors of clothing, definitely not a man you'd want to meet in a dark alley -- or anywhere, for that matter. Elizabeth, more terrified than ever, cannot look away from his eyes. But she musters her courage -</context>
      <utterance>She's invoked the right of</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am here to -- The Bosun SLAPS her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOSUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His wrist is grabbed -- painfully -- by Barbossa.</context>
      <utterance>You'll speak when spoken to!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you'll not lay a hand on those under the protection of parlay!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOSUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Barbossa releases him. Turns to Elizabeth, smiles -- it shows both silver and gold teeth.</context>
      <utterance>Aye, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Barbossa is both impressed and amused.</context>
      <utterance>Captain Barbossa ... I have come to negotiate the cessation of hostilities against Port Royal.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was a lot of long words in there, miss, and we're not but humble pirates. What is it you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Barbossa and the pirates laugh.</context>
      <utterance>I want you to leave. And never come back.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am disinclined to acquiesce to your request.  Means' No. '</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She quickly slips the medallion off, darts to the side rail, dangles it over the side of the ship. The pirates go quiet.</context>
      <utterance>Very well.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll drop it!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My holds are bursting with swag. That bit of shine matters to me ... Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because it's what you're searching for. You've been searching for it for years. I recognize this ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw it eight years ago, when we made the crossing from England.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth glares at him. She's getting nowhere.</context>
      <utterance>Did you, now?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She flips the medallion up, off her finger -</context>
      <utterance>Fine. I suppose if this is worthless, there's no reason to keep it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have a name, missy?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth -  Turner.  I'm a maid in the governor's household.  Barbossa reacts to the name Turner: it confirms what he has suspected. The other pirates surreptitiously exchange glances and nods.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got sand, for a maid.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course.  I didn't steal it, if that's what you mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, nothing like that.  Very well. You hand that over, we'll put your town to our rudder and ne'er return.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I trust you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth hesitates, but she has no choice. She holds out the medallion. He grabs it, clutches it in his fist like hope.</context>
      <utterance>It's you who invoked the parlay! Believe me, Miss, you'd best hand it over, now... or these be the last friendly words you'll hear!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Barbossa grins devilishly -- but then nods to the Bosun.</context>
      <utterance>Our bargain. . ?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOSUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For the first time since the attack began, the BOOMING of the guns ceases. Elizabeth is surprised -- and relieved. The pirates hustle to follow orders. Barbossa turns away.</context>
      <utterance>Still the guns, and stow 'em! Signal the men, set the flags, and make good to clear port!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait! You must return me to shore! According to the rules of the Order of the Brethren -</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Barbossa wheels on her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>the code is more what you'd call guidelines than actual rules. (grins gold and silver) Welcome aboard the Black Pearl, Miss Turner. Elizabeth stares in speechless terror -</context>
      <utterance>First. Your return to shore was not part of our negotiations nor our agreement, and so I 'must' do nothing. Secondly: you must be a pirate for the pirate's code to apply. And you're not. And thirdly...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A group stares at him: Swann, Norrington, and Gillette among others, gathered around a map. The map is so large it drapes over the Governor's desk, the far end supported by a chair.</context>
      <utterance>They've taken her! They've taken Elizabeth!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're aware of the situation.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Swann's worry has made him short-tempered.</context>
      <utterance>We have to hunt them down -- and save her!</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Murtogg has remembered something. He ventures it warily:</context>
      <utterance>Where do you propose we start? If you have any information that concerns my daughter, then share it! If anyone does, tell me!  Leave, Mr. Turner.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURTOGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That Jack Sparrow... he talked about the Black Pearl.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mentioned it, is more what he did.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURTOGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still --</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can ask him where it is -- maybe he can lead us to it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We could strike a bargain -</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will slams the boarding axe into the desk, through the map.</context>
      <utterance>No. The pirates who invaded this fort left Sparrow locked in his cell. Ergo, he is not their ally, and therefore of no value.  We will determine their most likely course, and launch a search mission that sails with the tide.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norrington is quick to react; he throws a strong arm across Will's back, and guides him roughly to the door.</context>
      <utterance>That's not good enough. This is Elizabeth's life!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens the door, and then turns away. Will watches him walk back to the desk. Will's face sets in resolve, and he leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Turner, this is not the time for rash actions.  Do not make the mistake of thinking you are the only man here who loves Elizabeth.  Now, go home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Black Pearl?</context>
      <utterance>Are you familiar with that ship?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somewhat.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where does it make berth?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Surely you've heard the stories? The Black Pearl sails from the dreaded Isla de Mureta... an island that cannot be found -- except by those who already know where it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ship's real enough. So its anchorage must be a real place. Where is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why ask me?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because you're a pirate.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you want to turn pirate yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never.  They took Miss Swann.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So it is that you found a girl. Well, if you're intending to brave all and hasten to her rescue and so win fair lady's heart, you'll have to do it alone. I see no profit in it for me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can get you out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How? The key's run off.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I helped build these cells. Those are hook-and-ring hinges. The proper application of strength, the door'll lift free. Just calls for the right lever and fulcrum. . . Jack watches Will as he speaks, and it dawns on him -- Will is the spitting image of someone he's known in the past.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will gives him a puzzled look.</context>
      <utterance>Your name is Turner.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack grins.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Will Turner.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack keeps his hand out, still smiling. Will shakes it.</context>
      <utterance>Will Turner...  I'll tell you what, Mr. Turner. I've changed my mind. You spring me from this cell, and on pain of death, I'll you to the Black Pearl.  Do we have an accord? Will gives him a suspicious look. The deal seems too good.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Agreed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Agreed!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will heads for the door. Jack searches the desk, cupboards.</context>
      <utterance>Someone will have heard that. Hurry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not without my effects.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack finds his pistol, sword belt, and compass. Straps on the belt, checks the shot in his pistol.</context>
      <utterance>We need to go!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you bothering with that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My business, Will. As for your business -one question, or there's no use going.  This girl -- what does she mean to you? How far are you willing to go to save her?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd die for her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jack notices that Will is standing, frozen on the dock, staring at the boat in dismay.</context>
      <utterance>I knew the Harbormaster wouldn't report her. Honest men are slaves to their conscience, and there's no predicting 'em. But you can always trust a dishonest man to stay that way...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come aboard.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't set foot off dry land I was twelve, when the ship I was on exploded.  It's been a sound policy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will steels himself, steps into the boat as if its going to capsize with the slightest movement. Jack hoists the sail.</context>
      <utterance>No worries there. She's far more likely to rot out from under us.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He nods toward the H.M.S. Dauntless, looming in the harbor. Will whiteknuckles the gunwales.</context>
      <utterance>Besides, we are about to better our prospects considerably.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to steal a ship? That ship?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Commandeer. We're going to commandeer a ship. Nautical term.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's still against the law.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is either crazy, or brilliant.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Jolly Man nears the rudder of the much larger ship -</context>
      <utterance>Remarkable how often those two traits coincide.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody stay calm. We're taking over the ship!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack gives him a look, shakes his head: don't do that. The sailors all look at them -- and then burst out LAUGHING. They grin, shake their heads. Jack stands there, grinning with them -- but his gun is still level. The Lieutenant, GILLETTE, steps forward.</context>
      <utterance>Aye! Avast!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dead serious.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You understand this ship cannot be crewed by only two men. You'll never make it out of the bay.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More guffaws from the crew. A couple sailors move forward, hands on swords -- Gillette holds up a hand.</context>
      <utterance>We'll see about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, I'll not see any of my men killed or wounded in this foolish enterprise.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine by me. We brought you a nice little boat, so you can all get back to shore, safe and sound.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Agreed. You have the momentary advantage, sir. But I will see you smile from the yard arm sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As likely as not.  Will, short up the anchor, we've got ourselves a ship!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MURTOGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The windless turns, bringing Mullroy into view.</context>
      <utterance>I can't believe he's doing this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULLROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The windless turns some more, and there's Gillette.</context>
      <utterance>You didn't believe he was telling the truth, either.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another quarter turn -</context>
      <utterance>Do you have any idea, boy, what you're doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SWANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Commodore --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A moment.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SWANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norrington glances out at the bay. Sure enough, the Dauntless is on the move. Norrington takes a brass telescope from his belt, opens it, trains it on -- The main deck. He picks out Will -</context>
      <utterance>Dammit, man, it appears someone is stealing your ship!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- then spots Jack, at the wheel. Lowers the telescope.</context>
      <utterance>Rash, Turner, too rash.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is, without doubt, the worst pirate I have ever seen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack removes his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Can you swim?  Can. You. Swim?</utterance>
   <speaker>SENTRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course, sir. Like a fish. I grew up summers living in Dover, with my uncle -</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack lifts the man up, throws him overboard. Quickly unties the ropes to the grappling hooks. Will cranks the capstan bars, raising the foresail -</context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the distance is already too great. One brave sailor tries to swing across on a rope, Errol-Flynn style, but falls short with a splash. Jack waves, and shouts across the distance -</context>
      <utterance>Sailors! Back to the Interceptor!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norrington seethes, but his order to Gillette is measured:</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Commodore, for getting our ship ready to make way! We'd've had a hard time of it by ourselves!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Raise the sails.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>GILLETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The wind is quarter from astern ... by the time we're underway, we'll never catch them.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gillette looks surprised at the order -- but relays it.</context>
      <utterance>We need only to come about, to put them in range of the long nines.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hands! Come about! Jackets off the cannons!  We are to fire on our own ship?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The STEERSMAN turns the wheel. The Dauntless' course does not change one whit.</context>
      <utterance>Better to see it at the bottom of the sea than in the hands of a pirate.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEERSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Steersman spins the wheel. It goes round and round, with no signs of slowing.</context>
      <utterance>Captain, there's a problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEERSMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's disabled the rudder chain, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Interceptor dwindles with distance. Gillette watches it go, with some degree of admiration.</context>
      <utterance>So it would seem.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norrington reaches out, stops the spinning ship's wheel.</context>
      <utterance>He's got to be the best pirate I've ever seen.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So it would seem.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PINTEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll be dining with the Captain, and he requests you wear this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell the captain that I am disinclined to acquiesce to his request.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINTEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angry, Elizabeth holds out her hand. Pintel's grin fades.</context>
      <utterance>He said you say that! He also said if that be the case, you'll be dining with the crew, and you'll be naked.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINTEL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He exits, pouting. Elizabeth examines the dress -</context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The table is set. Elizabeth sits, cuts a tiny piece of meat, eats it daintily.</context>
      <utterance>Now, none of that. Please dig in.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth drops the pretense: she's starving, and begins to eat like it. Barbossa watches her intently.</context>
      <utterance>No need to stand on ceremony, and no call to impress anyone. You must be hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth does, a huge swig; she tears off a hunk of bread, devours it.</context>
      <utterance>Try the wine.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She starts to bite into the apple -- stops. She is suddenly aware of Barbossa's gaze -- and that he is not eating.</context>
      <utterance>And the apples -- one of those next.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shoves her plate away -- and takes the opportunity to palm her knife. Barbossa LAUGHS.</context>
      <utterance>It's poisoned!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, there would be no sense in killing you, Miss Turner.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why aren't you eating?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He produces the medallion, lets it dangle from his fingers.</context>
      <utterance>Would that I could.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a pirate medallion.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth gives an infinitesimal shrug, intrigued despite herself.</context>
      <utterance>It's a piece of the treasure of Isla de Muerta .</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT 'D</mode>
      <context>Barbossa stands, moves to a shelf. Puts a key to a medium- sized polished wooden box -- the Captain's chest. Opens it.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, so you don't know as much as you pretend. Back when Cortes was cutting a great bloody swath through the New World, a high priest gave. him all the gold they had, with one condition: that he spare the people's lives. Of course, Cortes being Cortes, he didn't.  He'd've made a great pirate, that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Inside the chest are charts, some gold, a sextant -- and a few pages of a Mayan CODEX, pieces of tree bark inscribed with Mayan glyphs. Barbossa removes them carefully, sets them on the table. Pours over them.</context>
      <utterance>So the priest, with his dying breath, called on the power of the blood of his people, and put on the gold a curse. If anyone took so much as a single piece, as he was compelled by greed, by greed he would be consumed.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Within a day of leaving port for Spain, the treasure ship carrying the gold ... something went wrong. The ship run aground, every man aboard dead, save one. He survived long enough to hide the gold ashore.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Barbossa is angry. He stands, sweeps the food off the table.</context>
      <utterance>That's all very interesting, but I hardly believe in ghost stories any more.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>for drink and food and pleasant company. But we found out: the drink could not sate us, and the food turned to ashes in our mouths, and no amount of pleasant company could ease our torment. (regains his composure) We are cursed men, Miss Turner, condemned, to be forever consumed by our own greed. Gold calls to UB, always, and we are driven, always, to find more, and add it to the treasure. Barbossa picks up the priceless Codex. Crushes them in his fist.</context>
      <utterance>You idiot girl! It's no make- believe! My crew and I, we found the gold, and we did more than take one piece, we took it all. Rich men we were and we spent it and traded it and gave it away in exchange</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is but one way to remove the curse. All of the scattered pieces of the treasure must be restored in full, and the blood repaid.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth stares at him, horrified. Using the toe of his boot, Barbossa flips an apple up off the floor, catches it, extends it to Elizabeth.</context>
      <utterance>We've recovered every piece -- save for this.  And as for the blood ... that's what we have you for.  And that's why there's no sense in killing you. Yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth slowly reaches for the apple -- and then comes up out of her chair, trying to run around Barbossa_ They struggle briefly, and then suddenly he shoves her away- Elizabeth's stolen KNIFE is buried in Barbossa's chest, to the hilt -- Barbossa is completely unaffected. He opens his shirt to get a better look at the knife, pulls it out with little effort. There is BLOOD on the blade, but none anywhere else.</context>
      <utterance>Apple?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth backs away, whirls and barrels out the door -</context>
      <utterance>I'm curious -- after killing me, what is it you were planning to do next?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look!  LOOK! The moonlight shows us for what we really are! We are not among the living and so we cannot die - He spins her back around to face him -- he leans forward, putting his face in the moonlight, turning it into a gleaming SKULL with gold and silver teeth -</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>(raises his hand)</context>
      <utterance>-- but neither are we dead! We have all the desires of the living, but cannot satisfy them! Ten years I have been parched of thirst, and unable to quench it! Ten years, I have been starving to death -- and haven't died!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth flinches away from the skeletal hand. It drops away -- he takes a bottle of wine from the opened case beside the cabin door, uncorks it with his teeth, raises it</context>
      <utterance>And I have not felt anything for ten years ... Not the wind on my face, nor the spray of the sea ...  ... nor the flesh of a woman ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For a man whose made an industry of avoiding boats, you're a quick study.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I worked passage from England as a cabin boy.  After my mother passed, I came out here ... looking for my father.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that so?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack says nothing. Will has lost the patience for guile.</context>
      <utterance>My father. William Turner?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode> CONT ' D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not a simpleton. At the jail - - it was only after you learned my name that you agreed to help.  Since that's what I wanted, I didn't press the matter. But now - {an accusation} You knew my father.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack considers his reply -- settles on 'truth.'</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew him. Probably one of the few who knew him as William Turner. Most everyone just called him Bill, or 'Bootstrap' Bill.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Bootstrap?'</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good man. Good pirate. And clever -"- I never met anyone with as clever a mind and hands as him. When you were puzzling out that cell door, it was like seeing his twin.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not true.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I swear, you look just like him.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not true that my father was a pirate.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Figured you wouldn't want to hear it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was a merchant marine! He was a respectable man who obeyed the law, and followed the rules--</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think your father is the only man who ever lived the Glasgow life, telling folk one thing, and then going off to do another? There's quite a few who come here, hoping to amass enough swag to ease the burdens of respectable</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>life. And they're all 'merchant marines.'</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father did not think of my mother -his family -- as a burden.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure -- because he could always go pirating.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will's sword is out, levelled at Jack. Jack gives him a disbelieving look, sighs.</context>
      <utterance>My father -- was not -- a pirate!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put it away, Will. It's not worth getting beat again.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't beat me. You ignored the rules of engagement. In a fair fight, I'd kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kicks a lever on a wench. The sail boom whips around and slams Will in the chest -- sweeping him off the ship. His sword clatters onto the deck. Will dangles above the water. Jack slips a loop of rope around the wheel to hold the course. Picks up the sword -- and pokes at Will with it. Will hand-over-hands away from the blade, to the end of the boom.</context>
      <utterance>Then that's not much incentive for me to fight fair, is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode> CONT ' D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As long as you're just hanging there, pay attention. Must, Should, do, don't, shall, shall not -- those are just suggestions. There are only two absolute rules.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Will looks away, not interested.</context>
      <utterance>What a man can do. And what a man can I t do.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jack swings the boom back in. Will drops to the deck. Jack holds the hilt of the sword out. Will takes it. Glares at Jack, considers what he'll do next. Jack watches him coolly. Will turns and strides to his spot on the deck, sits down, and resumes sharpening his sword: shhhk -- shhhk -- shhhk</context>
      <utterance>For instance: you can accept that your father was a pirate and still a good man... or you can't. Now me, I can sail this ship to Tortuga, by myself. . .  But I can't just let you drown.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tortuga?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh -- did I forget to mention that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANAMARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You stole my boat.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She SLAPS him again. Will shakes his head, heads for the bar. Jack gets up.</context>
      <utterance>AnaMaria! Have you seen Gibbs? I need to put together -</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Borrowed. Borrowed your boat.  Without permission.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ANAMARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My dory. The Jolly Mon. Where is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Safe! At Port Royal. With the Royal Navy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAMARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That boat is my livelihood!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll get it back. Or one better.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAMARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Away from them, a PATRON calls for his food. AnaMaria scowls at Jack, moves away -- comes back for. one more</context>
      <utterance>I will.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AT THE BAR, Will has spoken to the Bartender. Jack arrives, rubbing his chin.</context>
      <utterance>Jack! Over here!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Bartender nods 'yes.' Then nods 'out back.' Then produces a water bucket from behind the bar. Jack and Will exchange a look,-and Jack takes the bucket.</context>
      <utterance>He knows Gibbs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Curse you for breathing, you slack-jawed idiot  Mother's love, Jack, you know better than to wake a man when he's sleeping. It's bad luck!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, fortunately, I know how to counter it. The man who did the waking buys the man who was sleeping a drink, and the man who was sleeping it drinks it while listening to a proposition.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack helps Gibbs to his feet -- and then Gibbs is hit with a second wave of water. Will stands there with the bucket.</context>
      <utterance>Aye, that'll about do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blast it, I'm already awake!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. That was for the smell.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gibbs pauses. He takes a dainty sip.</context>
      <utterance>Just the one.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make it_ast, then. Now, what's the nature of this venture of yours?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, there's a hard tale, Jack. Most of the decent pirates in town won't sail with you -- seem to think you're a jinx.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gibbs evades answering by taking a long sip. Jack leans forward. Gibbs leans forward.</context>
      <utterance>Now where, I wonder, would they have gotten that idea?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Gibbs straightens up like he's been hit. He stares. He reaches for the drink as if to down it -- but then sets it back down. He leans forwards again. Jack has not moved.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going after the Black Pearl.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say again?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ilm going after the Black Pearl. I know where its going to be, and I'm going to take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack, it's a fool's errand: You've heard the tales they tell about the Pearl.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aye, and that's why I know where it's going to be, and that's why I know what Barbossa is up to. All I need is a crew.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A fool's errand.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE ON: Jack, as he smiles enigmatically, and shifts his eyes' -- behind him, Will, still on guard, glares a sailor away from the table.</context>
      <utterance>And you've got that, have you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gibbs' eyes widen over the edge of the tankard. Peers at Will. Then smiles, with more missing teeth than good ones.</context>
      <utterance>Back there, guarding the door is the son of old Bootstrap Bill Turner.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gibbs downs the drink, SLAMS the tankard on the table. Will reacts to the sound, draws both sword and dagger, kicks over a table for cover, and whirls on anyone who moves.</context>
      <utterance>Well, lookee there. I'll allow you may be onto something, Jack.  There's bound to be sailors on this rock crazy as you. I'll find some men.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kid's a bit of a stick, isn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That he is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Feast your eyes, Cap'n. All of 'em good sea-faring men, faithful hands before the mast, every one worth his salt --</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack holds up a hand -- enough. He moves down the line, Gibbs at his side. Then he notices AnaMaria in line, dressed like a man, He raises an eyebrow.</context>
      <utterance>-- and crazy, to boot.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAMARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack nods, continues. One sailor is quite fat, another thin and sickly. Jack is not happy with his choices. He stops in front of COTTON, a short sailor with a large, colorful PARROT on his shoulder. Jack raises an eyebrow.</context>
      <utterance>You owe me a boat.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cotton opens his mouth to show this -- Jack grimaces.</context>
      <utterance>Cotton here is mute, sir. Poor devil had his tongue cut out --</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- so he went and trained the parrot to do the talking for him, nobody knows how. Nobody knows the parrot's name, neither, so we just call it 'Cotton's parrot.' Jack decides to test this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cotton lifts the parrot off his shoulder, raises it --</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Cotton. Do you have the courage and fortitude to follow orders and stay true, in the face danger, and almost certain death?</utterance>
   <speaker>COTTON'S PARROT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wind in your SAILS! Wind in your SAILS!</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cotton nods vigorously, lowers the parrot, and it goes silent. Jack shakes his head. Steps back.</context>
      <utterance>Mostly, that seem to mean 'yes.'</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up, before you lose them all!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are the only ones worth having.  And we're going to need them-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On Jack, a ROARING wind blowing back his hair, eyes intent on their course. Gibbs climbs the tilted deck toward him.</context>
      <utterance>That fool will have us lose the canvas, and the masts besides!</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Werd best drop canvas, sirl</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She can hold a bit longer.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The wind picks up, howling. Jack smiles.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's in your head to put you in such a fine mood?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack turns back to the sea, enjoying himself. Gibbs stares at him like he's a crazy man.'</context>
      <utterance>We're catching up!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TWIGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON DECK, Barbossa moves to the rail. The storm clouds are breaking up. On the horizon is a dark, ominous shape: ISLA DE MUERTA. Mostly sheer unfriendly cliffs that shoot straight into the water. It is surrounded by a slate grey sea. Barbossa grasps the rail with both hands, his expression a mixture of loathing and fear. Jacoby approaches, hesitant.</context>
      <utterance>Isla de Muerta! Isla de Muerta, off the port bow!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Orders, Captain?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jacoby nods, backs away. Barbossa continues to stare -</context>
      <utterance>Bring her in, not too close. I won't brave the reef, not until high tide. We lay anchor before dark.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... that is, if it first doesn't sink back down to hell from where it came.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AnaMaria turns the wheel, adjusting course. The ship leans into the new direction. Jack looks down - ON THE COMPASS -- where the indicator spins, reverses, settles on -- northeast.</context>
      <utterance>Bear three points starboard.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>AnaMaria frowns, but follows the order, turns the wheel back, and the ship responds. Will works on deck, coiling a rope -- but he watches Jack and AnaMaria, clearly not happy. Gibbs hobbles up.</context>
      <utterance>Six points port!</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gibbs takes over the task. The ship shifts course again. Will has had enough.</context>
      <utterance>Left handed-ropes are coiled against the sun, or it's bad luck!  Anty-clockwise.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, lad, just because it don't point north don't mean it don't work.  That compass gives bearings to the Isla de Muerta, wherever it may lie.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gibbs settles in, happy to have a willing listener.</context>
      <utterance>Really?  So ... what's the story on the pistol?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll tell lee. Now, Jack Sparrow has an honest streak in him, and that's where the whole problem starts. This was when he was Captain of the Black Pearl -</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? He never told me that.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gibbs voice is a whisper, now, so Will has to lean closer.</context>
      <utterance>Ah -- he's learned, then. Plays things more close to the vest. See, Jack was a cartographer, back in Old England. Somehow I he came by the money to commission the Pearl. Hired himself a crew, promised each man an equal share.  So, they're forty days out, and the First Mate says, everything's an equal share, that should mean the location of the island, too. So Jack gave up the bearings.  That night, there was mutiny.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did he get off the island?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will and Gibbs jump. Jack is right there beside them.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Will and Gibbs aren't sure what to make of that. Jack laughs.</context>
      <utterance>My body's still there, rotting away, and I am but a ghost!</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you get off the island?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts off.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, that's a dark and unpleasant tale, best left untold.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait -- what about the pistol?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack lets this sink in. He pulls out the pistol, raises it.</context>
      <utterance>The pistol. When a pirate is marooned, Will, he's given a pistol with a single shot. No good for hunting, or surviving, really. But after three weeks of starvation and thirst -- the option of that pistol begins to look good.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I survived. And I still have that single shot. It's meant for one man. My mutinous first mate -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KOEHLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Moonrise, Captain! First night of full.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a torch. Moves into the cave. The pirates follow.</context>
      <utterance>Hah!  Be mindful of pits and crevasses. Stay together.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COTTON'S PARROT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indeed, the faint outline of Isla de Muerta is in the distance on the port side. Will stands, excited, jumps onto the rigging for a better look. But AnaMaria, at the helm, stares at Cotton, and the parrot.</context>
      <utterance>Land HO! Land HO! LAND ho! LAND ho!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAMARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How does he do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll be anchored on the lee side. Haul your wind, and keep to the weather of the island -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Depends.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>By now, the moving water tugs on the longboat, and they are sucked in --</context>
      <utterance>On whether the stories are all true. If they are, that's a waterfall that spills over at high tide, with a short drop to an underground lagoon. If not -</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The boat rushes forward, plunges into the darkness -</context>
      <utterance>-- well, too late.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Barbossa approaches the chest, shining in the beam of moonlight.</context>
      <utterance>You know the first thing I'm going to do after the curse is lifted?  Eat a whole bushel of apples.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He tosses the gold medallion onto the others. The pirates tense, waiting, expectant. A long beat. They all look at each other, look at themselves. Nothing happens.</context>
      <utterance>What was begun by blood, let blood now end!</utterance>
   <speaker>KOEHLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did it work?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEADEYE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't feel no different.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Barbossa frowns, draws his pistol, and SHOOTS the pirate next to him -- Jacoby -- square in the chest. Jacoby reacts in shock, grabs his chest ... but doesn't die.</context>
      <utterance>How do we tell?</utterance>
   <speaker>KOEHLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.  He shot me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth takes time to smile before answering:</context>
      <utterance>You. Maid. Your father. What was his name?!  Was your father William Turner?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pirates cry out in alarm. Barbossa gathers himself, getting his rage under steely control.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Barbossa SLAPS her hard across the face, sending her sprawling.</context>
      <utterance>Where's his child? The child that sailed from England eight years ago, the child who is the real owner of that medallion, the child in whose veins flows the blood of William Turner?! Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACOBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You brought us the wrong person!</utterance>
   <speaker>PINTEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She had the medallion! She's the right age. She said her name was Turner!</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Barbossa whirls on him --</context>
      <utterance>You brought us here for nothing?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're in league with Barbossa!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth can't comprehend that one.</context>
      <utterance>No, I'm -- rescuing you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will gains his footing in the rubble.</context>
      <utterance>You?!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miss Swann! We're here to rescue you!  It's going badly!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They race off, toward a bit of moonlight -</context>
      <utterance>This way!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm glad we got here in time.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Truthfully -- you were a bit late.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As if on cue, they hear the yells of pirates, coming closer. They take off -</context>
      <utterance>The trick isn't getting here, it's getting away.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sounds are closer.</context>
      <utterance>I'll lead them away.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go to the opposite end of the island, and signal the ship. I'll keep 'em busy.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure? Jack -- this is not something you have to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will nods, hesitates... gives Jack his sword - - now Jack has two, ..one for each hand. Elizabeth gives him a quick kiss. Will and Elizabeth race away, and are gone. Jack watches them for a moment, turns to face the pirates. He sticks the two swords in the ground, crossed. Leans casually against a rock. A group of pirates round a corner, cutlasses drawn, ready to fight -- but Jack raises his hand.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sure. When you've led the kind of life I have, there are debts that must be paid. Maybe I can balance the scales a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I invoke the right of parlay, according to the Code of the Brethren, set down by the pirates Morgan and Bartholomew...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack's smile remains. Barbossa puts a hand to his cutlass -</context>
      <utterance>I'm inclined to kill you now, Jack Sparrow, without so much as a word, if you don't lose that grin from your face.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Barbossa hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>The woman's blood didn't work, did it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know who's blood you need, to end the curse.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say the name, or I slit your throat.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Barbossa nods. Pintel steps forward, puts a blade to Jack's throat. Jack's smile widens.</context>
      <utterance>No you won't.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINTEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode>NODS</mode>
      <context>Surprised, Pintel lowers his cutlass. Jack's expression hasn't changed.</context>
      <utterance>Now.  No, don't kill him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Allow me the humor of listening to your terms.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Simple. I have something you want more than anything. The way to free you from the curse of the treasure. You have something I want -- more than anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Pearl?  Oh, that's fine. And just how do you expect this to work?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Barbossa stares at him, incredulous.</context>
      <utterance>You give me the Pearl. Then I tell you who you need.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's your offer? You, sailing away nice and pretty with the Black Pearl, and all I have is a name?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pirates laugh.</context>
      <utterance>I'm supposed to ... trust you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pirates laugh louder.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a man of my word.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT' D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see, I've got this honest streak in me -- in its own way, a sort of curse. Oh, and there's the fact that you have no choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll torture it out of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You left me on a desert island -- what worse can you do?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blast you! I'll throw you in prison.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait as long as you like.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're setting me up for a double cross, you with the ship, and me with nothing more than your word!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's say I tell you the wrong person. What would you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Track you down and - He sees where Jack is headed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Barbossa hesitates. The pirates are amazed at how the tide has turned; Barbossa has gone past considering the idea, and might even do it.</context>
      <utterance>And if I tell you the truth, you become mortal, and you won't come near me because you know I'd kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack, I don't trust you, and that's a fact. Never trust a smiling man, you can lay to that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, that's where we're different. I trust you ... to do what it takes to get what you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(decides, smiles)</context>
      <utterance>You're playing this as close to the edge as any man, I'll give you that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack nods.</context>
      <utterance>We might just have to sign articles, you and I. Jack, you're a pirate at heart, that's certain.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jack is caught completely off guard. For the first time, his smile fades.</context>
      <utterance>Pintel ... set sail. If this fool plan is to work, we'll need the medallion, and that means catching the ship which brought 'em here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What -- you don't have the medallion?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That fool woman took it. You be careful around her, Jack -- she's pretty enough, she'll steal your heart -- but pure evil inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll watch my back.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack nods, and is taken away. Barbossa stares after him, not hiding his mistrust.</context>
      <utterance>Bosun! Set up Mr. Sparrow's quarters, nice and fine ... in the brig.  Meaning no disrespect, of course.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands him the medallion.</context>
      <utterance>... you were in danger ... so I took the medallion. And I've kept it ever since. They thought I was you, that they needed my blood. And it didn't work.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would my father send this to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To keep it away from them? No pirate would sail to London, for fear of Execution Dock.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I had known-</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe he would make such a sacrifice for us.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AT THE HELM, Gibbs peers forward, scanning the horizon. There is a tiny island in front of them.</context>
      <utterance>I guess you can never truly know someone else's heart. Will glances at her, and nods.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shift your heading, steer clear of that island. Fifteen degrees starboard.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COTTON'S PARROT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cotton looks up - on the horizon, following: black sails. Gibbs and AnaMaria appear, and see the ship.</context>
      <utterance>Dead men tell NO tales! Dead men tell NO tales! Dead men tell NO tales!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAMARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we outrun them?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not a chance. Make for the reef.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ANAMARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like they mean to send us under.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AnaMaria, Gibbs, Cotton, even Elizabeth -- all know what this means. Will doesn't. He looks to Gibbs for an explanation:</context>
      <utterance>There -- she's raised the Jolly Roger, upside down.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT 'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a signal. If we resist, it won't just be death. There'll be torture as well.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Black Pearl fires again, a double-ball shot with a chain connecting the two. It hits the main mast dead ani a CRACKING, SPLINTING sound as it breaks, falls to the deck. Barbossa moves his ship alongside, preparing to board.</context>
      <utterance>We're not going to just surrender! GIBBS That we are.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can at least fight -- we might be able to kill a few-</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will stares -- and nods. But his expression is still defiant. The deck slants; the ship is sinking. pirates swarm across on ropes, and take control of the Interceptor.</context>
      <utterance>Will -- it'll go worse for us -- for Elizabeth, especially -- if we fight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shoves her into a group of pirates; they yell their approval. She is pushed from one to another. This goads Will to action. He head-butts the pirate behind him, grabs a pistol, waves it at the pirates.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome back, Miss. Last time on board, you played me right clever, make pretending and all. I hope your stay this time is more pleasant. Boys, show her some hospitality!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will leaps onto the ship's rail. He steadies himself with a hand on the rigging. Points the pistol at Barbossa.</context>
      <utterance>She goes free!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's in your head, boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She. Goes. Free.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got one shot -- and we can't die.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans out over the ocean.</context>
      <utterance>You can't. I can.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack pushes forward.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pintel squints at Will; the pirates murmur surprise.</context>
      <utterance>My name is Will Turner, the son of Bootstrap Bill Turner. His blood runs in my veins.  You need my blood. And on my word I will pull this trigger, and sink all the way down to Davy Jones' Locker!</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack drops his head. Barbossa grins at him.</context>
      <utterance>It's true - he's the spittin' image of old Bootstrap. Even talks the same!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like you're back to having nothing to offer.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINTEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Barbossa steps forward.</context>
      <utterance>And hers got Old Bill's courage. A curse on him, and you!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enough of that!  Name your terms.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth goes free!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got that part. Anything else?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Jack. And the crew. Free and unharmed. I f you agree... then... I will remain with you. Barbossa considers; his crew waits. Finally -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will -- you can't trust him.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must swear by the Holy Bible.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will lowers the gun ... steps down -- the pirates surround him. They snatch away the pistol.</context>
      <utterance>Eh? You have my word, then -- on the Good Book, I do swear, and the Lord spare my worthless soul. Barbossa crosses himself, as do many of his men.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Gibbs, AnaMaria, Cotton and the rest are led away under guard. Barbossa looks out to sea, toward the islet.</context>
      <utterance>Boatswain! Take your captives belowdecks. Chain them in the galley, and teach 'em how to row.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hah. Look there. That's the very same island we made Jack governor of on our last trip.  When you sail the open sea as long as I, you learn to trust the signs fate sends your way.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amen to that...</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack, Elizabeth ... I'm a man of my word and you're to be set free, right quick.  Men, break out the plank!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! You gave your word!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quiet, boy, or you'll lose your tongue. Those as know me know I wouldn't cross my word, and bring down bad luck on the ship.  I agreed to set them free. I didn't say when. .. nor where.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's pure evil to make a Captain walk the plank of his own ship, twice in one lifetime. No good can come of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, Jack. That reef is less than a league distant. It's a square deal all around, and you can't hope for better.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Barbossa smiles, shows a pistol. Points it at Jack.</context>
      <utterance>Someone needs to cut these bonds, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd best take a swim, Jack.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pirates mutter agreement.</context>
      <utterance>The last time you did this, you left me a pistol, with one shot.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PINTEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's proper, sir, according to the code.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By the Powers, you're right!  Where's Jack's pistol? Who's got it? Bring it forward!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pirate hands Jack's pistol to Barbossa.</context>
      <utterance>A gentleman might give us two pistols, seeing as there are two of us, this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pirates laugh. Barbossa tosses Jack the pistol -- but over his head, and down into the water with a splash.</context>
      <utterance>Tell you what. I'll give you one pistol, and let you be the gentleman, an' shoot the lady, and starve to death yourself!  That is, presuming you're not both drownded.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode>CONTID</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how did you get off that island, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can go to your grave not knowing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack glares at Barbossa. Then he's prodded with a cutlass, takes a step out. Reaches the end of the plank -- steps off. Jack plunges down into the water. Appears on the surface, floundering, struggles to stay afloat. Will and Elizabeth exchange helpless looks; there is nothing they can do.</context>
      <utterance>That's fair.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Barbossa indicates the plank.</context>
      <utterance>Here -- it will go well with your black heart !</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT' D</mode>
      <context>Barbossa raises an eyebrow, grins, nods.</context>
      <utterance>I will not walk into the ocean. You'll have to throw me in!</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pirates rush to comply. Lift her up, toss her over the rail -- with a scream she falls --</context>
      <utterance>Have at her, lads!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Jack lays on the beach. He has dismantled his pistol; the parts, ball and powder dry on his scarf.</context>
      <utterance>Not all that big, is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Has it changed since the last time you were here?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack checks to see if the pistol parts are dry; they are. He sets about re-assembling and loading his pistol.</context>
      <utterance>The trees are taller.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack has finished putting his pistol back together. He shoves it in his belt, walks off.</context>
      <utterance>I hope you have no intention of using that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth can't believe it.</context>
      <utterance>Not yet. Ask me again in a few weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain Sparrow! We have to get off this island -- immediately!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack heaves the trap door up and over, revealing a pit. Inside are barrels and bottles of rum ... all covered with dust and cobwebs, long abandoned. Jack's face falls.</context>
      <utterance>What is that? Is there a boat under there?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? What's wrong? How will this help us get off the island?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He jumps down into the pit, cracks open a bottle of rum,. takes a swig.</context>
      <utterance>It won't. It won't, and so we won't.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But ... you did it before! Last time -</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last time, I was here a grand total of three days. Last time, the rumrunners who used this island as a cache came by, and I bartered passage off.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But from the looks of this, they've long been'out of business, and so that won't be happening again.  We probably have your friend Norrington to thank for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So that's it? That's the secret grand adventure of the infamous</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack Sparrow? You spent three days on the beach drinking rum?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gathers up a few bottles, heads for the beach.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome to the Caribbean, love.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should look at our contretemps this way: we've got shade trees, thank the Lord. We've got some food on the trees, thank the Lord again. And we've got rum, praise the Lord. We can stay alive a month, maybe more. Keep a weather eye open for passing ships, and our chances are fair.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A month? Will doesn't have a month! We've got to do something to help him!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drinks -- and defiantly returns Elizabeth's angry gaze. But then turns away, sits down.</context>
      <utterance>You're right.  Here's luck to you, Will Turner.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be thinking I'm happy about this, Elizabeth. But I see no use in wailing and gnashing my teeth over that which I can do nothing about.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack tosses her a bottle.</context>
      <utterance>Not when you can drink instead, at least.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drink up me hearties, yo ho...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Please,</context>
      <utterance>What? What was that?  Something funny, Miss Swann? share.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing ... it's nothing. Just ... I'm reminded of a song I learned as a child. A song about pirates.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know a lot of songs about pirates, but none I'd teach a child. Let's hear it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, no ... it's silly. Back in England we didn't know a thing about pirates, really. They seemed so romantic and daring - Jack likes the way that sounds.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was before I met one, of course.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, perhaps ... with a bit more to drink, I might ...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gathers two more bottles, tosses one to her. She drops her half-finished bottle to catch it. Opens it, takes a sip.</context>
      <utterance>More to drink!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Elizabeth clears her throat, begins to sing self- consciously, becoming stronger as she goes on.</context>
      <utterance>Well?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gestures for him to drink. He does.</context>
      <utterance>We pillage, we plunder, we rifle, we loot, Drink up me hearties, yo ho.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We kidnap and ravage and we don't give a hoot, Drink up me hearties, yo ho -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JACK/ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yo ho, yo ho, it's a pirates life for me!</context>
      <utterance>Yo ho, yo ho, a pirate's life for me!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I LOVE this song!  Yo ho, yo ho, a pirate's life for me! We're beggars and blighters,</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hoist their bottles, but only Jack drinks. He drains the bottle, then tosses it away.</context>
      <utterance>ne'er do well cads, Drink up me hearties, yo ho!  Aye but we're loved by our mums and our dads. Drink up me hearties, yo ho!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I get the Black Pearl back, I'm going to teach it to the whole crew, and we'll sing it all the time!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth salutes the idea with her bottle. Jack doesn't have a bottle to salute back. She hands him hers. He drinks, then settles shakily to the ground. Elizabeth sits beside him.</context>
      <utterance>You'll be positively the most fearsome pirates to sail the Spanish Main.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth lays her head on his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Not just the Spanish Main. The whole ocean. .. the whole world. Wherever we want to go, we go. That's what a ship is, you know. Not just a keel and a hull and a deck and sails. That's what a ship need_ ... but what a ship is -- what the Black Pearl really-is ... is freedom.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack, it must be so terrible for you, to be trapped here on this island, all over again.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, well... the company is better than last time. And the scenery has definitely improved.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Sparrow! I'm not sure I've had enough rum to allow that kind of talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth shrugs with a sleight -- but promising -- smile. She picks up the empty bottle from the ground, holds it up.</context>
      <utterance>We've got a few bottles left ... and we've yet to tap the kegs.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To freedom.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They tap the bottles together. Elizabeth feigns a drink as he chugs. He taps his bottle against her again. She laughs, feigns another drink -</context>
      <utterance>To the Black Pearl.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing? You've burned our food, the shade -- the rum!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She wipes her hands together. One of the rum barrels in the fire EXPLODES.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, the rum is gone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One, because it is a vile drink that turns even the most respectable men into scoundrels. Two - She points to the sky.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That signal is over a thousand feet high, which means it can be seen for two hundred leagues in every direction. The entire Royal Navy is out to sea looking for me -- do you think there is even a chance they could mass it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You -- you burned up the island, for a one-time chance at being spotted?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth turns toward the sea.</context>
      <utterance>Exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She sits down, determined. Shields her eyes, scans the water, waiting, searching. Jack is speechless. He throws up his hands, stalks up the sand dune, just to get away from her.</context>
      <utterance>Just you wait, Captain. In an hour, maybe two, keep a 'weather eye open' and you'll be seeing white sails on that horizon!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth, I'm" relieved you're safe.  Clap him in irons. And behind his back this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETII</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Commodore, you can't do that!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're speaking up for him again?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He can locate Isla de Muerta -- but I doubt he'll be willing to help us from the brig.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We had time to get to know each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are bound for Port Royal, not Isla de Muerta.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. The pirates have taken Will -</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your father is frantic with worry. Our mission was to rescue you and return home. That is what we shall do. Mr. Turner's fate is regrettable. But so was his decision to engage in piracy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Commodore, please!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By remembering that I serve others, not only myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Commodore, I beg you -- please do this ... for me. As a wedding gift.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am to understand that you will accept my marriage proposal on the condition I rescue Mr. Turner?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norrington considers. To Gillette:</context>
      <utterance>Not as a condition -- a request.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gillette unlocks Jack's manacles. Jack raises an eyebrow.</context>
      <utterance>Free Mister Sparrow, and prepare to come about. He'll give you our heading.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crew men lead Jack toward the bridge. Sailors go about their tasks, and the ship begins its slow turn.</context>
      <utterance>Congratulations, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth, I hereby withdraw my proposal.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth looks at Norrington, seeing him in a new light.</context>
      <utterance>I know now where your heart truly lies.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They gaze at each other for a moment. Norrington looks away.</context>
      <utterance>And now I know... where yours does, as well.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You may seclude yourself in my cabin. I'm afraid we do not have any ladies' clothing aboard.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I can wear men's clothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That would hardly be proper.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norrington is exasperated, but then can't help but grin - this is exactly why he loves her. She grins back at him - she's not going to change.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I am not going to stay hidden in a some cabin, 80 I suppose it's going to be heaving bosoms and bare ankles for the remainder of the voyage!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth smiles, allows herself to be escorted away. Norrington watches her go ... then turns his gaze to the sea.</context>
      <utterance>Murtogg, take our guest below, and find her some trousers, and a shirt.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to William Turner?</utterance>
   <speaker>PINTEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, William Turner. Stupid blighter. He threw in with us after we relieved Jack Sparrow of his captaincy, but turned out, it never sat well with him- particularly after we found Cortes' treasure, and its peculiar condition. He thought we deserved to be cursed, for leaving ol' Jack to the fate we did. That's why he sent off a piece of the treasure -- to you, as it were: so it would never be recovered, and so cursed we_ remain.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then he ran. And he's hiding out someplace where you haven't been able to find him.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINTEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will reacts with shock at the account of his father's fate.</context>
      <utterance>That's a nice thought, to be sure, and I wager your da wishes he'd thought it hisself. But, no. See, what he'd done, _ didn't sit too well with Captain Barbossa ... so he chained a cannon to his legs and dumped him over.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINTEL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Barbossa appears behind Pintel, flanked by several other pirates. He regards Will for a moment, then:</context>
      <utterance>Yep, last I saw of Bootstrap Bill, was his face looking up, as he sank down to the crushing black oblivion of Davy Jones' locker.  It was only after, we found out we needed his blood to solve the curse. That's what you call ironic.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bring him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't tell Commodore Norrington everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nor did you, I noticed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He might delay the rescue ... and that would be too late.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These men will be facing an enemy that seemingly cannot be killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a plan. If it succeeds, then any battle will be decidedly brief ... and one-sided.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your plan?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts to speak; he turns away..</context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth -- below decks. I will not compromise your safety..</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant, escort Elizabeth to my quarters, and make sure she stays there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't like the situation, mister Sparrow. The island is riddled with caves. I will not put my men at a disadvantage.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Funny, I was thinking along those lines. How about you let me go in alone, and while you're setting up an ambush, I'll trick the pirates out to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You would do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They left me stranded. Twice. What have you got to lose?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing I wouldn't be please to be rid of.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew you'd listen to reason!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That chart I drew up'11 get you past the reefs. If you're steersman's good enough, that is.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be at the wheel myself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PINTEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No reason to fret. It's just a prick of the finger and a few drops of blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turner blood doesn't flow pure in his veins.  Best play it safe, and spill it all.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINTEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess there is a reason to fret.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will makes a decision. He intentionally stumbles. Pintel shoves him forward -- Will continues forward, grabs the pirate in front of him, swings him into the wall of the cave. Catches the pirate's torch, and uses it to ward off the others.</context>
      <utterance>Careful, now. You could fall in and still be wonder'n when you'll hit dirt.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You deserve to be cursed -- and remain cursed!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have any idea where you're going?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't talk. These caves magnify sound. Just follow me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you certain this is the right way?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will join him -- and see what Jack is staring at: Treasure piled on treasure, sparkling, glowing, seemingly endless. At the center is the moonlit clearing, and the stone Aztec chest.</context>
      <utterance>It's the right way.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The jump -- Barbossa is standing right behind them, flanked by his men. The trio whirl to run - - more pirates emerge from hiding. Nearly the entire crew of the Black Pearl is there. The pirates grab Will and Jack. Will struggles, but Jack does not fight at all.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Jack Sparrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He laughs, and moves toward the stone chest. The pirates follow, dragging Will and Jack with them.</context>
      <utterance>You couldn't have led him back more directly if you knew exactly where you were going.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks away -- as Will is manhandled toward the chest. Barbo8sa steps up to him (becoming skeletal in the moonlight) and puts the medallion around Will's neck.</context>
      <utterance>You did know where you were going! You did lead us directly to them!  Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He picks up the stone knife.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He raises the knife to Will's throat -</context>
      <utterance>What was begun by blood, let blood now end!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Barbossa pretends to think about his words.</context>
      <utterance>You don't want to be doing that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I really think I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That makes Barbossa pause. He steps out of the moonlight.</context>
      <utterance>All right then.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't I want to do this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because, right about now, the H.M.S. Dauntless is lying in wait in the harbor.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A buzz of apprehension sweeps through the pirates.</context>
      <utterance>- - and its guns and crew will cut you and your men to pieces the moment you step outside these caves.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINTEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you believe him?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.  But him I believe. He is genuinely angry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've no hope of surviving Norrington's attack ... that is, if you're mortal.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack shakes off the hands holding him, strolls toward Barbossa, Will, and the chest of coins.</context>
      <utterance>What're you suggesting?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will glares, listening to every word he says. Jack scoops up a handful of coins from the chest.</context>
      <utterance>Simple. Don't kill the boy yet. Wait for a more opportune moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Last ... One ... of Norrington's men.</context>
      <utterance>Like after you've killed... Every...</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't help wondering, Jack, why you're being so helpful and all? Last time you did that, it didn't end 80 well for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The situation has changed.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That so?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(beat)</context>
      <utterance>Aye. See, after you're done with the Royal Navy, you'll have a bit of a problem: the H.M.S. Dauntless. There you'll be, with two lovely ships on your hands, and what to do? Of course you'll decide you deserve the bigger one, and who's to argue? The Dauntless a first-rate ship-of-line, and with it, you can rule the seas.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack smiles and spreads his hands: me.</context>
      <utterance>But if you're Captain of the Dauntless, who's left for the Black Pearl?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Barbossa licks his lips. It's tempting ...</context>
      <utterance>I sail for you as part of your fleet, I give you fifteen percent of my plunder, and you get to introduce yourself at tea parties and brothels as 'Commodore Barbossa.'  Do we have an accord?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, you can take care of the Dauntless, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pirates yell to the affirmative.</context>
      <utterance>Men! Are you up for it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jack's expression falters; this he hadn't planned for.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Pintel, select five men to stay here. Take the rest of the men out ... not through the caves.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's ... another exit?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aye, for us there is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TALL SAILOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ship rats. Big ones.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHORT SAILOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They turn back toward the island, continue their vigil. A long pause.</context>
      <utterance>Hate those things.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHORT SAILOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Taste all right, though.</utterance>
   <speaker>TALL SAILOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From behind, the two sailors at the rail are well-lit by a lantern. Suddenly shadows appear, skeletons, climbing up the sailor's backs. -MOVE CLOSER and then the skeletons appear, reaching -- the two sailors are grabbed from behind</context>
      <utterance>That they do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BONED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>skeleton.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKINNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which would you prefer first, good sir -rum, or wine?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG-BONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They burst out laughing -- a hideous sound that wheezes through their bones. Behind them, unnoticed, Elizabeth peeks cautiously around a corner. She picks her moment and sneaks past quickly, down a gangway, disappearing into the blackness of the ship.</context>
      <utterance>I believe I'll have a spot o' rum, if you don't mind, and thank'ee kind sir!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GILLETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All the men in place, sir. Ready to fire.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's the sound of cannon fire -- coming from the Dauntless. Cannonballs hit the shore; men cry out in anguish.</context>
      <utterance>Wait for my order -- what the blazes is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The sailors scramble to find refuge -</context>
      <utterance>Men! Take cover!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack takes the opportunity to move toward him.</context>
      <utterance>You've been planning this from the beginning. Since you learned my name.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Will can answer, Jack smoothly slips the sword from a Pirate's scabbard -- tosses it to Will, who catches it despite his surprise.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, please -- do I really seem that clever?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He draws his own sword -- and clobbers the Pirate. Barbossa and the other pirates stare in shock -</context>
      <utterance>Use it well.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Swords are drawn, and the Pirates attack. Jack and Will take on multiple opponents, each with his own style: Will parries, glissades and disarms with lightning fast and perfect form, while Jack uses his blade, fists, acrobatics and anything within reach to survive.</context>
      <utterance>Confound it, Jack -- I was actually beginning to like you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sailors recover their nerve, and engage the enemy. It's a full on battle, Royal Navy against Skeleton Pirates -</context>
      <utterance>Steady, men! Remember -- we're the Navy!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norrington, in the midst of a swordfight, tries to see -</context>
      <utterance>The Navy men are driven back, surrounded - Suddenly there is a massive BOOM of cannon fire.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is happening out there?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just so you know, Jack -- I don't think you're that clever. I think you're a fool. A mortal fool.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack drives him back, making Barbossa laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Remarkable how often those two traits coincide.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't beat me, Jack.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack stares down at the sword jutting from his chest. He takes a few steps backward, toward the Aztec gold -- when he steps into the moonlight, JACK BECOME SKELETAL.</context>
      <utterance>Jack!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Skeleton Jack pulls the sword from his chest. He pulls something from his pocket: one of the Aztec coins.</context>
      <utterance>Well, isn't that interesting.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT' D</mode>
      <context>Barbossa grabs up his sword, and rushes Jack. Both men are in moonlight now, two skeletons in pitched battle.</context>
      <utterance>They're so pretty, I just couldn't resist stealing one. It's a curse, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what now, Jack Sparrow? Are we to be two immortals, locked in epic battle until the trumpets of Judgment Day?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shoves Barbossa back, out of the moonlight. Barbossa stalks the room, his attention focused on Jack.</context>
      <utterance>Or you could surrender.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or I could chain you to a cannonball and drop you in the deepest part of the ocean, where you can contemplate your folly forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Barbossa charges -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BARBOSSA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hah. Ten years you carried that pistol, and you end up wasting your shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will stands over the Aztec chest, holding a bloody sword, his left hand in a fist. He opens the fist - -- the medallion, blood covering it, drops from his hand, revealing the cut in his palm. Barbossa stares, then looks down at his chest. Blood blossoms on his shirt around the bullet hole. It spreads quickly. Barbossa clutches his chest, his face registering pain for the first time in years. Barbossa falls heavily to the ground, dead. Jack blows the smoke from the barrel of his pistol... tosses it away.</context>
      <utterance>He didn't waste it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you're the worst pirate I've ever heard of.  You're a man who can be trusted, who can be counted on, and who can It betray his friends. What kind of pirate is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the other hand, maybe I'm a man who can't pass up a chance for revenge against the black-hearted bastard who stole my ship and left me to die in the middle of the ocean -- twice! -- and who knows how to get what he wants. Now that's a great pirate. Jack cuts his palm, grips the coin he stole above the chest ... and then hesitates. Will looks at him... Jack releases the coin. It lands in the chest beside the other bloody coin. Suddenly, the lid of the chest, all on its own, SLAMS SHUT. Elizabeth stares at it.</context>
      <utterance>The worst.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's get out of here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth can't believe that's what he noticed. Indignant, she steps away from him.</context>
      <utterance>Miss Swann -- are you wearing trousers? And how did you get off the island?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches a hand behind his neck, decisively kisses him.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I am wearing trousers. And as for how we got off the island -- ah, that's a grand adventure, but now is not the time to talk about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There. And don't you dare tell me that wasn't a proper kiss!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth, I think it doesn't matter- that we are of a different class -</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pure consternation on Elizabeth's face -</context>
      <utterance>-- but that was not a proper kiss.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Will sweeps her in his arms, leans her back, and kisses her long and well - Jack puts a hand on Norrington's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>This is a proper kiss.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tough luck. I was rooting for you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the crowd, Elizabeth squeezes the hand of her father, Swann. She lets go as Swann stands.</context>
      <utterance>...and though I do say so with regret, the law is clear. The penalty for piracy is death by hanging.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWANN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By your leave, I wish to speak on behalf of the boy.  It is clear that these deeds were performed out of a sincere desire to do good, at great personal risk. It seems to me, that in the rare occasion where the right course is committing an act of piracy, then an act of piracy is the right course!  So in my capacity as Governor, I intend to grant a pardon to --</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All eyes turn. Gillette stands at the top of a stairway.</context>
      <utterance>Sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLETTE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Will and Elizabeth exchange looks. You? Not me, you? No, not me either! Swann notices something the parapet, points</context>
      <utterance>Jack and his crew have escaped!  There was no damage to the cell ... they must have been set free.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GILLETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir! Shall I break out the cannons?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norrington raises his hand ... twirls a key on his finger.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think that will be necessary.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORRINGTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Will, Elizabeth and Swann look out toward ocean-</context>
      <utterance>A day's head start. That's all he gets.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ANAMARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack runs a hand lovingly along the rail, then takes the wheel. It feels good -- right -- in his hands. He enjoys it, and then shifts to 'Captain' mode.</context>
      <utterance>Captain Sparrow -- the Black Pearl is yours!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>AnaMaria, trim the mainsail!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAMARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aye, aye, sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gibbs actually stomps the deck, executes a salute.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Gibbs, organize a cleaning detail - you and Cotton. I want every inch of the Pearl spic-and-span and ship-shape!</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
