<movie id="450" title="Pulp Fiction">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="55">
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, forget it, it's too risky. I'm through doin' that shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You always say that, the same thing every time: never again, I'm through, too dangerous.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know that's what I always say. I'm always right too, but –</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>– but you forget about it in a day or two -</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>– yeah, well, the days of me forgittin' are over, and the days of me rememberin' have just begun.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When you go on like this, you know what you sound like?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I sound like a sensible fucking man, is what I sound like.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sound like a duck.  Quack, quack, quack, quack, quack, quack, quack...</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well take heart, 'cause you're never gonna hafta hear it again. Because since I'm never gonna do it again, you're never gonna hafta hear me quack about how I'm never gonna do it again.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy and girl laugh, their laughter putting a pause in there, back and forth.</context>
      <utterance>After tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A WAITRESS comes by with a pot of coffee.</context>
      <utterance>Correct. I got all tonight to quack.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I get anybody anymore coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Waitress pours the Young Woman's coffee. The Young Man lights up another cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yes, thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Waitress leaves. The Young Man takes a drag off of his smoke. The Young Woman pours a ton of cream and sugar into her coffee. The Young Man goes right back into it.</context>
      <utterance>I'm doin' fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean the way it is now, you're takin' the same fuckin' risk as when you rob a bank. You take more of a risk. Banks are easier! Federal banks aren't supposed to stop you anyway, during a robbery. They're insured, why should they care? You don't even need a gun in a federal bank. I heard about this guy, walked into a federal bank with a portable phone, handed the phone to the teller, the guy on the other end of the phone said: "We got this guy's little girl, and if you don't give him all your money, we're gonna kill 'er."</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did it work?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuckin' A it worked, that's what I'm talkin' about! Knucklehead walks in a bank with a telephone, not a pistol, not a shotgun, but a fuckin' phone, cleans the place out, and they don't lift a fuckin' finger.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did they hurt the little girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. There probably never was a little girl – the point of the story isn't the little girl. The point of the story is they robbed the bank with a telephone.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna rob banks?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sayin' I wanna rob banks, I'm just illustrating that if we did, it would be easier than what we been doin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you don't want to be a bank robber?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naw, all those guys are goin' down the same road, either dead or servin' twenty.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And no more liquor stores?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What have we been talking about? Yeah, no more-liquor-stores. Besides, it ain't the giggle it usta be. Too many foreigners own liquor stores. Vietnamese, Koreans, they can't fuckin' speak English. You tell 'em: "Empty out the register," and they don't know what it fuckin' means. They make it too personal. We keep on, one of those gook motherfuckers' gonna make us kill 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not gonna kill anybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't wanna kill anybody either. But they'll probably put us in a situation where it's us of them. And if it's not the gooks, it these old Jews who've owned the store for fifteen fuckin' generations. Ya got Grandpa Irving sittin' behind the counter with a fuckin' Magnum. Try walkin' into one of those stores with nothin' but a telephone, see how far it gets you. Fuck it, forget it, we're out of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what else is there, day jobs?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not this life.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He calls to the Waitress.</context>
      <utterance>Well what then?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then looks to his girl.</context>
      <utterance>Garcon! Coffee!</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This place. The Waitress comes by, pouring him some more.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She splits.</context>
      <utterance>"Garcon" means boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here? It's a coffee shop.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with that? People never rob restaurants, why not? Bars, liquor stores, gas stations, you get your head blown off stickin' up one of them. Restaurants, on the other hand, you catch with their pants down. They're not expecting to get robbed, or not as expecting.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bet in places like this you could cut down on the hero factor.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Young Woman visibly takes in the idea. The Young Man continues in a low voice.</context>
      <utterance>Correct. Just like banks, these places are insured. The managers don't give a fuck, they're just tryin' to get ya out the door before you start pluggin' diners. Waitresses, forget it, they ain't takin' a bullet for the register. Busboys, some wetback gettin' paid a dollar fifty a hour gonna really give a fuck you're stealin' from the owner. Customers are sittin' there with food in their mouths, they don't know what's goin' on. One minute they're havin' a Denver omelet, next minute somebody's stickin' a gun in their face.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, I got the idea last liquor store we stuck up. 'Member all those customers kept comin' in?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you got the idea to take everybody's wallet.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was a good idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We made more from the wallets then we did the register.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes we did.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A lot of people go to restaurants.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A lot of wallets.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Young Woman scans the restaurant with this new information. She sees all the PATRONS eating, lost in conversations. The tired WAITRESS, taking orders. The BUSBOYS going through the motions, collecting dishes. The MANAGER complaining to the COOK about something. A smiles breaks out on the Young Woman's face.</context>
      <utterance>Pretty smart, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretty smart.  I'm ready, let's go, right here, right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember, same as before, you're crowd control, I handle the employees.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both take out their .32-caliber pistols and lay them on the table. He looks at her and she back at him.</context>
      <utterance>Got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you, Pumpkin.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that, Pumpkin and Honey Bunny grab their weapons, stand up and rob the restaurant. Pumpkin's robbery persona is that of the in-control professional. Honey Bunny's is that of the psychopathic, hair-triggered, loose cannon.</context>
      <utterance>I love you, Honey Bunny.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUMPKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody be cool this is a robbery!</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEY BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any of you fuckin' pricks move and I'll execute every one of you motherfuckers! Got that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>– Okay now, tell me about the hash bars?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What so you want to know?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, hash is legal there, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it's legal, but is ain't a hundred percent legal. I mean you can't walk into a restaurant, roll a joint, and start puffin' away. You're only supposed to smoke in your home or certain designated places.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those are hash bars?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it breaks down like this: it's legal to buy it, it's legal to own it and, if you're the proprietor of a hash bar, it's legal to sell it. It's legal to carry it, which doesn't really matter 'cause – get a load of this – if the cops stop you, it's illegal for this to search you. Searching you is a right that the cops in Amsterdam don't have.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That did it, man – I'm fuckin' goin', that's all there is to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll dig it the most. But you know what the funniest thing about Europe is?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the little differences. A lotta the same shit we got here, they got there, but there they're a little different.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Examples?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, in Amsterdam, you can buy beer in a movie theatre. And I don't mean in a paper cup either. They give you a glass of beer, like in a bar. In Paris, you can buy beer at MacDonald's. Also, you know what they call a Quarter Pounder with Cheese in Paris?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't call it a Quarter Pounder with Cheese?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, they got the metric system there, they wouldn't know what the fuck a Quarter Pounder is.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd they call it?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Royale with Cheese.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Royale with Cheese. What'd they call a Big Mac?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big Mac's a Big Mac, but they call it Le Big Mac.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Le Big Mac. What do they call a Whopper?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dunno, I didn't go into a Burger King. But you know what they put on french fries in Holland instead of ketchup?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mayonnaise.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamn!</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I seen 'em do it. And I don't mean a little bit on the side of the plate, they fuckin' drown 'em in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uuccch!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should have shotguns for this kind of deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many up there?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three or four.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Counting our guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So there could be five guys up there?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They CLOSE the trunk.</context>
      <utterance>We should have fuckin' shotguns.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's her name?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mia.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did Marsellus and her meet?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dunno, however people meet people. She usta be an actress.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She ever do anything I woulda saw?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think her biggest deal was she starred in a pilot.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's a pilot?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you know the shows on TV?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't watch TV.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, but you're aware that there's an invention called television, and on that invention they show shows?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They enter the apartment building.</context>
      <utterance>Well, the way they pick the shows on TV is they make one show, and that show's called a pilot. And they show that one show to the people who pick the shows, and on the strength of that one show, they decide if they want to make more shows. Some get accepted and become TV programs, and some don't, and become nothing. She starred in one of the ones that became nothing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You remember Antwan Rockamora? Half- black, half-Samoan, usta call him Tony Rocky Horror.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah maybe, fat right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't go so far as to call the brother fat. He's got a weight problem. What's the nigger gonna do, he's Samoan.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I know who you mean, what about him?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The elevator arrives, the men step inside.</context>
      <utterance>Well, Marsellus fucked his ass up good. And word around the campfire, it was on account of Marsellus Wallace's wife.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd he do, fuck her?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No no no no no no no, nothin' that bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well what then?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He gave her a foot massage.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jules nods his head: "Yes."</context>
      <utterance>A foot massage?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jules nods his head: "Yes."</context>
      <utterance>That's all?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did Marsellus do?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The elevator doors open, Jules and Vincent exit.</context>
      <utterance>Sent a couple of guys over to his place. They took him out on the patio of his apartment, threw his ass over the balcony. Nigger fell four stories. They had this garden at the bottom, enclosed in glass, like one of them greenhouses – nigger fell through that. Since then, he's kinda developed a speech impediment.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a damn shame.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="34">
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still I hafta say, play with matches, ya get burned.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whaddya mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't be givin' Marsellus Wallace's new bride a foot massage.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't think he overreacted?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Antwan probably didn't expect Marsellus to react like he did, but he had to expect a reaction.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was a foot massage, a foot massage is nothing, I give my mother a foot massage.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jules stops Vincent.</context>
      <utterance>It's laying hands on Marsellus Wallace's new wife in a familiar way. Is it as bad as eatin' her out – no, but you're in the same fuckin' ballpark.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa... whoa... whoa... stop right there. Eatin' a bitch out, and givin' a bitch a foot massage ain't even the same fuckin' thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not the same thing, the same ballpark.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Foot massages don't mean shit.</context>
      <utterance>It ain't no ballpark either. Look maybe your method of massage differs from mine, but touchin' his lady's feet, and stickin' your tongue in her holyiest of holyies, ain't the same ballpark, ain't the same league, ain't even the same fuckin' sport.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you ever given a foot massage?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be tellin' me about foot massages – I'm the foot fuckin' master.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Given a lot of 'em?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit yeah. I got my technique down man, I don't tickle or nothin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jules looks at him a long moment – he's been set up.</context>
      <utterance>Have you ever given a guy a foot massage?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts walking down the hall. Vincent, smiling, walks a little bit behind.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you give me a foot massage – I'm kinda tired.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men stand in front of the door numbered "49." They whisper.</context>
      <utterance>Man, you best back off, I'm gittin' pissed – this is the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What time is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seven-twenty-two in the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They move a little away from the door, facing each other, still whispering.</context>
      <utterance>It ain't quite time, let's hang back.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, just because I wouldn't give no man a foot massage, don't make it right for Marsellus to throw Antwan off a building into a glass- motherfuckin-house, fuckin' up the way the nigger talks. That ain't right, man. Motherfucker do that to me, he better paralyze my ass, 'cause I'd kill'a motherfucker.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sayin' he was right, but you're sayin' a foot massage don't mean nothing, and I'm sayin' it does. I've given a million ladies a million foot massages and they all meant somethin'. We act like they don't, but they do. That's what's so fuckin' cool about 'em. This sensual thing's goin' on that nobody's talkin about, but you know it and she knows it, fuckin' Marsellus knew it, and Antwan shoulda known fuckin' better. That's his fuckin' wife, man. He ain't gonna have a sense of humor about that shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's an interesting point, but let's get into character.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's her name again?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mia. Why you so interested in big man's wife?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Marsellus is leavin' for Florida and when he's gone, he wants me to take care of Mia.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Making a gun out of his finger and placing it to his head.</context>
      <utterance>Take care of her?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not that! Take her out. Show her a good time. Don't let her get lonely.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gonna be takin' Mia Wallace out on a date?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jules just looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>It ain't a date. It's like when you and your buddy's wife go to a movie or somethin'. It's just... you know... good company.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jules just looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>It's not a date.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="75">
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men stroll inside. The three young caught-off-guard Guys are: MARVIN, the black young man, who open the door, will, as the scene progresses, back into the corner. ROGER, a young blond-haired surfer kid with a "Flock of Seagulls" haircut, who has yet to say a word, sits at the table with a big sloppy hamburger in his hand. BRETT, a white, preppy-looking sort with a blow-dry haircut. Vincent and Jules take in the place, with their hands in their pockets. Jules is the one who does the talking.</context>
      <utterance>Hey kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer.</context>
      <utterance>How you boys doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I trippin', or did I just ask you a question.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Jules and Brett talk, Vincent moves behind the young Guys.</context>
      <utterance>We're doin' okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brett shakes his head: "No."</context>
      <utterance>Do you know who we are?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer.</context>
      <utterance>We're associates of your business partner Marsellus Wallace, you remember your business partner dont'ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now I'm gonna take a wild guess here: you're Brett, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Brett.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought so. Well, you remember your business partner Marsellus Wallace, dont'ya Brett?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I remember him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good for you. Looks like me and Vincent caught you at breakfast, sorry 'bout that. What'cha eatin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hamburgers.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hamburgers. The cornerstone of any nutritious breakfast. What kinda hamburgers?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cheeseburgers.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I mean where did you get'em? MacDonald's, Wendy's, Jack-in-the- Box, where?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big Kahuna Burger.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big Kahuna Burger. That's that Hawaiian burger joint. I heard they got some tasty burgers. I ain't never had one myself, how are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're good.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mind if I try one of yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yours is this one, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Jules grabs the burger and take a bite of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uuummmm, that's a tasty burger.  Vince, you ever try a Big Kahuna Burger?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jules holds out the Big Kahuna.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna bite, they're real good.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if you like hamburgers give 'em a try sometime. Me, I can't usually eat 'em 'cause my girlfriend's a vegetarian. Which more or less makes me a vegetarian, but I sure love the taste of a good burger.  You know what they call a Quarter Pounder with Cheese in France?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell 'em, Vincent.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Royale with Cheese.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Royale with Cheese, you know why they call it that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because of the metric system?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Check out the big brain on Brett. You'a smart motherfucker, that's right. The metric system.  What's in this?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sprite.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sprite, good, mind if I have some of your tasty beverage to wash this down with?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jules grabs the cup and takes a sip.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roger nods his head: "Yes."</context>
      <utterance>Uuuuummmm, hit's the spot!  You, Flock of Seagulls, you know what we're here for?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why don't you tell my boy here Vince, where you got the shit hid.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's under the be –</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>– I don't remember askin' you a goddamn thing.  You were sayin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent moves to the bed, reaches underneath it, pulling out a black snap briefcase.</context>
      <utterance>It's under the bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent flips the two locks, opening the case. We can't see what's inside, but a small glow emits from the case. Vincent just stares at it, transfixed.</context>
      <utterance>Got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer from the transfixed Vincent.</context>
      <utterance>We happy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent looks up at Jules.</context>
      <utterance>Vincent!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Closing the case.</context>
      <utterance>We happy?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, what's your name? I got his name's Vincent, but what's yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name's Pitt, and you ain't talkin' your ass outta this shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Brett talks, Jules takes out his gun and SHOOTS Roger three times in the chest, BLOWING him out of his chair. Vince smiles to himself. Jules has got style. Brett has just shit his pants. He's not crying or whimpering, but he's so full of fear, it's as if his body is imploding.</context>
      <utterance>I just want you to know how sorry we are about how fucked up things got between us and Mr. Wallace. When we entered into this thing, we only had the best intentions –</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm sorry. Did that break your concentration? I didn't mean to do that. Please, continue. I believe you were saying something about "best intentions." Brett can't say a word.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jules SNAPS, SAVAGELY TIPPING the card table over, removing the only barrier between himself and Brett. Brett now sits in a lone chair before Jules like a political prisoner in front of an interrogator.</context>
      <utterance>Whatsamatter? Oh, you were through anyway. Well, let me retort. Would you describe for me what Marsellus Wallace looks like? Brett still can't speak.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What country you from!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"What" ain't no country I know! Do they speak English in "What?"</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>English-motherfucker-can-you-speak- it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you understand what I'm sayin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now describe what Marsellus Wallace looks like!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jules takes his .45 and PRESSES the barrel HARD in Brett's cheek.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brett is regressing on the spot.</context>
      <utterance>Say "What" again! C'mon, say "What" again! I dare ya, I double dare ya motherfucker, say "What" one more goddamn time!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brett does his best.</context>
      <utterance>Now describe to me what Marsellus Wallace looks like!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well he's... he's... black –</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>– go on!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and he's... he's... bald –</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>– does he look like a bitch?!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jules' eyes go to Vincent, Vincent smirks, Jules rolls his eyes and SHOOT Brett in the shoulder. Brett SCREAMS, breaking into a SHAKING/TREMBLING SPASM in the chair.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does-he-look-like-a-bitch?!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why did you try to fuck 'im like a bitch?!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now in a lower voice.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes ya did Brett. Ya tried ta fuck 'im. You ever read the Bible, Brett?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men EMPTY their guns at the same time on the sitting Brett.</context>
      <utterance>There's a passage I got memorized, seems appropriate for this situation: Ezekiel 25:17. "The path of the righteous man is beset on all sides by the inequities of the selfish and the tyranny of evil men. Blessed is he who, in the name of charity and good will, shepherds the weak through the valley of darkness, for he is truly his brother's keeper and the finder of lost children. And I will strike down upon thee with great vengeance and furious anger those who attempt to poison and destroy my brothers. And you will know my name is the Lord when I lay my vengeance upon you."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MARSELLUS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>A hand lays an envelope full of money on the table in front of Butch. Butch picks it up.</context>
      <utterance>I think you're gonna find – when all this shit is over and done – I think you're gonna find yourself one smilin' motherfucker. Thing is Butch, right now you got ability. But painful as it may be, ability don't last. Now that's a hard motherfuckin' fact of life, but it's a fact of life your ass is gonna hafta git realistic about. This business is filled to the brim with unrealistic motherfuckers who thought their ass aged like wine. Besides, even if you went all the way, what would you be? Feather-weight champion of the world. Who gives a shit? I doubt you can even get a credit card based on that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSELLUS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now the night of the fight, you may fell a slight sting, that's pride fuckin' wit ya. Fuck pride! Pride only hurts, it never helps. Fight through that shit. 'Cause a year from now, when you're kickin' it in the Caribbean you're gonna say, "Marsellus Wallace was right."</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got no problem with that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSELLUS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Butch nods his head: "yes."</context>
      <utterance>In the fifth, your ass goes down.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSELLUS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say it!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the fifth, my ass goes down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's the big man?</utterance>
   <speaker>ENGLISH DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VINCENT'S POV: Butch shakes hands with a huge figure with his back to us. The huge figure is the infamous and as of yet still UNSEEN Marsellus.</context>
      <utterance>He's over there, finishing up some business.</utterance>
   <speaker>ENGLISH DAVE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hang back for a second or two, and when you see the white boy leave, go on over. In the meanwhile, can I make you an espresso?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How 'bout a cup of just plain lo' American?</utterance>
   <speaker>ENGLISH DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Comin' up. I hear you're taking Mia out tomorrow?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At Marsellus' request.</utterance>
   <speaker>ENGLISH DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you met Mia?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>English Dave smiles to himself.</context>
      <utterance>Not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's so funny?</utterance>
   <speaker>ENGLISH DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not a goddamn thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>English Dave puts Vince's coffee in front of him.</context>
      <utterance>Look, I'm not a idiot. She's the big man's fuckin' wife. I'm gonna sit across a table, chew my food with my mouth closed, laugh at her jokes and that's all I'm gonna do.</utterance>
   <speaker>ENGLISH DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch bellies up to the bar next to Vincent, drinking his cup of "Plain ol' American."</context>
      <utterance>My name's Paul, and this is between y'all.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I get a pack'a Red Apples?</utterance>
   <speaker>ENGLISH DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Filters?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>While Butch waits for his smokes, Vincent just sips his coffee, staring at him. Butch looks over at him.</context>
      <utterance>Non.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lookin' at somethin', friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch does a slow turn toward Vincent.</context>
      <utterance>I ain't your friend, palooka.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch turns his body to Vincent, when...</context>
      <utterance>I think ya heard me just fine, punchy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSELLUS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Vincent walks forward OUT OF FRAME, never giving Butch another glance. We DOLLY INTO CU on Butch, left alone in the FRAME, looking like he's ready to go into the manners-teaching business. BUTCH'S POV: Vincent hugging and kissing the obscured figure that is Marsellus. Butch makes the wise decision that is this asshole's a friend of Marsellus, he better let it go – for now.</context>
      <utterance>Vincent Vega has entered the building, git your ass over here!</utterance>
   <speaker>ENGLISH DAVE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Butch is snapped out of his ass-kicking thoughts. He pays English Dave and walks out of the SHOT.</context>
      <utterance>Pack of Red Apples, dollar-forty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jody, Vincent and a young woman named TRUDI sit at the kitchen table of a suburban house in Echo Park. Even though Vince is at the same table, he's not included in the conversation.</context>
      <utterance>...I'll lend it to you. It's a great book on body piercing.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know how they use that gun when they pierce your ears? They don't use that when they pierce your nipples, do they?</utterance>
   <speaker>JODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vince has been letting this conversation go through one ear and out the other, until that last remark.</context>
      <utterance>Forget that gun. That gun goes against the entire idea behind piercing. All of my piercing, sixteen places on my body, every one of 'em done with a needle. Five in each ear. One through the nipple on my left breast. One through my right nostril. One through my left eyebrow. One through my lip. One in my clit. And I wear a stud in my tongue.</utterance>
   <speaker>JODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That thought never occurred to Vincent, but he can't deny it makes sense. Jody continues talking to Trudi, leaving Vincent to ponder the truth of her statement.</context>
      <utterance>It's a sex thing. It helps fellatio.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vince, you can come in now!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now this is Panda, from Mexico. Very good stuff. This is Bava, different, but equally good. And this is Choco from the Hartz Mountains of Germany. Now the first two are the same, forty- five an ounce – those are friend prices – but this one...  ...this one's a little more expensive. It's fifty-five. But when you shoot it, you'll know where that extra money went. Nothing wrong with the first two. It's real, real, real, good shit. But this one's a fuckin' madman.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember, I just got back from Amsterdam.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I a nigger? Are you in Inglewood? No. You're in my house. White people who know the difference between good shit and bad shit, this is the house they come to. My shit, I'll take the Pepsi Challenge with Amsterdam shit any ol' day of the fuckin' week.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a bold statement.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent takes out a roll of money that would choke a horse to death.</context>
      <utterance>This ain't Amsterdam, Vince. This is a seller's market. Coke is fuckin' dead as disco. Heroin's comin' back in a big fuckin' way. It's this whole seventies retro. Bell bottoms, heroin, they're as hot as hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me three hundred worth of the madman. If it's as good as you say, I'll be back for a thousand.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just hope I still have it. Whaddya think of Trudi? She ain't got a boyfriend, wanna hand out an' get high?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which one's Trudi? The one with all the shit in her face?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent and Lance giggle at the "faux pas."</context>
      <utterance>No, that's Jody. That's my wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm on my way somewhere. I got a dinner engagement. Rain check?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent takes out his case of the works (utensils for shooting up).</context>
      <utterance>No problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't mind if I shoot up here?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me casa, su casa.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent takes his works out of his case and, as the two continue to talk, Vince shoots up.</context>
      <utterance>Mucho gracias.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still got your Malibu?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what some fucker did to it the other day?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuckin' keyed it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh man, that's fucked up.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me about it. I had the goddamn thing in storage three years. It's out five fuckin' days – five days, and some dickless piece of shit fucks with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he cooks his heroin...</context>
      <utterance>They should be fuckin' killed. No trial, no jury, straight to execution.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just wish I caught 'em doin' it, ya know? Oh man, I'd give anything to catch 'em doin' it. It'a been worth his doin' it, if I coulda just caught 'em, you know what I mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's chicken shit. You don't fuck another man's vehicle.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSEUP – THE NEEDLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Going into Vincent's vein.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CLOSEUP – NOTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>"Hi Vincent, I'm getting dressed. The door's open. Come inside and make yourself a drink. Mia"</context>
      <utterance>The Note reads:</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Vincent. I'm getting dressed. The door's open. Come inside and make yourself a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>FADE TO WHITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Music in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PREACHER MAN".</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mia's mouth comes toward a microphone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vincent.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vincent. I'm on the intercom.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent walks.</context>
      <utterance>To your right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent finds the intercom on the wall.</context>
      <utterance>...warm. Warmer. Disco.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Push the button if you want to talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The bar's by the fireplace.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(licks lips)</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck is this place?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Jackrabbit Slim's. An Elvis man should love it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Mia, let's go get a steak.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mia draws a square with her hands. Dotted lines appear on the screen, forming a sqaure. The lines disperse.</context>
      <utterance>You can get a steak here, daddy-o. Don't be a...</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After you, kitty-cat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="66">
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, I'm Buddy, what can I get'cha?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll have the Douglas Sirk steak.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How d'ya want it, burnt to a crisp, or bloody as hell?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bloody as hell. And to drink, a vanilla coke.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How 'bout you, Peggy Sue?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll have the Durwood Kirby burger – bloody – and a five-dollar shake.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How d'ya want that shake, Martin and Lewis, or Amos and Andy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Martin and Lewis.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you just order a five-dollar shake?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure did.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A shake? Milk and ice cream?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It costs five dollars?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't put bourbon in it or anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nope.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent takes a look around the place. The YUPPIES are dancing, the DINERS are biting into big, juicy hamburgers, and the icons are playing their parts. Marilyn is squealing, The Midget is paging Philip Morris, Donna Reed is making her customers drink their milk, and Dean and Jerry are acting a fool.</context>
      <utterance>Just checking. Buddy exits.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whaddya think?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent takes out his pouch of tobacco and begins rolling himself a smoke. After a second of watching him –</context>
      <utterance>It's like a wax museum with a pulse rate.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rollin' a smoke.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just tobacco.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he finishes licking it –</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Well in that case, will you roll me one, cowboy?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands her the rolled smoke. She takes it, putting it to her lips. Out of nowhere appears a Zippo lighter in Vincent's hand. He lights it.</context>
      <utterance>You can have this one, cowgirl.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He begins rolling one for himself. As this time, the SOUND of a subway car fills the diner, making everything SHAKE and RATTLE. Marilyn Monroe runs to a square vent in the floor. An imaginary subway train BLOWS the skirt of her white dress around her ears as she lets out a squeal. The entire restaurant applauds. Back to Mia and Vincent.</context>
      <utterance>Think nothing of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marsellus said you just got back from Amsterdam.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure did. I heard you did a pilot.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was my fifteen minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was show about a team of female secret agents called "Fox Force Five."</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Fox Force Five." Fox, as in we're a bunch of foxy chicks. Force, as in we're a force to be reckoned with. Five, as in there's one... two ... three... four... five of us. There was a blonde one, Sommerset O'Neal from that show "Baton Rouge," she was the leader. A Japanese one, a black one, a French one and a brunette one, me. We all had special skills. Sommerset had a photographic memory, the Japanese fox was a kung fu master, the black girl was a demolition expert, the French fox' specialty was sex...</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was your specialty?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Knives. The character I played, Raven McCoy, her background was she was raised by circus performers. So she grew up doing a knife act. According to the show, she was the deadliest woman in the world with a knife. But because she grew up in a circus, she was also something of an acrobat. She could do illusions, she was a trapeze artist – when you're keeping the world safe from evil, you never know when being a trapeze artist's gonna come in handy. And she knew a zillion old jokes her grandfather, an old vaudevillian, taught her. If we woulda got picked up, they woulda worked in a gimmick where every episode I woulda told and ol joke.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you remember any of the jokes?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I only got the chance to say one, 'cause we only did one show.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. It's really corny.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, don't be that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You won't like it and I'll be embarrassed.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You told it in front of fifty million people and you can't tell it to me? I promise I won't laugh.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I'm afraid of.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not what I meant and you know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're quite the silver tongue devil, aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I meant I wouldn't laugh at you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not what you said Vince. Well now I'm definitely not gonna tell ya, 'cause it's been built up too much.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buddy comes back with the drinks. Mia wraps her lips around the straw of her shake.</context>
      <utterance>What a gyp.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yummy!</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I have a sip of that? I'd like to know what a five-dollar shake tastes like.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slides the shake over to him.</context>
      <utterance>Be my guest.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent smiles.</context>
      <utterance>You can use my straw, I don't have kooties.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but maybe I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a sip.</context>
      <utterance>Kooties I can handle.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamn! That's a pretty fuckin' good milk shake.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Told ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then the first of an uncomfortable silence happens.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know if it's worth five dollars, but it's pretty fuckin' good. He slides the shake back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you hate that?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uncomfortable silences. Why do we feel it's necessary to yak about bullshit in order to be comfortable?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's when you know you found somebody special. When you can just shit the fuck up for a minute, and comfortably share silence.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think we're there yet. But don't feel bad, we just met each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I'll tell you what, I'll go to the bathroom and powder my nose, while you sit here and think of something to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll do that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="42">
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you love it when you go to the bathroom and you come back to find your food waiting for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're lucky we got it at all. Buddy Holly doesn't seem to be much of a waiter. We shoulda sat in Marilyn Monroe's section.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which one, there's two Marilyn Monroes.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pointing at Marilyn in the white dress serving a table.</context>
      <utterance>No there's not.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then, pointing at a BLONDE WAITRESS in a tight sweater and capri pants, taking an order from a bunch of FILM GEEKS –</context>
      <utterance>That's Marilyn Monroe...</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... and that's Mamie Van Doren. I don't see Jayne Mansfield, so it must be her night off.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretty smart.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have moments.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did ya think of something to say?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, there's something I've wanted to ask you about, but you seem like a nice person, and I didn't want to offend you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oooohhhh, this doesn't sound like mindless, boring, getting-to-know- you chit-chat. This sounds like you actually have something to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only if you promise not to get offended.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't promise something like that. I have no idea what you're gonna ask. You could ask me what you're gonna ask me, and my natural response could be to be offended. Then, through no fault of my own, I woulda broken my promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then let's just forget it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is an impossibility. Trying to forget anything as intriguing as this would be an exercise in futility.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mia nods her head: "Yes."</context>
      <utterance>Is that a fact?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Besides, it's more exciting when you don't have permission.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think about what happened to Antwan?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's Antwan?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tony Rocky Horror.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He fell out of a window.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's one way to say it. Another way is, he was thrown out. Another was is, he was thrown out by Marsellus. And even another way is, he was thrown out of a window by Marsellus because of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that a fact?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No it's not, it's just what I heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who told you this?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mia and Vincent smile.</context>
      <utterance>They.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They talk a lot, don't they?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They certainly do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent is slow to answer.</context>
      <utterance>Well don't by shy Vincent, what exactly did they say?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me help you Bashful, did it involve the F-word?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. They just said Rocky Horror gave you a foot massage.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And...?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No and, that's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You heard Marsellus threw Rocky Horror out of a four-story window because he massaged my feet?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you believed that?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At the time I was told, it seemed reasonable.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marsellus throwing Tony out of a four story window for giving me a foot massage seemed reasonable?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it seemed excessive. But that doesn't mean it didn't happen. I heard Marsellus is very protective of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A husband being protective of his wife is one thing. A husband almost killing another man for touching his wife's feet is something else.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But did it happen?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The only thing Antwan ever touched of mine was my hand, when he shook it. I met Anwan once – at my wedding – then never again. The truth is, nobody knows why Marsellus tossed Tony Rocky Horror out of that window except Marsellus and Tony Rocky Horror. But when you scamps get together, you're worse than a sewing circle.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>ED SULLIVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed Sullivan is with Marilyn Monroe, who holds a trophy.</context>
      <utterance>Ladies and gentlemen, now the moment you've all been waiting for, the worldfamous Jackrabbit Slim's twist contest. Patrons cheer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED SULLIVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marilyn holds the trophy.</context>
      <utterance>...One lucky couple will win this handsome trophy that Marilyn here is holding.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED SULLIVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mia holds her hand.</context>
      <utterance>...Now, who will be our first contestants?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent reacts.</context>
      <utterance>Right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanna dance.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, no no, no, no, no, no.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, no, no, no, no, no. I do believe Marsellus, my husband, your boss, told you to take me out and do whatever I wanted, Now, I want to dance. I want to win. I want that trophy.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, dance good.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent and Mia walk onto the dance floor, toward Ed Sullivan.</context>
      <utterance>All right, you asked for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED SULLIVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent and Mia walk up to the microphone.</context>
      <utterance>Let's hear it for our first contestants. Patrons cheer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED SULLIVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now let's meet our first contestants here this evening. Young lady, what is your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Missus Mia Wallace.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED SULLIVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And, uh, how 'bout your fella here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vincent Vega.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED SULLIVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mia and Vincent dance to Chuck Berry's "YOU NEVER CAN TELL". They make hand movements as they dance.</context>
      <utterance>All right, let's see what you can do. Take it away!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was than an uncomfortable silence?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mia moves away to attend to both. Vincent hangs up his overcoat on a big bronze coat rack in the alcove.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know what that was.  Music and drinks!</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna take a piss.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mia moves to her CD player, thumbs through a stack of CDs and selects one: k.d. lang. The speakers BLAST OUT a high energy country number, which Mia plays air-guitar to. She dances her way around the room and finds herself by Vincent's overcoat hanging on the rack. She touches its sleeve. It feels good. Her hand hoes in its pocket and pulls out his tobacco pouch. Like a little girl playing cowboy, she spreads the tobacco on some rolling paper. Imitating what he did earlier, licks the paper and rolls it into a pretty good cigarette. Maybe a little too fat, but not bad for a first try. Mia thinks so anyway. Her hand reaches back in the pocket and pulls out his Zippo lighter. She SLAPS the lighter against her leg, trying to light it fancy-style like Vince did. What do you know, she did it! Mia's one happy clam. She triumphantly brings the fat flame up to her fat smoke, lighting it up, then LOUDLY SNAPS the Zippo closed. The Mia-made cigarette is brought up to her lips, and she takes a long, cool drag. Her hand slides the Zippo back in the overcoat pocket. But wait, her fingers touch something else. Those fingers bring out a plastic bag with white powder inside, the madman that Vincent bought earlier from Lance. Wearing a big smile, Mia brings the bag of heroin up to her face.</context>
      <utterance>That was a little bit more information than I needed to know, but go right ahead. Vincent shuffles off to the john.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Disco! Vince, you little cola nut, you've been holding out on me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BATHROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vince continues.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now that he's given himself a little pep talk, Vincent's ready for whatever's waiting for him on the other side of that door. So he goes through it.</context>
      <utterance>So you're gonna go out there, drink your drink, say "Goodnight, I've had a very lovely evening," go home, and jack off. And that's all you're gonna do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent moves like greased lightning to Mia's fallen body. Bending down where she lays, he puts his fingers on her neck to check her pulse. She slightly stirs. Mia is aware of Vincent over her, speaking to her.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ!</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches her and hoists the dead weight up in his arms.</context>
      <utterance>Okay honey, we're getting you on your feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We follow behind as he hurriedly walks the practically- unconscious Mia through the house and out the front door.</context>
      <utterance>We're on our feet now, and now we're gonna talk out to the car. Here we go, watch us walk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JODY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lance! The phone's ringing!</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can hear it!</utterance>
   <speaker>JODY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you told those fuckin' assholes never to call this late!</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told 'em and that's what I'm gonna tell this fuckin' asshole right now!  Hello, do you know how late it is? You're not supposed to be callin' me this fuckin' late.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lance, this is Vincent, I'm in big fuckin' trouble man, I'm on my way to your place.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa, hold you horses man, what's the problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You still got an adrenaline shot?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need it man, I got a chick she's fuckin' Doing on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't bring her here! I'm not even fuckin' joking with you, don't you be bringing some fucked up pooh-butt to my house!</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's ODin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. She's dyin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then bite the fuckin' bullet, take 'er to a hospital and call a lawyer!</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Negative.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She ain't my fuckin' problem, you fucked her up, you deal with it – are you talkin' to me on a cellular phone?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know you, who is this, don't come here, I'm hangin' up.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment inside Lance's house, WE HEAR VINCENT's Malibu coming up the street. Lance hangs up the phone, goes to his curtains and YANKS the cord. The curtains open with a WHOOSH in time to see Vincent's Malibu DRIVING UP on his front lawn and CRASHING into his house. The window Lance is looking out of SHATTERS from the impact.</context>
      <utterance>Too late, I'm already here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JODY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Lance CHARGES from the window, out the door to his front lawn.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell was that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you lost your mind?! You crashed your car in my fuckin' house! You talk about drug shit on a cellular fuckin' phone –</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're through havin' your little hissy fit, this chick is dyin', get your needle and git it now!</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you deaf? You're not bringin' that fucked up bitch in my house!</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This fucked up bitch is Marsellus Wallace's wife. Now if she fuckin' croaks on me, I'm a grease spot. But before he turns me into a bar soap, I'm gonna be forced to tell 'im about how you coulda saved her life, but instead you let her die on your front lawn.</utterance>
   <speaker>JODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she walks in the living room, she sees Vincent and Lance standing over Mia, who's lying on the floor in the middle of the room. From here on in, everything in this scene is frantic, like a DOCUMENTARY in an emergency ward, with the big difference here being nobody knows what the fuck they're doing.</context>
      <utterance>It's only one-thirty in the goddamn mornin'! What the fuck's goin' on out here?</utterance>
   <speaker>JODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lance looks up at Jody.</context>
      <utterance>Who's she?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get that black box in the bedroom I have with the adrenaline shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>JODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with her?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's ODing on us.</utterance>
   <speaker>JODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well get her the hell outta here!</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE AND VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get the fuckin' shot!</utterance>
   <speaker>JODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She angrily turns and disappears into the bedroom looking for the shot. WE MOVE into the room with the two men.</context>
      <utterance>Don't yell and me!</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You two are a match made in heaven.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, just keep talkin' to her, okay? While she's gettin' the shot, I gotta get a medical book.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you need a medical book for?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To tell me how to do it. I've never given an adrenaline shot before.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've had that thing for six years and you never used it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never had to use it. I don't go joypoppin' with bubble-gummers, all of my friends can handle their highs!</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well then get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am, if you'll let me.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not fuckin' stoppin' you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WE FOLLOW Lance as he runs out of the living room into a...</context>
      <utterance>Stop talkin' to me, and start talkin' to her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hurry up man! We're losin' her!</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WE HEAR Jody in the living room now as she talks to Vincent.</context>
      <utterance>I'm looking as fast as I can! Lance continues his frenzied search.</utterance>
   <speaker>JODY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he lookin' for?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Jody calls to LANCE.</context>
      <utterance>I dunno, some medical book.</utterance>
   <speaker>JODY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you lookin' for?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he continues searching, flipping and knocking over shit, Jody appears in the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>My black medical book!</utterance>
   <speaker>JODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whata're you looking for?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My black fuckin' medical book. It's like a text book they give to nurses.</utterance>
   <speaker>JODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never saw a medical book.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trust me, I have one.</utterance>
   <speaker>JODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lance spins toward her.</context>
      <utterance>Well if it's that important, why didn't you keep it with the shot?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know! Stop bothering me!</utterance>
   <speaker>JODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>While you're lookin' for it, that girl's gonna die on our carpet. You're never gonna find it in all this shit. For six months now, I've been telling you to clean this room –</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Lance angrily knocks over a pile of shit and leaves the SHOT heading for the living room.</context>
      <utterance>– get your ass in here, fuck the book!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lance bends down by the black case brought in by Jody. He opens it and begins preparing the needle for injection.</context>
      <utterance>Quit fuckin' around man and give her the shot!</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jody stumbles back in the room, hanging back from the action.</context>
      <utterance>While I'm doing this, take her shirt off and find her heart. Vince rips her blouse open.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does it have to be exact?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it has to be exact! I'm giving her an injection in the heart, so I gotta exactly hit her in the heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vince points to Mia's right breast. Lance glances over and nods.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't know exactly where her heart is, I think it's here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Lance readies the injection, Vincent looks up at Jody.</context>
      <utterance>That's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need a big fat magic marker, got one?</utterance>
   <speaker>JODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need a big fat magic marker, any felt pen'll do, but a magic marker would be great.</utterance>
   <speaker>JODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jody runs to the desk, opens the top drawer and, in her enthusiasm, she pulls the drawer out of the desk, the contents of which (bills, papers, pens) spill to the floor. The injection is ready. Lance hands Vincent the needle.</context>
      <utterance>Hold on.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's ready, I'll tell you what to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gonna give her the shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you're gonna give her the shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never does this before.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jody hurriedly joins them in the huddle, a big fat red magic marker in her hand.</context>
      <utterance>I've never done this before either, and I ain't starting now. You brought 'er here, that means you give her the shot. The day I bring an ODing bitch to your place, then I gotta give her the shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>JODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent grabs the magic marker out of Jody's hand and makes a big red dot on Mia's body where her heart is.</context>
      <utterance>Got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, what do I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lance demonstrates a stabbing motion, which looks like "The Shape" killing its victims in "HALLOWEEN".</context>
      <utterance>Well, you're giving her an injection of adrenaline straight to her heart. But she's got a breast plate in front of her heart, so you gotta pierce through that. So what you gotta do is bring the needle down in a stabbing motion.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta stab her?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then once you do, push down on the plunger.</context>
      <utterance>If you want the needle to pierce through to her heart, you gotta stab her hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happens after that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm curious about that myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This ain't a fuckin' joke man!</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent lifts the needle up above his head in a stabbing motion. He looks down on Mia. Mia is fading fast. Soon nothing will help her. Vincent's eyes narrow, ready to do this.</context>
      <utterance>She's supposed to come out of it like –  – that.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lance, on this knees right beside Vincent, does not know what to expect.</context>
      <utterance>Count to three.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Needle raised ready to strike.</context>
      <utterance>One... RED DOT on Mia's body.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Jody's face is alive with anticipation. NEEDLE in that air, poised like a rattler ready to strike.</context>
      <utterance>...two...</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The needle leaves frame, THRUSTING down hard. Vincent brings the needle down hard, STABBING Mia in the chest. Mia's head is JOLTED from the impact. The syringe plunger is pushed down, PUMPING the adrenaline out through the needle. Mia's eyes POP WIDE OPEN and she lets out a HELLISH cry of the banshee. She BOLTS UP in a sitting position, needle stuck in her chest – SCREAMING. Vincent, Lance and Jody, who were in sitting positions in front of Mia, JUMP BACK, scared to death. Mia's scream runs out. She slowly starts taking breaths of air. The other three, now scooted halfway across the room, shaken to their bones, look to see if she's alright.</context>
      <utterance>...three!</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mia, still breathing, not looking up at them, says in a relatively normal voice.</context>
      <utterance>If you're okay, say something.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent and Lance collapse on their backs, exhausted and shaking from how close to death Mia came.</context>
      <utterance>Something.</utterance>
   <speaker>JODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anybody want a beer?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Vincent's out of the car, standing on the walkway, a big distance between the two.</context>
      <utterance>Mia! She turns around.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are your thoughts on how to handle this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mia smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Well I'm of the opinion that Marsellus can live his whole live and never ever hear of this incident.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about it. If Marsellus ever heard of this, I'd be in as much trouble as you.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I seriously doubt that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you can keep a secret, so can I.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two walk toward each other, holding out their hands to shake and shake they do.</context>
      <utterance>Let's shake on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mia lets go of Vincent's hand and silently makes the see-no- evil, hear-no-evil, and speak-no-evil sign with her hands. Vincent smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Mum's the word.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent turns to leave.</context>
      <utterance>If you'll excuse me, I gotta go home and have a heart attack. Mia giggles.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent turns around.</context>
      <utterance>You still wanna hear my "FOX FORCE FIVE" joke?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, but I think I'm still a little too petrified to laugh.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh. You won't laugh because it's not funny. But if you still wanna hear it, I'll tell it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both smile, but neither laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Three tomatoes are walking down the street, a poppa tomato, a momma tomato, and a little baby tomato. The baby tomato is lagging behind the poppa and momma tomato. The poppa tomato gets mad, goes over to the momma tomato and stamps on him –  – and says: catch up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mia turns and walks inside her house.</context>
      <utterance>See ya 'round, Vince.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Butch, stop watching TV a second. We got a special visitor. Now do you remember when I told you your daddy dies in a P.O.W. camp?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAPT. KOONS steps inside the room toward the little boy and bends down on one knee to bring him even with the boy's eyeline. When Koons speaks, he speaks with a slight Texas accent.</context>
      <utterance>Well this here is Capt. Koons. He was in the P.O.W. camp with Daddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPT. KOONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Captain pulls a gold wrist watch out of his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, little man. Boy I sure heard a bunch about you. See, I was a good friend of your Daddy's. We were in that Hanoi pit of hell over five years together. Hopefully, you'll never have to experience this yourself, but when two men are in a situation like me and your Daddy were, for as long as we were, you take on certain responsibilities of the other. If it had been me who had not made it, Major Coolidge would be talkin' right now to my son Jim. But the way it worked out is I'm talkin' to you, Butch. I got somethin' for ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPT. KOONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Capt. Koons hands the watch to Butch. A little hand comes into FRAME to accept it.</context>
      <utterance>This watch I got here was first purchased by your great-granddaddy. It was bought during the First World War in a little general store in Knoxville, Tennessee. It was bought by private Doughboy Ernie Coolidge the day he set sail for Paris. It was your great-granddaddy's war watch, made by the first company to ever make wrist watches. You see, up until then, people just carried pocket watches. Your great-granddaddy wore that watch every day he was in the war. Then when he had done his duty, he went home to your great- grandmother, took the watch off his wrist and put it in an ol' coffee can. And in that can it stayed 'til your grandfather Dane Coolidge was called upon by his country to go overseas and fight the Germans once again. This time they called it World War Two. Your great-granddaddy gave it to your granddad for good luck. Unfortunately, Dane's luck wasn't as good as his old man's. Your granddad was a Marine and he was killed with all the other Marines at the battle of Wake Island. Your granddad was facing death and he knew it. None of those boys had any illusions about ever leavin' that island alive. So three days before the Japanese took the island, your 22-year old grandfather asked a gunner on an Air Force transport named Winocki, a man he had never met before in his life, to deliver to his infant son, who he had never seen in the flesh, his gold watch. Three days later, your grandfather was dead. But Winocki kept his word. After the war was over, he paid a visit to your grandmother, delivering to your infant father, his Dad's gold watch. This watch. This watch was on your Daddy's wrist when he was shot down over Hanoi. He was captured and put in a Vietnamese prison camp. Now he knew if the gooks ever saw the watch it'd be confiscated. The way your Daddy looked at it, that watch was your birthright. And he'd be damned if and slopeheads were gonna put their greasy yella hands on his boy's birthright. So he hid it in the one place he knew he could hide somethin'. His ass. Five long years, he wore this watch up his ass. Then when he died of dysentery, he gave me the watch. I hid with uncomfortable hunk of metal up my ass for two years. Then, after seven years, I was sent home to my family. And now, little man, I give the watch to you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KLONDIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's time, Butch.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Klondike steps inside, closing the door on the WILD MOB outside. He goes to the long yellow robe hanging on a hook. Butch hops off the table and, without a word, Klondike helps him on with the robe, which says on the back: "BATTLING BUTCH</context>
      <utterance>I'm ready.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>"THE GOLD WATCH"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We hear over the black and white title:</utterance>
   <speaker>SPORTSCASTER #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The SOUND of chaos in the b.g.</context>
      <utterance>– Well Dan, that had to be the bloodiest and, hands-down, the most brutal fight this city has ever seen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SPORTSCASTER #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Coolidge was out of there faster than I've ever seen a victorious boxer vacate the ring. Do you think he knew Willis was dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPORTSCASTER #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My guess would be yes, Richard. I could see from my position here, the frenzy in his eyes give way to the realization of what he was doing. I think any man would've left the ring that fast.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SPORTSCASTER #1</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you feel this ring death tragedy will have an effect on the world of boxing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPORTSCASTER #2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She takes a sip of coffee, then hears a NOISE behind her in the alley. She sticks her head out of the car door to see:</context>
      <utterance>Oh Dan, a tragedy like this can't help but shake the world of boxing to its very foundation. But it's of paramount importance that during the sad weeks ahead, the eyes of the W.B.A. remain firmly fixed on the – CLICK – Esmarelda shuts off the radio.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ESMARELDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you the man I was supposed to pick up?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're the cab I called, I'm the guy you're supposed to pick up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESMARELDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where to?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ignition key is TWISTED. The engine ROARS to life. The meter is FLIPPED on. Esmarelda's bare foot STOMPS on the gas pedal.</context>
      <utterance>Outta here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="38">
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mia. How you doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the room, black boxer FLOYD RAY WILLIS lies on a table – dead. His face looks like he went dunking for bees. His TRAINER is on his knees, head on Floyd's chest, crying over the body. The huge figure that is Marsellus Wallace stands at the table, hand on the Trainer's shoulder, lending emotional support. We still do not see Marsellus clearly, only that he is big. Mia sits in a chair at the far end of the room. Marsellus looks up, sees English Dave and walks over to him.</context>
      <utterance>Great. I never thanked you for the dinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSELLUS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'cha got?</utterance>
   <speaker>ENGLISH DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He booked.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSELLUS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm prepared to scour the earth for this motherfucker. If Butch goes to Indo China, I want a nigger hidin' in a bowl of rice, ready to pop a cap in his ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>ENGLISH DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take care of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, how do I open the window back here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESMARELDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She presses a button and the back window moves down. Butch tosses his boxing glove out the window, then starts untying the other one. Esmeralda can't keep quiet anymore.</context>
      <utterance>I have to do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESMARELDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, mister?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESMARELDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he tosses his other glove out the window.</context>
      <utterance>You were in that fight? The fight on the radio – you're the fighter?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever gave you that idea?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESMARELDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No c'mon, you're him, I know you're him, tell me you're him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESMARELDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You killed the other boxing man.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESMARELDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He finished wiping himself down.</context>
      <utterance>The radio said he was dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence, as Butch digs in his bag for a t-shirt.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry 'bout that, Floyd. He tosses the towel out the window.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESMARELDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does it feel like?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does what feel like?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESMARELDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch pulls on his tee-shirt.</context>
      <utterance>Killing a man. Beating another man to death with your bare hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you some kinda weirdo?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESMARELDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's a subject I have much interest in. You are the first person I ever met who has killed somebody. So, what was it like to kill a man?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Esmarelda bounces in her seat with excitement.</context>
      <utterance>Tell ya what, you give me one of them cigarettes, I'll give you an answer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESMARELDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch leans forward. Esmarelda, keeping her eyes on the road, passes a cigarette back to him. He takes it. Then, still not looking behind her, she brings up her hand, a lit match in it. Butch lights his smoke, then blows out the match. He takes a long drag.</context>
      <utterance>Deal!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her license.</context>
      <utterance>So...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Esmarelda Villalobos – is that Mexican?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESMARELDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The name is Spanish, but I'm Columbian.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a very pretty name.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESMARELDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It mean "Esmarelda of the wolves."</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's one hell of a name you got there, sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESMARELDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. And what is your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Butch.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESMARELDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Butch. What does it mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm an American, our names don't mean shit. Anyway, moving right along, what is it you wanna know, Esmarelda?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESMARELDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to know what it feels like to kill a man –</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Esmarelda nods her head: "yes."</context>
      <utterance>– I couldn't tell ya. I didn't know he was dead 'til you told me he was dead. Now I know he's dead, do you wanna know how I feel about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't feel the least little bit bad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd I tell ya, soon as the word got out a fix was in, the odds would be outta control. Hey, if he was a better fighter he's be alive. If he never laced up his gloves in the first place, which he never shoulda done, he'd be alive. Enough about the poor unfortunate Mr. Floyd, let's talk about the rich and prosperous Mr. Butch. How many bookies you spread it around with?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode>PAUSE</mode>
      <context>Butch hangs up the phone. He looks at the cab waiting to take him wherever he wants to go.</context>
      <utterance>Eight? How long to collect?  So by tomorrow evening, you'll have it all?  Good news Scotty, real good news – I understand a few stragglers aside. Me an' Fabienne're gonna leave in the morning. It should take us a couple days to get into Knoxville. Next time we see each other, it'll be on Tennessee time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fabienne my love, our adventure begins.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="60">
   <speaker>ESMARELDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Handing her the money.</context>
      <utterance>Forty-five sixty.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Esmarelda's eyes light up. She goes to take it. Butch holds it out of reach.</context>
      <utterance>Merci beaucoup. And here's a little something for the effort. Butch holds up a hundred dollar bill.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now if anybody should ask you about who your fare was tonight, what're you gonna tell 'em?</utterance>
   <speaker>ESMARELDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives her the bill.</context>
      <utterance>The truth. Three well-dressed, slightly toasted, Mexicans.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bon soir, Esmarelda.</utterance>
   <speaker>ESMARELDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tweaks her nose, she smiles, and he turns and walks away. She drives off.</context>
      <utterance>Sleep well, Butch.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch flicks the switch back, making the room dark again.</context>
      <utterance>Keep the light off.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that better, sugar pop?</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oui. Hard day at the office?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretty hard. I got into a fight.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch climbs into bed, spooning Fabienne from behind. When Butch and Fabienne speak to each other, they speak in babytalk.</context>
      <utterance>Poor baby. Can we make spoons?</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was looking at myself in the mirror.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish I had a pot.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were lookin' in the mirror and you wish you had some pot?</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A pot. A pot belly. Pot bellies are sexy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well you should be happy, 'cause you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up, Fatso! I don't have a pot! I have a bit of a tummy, like Madonna when she did "Lucky Star," it's not the same thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't realize there was a difference between a tummy and a pot belly.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The difference is huge.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want me to have a pot?</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Pot bellies make a man look either oafish, or like a gorilla. But on a woman, a pot belly is very sexy. The rest of you is normal. Normal face, normal legs, normal hips, normal ass, but with a big, perfectly round pot belly. If I had one, I'd wear a tee-shirt two sizes too small to accentuate it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think guys would find that attractive?</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't give a damn what men find attractive. It's unfortunate what we find pleasing to the touch and pleasing to the eye is seldom the same.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you a pot belly, I'd punch you in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd punch me in my belly?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right in the belly.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd smother you. I'd drop it on your right on your face 'til you couldn't breathe.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd do that to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you get everything, sugar pop?</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good job.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did everything go as planned?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't listen to the radio?</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never listen to your fights. Were you the winner?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won alright.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you still retiring?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure am.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the man you fought?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Floyd retired too.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?! He won't be fighting no more?!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not no more.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So it all worked out in the finish?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fabienne rolls over and Butch gets on top of her. They kiss.</context>
      <utterance>We ain't at the finish, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch nods his head: "yes."</context>
      <utterance>We're in a lot of danger, aren't we?</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch nods his head: "yes."</context>
      <utterance>If they find us, they'll kill us, won't they?</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch nods his head: "no."</context>
      <utterance>But they won't find us, will they?</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch nods his head: "yes."</context>
      <utterance>Do you still want me to go with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch's hand goes out of frame and starts massaging her crotch. Fabienne reacts.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to be a burden or a nuisance -</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say it!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fabienne, I want you to be with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forever?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch continues to massage her crotch.</context>
      <utterance>...and ever. Fabienne lies her head back.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you love me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oui.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch kisses her on the mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Butch? Will you give me oral pleasure?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods her head: "yes."</context>
      <utterance>Will you kiss it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch's head goes down out of frame to carry out the oral pleasure. Fabienne's face is alone in the frame.</context>
      <utterance>But you first.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Butch my love, the adventure begins.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I cracked a rib.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Giving me oral pleasure?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No retard, from the fight.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't call me retard.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name is Fabby! My name is Fabby!</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up fuck head! I hate that Mongoloid voice.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, sorry, sorry, sorry, I take it back! Can I have a towel please, Miss Beautiful Tulip.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She finishes drying her hair and wraps the towel like a turban on her head.</context>
      <utterance>Oh I like that, I like being called a tulip. Tulip is much better than Mongoloid.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands him a towel.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't call you a Mongoloid, I called you a retard, but I took it back.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Merci beaucoup.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Butch?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, lemon pie.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are we going to go?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure yet. Wherever you want. We're gonna get a lot of money from this. But it ain't gonna be so much, we can live like hogs in the fat house forever. I was thinking we could go somewhere in the South Pacific. The kinda money we'll have'll carry us a long way down there.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So if we wanted, we could live in Bora Bora?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You betcha. And if after awhile you don't dig Bora Bora, then we can move over to Tahiti or Mexico.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I do not speak Spanish.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't speak Bora Boran either. Besides, Mexican is easy: Donde esta el zapataria?</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's the shoe store?</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Donde esta el zapataria?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch exits the bathroom. We stay on Fabienne as she brushes her teeth. Butch keeps on from the other room.</context>
      <utterance>Excellent pronunciation. You'll be my little mama ceta in no time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Que hora es?</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Que hora es?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What time is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What time is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Fabienne brushes her teeth. We watch her for a moment or two, then she remember something.</context>
      <utterance>Time for bed. Sweet dream, jellybean.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks out of the bathroom to ask Butch a question, only to find him sound asleep in bed. She looks at him for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Butch.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She exits frame, going back in the bathroom. WE STAY on the WIDE SHOT of the unconscious Butch in bed.</context>
      <utterance>Forget it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="38">
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch squints down the front of the bed at her, trying to focus. Butch, still trying to chase the cobwebs away, sees on TV Hell's Angels tear-assin' through a Vietnamese prison camp.</context>
      <utterance>Merde! You startled me. Did you have a bad dream?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you watching?</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A motorcycle movie, I'm not sure the name.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fabienne enters the room.</context>
      <utterance>Are you watchin' it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In a way. Why? Would you like for me to switch it off?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches over and turns off the TV.</context>
      <utterance>Would you please?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a little too early in the morning for explosions and war.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was it about?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fabienne laughs.</context>
      <utterance>How should I know, you were the one watchin' it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, imbecile, what was your dream about?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I... don't remember. It's really rare I remember a dream.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just woke up from it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fabienne, I'm not lying to you, I don't remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, let's look at the grumpy man in the morning. I didn't say you were lying, it's just odd you don't remember your dreams. I always remember mine. Did you know you talk in your sleep?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't talk in my sleep, do I talk in my sleep?</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laying on top of him.</context>
      <utterance>What did I say?</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses Butch.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I couldn't understand you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you get up and we'll get some breakfast at that breakfast place with the pancakes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fabienne gives Butch a sweet long kiss.</context>
      <utterance>One more kiss and I'll get up.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Satisfied?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch climbs out of bed and starts pulling clothes out of the suitcase that Fabienne brought.</context>
      <utterance>Then get up, lazy bones.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What time is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Almost nine in the morning. What time does our train arrive?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eleven.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna order a big plate of blueberry pancakes with maple syrup, eggs over easy, and five sausages.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch is finished dressing.</context>
      <utterance>Anything to drink with that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he goes through the suitcase.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yes, that looks nice. To drink, a tall glass or orange juice and a black cup of coffee. After that, I'm going to have a slice of pie.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pie for breakfast?</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any time of the day is a good time for pie. Blueberry pie to go with the pancakes. And on top, a thin slice of melted cheese –</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>– where's my watch?</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's not. It's not here.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>By now, Butch is frantically rummaging through the suitcase.</context>
      <utterance>Have you looked?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's now throwing clothes.</context>
      <utterance>Yes I've fuckin' looked!!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fabienne can hardly speak, she's never seen Butch this way.</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck do you think I'm doing?! Are you sure you got it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uhhh... yes... beside the table drawer</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="30">
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>– on the little kangaroo.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, it was on your little kangaroo.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well it's not here!</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well it should be!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch lowers his voice, which only serves to make him more menacing.</context>
      <utterance>Oh it most definitely should be here, but it's not. So where is it? Fabienne is crying and scared.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fabienne, that was my father's fuckin' watch. You know what my father went through to git me that watch?... I don't wanna get into it right now... but he went through a lot. Now all this other shit, you coulda set on fire, but I specifically reminded you not to forget my father's watch. Now think, did you get it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I believe so...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You believe so? You either did, or you didn't, now which one is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch freaks out, he punches the air. Fabienne SCREAMS and backs into a corner, Butch picks up the motel TV and THROWS IT AGAINST the wall. Fabienne SCREAMS IN HORROR. Butch looks toward her, suddenly calm.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bends down in front of the woman who has sunk to the floor. He touches her hand, she flinches.</context>
      <utterance>No! It's not your fault.  You left it at the apartment.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch goes to the closet.</context>
      <utterance>If you did leave it at the apartment, it's not your fault. I had you bring a bunch of stuff. I reminded you about it, but I didn't illustrate how personal the watch was to me. If all I gave a fuck about was my watch, I should've told you. You ain't a mind reader. He kisses her hand. Then rises. Fabienne is still sniffling.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch puts on his high school jacket.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be. It just means I won't be able to eat breakfast with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why does it mean that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I'm going back to my apartment to get my watch.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Won't the gangsters be looking for you there?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rising from the floor.</context>
      <utterance>That's what I'm gonna find out. If they are, and I don't think I can handle it, I'll split.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch brings her close and puts his hands on her face.</context>
      <utterance>I was so dreadful. I saw your watch, I thought I brought it. I'm so sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't feel bad, sugar pop. Nothing you could ever do would make me permanently angry at you.  I love you, remember?  Now here's some money, order those pancakes and have a great breakfast.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't go.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be back before you can say, blueberry pie.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blueberry pie.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well maybe not that fast, but fast. Okay? Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her once more and heads for the door.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bye-bye, sugar pop.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna take your Honda.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that, he's out the door. Fabienne sits on the bed and looks at the money he gave her.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PEDESTRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch look at him, spaced-out.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus, are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marsellus Wallace lies sprawled out in the street. GAWKERS gather around the body.</context>
      <utterance>I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAWKER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This jerk's yelling makes Marsellus come to. TWO PEDESTRIANS help the shaken Butch out of the wreckage. The woozy Marsellus gets to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>He's dead! He's dead!</utterance>
   <speaker>GAWKER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you need a witness in court, I'll be glad to help. He was a drunken maniac. He hit you and crashed into that car.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSELLUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>GAWKER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marsellus follows the Gawker's finger and sees Butch Coolidge down the street, looking a shambles.</context>
      <utterance>Him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSELLUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The big man takes out a .45 Automatic and the Gawkers back away. Marsellus starts moving toward Butch. Butch sees the fierce figure making a wobbly bee-line toward him.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I'll be damned.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marsellus brings up his weapon and FIRES, but he's so hurt, shaky and dazed that his arm goes wild. He HITS a LOOKY-LOO WOMAN in the hip. She falls to the ground, screaming.</context>
      <utterance>Sacre bleu.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOOKY-LOO WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's all Butch needs to see. He's outta here. Marsellus RUNS after him. The CROWD looks agape. Butch is in a mad, limping RUN. The big man's hot on his ass with a cockeyed wobbly run. Butch cuts across traffic and dashes into a business with a sign that reads "MASON-DIXIE PAWNSHOP".</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God, I've been shot!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I help you wit' somethin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch quickly takes measure of the situation, than stands next to the door.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you just wait one goddamn minute</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He BREAKS the finger. Marsellus lets out a pain sound. Butch then places the barrel of the .45 between his eyes, PULLS back the hammer and places his open hand behind the gun to shield the splatter.</context>
      <utterance>So you like chasing people, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well guess what, big man, you caught me –</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Butch and Marsellus look up at Maynard, who's brandishing a pumpaction shotgun, aimed at the two men.</context>
      <utterance>– hold it right there, godammit!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look mister, this ain't any of your business –</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch does.</context>
      <utterance>– I'm makin' it my business! Now toss that gun!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch slowly gets up and moves to the counter. As soon as he gets there, Maynard HAULS OFF, HITTING him hard in the face with the butt of the shotgun, knocking Butch down and out. After Butch goes down, Maynard calmly lays the shotgun on the counter and moves to the telephone. Marsellus Wallace, from his position on the floor, groggily watches the pawnshop owner dial a number. Maynard waits on the line while the other end rings. Then it picks up.</context>
      <utterance>Now you on top, stand up and come to the counter.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marsellus passes out.</context>
      <utterance>Zed? It's Maynard. The spider just caught a coupl'a flies.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A BUZZER buzzes.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody kills anybody in my place of business except me or Zed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without saying another word, Maynard climbs up the stairs that lead to red curtains and goes through them. WE HEAR, on the other side of the curtains, Maynard let Zed inside the store. Butch and Marsellus look around the room. The basement of the pawnshop has been converted into a dungeon. After taking in their predicament, Butch and Marsellus look at each other, all traces of hostility gone, replaced by a terror they both share at what they've gotten themselves into. Maynard and ZED come through the curtains. Zed is an even more intense version of Maynard, if such a thing is possible. The two hillbillys are obviously brothers. Where Maynard is a vicious pitbull, Zed is a deadly cobra. Zed walks in and stands in front of the two captives. He inspects them for a long time, then says:</context>
      <utterance>That's Zed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said you waited for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then how come they're all beat up?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They did that to each other. They was fightin' when they came in. This one was gonna shoot that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch makes no reply.</context>
      <utterance>You were gonna shoot him?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, is Grace gonna be okay in front of this place?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it ain't Tuesday is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's Thursday.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then she'll be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bring out The Gimp.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think The Gimp's sleepin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maynard opens a trap door in the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I guess you'll just wake 'em up then, won't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maynard reaches into the hole and comes back holding onto a leash. He gives it a rough yank and, from below the floor, rises</context>
      <utterance>Wake up!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maynard hangs back while Zed appraises the two men.</context>
      <utterance>Down! The Gimp gets on its knees.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's first?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then with his little finger, Zed does a silent "Eenie, meany, miney, moe... " just his mouth mouthing the words and his finger going back and forth between the two. Butch are Marsellus are terrified. Maynard looks back and forth at the victims. The Gimps's eyes go from one to the other inside the mask. Zed continues his silent sing-song with his finger moving left to right, then it stops.</context>
      <utterance>I ain't fer sure yet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wanna do it here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zed grabs Marsellus' chair and DRAGS him into Russell's old room. Russell, no doubt, was some other poor bastard that has the misfortune of stumbling into the Mason-Dixie pawnshop. Whatever happened to Russell is known only to Maynard and Zed because his old room, a back room in the back of the back room, is empty. As Marsellus is dragged away, he locks eyes with Butch before he disappears behind the door of Russell's old room.</context>
      <utterance>Naw, drag big boy to Russell's old room.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Gimp rises. Maynard ties The Gimp's leash to a hook on the ceiling.</context>
      <utterance>Up!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Gimp bows its head: "yes." Maynard disappears into Russell's old room. There must be a stereo in there because suddenly The Judds, singing in harmony, fills the air. Butch looks at The Gimp. The Gimp giggles from underneath the mask as if this were the funniest moment in the history of comedy. From behind the door we hear country MUSIC, struggling, and:</context>
      <utterance>Keep an eye on this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>We the HEAR Maynard and Zed beat on Marsellus.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa, this boy's got a bit of fight in 'em!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZED</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Butch pauses, listens to the voices. Then, in a panic, hurriedly struggles to get free. The Gimp is laughing wildly. The ropes are on too tight and Butch can't break free. The Gimp slaps his knee laughing In the back room, we hear:</context>
      <utterance>You wanna fight? You wanna fight? Good, I like to fight!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYNARD</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Butch stops struggling and lifts up on his arms. Then, quite easily, the padded chair back slides up and off as if it were never connected by a bolt. The Gimp sees this and its eyes widen.</context>
      <utterance>That's it... that's it boy, you're goin' fine. Oooooooh, just like that... that's good.  Stay still... stay still goddamn ya! Zed goddammit, git over here and hold 'em!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE GIMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Gimp FLAILS WILDLY, trying to get the leash off the hook. He tries to yell, but all that comes out are excited gurgles and grunts. Butch is out of his chair, quickly dispensing three BOXER'S PUNCHES to its face. The punches knock The Gimp out, making him fall to his knees, this HANGING HIMSELF by the leash attached to the hook, Butch removes the ball gag, then silently makes his way through the red curtains.</context>
      <utterance>Huhng?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maynard turns and sees Butch holding the sword. Butch SCREAMS... with one mighty SWING, SLASHES Maynard across the front, moving past him, eyes and blade now locked on Zed. Maynard stands trembling, his front sliced open, in shock. Butch, while never taking his eyes off Zed, THRUSTS the sword behind him, SKEWERING Maynard, then EXTRACTS it, pointing the blade toward Zed. Maynard COLLAPSES. Zed disengages from Marsellus in a hurry and his eyes go from the tip of Butch's sword to Marsellus' .45 Automatic, which lies within reach. Butch's eyes follow Zed's.</context>
      <utterance>Hey hillbilly.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then a VOICE says:</context>
      <utterance>You want that gun, Zed? Pick it up. Zed's hand inches toward the weapon. Butch GRIPS the sword tighter. Zed studies Butch. Butch looks hard at Zed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSELLUS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Butch steps aside, REVEALING Marsellus standing behind him, holding Maynard's pump-action shotgun.</context>
      <utterance>Step aside, Butch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSELLUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Long pause.</context>
      <utterance>Naw man. I'm pretty fuckin' far from okay!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What now?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSELLUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What now? Well let me tell you what now. I'm gonna call a couple pipe- hittin' niggers, who'll go to work on homes here with a pair of pliers and a blow torch.  Hear me talkin' hillbilly boy?! I ain't through with you by a damn sight. I'm gonna git Medieval on your ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I meant what now, between me and you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSELLUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, that what now? Well, let me tell ya what now between me an' you. There is no me an' you. Not no more.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So we're cool?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSELLUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah man, we're cool. One thing I ask – two things I ask: Don't tell nobody about this. This shit's between me and you and the soon-to-be-livin'- the-rest-of-his-short-ass-life-in- agonizing-pain, Mr. Rapist here. It ain't nobody else's business. Two: leave town. Tonight. Right now. And when you're gone, stay gone. You've lost your Los Angeles privileges. Deal?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men shake hands, then hug one another.</context>
      <utterance>Deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSELLUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch leaves Russell's old room through the red curtains. Marsellus walks over to a phone, dialing a number.</context>
      <utterance>Go on now, get your ass outta here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSELLUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello Mr. Wolf, it's Marsellus. Gotta bit of a situation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Butch, I was so worried!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey, grab your radio and your purse and let's go!</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what about all our bags?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck the bags. We'll miss our train if we don't split now.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is everything well? Are we in danger?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch runs out and hops back on the bike. Fabienne exits the motel room with the boom box and a large purse. When she sees Butch on the chopper, she stops dead.</context>
      <utterance>We're cool. In fact, we're super- cool. But we gots to go. I'll wait for you outside.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did you get this motorcycle?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fabienne slowly approaches the two-wheel demon.</context>
      <utterance>It's a chopper, baby, hop on.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to my Honda?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry baby, I crashed the Honda.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're hurt?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>I might've broke my nose, no biggie. Hop on. She doesn't move.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Butch realizes that this is not the way to get her on the bike. He turns off the engine and reaches out, taking her hand.</context>
      <utterance>Honey, we gotta hit the fuckin' road! Fabienne starts to cry.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, baby-love.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were gone so long, I started to think dreadful thoughts.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry I worried you, sweetie. Everything's fine. Hey, how was breakfast?</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was good –</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>– did you get the blueberry pancakes?</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, they didn't have blueberry pancakes, I had to get buttermilk – are you sure you're okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fabienne does climb on. Butch STARTS her up.</context>
      <utterance>Baby-love, from the moment I left you, this has been without a doubt the single weirdest day of my entire life. Climb on an' I'll tell ya about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Butch, whose motorcycle is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a chopper.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whose chopper is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zed's.</utterance>
   <speaker>FABIENNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's Zed?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUTCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that, the two lovebirds PEEL AWAY on Grace, as the SONG on the BOOM BOX RISES.</context>
      <utterance>Zed's dead, baby, Zed's dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever read the Bible, Brett?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRETT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a passage I got memorized, seems appropriate for this situation: Ezekiel 25:17. "The path of the righteous man is beset on all sides by the inequities of the selfish and the tyranny of evil men..."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Friend of yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Waiting for them isn't the smartest move. Bursting out the door and blowing them all away while they're fuckin' around is the way to go.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Marvin-Vincent-Vincent-Marvin.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FOURTH MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Fourth Man is taken out of the scenario by the two men's bullets who, unlike his, HIT their marks. He drops DEAD. The two men lower their guns. Jules, obviously shaken, sits down in a chair. Vincent, after a moment of respect, shrugs it off. Then heads toward Marvin in the corner.</context>
      <utterance>I don't understand –</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why the fuck didn't you tell us about that guy in the bathroom? Slip your mind? Forget he was in there with a goddamn hand cannon?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should be fuckin' dead right now.  Did you see that gun he fired at us? It was bigger than him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should be fuckin' dead!</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jules rises, moving toward Vincent.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, we were lucky.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent prepares to leave.</context>
      <utterance>That shit wasn't luck. That shit was somethin' else.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was... divine intervention. You know what divine intervention is?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I think so. That means God came down from Heaven and stopped the bullets.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, man, that's what is means. That's exactly what it means! God came down from Heaven and stopped the bullets.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we should be going now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't do that! Don't you fuckin' do that! Don't blow this shit off! What just happened was a fuckin' miracle!</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chill the fuck out, Jules, this shit happens.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wrong, wrong, this shit doesn't just happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you wanna continue this theological discussion in the car, or at the jailhouse with the cops?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should be fuckin' dead now, my friend! We just witnessed a miracle, and I want you to fuckin' acknowledge it!</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay man, it was a miracle, can we leave now?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="35">
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Ever seen that show "COPS?" I was watchin' it once and this cop was on it who was talkin' about this time he got into this gun fight with a guy in a hallway. He unloads on this guy and he doesn't hit anything. And these guys were in a hallway. It's a freak, but it happens.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you wanna play blind man, then go walk with a Shepherd. But me, my eyes are wide fuckin' open.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck does that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it for me. For here on in, you can consider my ass retired.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't blaspheme!</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddammit, Jules –</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>– I said don't do that –</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>– you're fuckin' freakin' out!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm tellin' Marsellus today I'm through.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>While you're at it, be sure to tell 'im why.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, I will.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll bet ya ten thousand dollars, he laughs his ass off.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent turns to the backseat with the .45 casually in his grip.</context>
      <utterance>I don't give a damn if he does.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marvin, what do you make of all this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't even have an opinion.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marvin is hit in the upper chest, below the throat. He GURGLES blood and SHAKES.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Marvin. Do you think God came down from Heaven and stopped the bullets? Vincent's .45 goes BANG!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck's happening?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just accidentally shot Marvin in the throat.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why the fuck did you do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean to do it. I said it was an accident.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've seen a lot of crazy-ass shit in my time –</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>– chill out, man, it was an accident, okay? You hit a bump or somethin' and the gun went off.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The car didn't hit no motherfuckin' bump!</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look! I didn't mean to shoot this son-ofa-bitch, the gun just went off, don't ask me how!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at this mess! We're drivin' around on a city street in broad daylight –</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>– I know, I know, I wasn't thinkin' about the splatter.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well you better be thinkin' about it now, motherfucker! We gotta get this car off the road. Cops tend to notice shit like you're driving a car drenched in fuckin' blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't we just take it to a friendly place?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the Valley, Vincent. Marsellus don't got no friendly places in the Valley.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jules takes out a cellular phone and starts punching digits.</context>
      <utterance>Well, don't look at me, this is your town, Jules.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who ya callin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A buddy of mine in Toluca Lake.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Toluca Lake.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On the other side of the hill, by Burbank Studios. If Jimmie's ass ain't home, I don't know what the fuck we're gonna go. I ain't got any other partners in 818.  Jimmie! How you doin' man, it's Jules.  Listen up man, me an' my homeboy are in some serious shit. We're in a car we gotta get off the road, pronto! I need to use your garage for a couple hours.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We gotta be real fuckin' delicate with this Jimmie's situation. He's one remark away from kickin' our asses out the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If he kicks us out, whadda we do?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jules rises and dries his hands. Vincent takes his place at the sink.</context>
      <utterance>Well, we ain't leavin' 'til we made a couple phone calls. But I never want it to reach that pitch. Jimmie's my friend and you don't bust in your friend's house and start tellin' 'im what's what.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just tell 'im not to be abusive. He kinda freaked out back there when he saw Marvin.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent finishes, then dries his hands on a white towel.</context>
      <utterance>Put yourself in his position. It's eight o'clock in the morning. He just woke up, he wasn't prepared for this shit. Don't forget who's doin' who a favor.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When Vincent is finished drying his hands, the towel is stained with red.</context>
      <utterance>If the price of that favor is I gotta take shit, he can stick his favor straight up his ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck did you just do to his towel?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just dryin' my hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're supposed to wash 'em first.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You watched me wash 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I watched you get 'em wet.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I washed 'em. Blood's real hard to get off. Maybe if he had some Lava, I coulda done a better job.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I used the same soap you did and when I dried my hands, the towel didn't look like a fuckin' Maxie pad. Look, fuck it, alright. Who cares? But it's shit like this that's gonna bring this situation to a boil. If he were to come in here and see that towel like that... I'm tellin' you Vincent, you best be cool. 'Cause if I gotta get in to it with Jimmie on account of you... Look, I ain't threatenin' you, I respect you an' all, just don't put me in that position.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jules, you ask me nice like that, no problem. He's your friend, you handle him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamn Jimmie, this is some serious gourmet shit. Me an' Vincent woulda been satisfied with freeze-dried Tasters Choice. You spring this gourmet fuckin' shit on us. What flavor is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Knock it off, Julie.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not a cobb or corn, so you can stop butterin' me up. I don't need you to tell me how good my coffee is. I'm the one who buys it, I know how fuckin' good it is. When Bonnie goes shoppin;, she buys shit. I buy the gourmet expensive stuff 'cause when I drink it, I wanna taste it. But what's on my mind at this moment isn't the coffee in my kitchen, it's the dead nigger in my garage.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jimmie –</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>– I'm talkin'. Now let me ask you a question, Jules. When you drove in here, did you notice a sign out front that said, "Dead nigger storage?" Jules starts to "Jimmie" him –</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>– answer to question. Did you see a sign out in front of my house that said, "Dead nigger storage?"</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naw man, I didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know why you didn't see that sign?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jules starts to "Jimmie" him.</context>
      <utterance>'Cause storin' dead niggers ain't my fuckin' business!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>– I ain't through! Now don't you understand that if Bonnie comes home and finds a dead body in her house, I'm gonna get divorced. No marriage counselor, no trial separation – fuckin' divorced. And I don't wanna get fuckin' divorced. The last time me an' Bonnie talked about this shit was gonna be the last time me an' Bonnie talked about this shit. Now I wanna help ya out Julie, I really do. But I ain't gonna lose my wife doin' it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jimmie –</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>– don't fuckin' Jimmie me, man, I can't be Jimmied. There's nothin' you can say that's gonna make me forget I love my wife. Now she's workin' the graveyard shift at the hospital. She'll be comin' home in less than an hour and a half. Make your phone calls, talk to your people, than get the fuck out of my house.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all we want. We don't wanna fuck up your shit. We just need to call our people to bring us in.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I suggest you get to it. Phone's in my bedroom.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got to appreciate what an explosive element this Bonnie situation is. If she comes home from a hard day's work and finds a bunch of gangsters doin' a bunch of gangsta' shit in her kitchen, ain't no tellin' what she's apt to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSELLUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've grasped that, Jules. All I'm doin' is contemplating the "ifs."</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't wanna hear about no motherfuckin' "ifs."What I wanna hear from your ass is: "you ain't got no problems, Jules. I'm on the motherfucker. Go back in there, chill them niggers out and wait for the cavalry, which should be comin' directly."</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSELLUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ain't got no problems, Jules. I'm on the motherfucker. Go back in there, chill them niggers out and wait for The Wolf, who should be comin' directly.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sendin' The Wolf?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARSELLUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Feel better?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit Negro, that's all you had to say.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is she the hysterical type?  When she due?  Give me the principals' names again?  Jules... We SEE his book. The page has written on it: "1265 Riverside Drive Toluca Lake 1 body  Bloody shot-up car Jules "</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Vincent... Jimmie... Bonnie...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're Jimmie, right? This is your house?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Winston Wolf, I solve problems.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good, 'cause we got one.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I heard. May I come in?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the dining room, Jules and Vincent stand up.</context>
      <utterance>Please do.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must be Jules, which would make you Vincent. Let's get down to brass tacks, gentlemen. If I was informed correctly, the clock is ticking, is that right, Jimmie?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your wife, Bonnie...  ...comes home at 9:30 in the AM, is that correct?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was led to believe if she comes home and finds us here, she wouldn't appreciate it none too much.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She won't at that.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That gives us forty minutes to get the fuck outta Dodge, which, if you do what I say when I say it, should by plenty. Now you got a corpse in a car, minus a head, in a garage. Take me to it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jimmie?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do me a favor, will ya? Thought I smelled some coffee in there. Would you make me a cup?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, how do you take it?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jimmie exists. The Wolf continues his examination.</context>
      <utterance>Lotsa cream, lotsa sugar.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About the car, is there anything I need to know? Does it stall, does it make a lot of noise, does it smoke, is there gas in it, anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aside from how it looks, the car's cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Positive? Don't get me out on the road and I find out the brake lights don't work.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey man, as far as I know, the motherfucker's tip-top.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good enough, let's go back to the kitchen.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a sip, then, pacing as he thinks, lays out for the three men the plan of action.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Jimmie.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay first thing, you two.  Take the body, stick it in the trunk. Now Jimmie, this looks to be a pretty domesticated house. That would lead me to believe that in the garage or under the sink, you got a bunch of cleansers and cleaners and shit like that, am I correct?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Exactly. Under the sink.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Wolf and Jimmie turn, heading for the bedroom, leaving Vincent and Jules standing in the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Good. What I need you two fellas to do is take those cleaning products and clean the inside of the car. And I'm talkin' fast, fast, fast. You need to go in the backseat, scoop up all those little pieces of brain and skull. Get it out of there. Wipe down the upholstery – now when it comes to upholstery, it don't need to be spic and span, you don't need to eat off it. Give it a good once over. What you need to take care of are the really messy parts. The pools of blood that have collected, you gotta soak that shit up. But the windows are a different story. Them you really clean. Get the Windex, do a good job. Now Jimmie, we need to raid your linen closet. I need blankets, I need comforters, I need quilts, I need bedspreads. The thicker the better, the darker the better. No whites, can't use 'em. We need to camouflage the interior of the car. We're gonna line the front seat and the backseat and the floor boards with quilts and blankets. If a cop stops us and starts stickin' his big snout in the car, the subterfuge won't last. But at a glance, the car will appear to be normal. Jimmie – lead the way, boys – get to work.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Wolf stops and turns around.</context>
      <utterance>A "please" would be nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come again?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Wolf takes a step toward him.</context>
      <utterance>I said a "please" would be nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Set is straight, Buster. I'm not here to say "please."I'm here to tell you want to do. And if self- preservation is an instinct you possess, you better fuckin' do it and do it quick. I'm here to help. If my help's not appreciated, lotsa luck gentlemen.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It ain't that way, Mr. Wolf. Your help is definitely appreciated.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't mean any disrespect. I just don't like people barkin' orders at me.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I'm curt with you, it's because time is a factor. I think fast, I talk fast, and I need you guys to act fast if you want to get out of this. So pretty please, with sugar on top, clean the fuckin' car.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jimmie comes over with a handful of linen.</context>
      <utterance>It's a 1974 Chevy Nova.  White.  Nothin', except for the mess inside.  About twenty minutes.  Nobody who'll be missed.  You're a good man, Joe. See ya soon.  How we comin', Jimmie?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Wolf, you gotta understand somethin' –</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>– Winston, Jimmie – please, Winston.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta understand something, Winston. I want to help you guys out and all, but that's my best linen. It was a wedding present from my Uncle Conrad and Aunt Ginny, and they ain't with us anymore –</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>– let me ask you a question, if you don't mind?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were you Uncle Conrad and Aunt Ginny millionaires?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, your Uncle Marsellus is. And I'm positive if Uncle Conrad and Aunt Ginny were millionaires, they would've furnished you with a whole bedroom set, which your Uncle Marsellus is more than happy to do.  I like oak myself, that's what's in my bedroom. How 'bout you Jimmie, you an oak man?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oak's nice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will never forgive your ass for this shit. This is some fucked-up repugnant shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you ever hear the philosophy that once a man admits he's wrong, he's immediately forgiven for all wrong-doings?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, get outta my face with that shit! The motherfucker who said that never had to pick up itty-bitty pieces of skull with his fingers on account of your dumb ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got a threshold, Jules. I got a threshold for the abuse I'll take. And you're crossin' it. I'm a race car and you got me in the red. Redline 7000, that's where you are. Just know, it's fuckin' dangerous to be drivin' a race car when it's in the red. It could blow.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gettin' ready to blow? I'm a mushroom-cloud-layin' motherfucker! Every time my fingers touch brain I'm "SUPERFLY T.N.T," I'm the "GUNS OF NAVARONE." I'm what Jimmie Walker usta talk about. In fact, what the fuck am I doin' in the back? You're the motherfucker should be on brain detail. We're tradin'. I'm washin' windows and you're pickin' up this nigger's skull.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine job, gentlemen. We may get out of this yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe that's the same car.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, let's not start suckin' each other's dicks quite yet. Phase one is complete, clean the car, which moves us right along to phase two, clean you two.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Strip.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All the way?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they follow directions, The Wolf enjoys a smoke.</context>
      <utterance>To your bare ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quickly gentlemen, we got about fifteen minutes before Jimmie's better- half comes pulling into the driveway.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This morning air is some chilly shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure this is absolutely necessary?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what you two look like?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like a couple of guys who just blew off somebody's head. Yes, strippin' off those bloody rags is absolutely necessary. Toss the clothes in Jim's garbage bag.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now Jimmie, don't do nothin' stupid like puttin' that out in front of your house for Elmo the garbage man to take away.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands the now-naked men a bar of soap.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, we're takin' it with us. Jim, the soap.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hits the trigger, water SHOOTS OUT, SMACKING both men.</context>
      <utterance>Okay gentlemen, you're both been to County before, I'm sure. Here it comes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamn, that water's fuckin' cold!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men, trembling, scrub themselves.</context>
      <utterance>Better you than me, gentlemen.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Wolf stops the hose, tossing it on the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be afraid of the soap, spread it around.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jimmie tosses them each a towel, which they rub furiously across their bodies.</context>
      <utterance>Towel 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're dry enough, give 'em their clothes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perfect. Perfect. We couldn't've planned this better. You guys look like... what do they look like, Jimmie?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Wolf and Jimmie laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Dorks. They look like a couple of dorks.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ha ha ha. They're your clothes, motherfucker.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess you just gotta know how to wear them.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, our asses ain't the expert on wearin' dorky shit that your is.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, gentlemen, we're laughin' and jokin' our way into prison. Don't make me beg.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen, let's get our rules of the road straight. We're going to a place called Monster Joe's Truck and Tow. Monster Joe and his daughter Raquel are sympathetic to out dilemma. The place is North Hollywood, so a few twist and turns aside, we'll be goin' up Hollywood Way. Now I'll drive the tainted car. Jules, you ride with me. Vincent, you follow in my Porsche. Now if we cross the path of any John Q. Laws, nobody does a fuckin' thing 'til I do something.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode>TO JULES</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did I say?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't do shit unless –</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>– unless what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unless you do it first.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spoken like a true prodigy.  How 'bout you, Lash Larue? Can you keep your spurs from jingling and jangling?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm cool, Mr. Wolf. My gun just went off, I dunno how.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOLF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fair enough.  I drive real fuckin' fast, so keep up. If I get my car back any different than I gave it, Monster Joe's gonna be disposing of two bodies.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We cool?</utterance>
   <speaker>WINSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jules and Vincent bump fists.</context>
      <utterance>Like it never happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boys, this is Raquel. Someday, all this will be hers.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAQUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Winston laughs, the boys groan.</context>
      <utterance>Hi. You know, if they ever do "I SPY: THE MOTION PICTURE," you guys, I'd be great. What's with the outfits. You guys going to a volleyball game?</utterance>
   <speaker>WINSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm takin' m'lady out to breakfast. Maybe I can drop you two off. Where do you live?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Redondo Beach.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Winston grabs Jules' wrist and pantomimes like he's in a "DEAD ZONE" trance.</context>
      <utterance>Inglewood.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's your future: I see... a cab ride.  Sorry guys, move out of the sticks.  Say goodbye, Raquel.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAQUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Raquel.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Winston turns to leave.</context>
      <utterance>I'll see you two around, and stay outta trouble, you crazy kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns around.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Wolf.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Wolf smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I was a pleasure watchin' you work.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and banters with Raquel as they get in the Porsche.</context>
      <utterance>Call me Winston.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You hear that, young lady? Respect. You could lean a lot from those two fine specimens. Respect for one's elders shows character.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAQUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have character.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just because you are a character doesn't mean you have character.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAQUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men left alone look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Oh you're so funny, oh you're so funny. The Porsche SHOOTS OFF down the road.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wanna share a cab?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know I could go for some breakfast. Want to have breakfast with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="62">
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks a bunch.  Want a sausage?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naw, I don't eat pork.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you Jewish?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't Jewish man, I just don't dig on swine.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're filthy animals. I don't eat filthy animals.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sausages taste good. Pork chops taste good.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A sewer rat may taste like pumpkin pie. I'll never know 'cause even if it did, I wouldn't eat the filthy motherfucker. Pigs sleep and root in shit. That's a filthy animal. I don't wanna eat nothin' that ain't got enough sense to disregard its own feces.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about dogs? Dogs eat their own feces.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't eat dog either.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, but do you consider a dog to be a filthy animal?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't go so far as to call a dog filthy, but they're definitely dirty. But a dog's got personality. And personality goes a long way.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So by that rationale, if a pig had a better personality, he's cease to be a filthy animal?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men laugh.</context>
      <utterance>We'd have to be talkin' 'bout one motherfuckin' charmin' pig. It'd have to be the Cary Grant of pigs.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good for you. Lighten up a little. You been sittin' there all quiet.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just been sittin' here thinkin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The miracle we witnessed.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The miracle you witnessed. I witnessed a freak occurrence.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know that a miracle is?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An act of God.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's an act of God?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess it's when God makes the impossible possible. And I'm sorry Jules, but I don't think what happened this morning qualifies.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you see, Vince, that shit don't matter. You're judging this thing the wrong way. It's not about what. It could be God stopped the bullets, he changed Coke into Pepsi, he found my fuckin' car keys. You don't judge shit like this based on merit. Whether or not what we experienced was an according-to-Hoyle miracle is insignificant. What is significant is I felt God's touch, God got involved.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But why?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what's fuckin' wit' me! I don't know why. But I can't go back to sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're serious, you're really gonna quit?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent takes a bite of food. Jules takes a sip of coffee In the b.g., we see a PATRON call the Waitress.</context>
      <utterance>The life, most definitely.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We recognize the patron to be Pumpkin from the first scene of Pumpkin and Honey Bunny.</context>
      <utterance>Garcon! Coffee!</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So if you're quitting the life, what'll you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I've been sitting here contemplating. First, I'm gonna deliver this case to Marsellus. Then, basically, I'm gonna walk the earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, walk the earth?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, like Caine in "KUNG FU." Just walk from town to town, meet people, get in adventures.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long do you intend to walk the earth?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Until God puts me where he want me to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if he never does?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it takes forever, I'll wait forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you decided to be a bum?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll just be Jules, Vincent – no more, no less.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No Jules, you're gonna be like those pieces of shit out there who beg for change. They walk around like a bunch of fuckin' zombies, they sleep in garbage bins, they eat what I throw away, and dogs piss on 'em. They got a word for 'em, they're called bums. And without a job, residence, or legal tender, that's what you're gonna be – a fuckin' bum!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look my friend, this is just where me and you differ –</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>– what happened was peculiar – no doubt about it – but it wasn't water into wine.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All shapes and sizes, Vince.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop fuckin' talkin' like that!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you find my answers frightening, Vincent, you should cease askin' scary questions.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jules, alone, takes a mouthful of muffin, then... Pumpkin and Honey Bunny rise with guns raised.</context>
      <utterance>I gotta take a shit. To be continued. Vincent exits for the restroom.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUMPKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody be cool, this is a robbery!</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEY BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jules looks up, not believing what he's seeing. Under the table, Jules' hand goes to his .45 Automatic. He pulls it out, COCKING IT.</context>
      <utterance>Any of you fuckin' pricks move and I'll execute every one of you motherfuckers! Got that?!</utterance>
   <speaker>PUMPKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Customers stay seated, waitresses on the floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEY BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Like lightning, Pumpkin moves over to the kitchen. While Honey Bunny SCREAMS out threats to the PATRONS, keeping them terrified.</context>
      <utterance>Now mean fuckin' now! Do it or die, do it or fucking die!</utterance>
   <speaker>PUMPKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Three COOKS and two BUSBOYS come out of the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>You Mexicans in the kitchen, get out here! Asta luego!</utterance>
   <speaker>PUMPKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On the floor or I'll cook you ass, comprende? They comprende. The portly MANAGER speaks up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the manager here, there's no problem, no problem at all – Pumpkin heads his way.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUMPKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches him and sticks the barrel of his gun hard in the Manager's neck.</context>
      <utterance>You're gonna give me a problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>PUMPKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? You said you're gonna give me a problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm not. I'm not gonna give you any problem!</utterance>
   <speaker>PUMPKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, Honey Bunny. He looks like the hero type to me!</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEY BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Patrons SCREAM. Jules watches all this silently, his hand tightly gripping the .45 Automatic under the table.</context>
      <utterance>Don't take any chances. Execute him!</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please don't! I'm not a hero. I'm just a coffee shop manager. Take anything you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUMPKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell everyone to cooperate and it'll be all over.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody just be calm and cooperate with them and this will be all over soon!</utterance>
   <speaker>PUMPKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well done, now git your fuckin' ass on the ground.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="74">
   <speaker>PUMPKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pumpkin goes around collecting wallets. Jules sits with his .45 ready to spit under the table. Pumpkin sees Jules sitting in his booth, holding his wallet, briefcase next to him. Pumpkin crosses to him, his tone more respectful, him manner more on guard.</context>
      <utterance>Okay people, I'm going to go 'round and collect your wallets. Don't talk, just toss 'em in the bag. We clear?</utterance>
   <speaker>PUMPKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jules DROPS his wallet in the bag. Using his gun as a pointer, Pumpkin points to the briefcase.</context>
      <utterance>In the bag.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUMPKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's in that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My boss' dirty laundry.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUMPKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You boss makes you do his laundry?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When he wants it clean.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUMPKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds like a shit job.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Funny, I've been thinkin' the same thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUMPKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jules' free hand lays palm flat on the briefcase.</context>
      <utterance>Open it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pumpkin is definitely surprised by his answer. He aims the gun right in the middle of Jules' face and pulls back the hammer.</context>
      <utterance>'Fraid I can't do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUMPKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't hear you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This exchange has been kind of quiet, not everybody heard it, but Honey Bunny senses something's wrong.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEY BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's goin' on?</utterance>
   <speaker>PUMPKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like we got a vigilante in our midst.</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEY BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shoot 'em in the face!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't mean to shatter your ego, but this ain't the first time I've had gun pointed at me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUMPKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't open up that case, it's gonna be the last.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quit causing problems, you'll get us all killed! Give 'em what you got and get 'em out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep your fuckin' mouth closed, fat man, this ain't any of your goddamn business!</utterance>
   <speaker>PUMPKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm countin' to three, and if your hand ain't off that case, I'm gonna unload right in your fuckin' face. Clear? One...</utterance>
   <speaker>PUMPKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...two... three.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jules raises his hand off the briefcase.</context>
      <utterance>You win.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all yours, Ringo.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUMPKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jules flips the locks and opens the case, revealing it to Pumpkin but not to us. The same light SHINES from the case. Pumpkin's expression goes to amazement. Honey Bunny, across the room, can't see shit.</context>
      <utterance>Open it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEY BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it? What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PUMPKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jules nods his head: "yes."</context>
      <utterance>Is that what I think it is?</utterance>
   <speaker>PUMPKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jules nods his head: "yes."</context>
      <utterance>It's beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEY BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jules SLAMS the case closed, then sits back, as if offering the case to Pumpkin. Pumpkin, one big smile, bends over to pick up the case. Like a rattlesnake, Jules' free hand GRABS the wrist of Pumpkin's gun hand, SLAMMING it on the table. His other hand comes from under the table and STICKS the barrel of his .45 hand under Pumpkin's chin. Honey Bunny freaks out, waving her gun in Jules' direction.</context>
      <utterance>Goddammit, what is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEY BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let him go! Let him go! I'll blow your fuckin' head off! I'll kill ya! I'll kill ya! You're gonna die, you're gonna fuckin' die bad!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell that bitch to be cool! Say, bitch be cool! Say, bitch be cool!</utterance>
   <speaker>PUMPKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chill out, honey!</utterance>
   <speaker>HONEY BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let him go!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell her it's gonna be okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUMPKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna be okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Promise her.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUMPKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell her to chill.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUMPKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just chill out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's her name?</utterance>
   <speaker>PUMPKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whenever Jules talks to Yolanda, he never looks at her, only at Pumpkin.</context>
      <utterance>Yolanda.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, we cool Yolanda? We ain't gonna do anything stupid, are we?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOLANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you hurt him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody's gonna hurt anybody. We're gonna be like three Fonzies. And what' Fonzie like?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon Yolanda, what's Fonzie like?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOLANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's cool?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pumpkin looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Correct-amundo! And that's what we're gonna be, we're gonna be cool.  Now Ringo, I'm gonna count to three and I want you to let go your gun and lay your palms flat on the table. But when you do it, do it cool. Ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pumpkin lets go of his gun and places both hands on the table. Yolanda can't stand it anymore.</context>
      <utterance>One... two... three.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOLANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, now let him go!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yolanda, I thought you were gonna be cool. When you yell at me, it makes me nervous. When I get nervous, I get scared. And when motherfuckers get scared, that's when motherfuckers get accidentally shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOLANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just know: you hurt him, you die.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That seems to be the situation. Now I don't want that and you don't want that and Ringo here don't want that. So let's see what we can do.  Now this is the situation. Normally both of your asses would be dead as fuckin' fried chicken. But you happened to pull this shit while I'm in a transitional period. I don't wanna kill ya, I want to help ya. But I'm afraid I can't give you the case. It don't belong to me. Besides, I went through too much shit this morning on account of this case to just hand it over to your ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Yolanda WHIPS her gun toward the stranger. Vincent, by the bathroom, has his gun out, dead-aimed at Yolanda.</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck's goin' on here?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's cool, Vincent! It's cool! Don't do a goddamn thing. Yolanda, it's cool baby, nothin's changed. We're still just talkin'.  Tell her we're still cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUMPKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's cool, Honey Bunny, we're still cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell's goin' on, Jules?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothin' I can't handle. I want you to just hang back and don't do shit unless it's absolutely necessary.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Check.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yolanda, how we doin, baby?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOLANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta go pee! I want to go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just hang in there, baby, you're doing' great, Ringo's proud of you and so am I. It's almost over.  Now I want you to go in that bag and find my wallet.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUMPKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which one is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pumpkin looks in the bag and – sure enough – there's a wallet with "Bad Motherfucker" embroidered on it.</context>
      <utterance>It's the one that says Bad Motherfucker on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's my bad motherfucker. Now open it up and take out the cash. How much is there?</utterance>
   <speaker>PUMPKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About fifteen hundred dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put it in your pocket, it's yours. Now with the rest of them wallets and the register, that makes this a pretty successful little score.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jules, if you give this nimrod fifteen hundred buck, I'm gonna shoot 'em on general principle.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ain't gonna do a goddamn thing, now hang back and shut the fuck up. Besides, I ain't givin' it to him. I'm buyin' somethin' for my money. Wanna know what I'm buyin' Ringo?</utterance>
   <speaker>PUMPKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your life. I'm givin' you that money so I don't hafta kill your ass. You read the Bible?</utterance>
   <speaker>PUMPKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not regularly.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grabbing the trash bag full of wallets, the two RUN out the door. Jules, who was never risen from his seat the whole time, takes a sip of coffee.</context>
      <utterance>There's a passage I got memorized. Ezekiel 25:17. "The path of the righteous man is beset on all sides by the inequities of the selfish and the tyranny of evil men. Blessed is he who, in the name of charity and good will, shepherds the weak through the valley of the darkness. For he is truly his brother's keeper and the finder of lost children. And I will strike down upon thee with great vengeance and furious anger those who attempt to poison and destroy my brothers. And you will know I am the Lord when I lay my vengeance upon you." I been sayin' that shit for years. And if you ever heard it, it meant your ass. I never really questioned what it meant. I thought it was just a coldblooded thing to say to a motherfucker 'fore you popped a cap in his ass. But I saw some shit this mornin' made me think twice. Now I'm thinkin', it could mean you're the evil man. And I'm the righteous man. And Mr. .45 here, he's the shepherd protecting my righteous ass in the valley of darkness. Or is could by you're the righteous man and I'm the shepherd and it's the world that's evil and selfish. I'd like that. But that shit ain't the truth. The truth is you're the weak. And I'm the tyranny of evil men. But I'm tryin'. I'm tryin' real hard to be a shepherd. Jules lowers his gun, lying it on the table. Pumpkin looks at him, to the money in his hand, then to Yolanda. She looks back.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent appears next to Jules.</context>
      <utterance>It's cold. He pushes it aside.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we oughta leave now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent throws some money on the table and Jules grabs the briefcase. Then, to the amazement of the Patrons, the Waitresses, the Cooks, the Bus Boys, and the Manager, these two bad-ass dudes – wearing UC Santa Cruz and "I'm with Stupid" tee-shirts, swim trunks, thongs and packing .45 Automatics – walk out of the coffee shop together without saying a word.</context>
      <utterance>That's probably a good idea.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
