<movie id="455" title="Rambo First Blood II The Mission">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LEWIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They descend two flights to a door of steel bars on a sliding track. The MPs flank Lewis as he unlocks the door.</context>
      <utterance>Shit. Maintenance never gets down here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SINGLETERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what am I supposed to do? Can't transfer him to Leavenworth. He's civilian. So I put him in an isolation cell that hasn't been used since the Spanish Inquisition.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIGHT ON BARRED DOOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>rolling aside on metal tracks. CLANG.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lewis opens a cabinet near the single locked cell and removes a SMALL RIFLE. He feeds a SYRINGE-LIKE SHELL into the single-shot bolt action.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe you should have tried cutting him some slack.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SINGLETERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trautman pushes the barrel aside with a contemptuous snort and steps up to the cell door.</context>
      <utterance>Tranquilizer syrette gun. Borrowed it from the Animal Control Department.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two MPs flank the door. One pulls on the latching lever. Bolts slide. The door swings open, revealing blackness.</context>
      <utterance>Gimme a break.  Open it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He closes the door until it latches.</context>
      <utterance>Wait outside.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, John.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Colonel.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo motions to the narrow bunk, dropping into an Oriental squat himself as the Colonel sits. Trautman's manner with Rambo is familiar, somehow paternal. A bit of an ironic grin twitches briefly.</context>
      <utterance>Mind if I sit down?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hear you're not enjoying it here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trautman sighs and leans back.</context>
      <utterance>I could take it or leave it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seems like I'm always pulling you out of some goddamn toilet or other, doesn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I out of here?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That depends on you.  Christ, look at you. I give you this easy duty until I can get you an assignment... all you have to do is eat ice cream and watch soap operas... and you have to make it Rambo's last stand.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There were treating me like a headcase.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo looks at his hands. When he finally speaks his voice seems distant, disembodied.</context>
      <utterance>Hard to believe. You shoot up one little town in Oregon with a fifty caliber machine gun... one little dogpatch town... and everybody figures your wrapper's broken. No sense of humor.  What did you expect? An engraved plague from the chamber of commerce?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The colonel nods slowly. He notices a battered shoebox on the floor beside the bed. The cell is absolutely devoid of personal articles otherwise.</context>
      <utterance>In 'Nam I flew gunships. Million dollar equipment. Back here nobody trusts me to park cars. I keep thinking it's going to be okay... but I've been out six years and it's not okay. Sometimes I feel like I'm coming right out of my skin.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This your stuff?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it. My life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hardcore outfit. The best I ever trained.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those men are all dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He fishes something from among the pathetic debris of Rambo's life.</context>
      <utterance>You're not.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Congressional Medal of Honor.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Big time.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Plus, what else? Two Silver Stars, four Bronze Stars, two Soldier's Medals, four Vietnamese Crosses of Gallantry and... uh, a handful of Purple Hearts.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five. I never wanted that stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just wanted... I don't know... after all that... I just wanted one person, one person, to come up to me and say "you did good, John." And mean it. That's all.  After all that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The colonel studies Rambo a moment, then stands abruptly.</context>
      <utterance>You just picked that wrong war to be a hero in.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's take a walk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kirkhill extends his hand in greeting, but Rambo coolly half-turns to reveal his hands, locked in WRIST-CUFFS separated by a steel bar so that they can hang comfortably at his sides. Kirkhill grins affably. Drops his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Jason Kirkhill... John Rambo.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo scans Kirkhill's face, noting the cold scrutiny all but concealed in the smile lines.</context>
      <utterance>Good to meet you, Rambo. How are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kirkhill drops the smile.</context>
      <utterance>You a spook?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo turns to Trautman.</context>
      <utterance>That's right. CIA Special Operations Division.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't work with spooks. Not after that op in Cambodia.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm authorized to get you out of here. I thought that's what you wanted.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the job?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Classic special forces op... hit fast... in and out. Two men. Two days.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why me?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Area familiarity.</context>
      <utterance>We like you.  At least the computer at Langley likes you. Pulled your file because of various factors. Service record.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kirkhill's eyes get hard.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not jumping blind.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo seems about to turn away.</context>
      <utterance>It's yes or no. In or out... now. If it's "out," we will not have had this conversation. If you come in, you will not be working for us. No knowledge. No comment. Do you understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kirkhill looks pained, like he has gas.</context>
      <utterance>Tell him. I'll take responsibility.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>North Vietnam. What they call the Democratic Republic of Vietnam now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We left some people behind there, John... POWs.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This just occurred to somebody, now?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Something flows there... Trautman knows his soul.</context>
      <utterance>We don't leave our men, Rambo. Rambo and Trautman lock eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He whips one hand around from his side, tossing the manacle bar at a surprised Kirkhill's feet. The wrist-cuffs are still closed.</context>
      <utterance>You got it. I'm in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is your mission packet...</utterance>
   <speaker>AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sign here, please. And here.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo unseals the folder, removing a sheaf of photocopied documents, as Kirkhill perches on the table next to him.</context>
      <utterance>Memorize it here. It doesn't leave this room.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The twenty-four hundred American servicemen missing in action in Vietnam, Laos and Cambodia are officially listed "Presumed Killed." Certainly most of them are. Rambo is leafing through the contents of his PACKET. He skips a stack of reports and fishes out several grainy 8 X 10 prints.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But reports keep filtering in. Sightings by refugees. Nothing verified. Finally, we feel we've got enough to proceed on. Rambo studies the prints. They seem to be high altitude surveillance photos of a small COMPOUND OF BUILDINGS, surrounded by forests.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>barracks. It could be anything.</context>
      <utterance>Memo E-7 on top will cover the details. An abandoned Vietnamese Army base in the North-central highlands may have a compound used as an internment camp. As you can see the intelligence is soft. These LANDSAT photos show huts...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the plan?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This operation is in two phases. Recon and rescue. You are phase one. Your two-man team will probe the site, confirm the presence of American POWs, if any, make photographic and tactical observations, then proceed to the extraction point without engaging the enemy.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't try to pull out any of our guys if we find them?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Negative. Absolutely not. The phase two assault team will get them out.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We just take pictures?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't look so disappointed. It should be hairy enough... even for you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An American in his late twenties, the man speaks with one of those hard-to-dislike Southern accents. Probably North Carolina. He is lanky but muscular, with boyish good looks and hair cut so short it barely qualifies as stubble. Though dressed in a loud Hawaiian shirt and Madras slacks, it is painfully obvious the man is military. His arm is draped around a gorgeous but overly made-up Thai girl.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry old buddy, I saw it first.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No problem. We'll share it. Get your tail in there, sweet thing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo speaks quietly to the driver in Thai.</context>
      <utterance>Indra Hotel. And don't take the scenic route, Smiley... I know my way around this burg. Comprende?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girl giggles as the American slips his hand up from her stockinged knee, between her thighs.</context>
      <utterance>Same place for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She giggles, like a chirping bird.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, you fair flower of the Orient.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to Rambo, who hasn't commented or taken any observable notice of him.</context>
      <utterance>She thinks everything I say is funny. Don't you, Angel-pie? Man, Thai women are the best. Got the kinda legs I like... feet at one end and pussy at the other.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't say a helluva lot, do you, pal? You speak English?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girl coos to the American in pidgin English.</context>
      <utterance>Sometimes.</utterance>
   <speaker>THAI GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got money? I stay you whole week.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lowers his voice conspiratorially, leaning close to her.</context>
      <utterance>Sweet thing, there's nothin' I'd like more than to wugga-wugga with you for a week, but tonight's all we got.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo grabs the man brutally by his collar.</context>
      <utterance>See, I'm on this secret mission, and tomorrow mornin' I head out to...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The American freezes at the sound of his name. Turns slowly.</context>
      <utterance>That's enough, Brewer.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo speaks sharply to the girl in Thai.</context>
      <utterance>You're Rambo?  Ke-rist!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The driver, confused, skids to a stop and the girl gets out into the din of a cluttered shop district. A flash of slit skirt and then only fading curses behind them as the taxi moves on.</context>
      <utterance>Get out. Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeez, I never would have guessed. You undercover, Lieutenant? Great disguise.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He says he's team leader on this show.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's correct.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Begging the Colonel's pardon but I understood I was up to lead my next mission.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not this one. You're on communications and camera. Same image-intensified gear you used in El Salvador last year.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This clown almost blew mission security on the street. I'm not jumping with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clown? Now back up there, buddy...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen up. You two are married as of now. Get used to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I say we tape him to a chair.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know you were a stick man, Rambo.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was crossed-trained in gunships.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long have you been setting up?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About 22 hours on site.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They pass a tent-like CAMOUFLAGE CANOPY under which an ALL-BLACK SIKORSKY UH-60 "BLACKHAWK" HELICOPTER squats ominously. It has no markings or insignia. There is another canopy behind it, the contents of which are screened from view. Nearby is a cluster of CONEX AIRLIFT CONTAINERS, two of which are joined together to form a building like a double-wide mobile home. Another unit contains a roaring generator, a fourth is topped by TRACKING GEAR. Cables snake through the mud, connecting the units. Kirkhill notices THREE WORK PARTY "GRUNTS" kibitzing nearby, taking pictures of each other with a pocket Instamatic. He snatches the camera from a surprised young corporal.</context>
      <utterance>Nice work.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens the camera and drops the film in the mud. The corporal reaches petulantly for the camera. Kirkhill drops it casually in the mud as well.</context>
      <utterance>This is a covert operation, numbnuts.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens the door to the large conex unit and follows the others inside.</context>
      <utterance>Check out the command hut.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They wipe their muddy feet and enter the air-conditioned command center. Rambo gazes around at the jumble of gear. He runs his hand over one console, causing a seated technician to glare at him.</context>
      <utterance>Mission control!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All this is for us?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They call us the field-unit meat- puppets.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MED. ON RAMBO AND BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>as they consider the aircraft.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ever do this from a jet?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>They turn to see a lanky long-haired man in a leather flying jacket duck under the fuselage from the far side and approach them.</context>
      <utterance>It's easy...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two other air crewmen jump down from the open rear passenger door of the plane.</context>
      <utterance>Just have to jump fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You the pilot?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doyle is a product of the sixties' school of ultra-cool, his brain a little torched by too many methed-out night- missions. Fuhrman, the co-pilot, grins too much and Lifer's eyes are just plain scary.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Doyle.  Lifer and Fuhrman.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You boys Air Force?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marines. 'Ex' though. We're private contractors now.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever do a tour 'in-country'?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two. 'Eye-corps' mostly.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>With each word he plops the torque-wrench onto the appropriate place.</context>
      <utterance>Thailand. The Mekong. Laos. 'Nam.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A straight dash across the Laotian panhandle, through the Annamese Mountains... some good dicey bits there... and on to the drop zone. Eighteen minutes each way in communist airspace.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We go low to stay off radar?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the rhubarb, babe.</utterance>
   <speaker>FUHRMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mowin' the lawn.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dig it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long before you're fully on line?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to a vending machine nestled improbably between two racks of electronics.</context>
      <utterance>Couple hours. Let me buy you a coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think they'll find any?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>POWs? I don't know. But either way it'll get that subcommittee off our necks. Cream?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Black. No sugar.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trautman watches the Special Operations Officer banging ineffectually on the COIN RETURN, amid a million dollars worth of equipment.</context>
      <utterance>The League of Families leans on Congress. Then they lean on us. Like we don't have enough to worry about in a dozen dirtwater countries. Damnit! He pounds the machine, which refuses to vend.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A couple klicks from insertion we go vertical to ten thousand and you punch out. Navigate in free fall like a regular HALO jump. You'll have a good moon.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got your moon right here...</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doyle notices that Brewer has casually lit up a cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>No problem. Duck soup.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brewer glances at the pool of jet fuel around the pumping area. Rambo plucks the cigarette from Brewer's lips.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, man... we got fuel on the deck. I don't like flying without a plane.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks Brewer in the eye and flicks the lit butt into the pool of gas. Which puts it out.</context>
      <utterance>No smoking on this mission. It's not healthy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo saunters away.</context>
      <utterance>Son of a bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice trick. Works nine times out of ten.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Again.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Insertion. Call in to base camp by TRANSAT. Proceed to point Tango November for rendezvous with our ground contact. Indigenous agent. Co Phuong Bao.  We've been over this three times.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brewer rolls his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>You stopped.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Co Phuong Bao. The guide takes us twelve klicks upriver to target at Ban... at Ban... Bo Peep. Shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Start over.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... to target at Ban Kia Na. We probe the site...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ninety.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... then proceed downriver to extraction at point Echo Delta. Doyle takes us out by helicopter, we all live happily ever after and that's the last time, Rambo! I swear to Christ.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both collapse, face-down, breathing heavily. Brewer rises first.</context>
      <utterance>One hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gettin' old, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When Rambo rises it is in pushup position, only this time using one arm. He starts. One, two, three...</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.  Second set. Let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to the MTOC nearby.</context>
      <utterance>The signal's coded into infrared pulses, picked up by the spy satellite, bounced to the ground station in Okinawa and relayed to the hut...</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No radio source. Nothing for the bad guys to triangulate on.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Show me how it operates.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I'm here for.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Show me in case you get zapped as soon as we land.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sees Rambo's expression.</context>
      <utterance>We're leaving tonight, not in a week.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright. Alright.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>They turn to see Rambo watching them from just outside the pool of light. A spectral figure. Brewer glances at the array of stuff.</context>
      <utterance>You jumping with all that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and vanishes in the dark.</context>
      <utterance>You break your leg, I'll have to shoot you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think he means it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crazy fucker.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brewer turns quizzically toward him.</context>
      <utterance>Well, son. You got that right. Anybody ever tell you about that guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about him?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Rambo adjusting his headset.</context>
      <utterance>Ready to roll, Lieutenant.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep it clean, Rambo, or I'll nail your hide to the shed.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got it, sir. Trautman exits and the steps are rolled away.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zen Rollercoaster, requesting clearance.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are cleared, Zen Rollercoaster.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We just entered Viet airspace, gentlemen. Eight klicks to insertion.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay tight on me, Brewer. I don't want to have to go looking for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Check.</utterance>
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Five-by-Five.</context>
      <utterance>AWACS Niner-One via Subic Bay reports them approaching insertion.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ready light changes from red to yellow. Rambo unbuckles from his seat. Rises. Brewer follows. Lifer steadies them at the door.</context>
      <utterance>Approaching ten thousand. Eleven seconds to insertion. Ten, nine... Slowing to two-thirty...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ready-light turns GREEN.</context>
      <utterance>... three seconds. Two. One. Have a nice day.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo takes a single, powerful running stride from the opposite wall and is out the door. Gone. Brewer is right behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You read me, Brewer?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Read you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Home on my strobe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep it down, man. I got problems.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TIGHT ON BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SUDDENLY A DARK OBJECT SHOOTS INTO FRAME, seizing him. Brewer's head snaps around. The object is Rambo's hand, painted camo-green. Rambo drags him with a sucking POP from the mud. The Team Leader glares.</context>
      <utterance>sighing with relief.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brewer pauses a moment, assimilating the implicit warning. Then reaches for his harness buckles to free himself.</context>
      <utterance>That's one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kirkhill watches the message print out on the main screen. Turns to Trautman.</context>
      <utterance>It's coming in.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A cheer goes up in the command center. The home team just scored.</context>
      <utterance>They're in! On the money.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you call that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Modified M-16 A2 and over-under M-79 grenade launcher, with Sionics sound suppressor, Tracor starlight scope and LAC/R-100 Laser sighting system.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Batteries not included.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo gazes around him.</context>
      <utterance>AC-System 'Big-Ear' telescopic mike with built-in audio processor. Can pull a whisper out of a loud cocktail party at 50 meters.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cocktail party. Uh huh, right.  Let's saddle up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo flips open his rucksack.</context>
      <utterance>Where's your stuff?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it? Some C-4, a map and a knife?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brewer gestures at the Russian-made AK-47 slung over Rambo's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>There's a compass in the handle.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And a beat-to-shit AK? Every twelve-year-old in Nam's got one of those.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brewer hefts the separate rucksack containing the TRANSAT.</context>
      <utterance>Exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo snorts disgustedly.</context>
      <utterance>Uh... this thing's pretty heavy. You got room for it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a thought.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna know why I stood up for this show?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was in the brig. They gave me a deal. I blew up this Colonel's golf cart with an M-19. He wasn't in it or anything... it was the symbolic value. Seemed like a good idea at the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a real good reason to wind up in 'Nam.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've seen worse places.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are no worse places.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This place is a trip.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buddhist monastery. Fifteenth century.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has pulled up his pant-leg to reveal THREE SQUIRMING BLACK WORMS attached to his calf, sucking on him. Rambo moves off, scanning, unconcerned.</context>
      <utterance>Damn! Leeches.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get used to 'em.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You fucking crazy? I need it to burn these things off.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No cigarettes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo takes the pack from Brewer's breast pocket and grinds it into the mud under his boot.</context>
      <utterance>I had it cupped.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brewer is hurled against a stone wall and pinned with a knife to his throat so rapidly he's not sure how it happened. Rambo is in his face, speaking very softly.</context>
      <utterance>Look, Rambo. I've had enough of your bad-ass Indian-scout bullshit. You're years out of date... I'm makin' a career out of teaching you the hardware. As far as I'm concerned you're just along to back me up. And I heard about you... about how twitchy you really are. Kill any civilians lately?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shaking with rage, Brewer levels his weapon at Rambo's back. Then he realizes how silly that would be. Frustrated, he jogs to catch up.</context>
      <utterance>Listen real careful, freshmeat. I don't know why they sent you. Maybe they didn't want to waste a good man. But you screw up once more and I'll kill you myself. Rambo whips away, moves quietly off.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Moving in the shadows, Rambo walks through the ruins noiselessly. A voice emerges from the mist behind them, an almost childlike lilt.</context>
      <utterance>Man, are you strict.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Brewer whips around, centering the AIMING DOT of his sighting laser on a FIGURE sitting on a ledge above them. Sitting cross-legged and unperturbed is a diminutive VIETNAMESE WOMAN of about 28. The dot of Brewer's laser is centered on her forehead like a Hindu prayer mark. She is absolutely beautiful, with wide, calm eyes and strong but sensuous mouth which curves now in a small quirky grin.</context>
      <utterance>You are first tourist here in long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You come here see Buddha... ask for truth? Or just lost?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo pushes his rifle barrel aside and takes a step forward. When he speaks it is in FLUENT VIETNAMESE.</context>
      <utterance>Should I waste her?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not lost. Just looking for someone.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone called maybe 'Night Orchid'?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Co Phuong Bao.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's our contact.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Rambo. This is Brewer.  Her name is Co.</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It means "virgin." My mother was comedian.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sticks out his hand but Rambo motions "no". She bows slightly.</context>
      <utterance>Howdy, Co.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Where'd you learn?</context>
      <utterance>Uh, you speak pretty good English.</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You got time... want to eat?</context>
      <utterance>University of Saigon. Have Masters Degree in economics. Not use too much now... Communists in charge.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Co reaches up onto the ledge, her previous perch, and pulls down a small PACK, actually a FOOD TUBE of the sort worn over one shoulder by Viet Cong and other Vietnamese guerrillas.</context>
      <utterance>Sure. Whattaya got?</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She unrolls several rubber tree leaves holding rice with a pungent sauce. Rambo takes the food and the proffered CHOPSTICKS and, squatting, begins shoveling it expertly.</context>
      <utterance>Nuac mam.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really got a Masters Degree?</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brewer fumbles with the sticks. Switches to fingers.</context>
      <utterance>Sure. I only sound like forty-year- old in your language.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this stuff on the rice?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brewer's expression is less than enthusiastic.</context>
      <utterance>Fermented fish sauce.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do we get upriver?</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have arranged transportation. We meet soon. But I think you to be disappointed.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo stops, puzzled.</context>
      <utterance>I go up to this camp two months ago. Nobody there. Empty for years.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would they send us to a deserted camp?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo moves on, still concerned. something's a bit off.</context>
      <utterance>Who cares? Let's just do it and get out. Go have a Jacuzzi and get laid in Bangkok. Know what I mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll check it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come we didn't just drop near the camp... save this hassle?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brewer. Does a jet make noise?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did you find this clown?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought he was with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crazy motherfucker.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's she saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She likes you. Says you're dinky- dau.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Powerful warrior.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo motions suddenly for a "freeze". Co walks on ahead, toward the river, as the Americans melt into the shadows.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Dinky-dau, that's me. Hey, Co. You wanna meet Jake the one- eyed snake?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These guys look like they'd sell their mothers.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes they do. They're river pirates. Opium runners.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN TRONG KINH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wa-ky number one. You come number one sampan.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like my room in college.</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We sleep here today. Safe here while go up river.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kinh opens a greasy wooden locker, takes out his pride and joy, a Russian-made RPG-7 ROCKET-GRENADE LAUNCHER. His grin glistens evilly in the gloom.</context>
      <utterance>What about patrol boats?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up. Runs a hand through his hair.</context>
      <utterance>No, sir... we're already committed. They're in the jungle right now. I say we play the hand through... if they find something we just bury the report later. It's still airtight.  Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>some trucks or something.</context>
      <utterance>Goddamn it! Now the goddamn satellite shows the camp occupied...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's up?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Kirkhill. I'm a bit of a fifth wheel in your setup here... I thought I'd go out with the extraction team tonight. Unless you have an objection.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not necessary.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trautman is calling him on it with a deadpan response.</context>
      <utterance>That's a pretty hairy ride. Full Colonels are supposed to be above that sort of thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have fun.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brewer groans. Opens a C-ration can.</context>
      <utterance>Have some armpit sauce.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you get started working for the spooks?</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spooks?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Intelligence work.</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. They talk to me at university before fall of Saigon. Make deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody's makin' deals.</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My brother captain in ARVN... need papers to go United States, or North Vietnamese will execute. They make deal... I stay here and do work... my brother and my son can go United States.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Co's eyes drop and her whole demeaner deflates slightly.</context>
      <utterance>Your son?</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nguyen. He twelve now. Not see him for eight years.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Co shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Where's his father?</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her voice and expression convey the fatalistic acceptance of one who has seen death in all its forms. Expects it as an element of daily life.</context>
      <utterance>Dead. Killed in war.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Nguyen now? What city?</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huntington Beach, California.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's nice there. He's probably digging every minute. Got a surfboard. Breaking girls' hearts.</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Co gazes at the sunset beyond the door. A tear runs down her cheek. She catches herself. Wipes it away almost brutally. She abruptly goes on deck.</context>
      <utterance>Nguyen is good boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly there is a commotion on deck. The roar of a powerful ENGINE. Co bursts in a moment later.</context>
      <utterance>Some hardened guerrilla fighter they gave us. Rambo freezes him out with an evil look.</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A FAST LAUNCH roars toward them, silhouetted by the setting sun. UNIFORMED SOLDIERS on deck bring twin 50- caliber machine guns to bear. Rambo and Brewer dive under filthy bunks. Lock and load their weapons. Co pushes junk in over them. Kinh rips open the cabinet. Slams the shaft of a rocket grenade into the launch tube. Co barks an order at him. He hesitates. Lowers the weapon. Co removes a small packet of North Vietnamese bills from inside her blouse and hands it to Kinh.</context>
      <utterance>River patrol!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you doing, Brewer?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need a vacation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A brief glow of light illuminates the face of a TOWER GUARD hidden in shadows.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody home. Wait a minute! Cigarette.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nearby, another GUARD saunters out of the forest dressed in NVA regular private's uniform with the sleeves rolled up casually. His AK-47 is slung over his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>What's he here for?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Snoring. Five, six guys. Mumbling... Vietnamese. Somebody talking in his sleep. A toilet flushing.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brewer locks a 35mm SLR camera to an adapter on the starlight scope. He starts clicking off some shots. Brewer then scans the long hut across the compound.</context>
      <utterance>Guard barracks. Take some shots.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He whips off the earphones in pain as a LOW SCREAM echoes across the camp. It fades into a delirious moaning. Stops.</context>
      <utterance>Breathing. Moaning.  Shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo takes the earphones, listening to the girl's distant chattering.</context>
      <utterance>Cyclo-girl whore from village. Business slow there.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Apparently the guard agrees because he opens the gate and the girl slips inside.</context>
      <utterance>She's making him a pretty good deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brewer pans to the distant shape.</context>
      <utterance>What's that? By the far tower.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a guy in a cage.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>American?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't tell. Pretty tall. He's real scrunched up in that thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me see.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roundeye.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright. Home run.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Torture cage. Can't stand... can't sit... for days. Sometimes weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bastards. Let's get some shots.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That guy's not going to make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Rambo decides in that moment.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing we can do, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm getting him out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You're gonna blow the whole program.</context>
      <utterance>What? Are you crazy? We're supposed to take pictures and split.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You never been in one of those things.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo holds his wrists up, right under Brewer's nose... showing the chafing scars.</context>
      <utterance>I suppose you have...</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's orders! You remember... when they tell you to do something and then you do it. John Wayne is dead, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He can barely form words.</context>
      <utterance>You take pictures and split. I'm going in. Brewer throws down his rifle. He's apoplectic.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then a slow grin spreads.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck it. Fuck it. Aw... ke-rist.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How we gonna do it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PRISONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who're you?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>American. Come to get you out.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRISONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, you are one scary-looking motherfucker!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you walk?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRISONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo quickly picks the lock on the wrist clamps and then slips his LILE KNIFE from its sheath. Starts cutting the lashings on the bamboo cage.</context>
      <utterance>I could a couple of days ago. Gonna be... stiff.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRISONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door gives way and Rambo steadies De Fravio as he slumps forward.</context>
      <utterance>De Fravio. Dave De Fravio. Lieutenant... Air Force.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good to meet you, Dave. I'm Rambo. Okay, I'm going to carry you. Don't cough or make any noise.</utterance>
   <speaker>DE FRAVIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure thing, Rambo. You gettin' the other guys, too?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo slings De Fravio's gaunt six-foot frame over his shoulder in a fireman's carry and heads off in a crouching run.</context>
      <utterance>Not this time. We'll be back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DE FRAVIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys are real... aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>DE FRAVIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, I mean... I talk to people all the time... I know a lot of them aren't there. But this is real, isn't it? You're taking me home now?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>De Fravio sits frozen for a moment, then a dry sob wracks his entire body and he puts his arms around Brewer. He cries with utter abandon, quietly, while Brewer looks at him helplessly.</context>
      <utterance>That's right, buddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DE FRAVIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brewer looks at Rambo with a stricken expression. Then puts his arms clumsily around De Fravio, like somebody holding a baby for the first time. Co touches Rambo's hand. Motions "let's go" with a cock of her head. He nods.</context>
      <utterance>Thank God... thank you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trautman takes the printout.</context>
      <utterance>You're go for extraction. Mr. Kirkhill says wind 'er up. Here's the hardcopy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alternate LZ Zulu Sierra at 0500. It says "May have heat. Don't be late. All our love."</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's get that tent down!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>DE FRAVIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta tell you, it's just luck you guys came when you did. They move us around a lot... We only been at that camp a week. Got a smoke?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>DE FRAVIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of raggedy-ass rescue you call this?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why were you in the box?</utterance>
   <speaker>DE FRAVIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I caught this cobra, see...</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean the snake?</utterance>
   <speaker>DE FRAVIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. It's not hard once you get the hang of it. In the wrist. Anyway, I did what I always do when I get one...</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DE FRAVIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put it in the guard's barracks.  Man they got pissed. They beat the crap out of me, but... it's kind of a tradition. You oughta see 'em run around.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>De Fravio grins, showing bad teeth as well.</context>
      <utterance>You got a bad attitude.</utterance>
   <speaker>DE FRAVIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>De Fravio eyes Co as she hands him a plate of rice and meat.</context>
      <utterance>I know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DE FRAVIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>doing anything this weekend?</context>
      <utterance>Thanks lady. You're pretty cute...</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She exits with the dirty cooking utensils.</context>
      <utterance>Eat slowly. Don't make yourself sick.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An AK-47 muzzle is pressed into his kidney, held by one of Kinh's men. Two more are covering Brewer, who had just handed his rifle to Co, while donning his pack. Kinh steps up, grinning. Takes Rambo's rifle. A fourth guard eases an arm around his neck, a long knife held under his jawline. It has all happened smoothly and with precision planning.</context>
      <utterance>Twenty-five minutes. We'd better roll. Rambo freezes... looks down.</utterance>
   <speaker>KINH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wa-ky number ten. Do-ma.</utterance>
   <speaker>DE FRAVIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kinh backhands him to the deck.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, fuck your mama-san, too. In the...</utterance>
   <speaker>TIGHT ON RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She advances on him. Her black almond-shaped eyes glitter, alien as the depths of space. She spits in his face. Kinh snorts a feral laugh. Rambo doesn't react.</context>
      <utterance>his eyes cold, looking at Co.</utterance>
   <speaker>E.C.U. CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her eyes dart to the side.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DE FRAVIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow!</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes the .45 from her limp fingers.</context>
      <utterance>What just happened? Rambo moves over to Co. She seems to sag, depleted. In shock.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. But I lose many merits in next life. Very bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why'd they want us?</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They heard about escaped prisoner on radio. Make deal. More than we pay.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They sold us out? Now I'm pissed.</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo puts his hands on her shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>They were fools. To think there would be reward. And to ask my help.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rambo. NVA coming. Pig dog Kinh say meet them here. Whole garrison from Con Cuong is out.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo considers for a moment, then pulls away some underbrush beside a collapsed wall of the ruin.</context>
      <utterance>Let's ditch this Transat. We don't need it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brewer gets out his entrenching tool. A cold pre-dawn light suffuses the rain forest, giving it an expectant quality. Rambo scans the ridgeline with Brewer's scope.</context>
      <utterance>Bury it here. Work fast.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You better take off.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't you coming with us, sweet thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to head off along a diverging trail. Rambo touches her shoulder. She turns.</context>
      <utterance>My orders stay here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her grin is ironic.</context>
      <utterance>See you in California.</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo watches her go. A tiny, anonymous peasant girl.</context>
      <utterance>Land of big PX. Maybe I take you for a ride in my Cadillac.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FUHRMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The steep slopes fall away and Doyle dives the ship across the rolling foothills. We HEAR a faint call, barely audible over static.</context>
      <utterance>Three minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zen Hammer this is Slam Dunk One, do you copy? Over.</utterance>
   <speaker>FUHRMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roger, Slam Dunk One... what is your position?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FUHRMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roger... we have you on visual. We are coming in. How many are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three. We got an American POW with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Relay to command. They have one of ours.</utterance>
   <speaker>TELECOM TECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kirkhill's reaction is unexpected. He whips around.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Kirkhill... I have an AWACS relay. Zen Hammer reports the ground team has an American POW with them.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>TELECOM TECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They've got one of ours.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The puzzled techs drop their headsets and leave.</context>
      <utterance>This station is now on Condition Bravo. Harrison. Meyers. Goodell. Out... now!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go to your COMINT priority frequency. Give me the mike... Zen Hammer, this is Coach One. This is an Alpha-Kilo-Victor command priority.</utterance>
   <speaker>FUHRMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roger, Coach One... go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to abort the operation immediately.</utterance>
   <speaker>FUHRMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He presses the helmet-headphone tight to his ear, then turns to Trautman, cupping his hand over the mike.</context>
      <utterance>Say again, Coach One?</utterance>
   <speaker>FUHRMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wants us to abort before pick-up.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Confirm it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FUHRMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doyle looks at both of them and shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>It is confirmed.  Coach One... we have them in sight...  Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turnin' around.</utterance>
   <speaker>FUHRMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you liked those guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do. But they ain't payin' the rent, Jack.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay on your heading, Captain.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Sir. Can't do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's an order.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trautman has his hand on the butt of his .45 when he hears the clack of a rifle bolt over the rotor noise and turns. Lifer has an M-16 in his lap, not exactly aimed at the colonel, but not aimed away, either.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We ain't Uncle Sam's misguided children no more, Colonel. We're independent contractors.</utterance>
   <speaker>FUHRMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kirkhill.</context>
      <utterance>That's right, Sir. We don't like this, but we are working for Mr.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You pathetic scum.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if there weren't POWs before, there are now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hey, Zen Hammer, where are you going? (pause) Do you read, Zen Hammer? Over. Son of a bitch! They're ditching us! The water is shot into spray around them. A mortar shell lands so close it knocks them down, drenching them with slimy black mud. The radio disappears in the water. Rising, Brewer takes a round in the thigh. Drops. Disappears for a second... comes up gasping. Rambo watches the UH-60 diminishing to a black dot. He is so consumed with rage that his expression goes slack... blank... a murderous disconnection from conscience. And yet, in that same moment, a tremendous surge of blind will clears his mind, a determination to survive, to get out at whatever cost... to find whoever did this. It is no longer just a mission. It is a very personal piece of business. He turns and lets his rifle drop into the water. He takes De Fravio's and throws it away.</context>
      <utterance>Where's he going?</utterance>
   <speaker>DE FRAVIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In a ragged line, the NVA soldiers advance to the top of the dike. Twenty. Forty. Finally almost eighty, looking down at the Americans. Rambo slowly raises his hands.</context>
      <utterance>Oh... God. It gets quiet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kirkhill offers a glass to Trautman who ignores it.</context>
      <utterance>Have a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kirkhill sets the glass down and sits at the dinette, motioning Trautman to sit as well.</context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got five hours? I'll tell you about Secretaries of State, and funding committees and diplomatic relations... Trautman slowly sits opposite him, his demeanor becoming more reasonable.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take your time.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Colonel... we're all adults here. This is a war. A very quiet, very intense war. People get sacrificed.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kirkhill freezes, glancing down. The muzzle of Trautman's service .45 is jammed into his groin.</context>
      <utterance>Not my people.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you're right... some people do get sacrificed. Now tell me why you pulled the plug.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I'm some whacko? I like to hurt people? I'm doing a job here. If I knew what's right or wrong I'd be a goddamned priest, right? So I follow directives... I do what I'm told. It's simple. If your boy had done what he was told, there wouldn't be a problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trautman leans on the .45 a bit and Kirkhill backs into the seat cushion.</context>
      <utterance>Don't dance me, Kirkhill. You'll be walking funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, it was a screw-up, alright? They weren't supposed to find anything. We thought that camp was empty.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This mission was a scam from the word go?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kirkhill takes a healthy pull from his scotch.</context>
      <utterance>Word came down... they wanted an answer. And they knew the answer they wanted: no POWs. But it had to look good. Best effort. The whole dog-and-pony show.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rambo and Brewer were selected as write-offs.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was clean. Very clean... Rambo was a decorated Vietnam vet, a former POW himself... if he came out and said "No POWs" the sub-committee would buy it. He gets himself caught he's a private citizen, a whacko, acting on his own. If he gets proof, it gets lost somewhere between here and D.C. Airtight. But no... Rambo's gotta be a hero. Thinks he's starring in his own war movie or something. He put me in a corner. No choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Terminate with extreme prejudice."</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The colonel has let the pistol drop, until it is dangling, forgotten.</context>
      <utterance>That's a crock. We don't say that. Do you have any idea the shitstorm if he'd gotten back with that guy? If it went public? The White House would have to act through channels. We're talking ransom. Four billion bucks in war reparations to Vietnam to get the others back. That's billion, Colonel. With a "B". For a few guys that've had their brains in a blender for ten years? A pain in the ass to everybody? No way. There's no way.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So there never was a Phase Two rescue team?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a long silence, Trautman nods.</context>
      <utterance>Of course not. You can't get approval to rescue a kitten from a tree after Tehran.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kirkhill relaxes. It's going to be okay. The colonel is one of the boys.</context>
      <utterance>I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trautman doesn't take the glass.</context>
      <utterance>Here. Drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand your position.  I understand how a maggot like you can just slide out of a jam on a trail of slime. And call it -- expedience.  Expedience! Kirkhill slams his empty glass down. His tone becomes self-righteous.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're out of your depth, Trautman. Way out. I'm acting correctly here. Not you. Not your gung-ho jungle ace.  It's over. Walk away.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not over. You made one mistake.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trautman clicks the safety and reholsters the .45.</context>
      <utterance>What that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rambo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are they going to torture us?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A GUARD shoves Rambo on ahead as Brewer's carriers stop at the door of an isolation cell.</context>
      <utterance>What... whattaya do?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No talk!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>De Fravio's eyes focus. The merest spark of the old defiant De Fravio glimmers wanly.</context>
      <utterance>We were pulling for you, Dave. We hoped you'd make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DE FRAVIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Next time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OUT OF FRAME.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is a SICKENING THUD against flesh.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIGHT ON RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There are board red welts over both collarbones, oozing blood in places.</context>
      <utterance>grimacing from the blow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PODOVSK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Palyushin hauls Rambo onto a wooden stool against the wall. Podovsk sits next to him on a small metal desk. It is almost dark and the only light is from a single bare bulb.</context>
      <utterance>Put him in the chair.</utterance>
   <speaker>PODOVSK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Podovsk's English is lightly accented but clear and articulate. He has a nasal condition, however. Rambo doesn't answer.</context>
      <utterance>These people are so... vulgar in their approach. I am Lieutenant Commander Podovsk. I do not know who you are. Will you tell me?</utterance>
   <speaker>PODOVSK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Podovsk notices the long criss-crossed scars on Rambo's chest and back.</context>
      <utterance>No? Not even your name?  This is a poor beginning for an intimate relationship. By tomorrow or the next day you will tell me things you would not tell a lover.</utterance>
   <speaker>PODOVSK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see you are no stranger to pain. Then of course you must know how senseless it is to resist in the long run. Is it possible you have been among my Vietnamese comrades before? Podovsk catches something as Rambo breaks his gaze, looking away.</utterance>
   <speaker>PODOVSK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo gazes at a point in space.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. I think that must be it. Where were you held? Hanoi? Son Tay? I apologize. I'm getting ahead. Sometimes I get too eager. My comrade and I, in our capacity as advisors, have been sent from our center at Cam Ranh Bay to discover from you certain things... for example: whether you are working directly for the American government... Who your contacts were... and on and on. Quite a list. Will you tell me these things now?</utterance>
   <speaker>PODOVSK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course you won't. But, as a moral man, I felt compelled to ask. He stands with a shrug of finality and gestures to his massive assistant.</utterance>
   <speaker>PODOVSK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Lieutenant Palyushin. To him you are a piece of meat.  Proceed.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOW ANGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>on Palyushin walking forward.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PODOVSK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Palyushin nods and douses Rambo with a BUCKET OF WATER.</context>
      <utterance>I was sent here because of my command of your language. It will be frustrating if we cannot have a nice chat. Very frustrating.  Ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>PODOVSK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Palyushin, without ceremony, twists the knob. Rambo convulses with an explosive muscle contraction. Slams against the springs. His veins swell as if to burst.</context>
      <utterance>Test please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PODOVSK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He draws a folded piece of paper from his pocket. Opens it.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes. Here is something you might be interested in.</utterance>
   <speaker>PODOVSK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A transcript of the conversation between your helicopter pilot and his commander, intercepted and unscrambled by our overworked cryptography staff.  Mmm. "Zen Hammer... Slam Dunk." Colorful names. Here we are: "Ah, Coach One... we have them in sight." And the reply: "Abort immediately. Return to base camp." He graciously shows Rambo the printout.</utterance>
   <speaker>PODOVSK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He snaps his fingers and Palyushin cranks the knob. The lights dim. Rambo fights the scream unleashed within him with every fiber of his being. Straining like a demon, every muscle sharply defined and rock hard.</context>
      <utterance>It seems they intentionally abandoned you on direct orders. There are the people you protect with your silence? With your pain?</utterance>
   <speaker>PODOVSK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It bursts out, a roar that frays his vocal cords.</context>
      <utterance>But you must scream. You must. There is no shame.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BACK TO SCENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo is going berserk. His body is an out-of-control machine, lashing and tearing at the frame. The scream breaks and becomes a FEROCIOUS HOWL. The Viet guard steps forward, alarmed and unnerved. His rifle is raised, warding off evil. Podovsk motions him back and steps closer himself. The bedframe begins to twist, creaking and warping under Rambo's frenzied assault.</context>
      <utterance>The Lieutenant looks up, puzzled.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIGHT CUTS - RAPID SUCCESSION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Podovsk takes a reflexive step forward. Rambo's hand shoots out, free suddenly, like a grappling hook. Palyushin hits the CURRENT. Rambo jerks Podovsk into a headlock, a death embrace. Podovsk screams. Convulses.</context>
      <utterance>A weld. Springs pop.</utterance>
   <speaker>PODOVSK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Russian lashes about, convulsing in the current. The lieutenant cuts the power. Rambo snatches Podovsk's MAKAROV PISTOL from his holster. Aims it at his temple before Palyushin can reach for his. The Black Beret eases his hand away from his holster.</context>
      <utterance>Nyet! Nyet!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Co is furious at his dawdling.</context>
      <utterance>You are amazing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She spins and sprints away along the trail, disappearing in a moment. Rambo hesitates an instant, then runs the other way.</context>
      <utterance>Di di mau! Go! Go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trautman opens the door and the young corporal in the office beyond turns in his chair.</context>
      <utterance>Bob, hi. Did you get my telex?  Yeah, I know what time it is there... do you know what time it is here? Look, is there anything you can do up the line? You owe me one. I'm calling it in.  Yes, this time.  I know you're a general and I'm only a colonel.  So that's it, huh? Back off. Come home... that's it?  Thanks, buddy. He slams the receiver into its cradle, and sits, pondering. He is about to make a somewhat bizarre decision for a full colonel.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get me a "Loach," I'm going back out to Ban Bung Kla.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORPORAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DE FRAVIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brewer crawls stiffly to the opening, squinting at the glare.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Brewer. You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could use a beer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DE FRAVIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The place went apeshit.</context>
      <utterance>Your buddy made it out last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? How come he didn't take me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DE FRAVIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe because you're shot in the leg.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah. Listen, how long do they keep you in this disease hole?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who knows? I was in there for a month once. De Fravio did three months.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you keep from coming unglued?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Like that.</context>
      <utterance>Concentrate on a problem. Like, I built my dream house in my head, brick by brick. Board by board. If something really takes a day, I thought about it for a whole day.</utterance>
   <speaker>DE FRAVIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I built a shopping mall.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They slide the block into place and Brewer sits in front of it, COUGHING TO HIDE THE SCRAPE as the door is opened by two guards. Morning light blasts in, blinding him, as one guard hauls him roughly to his feet, despite his wounded leg.</context>
      <utterance>Guards. See ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guards guffaw and drag him off.</context>
      <utterance>Watch it. Don't fuck with me, man!  I'm dinky dau!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PODOVSK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you know where he is going. Is there a rendezvous point? Some guerrilla contract? A transmitter perhaps.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The interrogator scowls, briefly perplexed.</context>
      <utterance>No way. If I say anything... that's three.</utterance>
   <speaker>PODOVSK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I cannot be responsible for the safety of the prisoners if he is not captured. This government now considers the existence of POWs an embarrassment. An unmarked grave in the jungle may be their solution. I am only an advisor.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Palyushin explodes with a brutal blow to Brewer's ribs, which doubles him over in agony. He struggles to regain his breath, dragging at the air like a terminal emphysema patient. Brewer slowly raises his head.</context>
      <utterance>Advise my dick, you Siberian scumbag.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ke-rist. Whattaya trying to do, man, tickle me? Palyushin snarls and smashes the truncheon down even harder.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Podovsk catches his assistant's hand before he swings.</context>
      <utterance>This your first day?</utterance>
   <speaker>PODOVSK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think you can provoke us into beating you unconscious? We are not that... unskilled.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Podovsk takes the "fan belt" from Palyushin and smashes it across Brewer's face. Again. Brewer scream hideously. And again.</context>
      <utterance>I've had it with you, ratface. Don't piss me off!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>D-PLUS 58 HRS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The telecom tech turns as Kirkhill enters.</utterance>
   <speaker>TECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kirkhill scans a long PRINTOUT TRANSCRIPT.</context>
      <utterance>More AWACS intercepts. The Russian takes time to translate.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's giving them a run for their money. Says here they've got two Hueys from Danang. I didn't know those dinks had Hueys.</utterance>
   <speaker>TECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Captured.</context>
      <utterance>Half their air force is our stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Typical...</utterance>
   <speaker>TECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, there's something else... a TRANSAT relay. Just came through.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He snatches the sheet from the tech.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>E.C.U. - PRINTOUT SHEET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It reads:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo looks up along the tumbled stone wall. Sitting near the top in shadow, perched on a tree limb, is Co, beaming like a Cheshire cat.</context>
      <utterance>You not so hard to catch, dinky dau Rambo.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ. How'd you get here?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And how'd you sneak up like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carefully. Don't want to get shot by you. Bad karma. Anyway, you need me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think you are... .</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Invulnerable.</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo has to laugh.</context>
      <utterance>In-vul-nerabo. But you get ass kicked without me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Co looks him over carefully. She touches his forehead.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. We're a pretty good team.</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo lets her lead him to the path up the hill.</context>
      <utterance>You look like hell. Wounds infected. Come up to the ruins, I have medical kit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You try get across Laos? Get to Thailand?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What are you gonna do?</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Got some business there.</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go United States. See Nguyen. Maybe teach economics. Buy Cadillac. Watch "Dynasty."</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you going to get there? You can't trust the spooks to pull you out. They'll use you up and throw you away.</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. I go with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Co stops her work and replies very quietly.</context>
      <utterance>I couldn't get you in.</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes you can.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Co's gaze holds his and her Cheshire grin flickers.</context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo realizes she is serious. The silence drags when he realizes how good that sounds to him at this moment. And how small a price that is to repay her.</context>
      <utterance>As wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She seems a bit shocked, then smiles impishly.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Done. You got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Co's hands have been all over him but only now does he become aware of them on his shoulders. She draws her face up to his but Rambo pulls back from the kiss. Co looks puzzled as he slowly disengages from her contact.</context>
      <utterance>You too easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans back against the wall.</context>
      <utterance>You don't feel love, Rambo?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Co...</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She advances on him until her face is close to his, her words finding their mark.</context>
      <utterance>Why you don't feel love? Not allowed?  Dead inside, maybe? You make yourself dead already so they can't kill you? In-vulnerabo? Bullshit!</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She points into the undergrowth nearby, to a ghostly blossom growing there among the tangled vines.</context>
      <utterance>Bucu bullshit!  I have enough death already. Husband. Mother. Father. Brothers. Death everywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo studies her intently. An emotional moment for him. He takes her flawless face in his hands, draws her closer. Suddenly his head snaps around. A distant THUDDING of COPTER ROTORS becomes audible, growing slowly louder. Rambo leaps up, sprinting to a crumbled parapet. Below, in the valley, the two Hueys are slowly scanning, like angry insects.</context>
      <utterance>You see? A flower like that need good soil to grow. Many time under earth is bones of animal... or person. Killed in jungle. Make soil rich. Grows most beautiful flower. You call orchid. Many deaths in jungle. Vietnamese, V.C., American. Many beautiful flowers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's coming in on our open side. They sprint across the courtyard as the minigun ROARS again. The CURTAIN OF DEVASTATION sweeps toward them as they run. They make it behind one of the Buddhas, just as the hail of death passes across it. The rounds blast a layer of weathered stone off the serene face. Behind Rambo the second Huey pops above the trees, firing with a conventional door gun, an M-60. Rambo fires back. Tracers flash around him. He reloads. FIRES. CO CRIES OUT. She is SLAMMED AGAINST THE WALL. The second Huey banks away. Rambo crouches beside Co's crumpled figure.</context>
      <utterance>Minigun. Come on. Let's move.</utterance>
   <speaker>PALYUSHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Return to staging area. We have to reload.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo is rocking her, willing the life to stay in her, his expression anguished.</context>
      <utterance>Dinky-dau-Rambo.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John. My name is John.</utterance>
   <speaker>CO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't hurt. Why doesn't it hurt?</utterance>
   <speaker>PALYUSHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Air Two, circle in a holding pattern.  Air Three, are you in position?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ready, Air Command.</utterance>
   <speaker>PALYUSHIN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The pilot turns to Podovsk.</context>
      <utterance>Begin your run.</utterance>
   <speaker>PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many are down there?</utterance>
   <speaker>PODOVSK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pilot looks at him strangely. The massive assault helicopter noses down and thunders forward across the jungle.</context>
      <utterance>One.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo sobs. Somehow this one tragedy renders all the others pale.</context>
      <utterance>... you're gonna love it there. It'll be great. We can do what we want... you and me... go to the beach... with Nguyen... watch him ridin' his surfboard... Co's eyes are glazed, half-open. She is gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her mouth fiercely. Trying to make her live, to infuse her cooling flesh with some of his vast will.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, God...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The tech rereads the COMINT transcript.</context>
      <utterance>Well, have they got him yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>TECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um... actually, no. It looks like he shot down one of their gunships...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ almighty.</utterance>
   <speaker>TECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... and then he, uh... took the other one.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>TECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kirkhill sinks slowly into a chair.</context>
      <utterance>He... took it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>EMERGES.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is encrusted with dried mud, dried blood, streaked with rivulets of sweat. His eyes burn. Rambo has detached the door gun from its sling and, with the feed belt over one shoulder, carries it like a rifle. He motions with the muzzle. Tay and Vinh flop forward, face to the earth, hands laced behind their heads. Rambo moves past them, eyeing the wreckage of the camp warily.</context>
      <utterance>To Tay, Rambo is Death incarnate.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gawd, you look awful.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You comin'?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you handle the door gun?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tay and Vinh are still face-down and De Fravio covers them with an AK-47, found in the rubble. Smoke swirls in the idling rotor wash as the barracks begins to burn.</context>
      <utterance>Duck soup.</utterance>
   <speaker>DE FRAVIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I dreaming this? This is not real, right?  I oughta grease you pricks, but I've known you too long.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When De Fravio is aboard, crammed in with the others in the main bay, Rambo remounts the M-60 and jumps into the pilot's seat. He brings up the RPMs. The TURBINE WHINE INCREASES. Brewer, crouched behind Rambo, yells forward.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go, De Fravio. Move it!</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind them, diving out of the sun's glare, is Podovsk's massive assault helicopter. Rambo pops the Huey off the ground and runs hard at the treeline. The MIL MI-24 NOSEGUN begins firing and the ground erupts behind the Huey, fountains of earth chasing it as it climbs out. At full climb the laden Huey barely clears the trees and Rambo Immediately banks tight to get out of the nosegun's field of fire. The Soviet chopper tightens its arc, but swings wide, and Rambo spirals back. Brewer swings the door gun and gets off a long burst as the ground reels dizzyingly below and the horizon tilts.</context>
      <utterance>We got company. You better pull some pitch, buddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brewer! You know what that thing's packing?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a Soviet MIL MI-24. Probably has 12.7mm nose cannon, heat-seeking rockets and wire guided missiles, plus...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo noses the Huey down, building speed. Tail high, it shoots across the treetops, its NOSE RADIO ANTENNA ripping through the uppermost foliage.</context>
      <utterance>Forget it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DE FRAVIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I'm gonna be sick.</utterance>
   <speaker>PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're approaching the border. Should we notify the Laotian Air Force?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell. This is just like fucking Star Wars, man!</utterance>
   <speaker>DE FRAVIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brewer grins, realizing. Slaps him on the shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Star Wars?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gonna love it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brewer opens the enormous ammunition canister.</context>
      <utterance>How much we got left in that minigun?</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo is plugged into some insane second sight, knowing the curves before they curve. He flies with absolute concentration.</context>
      <utterance>Pretty low. Couple of seconds worth.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're in Laos, Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>PODOVSK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know that!  Fire all your rockets. Take him down!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TRAUTMAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Lifer turns to see Trautman step around the fuselage of the chopper.</context>
      <utterance>Getting ready to go somewhere?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Colonel. You're not cleared to be on this base anymore.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... and there's this guy with a black helmet and cape, right, and he's got this sword... except it's not a sword, it's light...</utterance>
   <speaker>DE FRAVIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look forward as a broad river appears beyond a ridge- line less than a kilometer ahead. The Thai border. A cheer goes up. A home run.</context>
      <utterance>There's the Mekong.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When the unidentified helicopter has crossed the river into Thailand, shoot it down with air-to-air rockets. Then proceed to the crash site and fire your remaining rockets into the wreckage. Is this understood, Zen Hammer?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, Sir... I'm experiencing a little hearing problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIRKHILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about? Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, uh... I've got something in my ear.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LOW ANGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kirkhill quails as Rambo grasps him by the collar and flings him backward into a chair. He raises the AK. Muzzle to Kirkhill's forehead.</context>
      <utterance>as Rambo walks to Kirkhill, looming. Stopping.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMBO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HOLD ON KIRKHILL, trembling.</context>
      <utterance>Mission accomplished. Pulls the trigger. The weapon CLICKS, EMPTY.</utterance>
   <speaker>BREWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo walks away... alone.</context>
      <utterance>Cover of Time Magazine, baby!</utterance>
   <speaker>DE FRAVIO</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Rambo turns. De Fravio, propped up on one elbow on his stretcher as he is carried past, gives him a broad, appreciative grin.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Rambo!</utterance>
   <speaker>DE FRAVIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rambo stands blinking for a second. He raises his hand in a big "thumbs up" and allows himself to grin.</context>
      <utterance>You did good, buddy. Real good!</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
