<movie id="457" title="Rebel Without A Cause">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The MAN whistles a nervous phrase, trying to make a joke of the situation which he doesn't understand.</context>
      <utterance>That was pretty what you were whistling. Whistle some more.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a cigarette?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The MAN fumbles in his pocket, finds a pack and drops it in his nervousness. The FIGURES wait until he picks it up. He offers one to BUZZ.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I think so--</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Filter tips.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smiling uncertainly, the MAN puts the cigarette in his mouth. BUZZ, still smiling, takes out a packet of wooden matches.</context>
      <utterance>You smoke it. Smoke it, Dad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="56">
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mixed up in that beating on Twelfth Street?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Plain drunkenness.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This says he was picked up there.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Plain drunkenness.</context>
      <utterance>They had him on the carpet for an hour at Headquarters. He's clear.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The officer leads JIM to JUDY's bench and stands him against the wall beside it. JIM is frisked, a look of prayer on his upturned face. The OFFICER finds the toy monkey in his pocket and would take it, but when JIM asks to keep it, the OFFICER hands it back and moves away. Another officer enters and leads the prisoner who is sitting next to JUDY into another room. JIM sits beside her. He smiles at her but receives only a chilling look. He winds the monkey up and sets it dancing on the floor, but she is not amused. Camera pans to show others reacting to the monkey with pleasure. We see PLATO look up and smile a little. Camera stops on the MEXICAN CHILDREN who are smiling too. A bald JUVENILE OFFICER named GENE, squats before them, smiling.</context>
      <utterance>Young squirt. All right--You want to lean him against something? Stand him over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The little boy shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>You going to tell me your name now?</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's your hair?</utterance>
   <speaker>GENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you get a haircut?</utterance>
   <speaker>GENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No--it just fell out!</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>GENE laughs as another Juvenile Officer enters and pauses to look at the children. His name is RAY.</context>
      <utterance>Aw--</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What gang does he belong to?</utterance>
   <speaker>GENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give him a couple of years.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's your mamma, honey?</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RAY and GENE exchange looks, then RAY moves across to JUDY-- camera following. He looks down at her, consults the file in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Judy--we're ready for you now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He hates me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rises. RAY leads her to one of the glass-walled offices. Camera moves with them. JIM watches them go.</context>
      <utterance>He hates me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What makes you think he hates you, Judy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inside small office as JUDY comes in, RAY following. He indicates a chair for her while he sits down behind a desk.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think. I know. He looks at me like I'm the ugliest thing in the world. He doesn't like my friends--he-- RAY leads her into the office.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He makes you feel pretty unhappy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He calls me a dirty tramp--my own father!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think your father means that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes! I don't know! I mean maybe he doesn't mean it but he acts like he does. We're altogether and we're going to celebrate Easter and catch a double bill. Big deal. So I put on my new dress and I came out and he--</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That one?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes--he started yelling for a handkerchief--screaming. He grabbed my face and he rubbed all my lipstick off--he rubbed till I thought I wouldn't have any lips left. And all the time yelling at me--that thing--the thing I told you he called me. Then I ran out of the house.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that why you were wandering around at one o'clock in the morning?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just talking a walk. I tried to call the kids but everybody was out and I couldn't find them. I hate my life. I just hate it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You weren't looking for company, were you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you stop to talk to anyone, Judy?  Do you enjoy that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I don't even know why I do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think you can get back at your Dad that way? I mean sometimes if we can't get as close to somebody as we'd like we have to try making them jealous--so they'll have to pay attention. Did you ever think of that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll never get close to anybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some kids stomped a man on Twelfth Street, Judy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know where they picked me up! Twelfth Street! I wasn't even near there!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like to go home if we can arrange it?  Did you notify the parents?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She wouldn't give me their number.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JUDY looks up hopefully.</context>
      <utterance>What's your number, Judy? We'll see if your Dad will come and get you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Camera moves close on JUDY. She looks up and speaks very quietly.</context>
      <utterance>Unless you really don't want to go home.  Would you rather stay here?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The wail of a siren is heard. JUDY looks off through the glass wall toward JIM. RAY is heard dialing. Med. shot. JIM's bench. JIM sits with his head back, eyes closed. As the siren mounts louder, JIM opens his mouth and imitates it--a long, forlorn wail. Med. shot, PLATO and NEGRO WOMAN. PLATO smiles faintly and moves out toward JIM, NEGRO WOMAN following. Camera pans with them. PLATO sits by JIM. She stands over them. JIM's wailing continues. Med. shot. JIM, PLATO, NEGRO WOMAN. An OFFICER moves into shot.</context>
      <utterance>Lexington 05549.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM continues for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! That's enough static out of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want me to imitate a stupid cop?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cut it out now. I'm warning you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The OFFICER moves out. The NEGRO WOMAN bends over PLATO who is shivering violently.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEGRO WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PLATO shakes his head. JIM notices him.</context>
      <utterance>You shivering, John? You cold?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PLATO looks up at JIM.</context>
      <utterance>Want my jacket?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your mother will be down in a few minutes, Judy--</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your mother will be down in a few minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RAY signals to a WOMAN OFFICER just outside and leads JUDY to the door. Outside door as RAY turns JUDY over to the WOMAN OFFICER.</context>
      <utterance>My mother?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's being called for.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said you'd call my father.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JUDY doesn't answer. RAY goes back inside as camera leads the WOMAN OFFICER and JUDY past JIM's bench. Camera stops on JIM, PLATO and the NEGRO WOMAN. JIM stares at JUDY and whistles but gets no reaction. GENE enters and comes to the</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Judy. Take it easy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="120">
   <speaker>GENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John Crawford?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEGRO WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PLATO rises and goes with GENE, the NEGRO WOMAN following. JIM is alone. He closes his eyes, throws his head back and gives another siren wail as camera moves close on his face.</context>
      <utterance>Come with me, John.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>JIM looks up suddenly, scared. Then he smiles mysteriously and staggers to his feet. Low angle. Tight three. JIM's parents and grandma framed in the doorway, frozen. They are all dressed in evening clothes. The MOTHER is a very chic but rather hard-faced woman. The FATHER is an unfeathered man. The GRANDMA is the smallest, also very chic and very bright-eyed. Med. shot. JIM as he faces them.</context>
      <utterance>Jim!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tight shot. The family.</context>
      <utterance>Happy Easter.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>Where were you tonight? They called us at the club and I got the fright of my life!</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Med. shot. JIM.</context>
      <utterance>Where were you tonight, Jimbo? Close shot. JIM. He says nothing. Close shot. FATHER laughing uncomfortably.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM turns suddenly and walks to the glass wall of the office behind which PLATO, the NEGRO WOMAN and GENE are visible. He looks through the glass partition which separates him from PLATO.</context>
      <utterance>You think I'm funny?</utterance>
   <speaker>GENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know why you shot those puppies, John?  Is that what they call you or do you have a nickname?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Plato.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEGRO WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's going to help you.</context>
      <utterance>You talk to the man nice now, hear?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody can help me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you tell me why you killed the puppies, Plato?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir. I just went next door to look at them like I always do. They were nursing on their mother and I did it. I guess I'm just no good?</utterance>
   <speaker>GENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think's going to happen, you do things like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. End up in the electric chair?</utterance>
   <speaker>GENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did you get the gun?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In my mother's drawer.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEGRO WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She scared without a man in the house.</context>
      <utterance>She keep it to protect herself, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's your mother tonight, Plato?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's away.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEGRO WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seems like she's always going somewhere. She got a sister in Chicago and she go for the holiday. She says her sister is all the family she has.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PLATO is silent.</context>
      <utterance>Where's your father?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEGRO WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They not together, sir. We don't see him in a long time now.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PLATO looks up as JIM and his family move into the next office. JIM smiles at PLATO, who returns it feebly, then looks away--embarrassed.</context>
      <utterance>Do you hear from him, son?</utterance>
   <speaker>GENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know if the boy ever talked to a psychiatrist?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Head-shrinker?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEGRO WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Mrs. Crawford don't believe in them!</utterance>
   <speaker>GENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Other office. JIM, his parents, GRANDMA and RAY are gathered in the small room. JIM is humming THE RIDE OF THE VALKRYIES to himself as if he had absolutely no interest in what is happening around him. RAY suspects this is something more than mere disinterest, so lets the humming go on, in order to discover its real purpose. GRANDMA watches everything like a tennis match, reacting with soft little sounds of terror or astonishment or sympathy. No one pays any attention to her. For a moment no one talks. RAY watches JIM as he hums. Then the FATHER shakes his head and looks up.</context>
      <utterance>Well maybe she better start.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't see what's so bad about taking a little drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I definitely don't. I did the sa--</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a minor, Mr. Stark, and it looks to me like he had more than a little drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, listen--</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM merely rolls his eyes at her, then away--but continues his humming.</context>
      <utterance>Jim--don't hum.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess I cut pretty loose in my day too.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really, Frank? When was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen--can't you wait till we get home?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa! Whoa! I know you're a little upset but--</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM stops humming and shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>What about you, Jim? Got anything to say for yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Not interested, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't you answer? What's the matter with you anyhow?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's just loaded, honey.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was talking to Jim.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me just explain to you--we just moved here, y'understand? The kid has no friends yet and--</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell him why we moved here.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold it, Jim.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't protect me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A car--</context>
      <utterance>You mind if I try? You have to slam the door in my face?  I try to get to him--what happens?  Don't I give you everything you want? A bicycle--you get a bicycle.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You buy me many things. Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence; JIM is fighting his emotion but his eyes grow wet.</context>
      <utterance>Not just buy! You hear all this talk about not lovely your kids enough. We give you love and affection, don't we?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM stares straight ahead, trying not to listen.</context>
      <utterance>Then what is it? I can't even touch you anymore but you pull away. I want to understand you. Why'd you get drunk? You must have had a reason.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was it because we went to that party?  You know what kind of drunken brawls those parties turn into-- it's no place for kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A minute ago you said you didn't care if he drinks.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said a little drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're tearing me apart!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop tearing me apart! You say one thing and he says another and then everybody changes back--</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a fine way to behave!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well you know who he takes after!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RAY pushes him out the door firmly, and into office vacated by PLATO and GENE.</context>
      <utterance>Outside, Jim. Come outside.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse us a minute?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>GENE's office. RAY and JIM alone.</context>
      <utterance>Sure. Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone should put poison in her epsom salts.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer. JIM turns away from RAY.</context>
      <utterance>Grandma?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get lost.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hang loose, boy. I'm warning you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wash up and go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly JIM flings himself at RAY who deftly flips him past and drops him near the desk.</context>
      <utterance>Big tough character. You don't kid me, pal. How come you're not wearing your boots?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's what you want, isn't it?</context>
      <utterance>Too bad you didn't connect. You could have gone to Juvenile Hall.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure it is. You want to bug us till we have to lock you up. Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave me alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know why--!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go on--don't give me that. Someone giving you hard looks?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just get so--  Boy, sometimes the temperature goes way up.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM starts crying.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Okay. Let it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You feel like you want to blow your wheels right now?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All the time! I don't know what gets into me--but I keep looking for trouble and I always--I swear you better lock me up. I'm going to smash somebody--I know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM smashes his fist against it, letting loose for a moment. RAY watches, then sits near him.</context>
      <utterance>Try the desk.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Routine check.</context>
      <utterance>That why you moved from the last town? 'Cause you were in trouble? You can talk about it if you want to--I know about it anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And they think they are protecting my by moving.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Why did you do it?</context>
      <utterance>You were getting a good start in the wrong direction back there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RAY just nods.</context>
      <utterance>Mess that kid up?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He called me chicken.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And your folks didn't understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They never do.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So then you moved?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They think I'll make friends if we move. Just move and everything'll be roses and sunshine.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM is silent; he picks at his nails.</context>
      <utterance>But you don't think that's a solution.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Things pretty tough for you at home?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM stares at his family through hole in door.</context>
      <utterance>She eats him alive and he takes it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a zoo!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A zoo. He always wants to be my pal, you know? But how can I give him anything when he's--I mean I love him and I don't want to hurt him--but I don't know what to do anymore except maybe die.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretty mixed up?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If he could--</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"If he could" what? You mean your father?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean if he had the guts to knock Mom cold once I bet she'd be happy and I bet she'd stop picking. They make mush out of him. Just mush. One thing I know is I never want to be like him.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chicken?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RAY shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>I bet you see right through me, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can anyone grow up in this circus?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got me, Jim--but they do. Want some water?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy--if I had one day when I didn't have to be all confused and ashamed of everything--or I felt I belonged some place.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here. Look, will you do something for me? If the pot starts boiling again, will you come and see me before you get yourself in a jam? Even if you just want to talk--come in and shoot the breeze. It's easier sometimes than talking to your folks.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay--</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any time--day or night. You calmed down enough to go back now?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RAY's office as JIM comes towards his MOTHER and forces himself to kiss her.</context>
      <utterance>You serious? RAY smiles and opens the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rises and takes his arm. They start out through the door into the hall, followed by GRANDMA and FATHER.</context>
      <utterance>All right, darling.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This was all very unfortunate, but he made a mistake and he's sorry-- so we're not going to have any more trouble. He's always been a lovely boy--</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lovely! Grandma--if you tell another lie you're going to turn to stone.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luck, Jim. Don't forget.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have some cigars.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No thanks, I don't smoke.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go on--Give 'em to your friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No--thanks, very much, Mr. Stark.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM grins at RAY who nods. They all leave. RAY looking after them, shakes his head and lights a cigarette. We see JIM and his family pass through the main door. Waiting to enter, in the custody of some uniformed police, are BUZZ and the kids we saw at the opening, sullen and truculent. As they march into the lobby and JIM grows smaller in the distance, the music comes up and out.</context>
      <utterance>Frank--he doesn't want any.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="63">
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy, who is her brother, BEAU, looks up but doesn't move. JUDY stops at her gate. A car careens down the alley, past him. Long shot. JUDY and BEAU seen through a window in JIM's house. JIM is in f.g. looking out through the curtains. He smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Beau!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you trying to do, get yourself killed?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>JIM turns from window and passes camera. Full shot JIM's dining room. The MOTHER is just settling a plate of eggs at JIM's place. They FATHER is seated, drinking coffee and looking at the newspaper. GRANDMA comes in from kitchen. JIM is neatly dressed in tie, tweed jacket and slacks.</context>
      <utterance>Your eggs are on the table, dear.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sit down and eat--you'll be late.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'd stick in my throat, Mom. I'm nervous or something--</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a wonder we don't all have TB or some other terrible disease after living in all those smokey cities!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, drink your milk anyhow.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There aren't so many factories here.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mother--</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You make any sandwiches?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My first day of school, mother'd make me eat and by golly I could never even swallow till recess--</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM makes a mouth-stuck-together-with-peanut-butter sound.</context>
      <utterance>There's nothing to be nervous about. Here's peanut butter and meat loaf--</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did I tell you? Peanut butter!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, there's a thermos of orange juice and some apple-sauce cake in the wax paper to wash it down.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I baked that!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Bye, Mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, dear.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So long, young fella. Knock 'em dead, like your old man used to!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure--  You know something? I have a feeling we're going to stay here.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Full shot. JIM's backyard as JIM comes out of the kitchen door into the early sunshine.</context>
      <utterance>And listen--watch out about the pals you choose--Know what I mean? Don't let them choose you-- But JIM is on his way out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>JIM blinks, pauses and sees JUDY. He takes off his tie and puts it in his pocket. Then he starts across the backyard, camera panning with him to: Full shot. The Alley with JIM coming out his gate, JUDY and BEAU visible beyond. He stops again.</context>
      <utterance>Come out of the alley, Beau! This is the last time I'm going to call you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts down the alley. BEAU skips after her and starts tightrope-walking the gutter gravel.</context>
      <utterance>Beau! All right--go to school alone!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JUDY glances at him briefly, but continues. JIM follows a few yards, but on his side of the alley.</context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. I saw you before.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bully for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to be unfriendly.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now that's true!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Life is crushing in on me."</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Life can be beautiful." Hey, I know where it was.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where what was.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where I saw you.  Everything going okay now?  You live around here?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who lives?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, I'm new.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Won't mother be proud.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JUDY looks up a little surprised.</context>
      <utterance>You're really flipped--aren't you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Dawson High School?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You going there?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah--why--</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dig the square wardrobe!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. So where's the high school?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An auto horn, stuck, in the distance.</context>
      <utterance>University and 10th--Want to carry my books?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The horn approaches, loud.</context>
      <utterance>I was just getting my car. I could take you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The kids take me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another angle. JIM and JUDY as the car, horn blowing, wheels into view above them and comes careening into the alley. JUDY sees it and moves a step away from JIM.</context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll bet you're a real yo yo.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodbye! See you!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JUDY comes to them quickly, smiling.</context>
      <utterance>Stella-a-a-a!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Steady Marlon!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JUDY and BUZZ kiss ardently and without love. JIM goes for his car.</context>
      <utterance>Wanna make the colored lights go around and around?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A new disease.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Friend of yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm glad they let you out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody chickened.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard about it. You're lucky he lived.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>During this JIM has gotten his car and has driven up.</context>
      <utterance>They always live.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's University and 10th?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That way!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That way!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simultaneously, the kids laugh wildly. The radio blares. JUDy lays her head on BUZZ's shoulder and his arm goes around her as the car zooms away. JIM looks after them a moment, then follows.</context>
      <utterance>That way!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm just starting here.</context>
      <utterance>Hi--can you tell we where I go?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONITOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Bassett's office--203. He'll tell you where your home room is--</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angle shot. Corridor. Shooting past a row of steel lockers. The clash and slam of doors as kids throw in coats, pull out books and primp for the day ahead. PLATO comes to his locker, which is the nearest, and opens it. Full shot. Corridor. JIM moves toward us from the distance. Crowded at the entrance to a classroom in f.g. are JUDY and her pals. They are sneaking a smoke, passing the cigarette from one cupped hand to another. As JIM comes near, JUDY sees him. So do the others. They fold their arms across their chests and whistle "We are the girls of the institute"--all but JUDY. JIM glances at her and continues on past camera. A bell starts ringing crazily over the music. Close shot. PLATO. He is straightening his tie in the mirror. Above it, pasted to the locker door, is a still of Alan Ladd. In the mirror we can see JIM moving past. PLATO sees him too. He wheels around and stares.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks a lot. JIM moves out.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The strident music of the students diminishes. The ringing of the bell stops. There remain only JIM's footsteps. Long shot. JIM moving off down the corridor. PLATO is in f.g. looking after him. He slams his locker and starts after JIM, moving at the same speed and hovering near the wall. The footsteps of the two boys echo stonily. They are alone. JIM stops at a bulletin board near a bend in the corridor. PLATO stops too. Bulletin board. JIM looking at the notices. PLATO drifts in several yards away and hangs near the wall watching JIM who doesn't see him. JIM reads: Insert: Bulletin board, "Attention All Juniors and Seniors"-- Planetarium field trip--2 pm--Sharp!" Another angle. JIM and PLATO as JIM turns from bulletin board and starts away.</context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi there.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You remember me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I don't think so--</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM starts toward camera as PLATO after another look, turns in the opposite direction and walks away from us, smashing his fist against the wall as he goes. JIM stops, full in camera. His face clouds, trying to remember. He turns full around to look after PLATO, then turns back and continues on his way. The footsteps fade.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry--I made a mistake.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="118">
   <speaker>LECTURER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>JIM looks around for a seat and passes down aisle. Seen beyond him is the projector, moving slowly, its great dumb- bell head sparkling with pin-points of light. JIM takes a seat in front row. PLATO, in the row behind him, moves over a seat to be nearer. They exchange looks. Full shot. Normal students watching intently.</context>
      <utterance>For many days before the end of our earth people will look into the night sky and notice a star, increasingly bright and increasingly near.</utterance>
   <speaker>LECTURER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Low angle. LECTURER. A dry, elderly man in a stiff white collar. He is seated at a desk, the light from the reading lamp spilling upward onto his face.</context>
      <utterance>As this star approaches us, the weather will change. The great polar fields of the north and south will rot and divide, and the seas will turn warmer.</utterance>
   <speaker>LECTURER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angle shot. Students. Some watching, some taking notes. An OLD LADY TEACHER in f.g. taps the heads of two kids in the row before her. They stop their whispering. She smiles at them.</context>
      <utterance>The last of us search the heavens and stand amazed. For the stars will still be there, moving through their ancient rhythms.</utterance>
   <speaker>LECTURER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Med. shot. PLATO staring upward.</context>
      <utterance>The familiar constellations that illuminate our night will seem as they have always seemed, eternal, unchanged and little moved by the shortness of time between our planet's birth and its demise.</utterance>
   <speaker>LECTURER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Med. shot. JIM (from PLATO's angle). JIM is seated in the row ahead of PLATO. His lips are parted as he looks up.</context>
      <utterance>Orion, the Hunter. PLATO looks off.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Once you been up there, you know you been some place!</utterance>
   <speaker>LECTURER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Two shot. JUDY and BUZZ. BUZZ has his arm around her. He is nuzzling her ear. She is blandly watching the dome.</context>
      <utterance>Gemini, the Twins.</utterance>
   <speaker>LECTURER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>BUZZ pokes JUDY who looks at him. He curves his wrist toward her, opening and closing his first two fingers like the pincers of a crab.</context>
      <utterance>Cancer, the Crab.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Med. shot. JIM (PLATO behind). Seen from JUDY's angle. JIM turns at the sound of the laughter, and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a crab! She laughs. So do the others.</utterance>
   <speaker>LECTURER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Taurus, the Bull.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angle shot. JUDY, BUZZ and group (seen from JIM's angle). He is in f.g. They are staring at him. Nobody laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Moo! He waits for approval.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUNCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, moo.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Moo. That's real cute. Moo.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, he's real rough--</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUNCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bet he fights with cows.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They turn from him. JIM withers and looks front. JUDY smiles a little and looks away so the others cannot notice her amusement.</context>
      <utterance>Moo.</utterance>
   <speaker>LECTURER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>PLATO leans in and touches JIM's shoulder, lightly at first, then harder. JIM turns to him.</context>
      <utterance>Sagittarius and Aries--all as they have ever been.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shouldn't monkey with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a wheel. So's she. It's hard to make friends with them.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns back, unhappy at having revealed himself. Another shot. JUDY, BUZZ, CRUNCH. JIM seen in b.g. The kids are whispering among themselves and pointing at JIM, who looks up and notices. He is getting uncomfortable.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to make friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>LECTURER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Full shot. The dome. The star rushes nearer, looming larger and larger. The music rises in tension and volume.</context>
      <utterance>And while the flash of our beginning has not yet traveled the light years into distance--</utterance>
   <speaker>LECTURER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Two shot. JIM and PLATO staring upward, cringing back into their seats as the light on their faces increases. Music is up loud. Full shot. The dome seen past PLATO's head. The heavens grow brighter as the star plummets near. Music at crescendo.</context>
      <utterance>Has not yet been seen by planets deep within the other galaxies, we will disappear into the blackness of the space from which we came.</utterance>
   <speaker>LECTURER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The sky is blasted by a wild flash of light. Music reaches explosion. The stars appear again. Moving shot. Faces of normal kids watching seriously--very impressed.</context>
      <utterance>Destroyed as we began in a burst of gas and fire.</utterance>
   <speaker>LECTURER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Med. shot. JIM and PLATO looking up.</context>
      <utterance>The heavens are still and cold once more. In all the complexity of our universe and the galaxies beyond, the Earth will not be missed.</utterance>
   <speaker>LECTURER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>PLATO ducks his head down on the back of JIM's chair. JIM looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Through the infinite reaches of space, the problems of Man seem trivial and naive indeed. And Man, existing alone, seems to be an episode of little consequences.</utterance>
   <speaker>LECTURER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The lights go on. The rustle and confusion of kids stretching after sitting too long. Scattered applause. JIM rises and ruffles PLATO's hair.</context>
      <utterance>That's all. Thank you very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PLATO looks up at him.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, it's over. The world ended.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Med. shot. LECTURER as he reaches over and turns a dial. "Morning Song" by Grieg comes on softly. Low angle. OLD LADY TEACHER rising. She stares around at the bustling students and claps her hands sharply, but the noise is barely heard above the tumult.</context>
      <utterance>What does he know about Man alone?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Full shot. Parking lot. Bus in f.g. Beyond it JUDY and the group are visible. PLATO squeezes out.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me. Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE TEACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John, where you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PLATO moves quickly past the teacher who climbs in. The door slams, the bus moves away. PLATO stops and looks after it. The last cars are clearing the lot. Only JIM's and BUZZ's remain. PLATO looks at the small, waiting group. Med. shot. The group seen from the rear. PLATO in the distance facing them.</context>
      <utterance>I forgot something. I'll get a hitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Med. shot. PLATO wild-eyed with fear.</context>
      <utterance>What you looking at?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs off, camera panning with him. His goal is the Planetarium Entrance, visible beyond. He races toward it frantically. Med. shot. The group looking off after PLATO. BUZZ, nearest camera, pulls a switch-knife from his pocket and pops the long blade open. JUDY stares at it, then looks up at BUZZ apprehensively. CRUNCH sits down on the bumper and lights a cigarette. Display lobby. Planetarium as PLATO rushes in, out of breath, stops and looks around. In distance he sees JIM leaning over the pendulum pit, smoking quietly. PLATO doesn't move. JIM hasn't even looked up.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your name!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim. What's yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM nods. PLATO goes over to him, camera following, until they are close together, both leaning over the rail.</context>
      <utterance>Plato. It's a nickname.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, I told you not to fool with them. Now they're waiting for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. That's why I came back.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You scared?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just don't want trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He has a knife.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw it. Gee, look at that thing swing, will you? Do you think it never stops?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. It's perpetual motion.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PLATO walks cautiously to the door and starts outside, camera following. Long shot. Kids (corner of Observatory) with PLATO leaning out of door, seeing them, pulling back quickly. Inside display lobby as PLATO pulls back through the door. JIM seems to have disappeared. PLATO stares around frightened.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I bet some little guy comes in here at night and pushes it. Go- go-go!</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM is looking at another exhibit whose mechanical voice is heard.</context>
      <utterance>Jim?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM nods. They watch the exhibit a while longer.</context>
      <utterance>They're still there!</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim--Do you think when the end of the world comes it'll be at night?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PLATO looks up questioning. JIM smiles and shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>No. In the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start moving, camera leading.</context>
      <utterance>I just have a feeling.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you don't want trouble, I know a place we can go-- JIM looks up at him.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doors to balcony (from inside) as JIM and PLATO come to them from behind camera, fling the doors open and step outside. Balcony as JIM and PLATO come onto it, lean on the parapet. PLATO points off.</context>
      <utterance>It's a big mansion and we could sneak around there and they wouldn't even know. You could be safe-- They turn a corner quickly.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>High long shot. Mansion. (Matte). It is falling into elegant ruin, casting long afternoon shadows on the great lawns and promenades. Closeup PLATO looking urgently at JIM.</context>
      <utterance>There it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two shot. JIM and PLATO. PLATO's back is to us. JIM looks past him and sees something.</context>
      <utterance>Should we go?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know something?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You watch too much television. Med. shot. The group and JIM. JUDY has come to BUZZ, stands on the wall above him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, he's real abstract and different.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly GOON starts clucking softly like a chicken. One by one the others pick it up. BUZZ, the last, crows. Silence. Med. shot. The group and JIM.</context>
      <utterance>I'm cute, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meaning me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The group gives a quick, short laugh. Med. shot. JIM as he takes off his glasses, smiles. Shakes his head disapprovingly.</context>
      <utterance>Chicken?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Close shot. PLATO watching anxiously. Med. shot. BUZZ with JUDY watching above him. JIM enters shot until he is close to BUZZ's face. He looks up at JUDY. Camera closes in until we are tight on the three. The heads are nearly touching.</context>
      <utterance>You shouldn't call me that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought only punks fought with knives.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's fighting? This is the test, man. It's a crazy game.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Close-up. CRUNCH. He is smiling. His arms are around the shoulders of the kids who flank him.</context>
      <utterance>Les jeux de courage!</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUNCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Med. shot. Group.</context>
      <utterance>Machismo. Machismo.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Machismo?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Close shot. PLATO seen between heads of MIL and COOKIE. COOKIE holds up a switch knife and tosses it over into the circle.</context>
      <utterance>Somebody find him a knife.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Full shot. Circle as the knife falls at JIM's feet. JIM stoops and picks up his weapon, then faces BUZZ. Then he springs his blade.</context>
      <utterance>Jim!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BUZZ hops from the parapet. They begin stalking each other. BUZZ slides his knife from hand to hand trying to hypnotize JIM. Suddenly he pokes out and pricks JIM's shirt. The group sighs "Ole!" JIM makes no effort at self-defense. Silence. BUZZ pricks JIM again, "Ole!"</context>
      <utterance>You know the action? No cutting. Just sticking--jab real cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM cuts out half-heartedly.</context>
      <utterance>What you waiting on, Toreador? I thought you wanted some action!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hah!</context>
      <utterance>Big brave bull. Hah! Toro! Hah!</utterance>
   <speaker>GOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Moo!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What's happening? Let's go!</context>
      <utterance>Come on--Fascinate us. Impress us.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BUZZ viciously slaps JIM across the face. JIM lashes out and misses. BUZZ hops back.</context>
      <utterance>You crud chicken! You're wasting our time!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Outside entrance of parking lot. A uniformed GUIDE of middle-age stares past camera. Cries of "Ole," are heard in the distance.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah--that's pretty close. How about a little closer, Toreador? Cut off a button and you get to join the club!</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look. There's your audience.</utterance>
   <speaker>LECTURER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inside circle. JIM is covered with sweat and about to drop. He is getting the worst of it, still refusing to defend himself. Close shot. PLATO. He is looking on in despair.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I don't think so. From the school?</utterance>
   <speaker>GROUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, with a cry, PLATO pushes through. Inside circle as PLATO comes through. His eyes are wild. He holds a tire chain in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Ole! Ole!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buzzy! Look out! He's got a chain!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BUZZ trips PLATO quickly and kicks him while he's down. CRUNCH grabs the chain.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Chicken Little!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly JIM transforms. He bores forward expertly--pricks BUZZ again and again. Cries of Ole greet him. BUZZ is surprised. Full shot. Group. We hear only the breathing of the combatants. Beyond we see the GUIDE approaching swiftly. The LECTURER trails at a safe distance. Closeup. CRUNCH. He looks up. His smile fades.</context>
      <utterance>All right--you want it, you got it!</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUNCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Group as they look off and see the GUIDE and LECTURER approach. BUZZ and JIM are both breathing hard. PLATO is getting to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>Honk. Let's split.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He folds up his knife and puts it away. So does JIM.</context>
      <utterance>Split for what? Couple old poopheads?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You satisfied or you want more?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How 'bout you? Say the word and you're cold, Jack--you're dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buzzie--we better get out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's eating you, Judy? You want him alive?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where can we meet?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Know the Millertown bluff?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The bluff, Buzz! That's dangerous up there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Draw him a picture, Chicken Little. Eight o'clock. Cookie, you call Moose and get a couple cars. We're going to have us some real kicks. Little chickie-run. You been on chickie-runs before?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The GUIDE bursts in among them. The LECTURER remains on the fringe.</context>
      <utterance>Sure--that's all I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right--all of you--start moving!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean l'il ol' us? What's the matter with the nice man?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't clown with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why'nt you go suck on something sweet?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think you're tough? I got a son twice your size and I can still handle him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LECTURER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't lose control, Mr. Jamison. I think if we just explain--</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Explain to these? They think they own the world!</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUNCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The world is round!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The world is flat!</utterance>
   <speaker>COOKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is wild laughter from the kids as they close around the GUIDE and start edging him away, up the steps toward the Planetarium balcony.</context>
      <utterance>All the world's a stage!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are gone. The LECTURER looks after them then comes to JIM. JIM looks down at his shirt. There are spots of blood. PLATO opens it, spits on a handkerchief and starts to wipe the blood away.</context>
      <utterance>The world goes round the sun! Goodbye proud world! I got the world on a string! The world's my oyster! Hey! A fish-eater! Brain food.</utterance>
   <speaker>LECTURER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes the world is too much with us, isn't it, son? What was the disturbance?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>LECTURER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're bleeding. Are you all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LECTURER hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>I scratched my mosquito bites. I'm fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LECTURER goes. JIM impatiently closes his shirt.</context>
      <utterance>I'm fine--thanks!</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you really going to meet them?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who knows. Plato?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's a chickie-run?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="72">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The figure straightens and turns around, smiling. It is the FATHER. He is neatly dressed in his business suit but wears a Mary Petty apron.</context>
      <utterance>Mom?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM leans against the wall, shaking his head and trying not to laugh. The FATHER laughs unhappily, trying to make it all seem a joke.</context>
      <utterance>Hiya, Jimbo.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You thought I was Mom?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah!</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just this get-up. The girl's out and I was bringing Mom's supper.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you dropped it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah! Shh!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's funny!</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts dabbing among the spilled dishes with a wet cloth. JIM watches him.</context>
      <utterance>I better clean this up before she sees it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The FATHER continues dabbing.</context>
      <utterance>Let her see. What could happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad-- The FATHER looks up at him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM touches his FATHER's elbow, bringing him to his feet. They look at each other a moment then JIM goes to his bedroom. The FATHER goes back to mopping up the mess. Inside JIM's room as he comes in, shuts the door and throws himself miserably on his bed. He writhes as if the pain he feels were physical. Outside, radios are heard in the night--tuned to different stations. He feels under his jacket and holds up his hand to the moonlight. There is blood on it. He reaches up and takes his alarm clock and is setting it as camera glides to his window and holds over the rooftops. Full shot. JUDY's backyard. Moonlight. JUDY stands near camera looking up at the moon. The radios seem louder out here. One breaks through.</context>
      <utterance>Dad--don't. Don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Time now for the seven o'clock news. Friends, the next time you go shopping.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Long shot. The FATHER standing erect on back porch, silhouetted against a window.</context>
      <utterance>Judy. She wheels around.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Med. shot. JUDY. She hasn't moved.</context>
      <utterance>What are you wishing for, Judy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JUDY comes forward, stands below him on the step. Her look is adoring.</context>
      <utterance>"Man in the Moon, how came you there-- Up in the sky where you are shining-- Floating so high in the frosty air--? Oh, say--Man in the Moon!"--</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They had schools in those days.</context>
      <utterance>We used to sing it in school.  Don't look at me with such horror.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But the same song. I think it's fantastic!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were romantic then too--</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you and Mom home tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing, only it'd be nice to spend an evening together for a change.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With us old creeps? Come on, we have to eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Daddy-- He looks at her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good evening.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns away and goes into the house. She hesitates and then follows. Something in the moods has changed. He has neglected to hold the door for her. Dining room. JUDY's house as the FATHER comes to the head of the table and takes his seat. Three places are set. JUDY follows. She stands above his chair, looking down at him as he drinks his tomato juice.</context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't you forget something?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JUDY doesn't answer, but leans down and kisses him quickly on the lips.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JUDY freezes, frightened. He collects himself a little.</context>
      <utterance>What's the matter with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're too old for that kind of stuff, kiddo. I thought you stopped doing that long ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The mother enters briskly from another part of the house--an attractive, brittle woman of thirty-five.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't want to stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY'S MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't want to stop what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was talking to Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't kiss her so it's a big thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY'S MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JUDY slides into her chair reluctantly and unfolds her napkin.</context>
      <utterance>Bertha! You can serve the souffle!  Fish souffle.  You don't have to stand there, darling. Drink your tomato juice.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess I just don't understand anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm tired, Judy. I'd like to change the subject.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to, that's all. Girls your age don't do that. You need an explanation?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She half-rises to kiss him again.</context>
      <utterance>Girls don't love their father? Since when? Since I got to be sixteen?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly the FATHER slaps her. Even as he does it he is as stunned as JUDY. The mother stops eating. She has never seen such a display and is shocked. He tries to control himself by buttering a piece of bread. There is a terrible silence into which BEAU enters in his pajamas. He runs to his FATHER's chair, then halts--looking from face to face. The FATHER puts an arm around him, hugs him almost savagely.</context>
      <utterance>Stop it now! Sit down!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, rascal.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JUDY rises, weeping.</context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts out. The FATHER rises and follows after her.</context>
      <utterance>May I please be excused?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY'S MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She'll outgrow it, dear. It's just the age.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door slams.</context>
      <utterance>The atomic age!</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You awake?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen--I took a steak out of the freezer. I thought we could have a real old-fashioned stag party--just the two of us, what do you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The FATHER turns away.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey--I want to ask you something.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shoot, Jimbo.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Suppose you knew that you had to do something very dangerous--where you have to prove something you need to know--a question of honor. Would you do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there some kind of trick answer?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What would you do, Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't do anything hasty. Let's get a little light on the subject. The FATHER turns on the light and looks at JIM who is now sitting on the edge of the bed. He removes his jacket and the bloody shirt is revealed. The FATHER stares.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd that happen! What kind of trouble you in?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Can you answer me now?</context>
      <utterance>The kind we've been talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen--nobody should make a snap decision--This isn't something you just--we ought to consider all the pros and cons--</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't have time.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes out, to the study next door. JIM rises.</context>
      <utterance>We'll make time. Where's some paper. We'll make a list and if we're still stuck then we ought to get some advice--</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can you do when you have to be a man?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, now--</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just give me a direct answer!  You going to stop me from going, Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know I never stop you from anything. Believe me--you're at a wonderful age. In ten years you'll look back on this and wish you were a kid again.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten years? Now, Dad--I need an answer now!</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>During this, JIM has kicked off his shoes and put on his boots and jacket and goes out. Living room featuring stairs. JIM comes running down the stairs and out the kitchen door.</context>
      <utterance>I just want to show you how foolish you are. When you're older you'll laugh at yourself for thinking this is so important--</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The FATHER comes down the stairs, goes to the front door and calls:</context>
      <utterance>Jim? Will you listen? You can't go out till we--Jim!</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes to kitchen door, calls again, gets no answer, comes back into the living room, sees he is still wearing the apron. He rips it off and throws it down--then starts for the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Jim? Jim!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="58">
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PLATO stops.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Chicken-Little.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Toreador? He beg off?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not scared of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?  Goon! You seen that adolescent type anywheres?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He won't show.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you going to wait all night? I'm getting nervous, man! We got to do something!</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUNCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Buzz!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BUZZ snaps on the spotlight again and swings it off. Full shot. JIM's car as JIM gets out and PLATO runs to him.</context>
      <utterance>Over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd you get here?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hitched.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, I bet you'd go to a hanging.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Should I leave?</context>
      <utterance>My personality's showing again.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BUZZ enters.</context>
      <utterance>No. It's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM gets out; PLATO starts to follow.</context>
      <utterance>Come on. Let's see what we're driving.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two boys move away. PLATO looks after them, hurt, then goes to side of JUDY and stands. Dolly shot. JIM and BUZZ as they come forward.</context>
      <utterance>Stay there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you say your name was?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim Stark.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buzz Gundersen.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They shake hands briefly as they walk. They come to MOOSE and stop.</context>
      <utterance>Glad to meet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got some goodies for you, Buzzie-boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MOOSE produces one and hands it to BUZZ who goes to one of the guarded cars, motioning JIM to come, too. Closer shot. BUZZ, JIM and MOOSE seen as hood is raised, revealing their faces beneath it. BUZZ explores the motor with the flashlight.</context>
      <utterance>Flashlight?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clean as a whistle. They both got plenty breeze.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look good to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. It's fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He closes the hood. Group moves across to other car. JUDY and PLATO. The other kids are behind them. JUDY looks to see that their attention isn't on her, then speaks quietly to PLATO.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he your friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. My best friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he like?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I don't know. You have to get to know him. He doesn't say much but when he does you know he means it. He's sincere.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's the main thing--don't you think so?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe next summer he's going to take me hunting with him--and fishing. I want him to teach me how and I bet he won't get mad if I goof. His name's Jim. It's really James but he likes Jim more.  People he really likes--he lets call him "Jamie."</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want to finish my hamburger? I only took a bite.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Full shot. Guarded cars. JIM is close in f.g. at wheel of his car. BUZZ is beyond, at wheel of his. Both boys are gunning their engines, listening critically. JIM lets his idle. JUDY, GOON and group. They watch in silent anticipation. PLATO starts away from them. Traveling shot. PLATO hurrying away from the group. He stops, looking off. JIM and BUZZ. PLATO in distance.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM opens his door.</context>
      <utterance>Better try the doors. Jump out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM shuts his door and tries again. So does BUZZ. Then both boys walk forward to the edge. Neither says a word. BUZZ puts his hand on JIM's shoulder. High angle. The edge of the bluff (process). JIM and BUZZ are directly below us. Under them the plateau falls steeply away in a sheer drop of a hundred feet to the ocean below. Two shot. JIM and BUZZ. JIM is staring below. He is beginning to perspire. He lights a cigarette. Without taking his hand from JIM's shoulder, BUZZ borrows the cigarette from his lips, takes a drag and hands it back. JIM takes another puff then tosses it into the abyss.</context>
      <utterance>No--quick, man! You got to break quick.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the edge, boy. This is the end.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like you, you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buzz? What are we doing this for?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Feel okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She bends out of sight for a moment as BUZZ goes on talking, then hands him the dirt. He rubs it into his palms.</context>
      <utterance>Give me some dirt.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JUDY and BUZZ kiss, without much interest.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Toreador! She signals. We head for the edge. The first guy who jumps--chicken!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's happening?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts out, without kissing him again.</context>
      <utterance>Good luck, Buzz.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Med. shot. JIM's car as JUDY comes to him.</context>
      <utterance>Judy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him a moment then bends and hands him some dirt. Their heads touch for an instant.</context>
      <utterance>Me too.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She breaks the look and hurries away. Long shot. The cars. They are lined up in two rows-- headlights facing each other. JUDY comes into shot. When she gets near camera, she stops and turns back to face them.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly the headlights of all the cars come on full. Reverse shot. JUDY. She is in the center of the glare. Behind her we see the other kids filing out of their cars, hurrying toward the edge of the bluff. The sound of the two motors revving then dying and revving again. Inside JIM's car. JIM grips the wheel firmly, relaxes his hands to rub his palms together and crack his knuckles. He grips the wheel again. Steps on the accelerator, winding his engine into a roar. He lets up, looks tensely at-- BUZZ in his car. His chin juts forward. He lets go of the wheel, starts to comb his hair. Slow pan shot. Spectators staring off at the cars. A boy has his arm around the girl in front of him, his cheek against hers. Both are looking off. Some of the kids smoke. All are involved in the blasting of engines. PLATO among the spectators near edge of the bluff. He is chewing his lip. Camera pans down to show that the fingers of both his hands are tightly crossed. Close shot. JUDY staring tensely into the glare. Suddenly she raises her hands high above her head. Close shot. JIM sweating it out. He leans forward, squinting, ready. Close shot. BUZZ. He puts his comb between his teeth and clamps it hard. He settles himself for the run. Long shot. Plateau. The cars are in close, seen from the rear. JUDY is a small distant figure, arms stretched high. The exhaust blasts. Now she drops her arms. The cars leap ahead. Med. shot. JUDY. She whirls to see the cars snap by, then begins running up the center of the plateau between the lines of spectators. Full shot. Spectators. Shooting over their shoulders as the cars approach and scream past. Pit shot. Cars. As they approach, gaining speed, and thunder over the camera. Inside JIM's car. (Process). He is tense. Inside BUZZ's car. (Process). His hands hard on the wheel. The comb is still between his teeth. He begins edging toward the door on his left. Moving close shot. JUDY biting hard on her finger, as she runs forward. Close shot. PLATO. Both hands cover his mouth. The fingers are still crossed. Inside JIM's car. (Process). As he edges to his left. He is driving with one hand. He opens the door, gets set for his jump. Inside BUZZ's car. (Process). He reaches for the door handle and misses. As he raises his arm to reach again, the strap of his windbreaker sleeve slips over the handle. He looks down in panic, then back at the drop ahead. He tugs but cannot get the sleeve loose. Closeup. PLATO staring. He shuts his eyes tight and keeps them shut. Shooting at backs of the two cars as they race through the row of lights toward the edge. Inside JIM's car. (Process). His face is soaked. He looks once toward BUZZ--then ahead. His eyes widen in fear. He shoves left and flings himself forward, and out. Outside JIM's car as he sprawls forward--into camera. Inside BUZZ's car. (Process). BUZZ leans way forward now. He seems to rise in his seat. His mouth opens and the comb falls out. Full shot spectators staring in disbelief. Suddenly a youth ducks his face into the neck of his girlfriend so he cannot see. At the same instant--</context>
      <utterance>Hit your lights!</utterance>
   <speaker>CROWD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rear view. Edge of the bluff as the two cars go over. There is NO human sound. Close shot. JIM as he stops rolling. BUZZ's car in flight. (Special effects). The car soars through the night, the vehicle of a terrible journey. Med. shot. BUZZ. (Process). Surprise has gone. He rides lightly on the thrill of his last moment--then suddenly, his face twists in a spasm of protest and loss. The kids staring at his flight. JIM unaware of the disaster--glad he made it. Low angle. Edge of the bluff. With headlights blazing, both cars dive down. Med. shot. JUDY standing frozen as the spectators shove past and around her. Wide angle. Edge of the bluff as spectators swarm to it, stand looking down. JIM on hands and knees, trying to rise. Legs rush by him, knock him onto his face. Long shot. (Special effects). Both cars plunge into the ocean below. JIM at edge of bluff. He is pushing through spectators.</context>
      <utterance>Oh!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PLATO working his way through the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Where's Buzz! Where's Buzz!</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CRUNCH. CRUNCH looks up as he hears JIM's repeated cry. JIM enters behind him, continuing blindly on his way.</context>
      <utterance>Jim! Jim!</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM doesn't move. PLATO grabs his arm and yanks.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Jim! We got to get out of here!</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM stands. PLATO pushes him.</context>
      <utterance>Get up! Get up! Come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start away, PLATO still pushing from behind. Med. shot. JUDY. She is standing alone in the wind on the emptying plateau. JIM and PLATO move past in the distance. JIM sees her and stops. Close shot. JUDY. She is shuddering violently but there are no tears. She seems not to see or hear or be aware of anything around her. Full shot. JIM and PLATO watching JUDY. JIM moves toward her, camera panning with him and leaving PLATO behind. JIM stands before JUDY until she notices him. He shakes his head for all the sorrow he feels, but no words come. Tentatively he offers her his hand. After a moment, she takes it. She knows only that help is being offered and that she will accept it with trust. JIM leads her away toward the car.</context>
      <utterance>Go on! Move!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets out and starts away, leaving door open.</context>
      <utterance>This is fine--</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PLATO looks at him. JUDY hesitates. JIM raises a hand to her in a shy farewell. She smiles vaguely, then hurries away from them. Near JIM's backyard (alley). JIM and PLATO.</context>
      <utterance>Judy. Will you be okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got to go in. You better get home too.  Hey--what?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you come home with me? I mean nobody's home at my house--and I'm not tired, are you? I don't have many--people I can talk to.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who has?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you want to come we could talk and then in the morning we could have breakfast like my dad used to--  Gee...if you could only have been my father...we could...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You better take off...</context>
      <utterance>Hey...you flipped--or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>O.K. G'night. I got to pick up my scooter. See you tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PLATO turns, walks up the alley to the street. JIM goes into his kitchen door. Hallway. JUDY's house. Three doors open onto it: one is closed--this is JUDY's room:--another, leading into BEAU's room is open, but the room beyond is dark: the third, also open, reveals the bedroom of JUDY's parents. As JUDY comes into the hallway, the parents, who are reading in their beds, look up. JUDY hesitates, then starts toward her own room.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAU</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>JUDY stops. BEAU appears at his door in white pajamas, a small ghost. JUDY looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, little cute sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, darling, baby-pie, glamor- puss, sweetie-- JUDY touches BEAU's head and tries to smile.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM as he completes his turn, pulling his head up and sitting. FATHER as he pretends to awaken with a start. Full shot, room as the MOTHER hurries to JIM, holds him, inspects him, kisses him.</context>
      <utterance>He's home! You're home! You're all right! The camera rights itself suddenly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened, darling. We were so worried. I was going to take a sleeping pill, but I wouldn't till I knew you were home.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to talk to someone, Mom. I have to talk to you both. And Dad this time you got to give me an answer.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm in terrible trouble.--You know that big high bluff near Miller- town Junction?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure--there was a bad accident there. They showed the pictures on</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="50">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't matter how. I was driving a stolen car--</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you enjoy doing this to me or what--</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom--I'm not--</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you wanted him to make a list!</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you let him tell it!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She never wants to hear. She doesn't care!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess when I nearly died giving birth to you--that shows how much I don't care!</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just relax, please relax!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you Dad, it was a question of honor. They called me chicken-- you know, chicken! I had to go or I would never have been able to face any of those kids again. So I got in one of these cars and a boy called Buzz got in the other. We had to drive fast and jump before the cars went over the edge of the bluff. I got out okay but Buzz didn't. He was killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good Lord!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't keep it to myself anymore--</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, just get it off your chest, son.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not what I mean. I've never done anything right. I've been going around with my head in a sling for years...I don't want to drag you into this but I can't help it. I don't think I can prove anything by going around pretending I'm tough any more, so maybe you look like one thing but you still feel like another.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're absolutely right!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you listening to me? You're involved in this! I want to go to the police and tell them I was mixed up in this thing tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did anyone see you there? I mean did they get your license number or anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so--</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well--</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the other boys--Do you think they'll go to the police?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that got to do with it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why should you be the only one.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look Jim. Far be it from me to tell you what to do, but there's--</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you going to preach now? Are we going to have a sermon?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just explaining what you mean! You can't be an idealist all your life! Nobody thanks you for sticking your neck out!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Except yourself!</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you wait a minute?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't want me to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! I don't want you to go to the police! There were other people and why should you be the only one involved!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I am involved! We're all involved, Mom! A boy was killed! I don't see how we can get out of that by pretending it didn't happen!</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know you did wrong. That's the main thing, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! It's nothing! Just nothing! You always told me to tell the truth. You think you can just turn that off?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not saying that! He's saying don't volunteer!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just tell a little white lie?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll learn as you get a little older, Jim.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to learn that!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it doesn't matter anyhow-- because we're moving.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! You're not tearing me loose any more.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I have to spell it out?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not going to use me as an excuse again, Mom. Every time you can't face yourself you want to move and you say it's because of me or the neighborhood or some other phony excuse. Now I want to do one thing right and I'm not letting you run away.  Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son--this is all happening so fast--</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You better give me something, Dad. You better give me something  Mom?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jimmy, you're very young--and a foolish decision now could wreck your whole life.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The FATHER is mute, helpless... Suddenly JIM screams.</context>
      <utterance>Dad--answer her--aren't you going to stand up for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaps at his FATHER, dragging him to his feet, hands at the man's throat.</context>
      <utterance>Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly JIM loosens his hands and rises. He looks swiftly at each of them--moves a few steps toward the door, looks back at them again--then rushes out of the house. The parents stand frozen.</context>
      <utterance>Stop it! You'll kill him! Jim! Do you want to kill your father?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>MOOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let go of me--</utterance>
   <speaker>MOOSE'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM starts forward up the steps. CRUNCH grabs him.</context>
      <utterance>You want a good crack in the mouth?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUNCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They move down the steps as JIM breaks away and continues up. He goes through the doors. Inside doors as JIM comes through and stops. He looks back through the glass. We see the group reach the curb where their cars are parked. There is a brief discussion which we cannot hear, then CRUNCH and MOOSE move off to MOOSE's car. JIM turns back. He looks worried as he passes camera. Med. shot. CRUNCH and MOOSE. They stop at MOOSE's car and look back at the entrance. The parents are seen beyond them, getting into their cars. CRUNCH is near tears with anger.</context>
      <utterance>This place appeal to you or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUNCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he going to pull--</utterance>
   <speaker>MOOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing, Crunch. They picked him up like the rest of--</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUNCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see any cops?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOOSE'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You monsters start home. We're going to--</utterance>
   <speaker>MOOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOOSE'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're following you so better get there.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUNCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see any cops?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No--</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUNCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nobody arrested him!</context>
      <utterance>He's going to cheese, I tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I should go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUNCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. We're going to bring him down.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crunch--my father's--You going to kill him?</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>W-O-J-T-what?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOODLUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>O-W-I-C-Z. Wojtowicz. What's the matter, man? That's the craziest name in town! It swings!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me--but--You know where I can find--I mean I don't remember his last name--</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look--can't you see I'm writing?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOODLUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, this cat never stops. He just keeps going like Big Jay at a session!</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOODLUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's writing a book about me--</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I could write about you they wouldn't print.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think his first name's Ray--I have to see him. It's very important.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the charge?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Assault with a deadly weapon.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen--</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not here. He's not at Juvenile Hall. I don't know where he is. He's out on a call and he'll be out all night. How old are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My parents know I'm out. They know I'm here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come back tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll wait for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM turns away, notices a phone on the wall--puts in a coin, asks for a number. Bedroom of JUDY's parents. Through an open door we hear a radio playing-- a late disc-jockey show for teenagers in which numbers are dedicated by request. JUDY'S MOTHER and FATHER are in bed, FATHER has phone in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you come back tomorrow, son?  Ever been booked before?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up phone, looks at his wife. She rolls over in bed. The FATHER turns off the bed lamp, then sits up, worried in the dark. JUDY's bedroom. It is her radio we have heard. She turns off light, opens the door a crack, and looks out toward her parent's room.</context>
      <utterance>Who wants her? Who? Jim who? Never heard of you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want!</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUNCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what we want. We want your friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got eyes for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cops are cruising every--</context>
      <utterance>Listen, you guys ought to go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PLATO reaches up swiftly and rings the bell. GOON grabs him. CRUNCH cracks him.</context>
      <utterance>Where does he live?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUNCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You better tell us and I'm not kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My old man's got a gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door opens and the NEGRO WOMAN is there. CRUNCH sends PLATO spinning into the house past her. He falls.</context>
      <utterance>His old man's got a gun. What do you think of that!  Your friend talked--  Now you talk! Talk!</utterance>
   <speaker>NEGRO WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She swings at CRUNCH who faces her, challenging.</context>
      <utterance>What you doing! What you doing to him! You clear out of here 'fore I call the police!</utterance>
   <speaker>NEGRO WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clear out. Go on! Go on now!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They turn and move past camera. PLATO gets up off the floor. We hear the sound of a heap starting. The NEGRO WOMAN closes the door. Inside PLATO's foyer as NEGRO WOMAN bolts the door.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go, Crunch.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEGRO WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why you like to mix with bad boys like that? Why you get in trouble all the--</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts up the stairs. She follows him heavily.</context>
      <utterance>I have to go out. I have to warn him.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEGRO WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>staying home while your mama's away. Bedroom of PLATO's mother, a lacy affair with imported dolls on the pillows. PLATO rushes in, opens the drawer of the night-table and pulls out a gun. He checks to see that it is loaded. The NEGRO WOMAN appears in the door and stares at him, turns on the light which illuminates the bed-lamp.</context>
      <utterance>You not going anywhere! You</utterance>
   <speaker>NEGRO WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But PLATO moves past her and out of the room. She turns after him.</context>
      <utterance>John! What you doing with that! You leave that be! Put it down before you hurt yourself. Hear me?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEGRO WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The slam of a door is heard below.</context>
      <utterance>John! You stay home! John! John!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="41">
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another angle.</context>
      <utterance>Coming up now another request--this time from the boys down at Anna's Pizza Paradise--A new arrangement of a great oldie in rhythm and blues. Jim, this is dedicated to you--from Buzz. JIM stares at the radio, then turns it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll be looking for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They saw where I jumped! I didn't chicken! What do I have to do-- kill myself?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't matter to them.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were looking for me, weren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No--I was just--maybe--</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tried to call you before.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought so.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JUDY comes forward.</context>
      <utterance>Want some milk?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes her head. He takes a sip.</context>
      <utterance>That's all I can do when I'm nervous. Drink milk. Here--have a slug.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You still pretty upset?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is shuddering a little.</context>
      <utterance>I'm numb.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You cold?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I guess just about everybody's cold.</context>
      <utterance>Even if I'm near a fire, I'm cold.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I swear, sometimes, you just want to hold onto somebody! Judy, what am I going to do? I can't go home again.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Neither can I.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No? Why not?  You know something? Sometimes I figure I'll never live to see my next birthday. Isn't that dumb?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They laugh a little.</context>
      <utterance>Every day I look in the mirror and say, "What? You still here?" Man!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JUDY shakes her head--beginning to warm to him.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! You smiled!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like even today. I woke up this morning, you know? And the sun was shining and everything was nice. Then the first thing that happens is I see you and I thought this is going to be one terrific day so you better live it up, boy, 'cause tomorrow maybe you'll be nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry I treated you mean today. You shouldn't believe what I say when I'm with the kids. Nobody acts sincere.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You don't have to prove anything.</context>
      <utterance>Why'd you get mixed up with them?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you knew me you wouldn't say that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think you trust anybody, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm getting that way, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you ever gone with anyone who--</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. Lots of times.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So have I. But I've never been in love. Isn't that awful?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks up. He kisses her forehead.</context>
      <utterance>Awful? No. It's just lonely. It's the loneliest time.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did you do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I felt like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JUDY rises.</context>
      <utterance>Your lips are soft when you kiss.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, but we can't stay here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where can we go? I can't go back into that zoo.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm never going back.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JUDY hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>Listen! I know a place! PLATO showed me before. An old deserted mansion near the planetarium  Would you go with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can trust me, Judy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start out.</context>
      <utterance>I feel as if I'm walking under water.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank? I'm frightened.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that pounding?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. First I thought it was Jim but--</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's home. I heard the car.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you going down there?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pounding ceases.</context>
      <utterance>Look--just relax, will you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See? It stopped.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes out of the bathroom, into the hall. Foyer. JIM's house as the FATHER comes down the stairs, turning on the light as he comes. He reaches the door and pauses. The MOTHER stops midway down the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>I still think you should go down.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's there?  Anyone there?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The FATHER opens the door and looks up sharply. Close shot. Door. FATHER's head in f.g. as he stares at it. Nailed to the door by its outstretched wings, its head hanging in an attitude of crucifixion, is the freshly killed carcass of a chicken. Low whistles are heard from outside. The FATHER, frightened, looks out into the night. Full shot. Front lawn and street. Shooting over the FATHER's head. The whistling continues.</context>
      <utterance>Open it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's out there?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's your son?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly the FATHER slams the door and rushes past us into the house. Full shot. Foyer as the FATHER rushes to the bottom of the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Where's your baby boy gone to, Daddy? We want him.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The MOTHER disappears.</context>
      <utterance>Look in his room!</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The FATHER dashes into the living room, then into the hall again and down through the kitchen door. Back yard as the FATHER comes out. He closes the door quietly and calls in a low voice:</context>
      <utterance>Jim! Jim!</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares around the yard, then hurries to the garage. JIM's car is missing. He looks up suddenly. Reverse shot. JUDY'S FATHER seen across the alley wall. He is standing in his own back yard.</context>
      <utterance>Son?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Med. shot. JIM'S FATHER. He smiles feebly.</context>
      <utterance>Is anything wrong? I'm your neighbor.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM'S FATHER closes his garage door and walks back toward his house.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no, thanks. I just wanted to-- to be sure my garage was closed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he there?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts for the house again after a quick look in the direction of JUDY'S FATHER. Full shot. JUDY's back yard. JUDY'S FATHER watches MR. STARK disappear, then...</context>
      <utterance>No, honey. No, he's not here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The alley by JIM's house. PLATO drives up on scooter. He checks the garage, sees JIM's car is gone, is about to take off in confusion, hears door slam in JIM's back yard, shuts off engine, fixes tie, combs hair, goes in the fence gate to JIM's back yard. Full shot. JIM's back yard. JIM'S FATHER is coming toward him. JIM'S FATHER and PLATO simultaneously say:</context>
      <utterance>Judy?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Jim?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Do you--do you know where he is?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Closeup. PLATO remembers about the mansion--then almost to himself:</context>
      <utterance>No. No, I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know where-- Back to full shot. FATHER and PLATO.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs to scooter.</context>
      <utterance>Hope I didn't bother you. Goodnight.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, come back here. Who are you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="41">
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's that!</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's me!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd you find me? What's happening?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're looking for you!--</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody! Crunch and Goon and everybody! I think they're going to kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We know.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They think you told the police on them. They--who's in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Judy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM gives PLATO a hand over the windowsill. Inside arcade. JIM and JUDY are seen in an entering shaft of moonlight. PLATO hits the floor and disappears into darkness.</context>
      <utterance>Help me in!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey where'd you go?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm here. Shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come out come out wherever you are!</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up. Are you nuts?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A match flares and lights a candle on an antique Spanish candelabra. PLATO is revealed bending over it. He lights the other candles through the following:</context>
      <utterance>No. I'm scared.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're safe here. I hope.  What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His wonderment is justified. The floor of the arcade is marble and there are marble benches and neo-Roman busts lining the walls.</context>
      <utterance>Wow! Well now-there-then!</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't it crazy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wowee ow wow! Let's take it for the summer.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jim!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No--come on. Should we rent or are we in a buying mood, dear?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You decide, darling. Remember our budget.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't give it a thought. Only three million dollars a month!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, we can manage that! I'll scrimp and save and work my fingers to the bone...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't we just rent it for the season?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see, we've just--oh, you tell him, darling. I'm so embarrassed I could die!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well--we're newlyweds.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's just one thing. What about--</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Children? Well, we really don't encourage them. They're so noisy and troublesome, don't you agree?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. And so terribly annoying when they cry. I just don't know what to do when they cry, do you dear?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course. Drown them like puppies.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, we're very modern.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shall I show you the nursery? It's far away from the rest of the house. If you have children--Oh I hate the word!--or if you decide to adopt one--they can carry on and you'll never even notice. In fact, if you lock them in you never have to see them again, much less talk to them.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Talk to them! Heavens!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody talks to children! They just tell them one thing and mean another.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's wonderful that you understand so well--and so young too! You know the most wonderful feature about the nursery?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's only one key.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll take it!</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PLATO leads them away from us down the arcade, the candelabra casting wild shadows on the walls. They are laughing as they disappear through the glass doors at the end and their laughter echoes stonily.</context>
      <utterance>Come on!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MOOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What time is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUNCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hang loose. We got all night.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That maid saw us. She could identify us too.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUNCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You still want to go home, Moose?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUNCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then shut your mouth before your guts run out!</utterance>
   <speaker>GOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What guts?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM falls in. PLATO rushes to him.</context>
      <utterance>Quick! Fill the pool!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's see how long we can stay under.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, you're schizoid!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm what? What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't talk underwater!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bet you hear everything I say!</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't he schizoid?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They laugh again. JIM swings up the ladder and goes to JUDY. PLATO follows.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! How 'bout that!</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Haven't you noticed your personality splitting?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all sit on the blanket.</context>
      <utterance>Not lately.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know so much about this junk, Plato?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM lies back with his head in JUDY's lap. She strokes his hair and smiles at him. PLATO looks away.</context>
      <utterance>I had to go to a head-shrinker. I only went twice though. My mother said it cost too much, so she went to Hawaii instead.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PLATO hesitates a moment, then leans back, cuddling between the two of them.</context>
      <utterance>No. Seriously. What's your trouble?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM puts his arm under PLATO's chin.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know but whatever it is, it's gone now. I mean I'm happy now. Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I came here before.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I was here? When I ran away. I used to run away a lot but they always took me back.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom and Dad. I used to be in my crib and I'd listen to them fight.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You remember that far back? Boy, I can't even remember yesterday.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Plato, where's your father now?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's dead. He was a hero in the China Sea.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You told me he's a big wheel in New York!</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did? Well, he might as well be dead. What's the difference?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PLATO closes his eyes. JUDY hums a lullaby as she strokes JIM's lips with a finger. He snaps at it. Then he kisses her hand, looks at her palm. They whisper.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes his palm and examines it.</context>
      <utterance>You have a long life-line.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses it, holds her cheek against it.</context>
      <utterance>So have you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ever been in a place like this before?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not exactly. It's certainly huge.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many rooms do you think there are?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at PLATO. JIM shrugs--tests to see if the boy is awake, but there is no reaction. Carefully, they crawl to their feet. JIM supporting PLATO's head with his hands as they do so. JIM takes the other blanket and covers PLATO with it. JUDY kneels on the other side and tucks it in. They look at each other across him and smile. Then suddenly JUDY bends down and kisses PLATO's cheek very softly. JUDY and JIM rise. JIM takes a candle from the candelabra and leads JUDY along the edge of the pool to the glass doors beyond. Silence except for their footfalls on the flagstone. In the distance we see the doors open and the couple pass through. When they close again, a sob comes from PLATO. High angle closeup. PLATO lying as they left him, but his eyes are open and he is crying. Camera booms up as PLATO throws off the blanket and looks after them. Camera booms higher until he is revealed as a small and lonely figure sitting by himself. The pool echoes his weeping.</context>
      <utterance>Should we explore?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="154">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She comes forward. JIM drips wax on the table-top and sticks the candle on it. His hand shakes. JUDY sits on the couch.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Will you look at this room!  Judy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want to read any books? Take your pick!  Isn't this the craziest?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes her hand. She looks at him and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your hand's all wet and it's shaky.  You're so funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know--you just are. Leaving a light for Plato. That was nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe he's scared of the dark.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM snuffs out the candle. They are left in moonlight. A pause.</context>
      <utterance>Are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here we are-- out of cigarettes-- Junior's in the nurs'ry-- See how late it gets--</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't need to do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's something I should tell you, Judy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know already. We don't have to pretend now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans back, relaxed at last. She snuggles close to him.</context>
      <utterance>What a relief!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this what it's like to love somebody?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You disappointed?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Funny Jimmy. You're so clean and you--this is silly.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You smell like baby powder.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So do you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never felt so clean before.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not for you and not for me.</context>
      <utterance>It's not going to be lonely, Judy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love somebody. All the time I've been looking for someone to love me and now--I love somebody. And it's so easy. Why is it easy now?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is for me too.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses his lips gently and looks into his face. He returns the kiss. Their arms go around each other.</context>
      <utterance>I love you, Jim. I really mean it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Full shot. Road near Planetarium. MOOSE's heap crawls up and turns left. A moment later, the police car appears and does likewise--still holding its distance. Full shot. The mansion as MOOSE's heap moves past on the road below. Suddenly it stops. Inside MOOSE's heap. CRUNCH looks off, curious.</context>
      <utterance>I mean it too. He kisses her again--</utterance>
   <speaker>GOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you stopping for?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUNCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You scam a car up there?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUNCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He switches on the spotlight. It illuminates JIM's heap.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody's lived in that hunk of junk for five-six years.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUNCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns off all the lights and gets out. The others follow. Med. shot. Police car. It has halted. One of the officers gets out and draws his gun. The other makes radio contact in a low voice:</context>
      <utterance>Well, what do you know! I feel a kick coming on!</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Unit 17. Unit 17.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come in, Unit 17.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Close shot. PLATO asleep on the blanket. Only a single candle burns in the candelabra. The same low whistles heard earlier come from all around him and rise in volume. Suddenly his eyes open. He doesn't move, but he has come suddenly awake. Low shot. PLATO lying in f.g. Next to his face are a pair of booted feet. He looks up. Camera pans up to show CRUNCH. He is smiling. He holds a tire chain in his hand which he swings.</context>
      <utterance>We just zeroed three kids in a heap. Crest Drive and Observatory. Looks like house-breaking. Send us some help. They may be armed. Over.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUNCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Full shot. The swimming pool. GOON and MOOSE are behind CRUNCH. They too are armed with tire chains. They all laugh. PLATO rolls away from them and runs toward the deep end of the pool.</context>
      <utterance>Good morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUNCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys run to their assigned places. PLATO sees no exit. He flings himself down the ladder and into the pool. He feints this way and that, the boys responding as if they were fencing. CRUNCH swings down the ladder and his boots make a loud report as they hit the pool. MOOSE advances down the steps at the shallow end. GOON climbs onto the pool bottom at the opposite side. The feinting continues, wordlessly, as the circle closes around PLATO. The only sounds are the stamping of their boots as they try to distract him from side to side, and the animalistic grunts they make to scare him. Suddenly PLATO sees an opening and plunges past MOOSE, pushing him over, and stumbles up the steps.</context>
      <utterance>Moose! Take the steps! Goon! The other side.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUNCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stream out of the pool after PLATO. He reaches the glass doors first, streaks though, and bangs them shut behind him. Traveling shot. Arcade. PLATO's face is visible only when the moonlight strikes him through the passing windows. The sound of running steps behind him. Full shot. Main room. A pattern of moonlight on the bare floor as PLATO dashes in and through it. He falls over a piece of furniture and comes scurrying in to camera, wheels around on hands and knees to face the door. The boys plunge into the moonlit square and stop. PLATO tries not to breathe. A match is struck. CRUNCH looks around, but can see nothing. That match goes out. The boys start up the stairs, whispering. Immediately, PLATO crawls forward, under the piano. He hears a murmur of voices from behind the oak door of the library--next to the piano. He moves to it stealthily. Close shot, PLATO at door listening through it, on hands and knees. His confusion mounts. He shakes his head to clear it. Then, suddenly he rises and tries the knob. The door is locked. He beats on it.</context>
      <utterance>Come on! Let's make it!</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys run across the room. As they hit the moonlit square. PLATO spins and fires. Somebody drops and starts moaning. JIM opens the door.</context>
      <utterance>Save me!</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you run out on me for! What you leave me alone for?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a rush of boys coming forward.</context>
      <utterance>Plato!</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want you for my father!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PLATO fires at JIM. JIM leaps at PLATO with a cry and knocks him down.</context>
      <utterance>Your father!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You crazy nut! You crazy, crazy nut!</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rolls away from JIM and runs to the main door.</context>
      <utterance>Get away from me!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Main door, from inside. PLATO falls upon it, fumbles with the bolt and swings the door wide. He steps out into the waning moonlight and we see him running down the lawn. JIM rushes into the doorway and stops short. Full shot. Mansion. The OFFICERS are moving away from us toward it. PLATO runs wildly toward them.</context>
      <utterance>Jim!</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PLATO stops, confused.</context>
      <utterance>Halt!</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM runs out on the promenade and starts over the balustrade.</context>
      <utterance>Come here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Close shot. PLATO. His face is working desperately in growing panic.</context>
      <utterance>Plato!</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come here, son.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Plato!</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Close shot. JIM as he screams.</context>
      <utterance>Just walk over here quietly now-- and there won't be any trouble. PLATO runs out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Full shot. Main doorway as JUDY rushes out, followed by GOON and MOOSE. They all stop dead at the balustrade.</context>
      <utterance>Plato!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reverse shot. Lawn. JIM seen in f.g. PLATO bolting toward the woods in the direction of the planetarium. The officers have both hit the ground in the distance. They fire again. JIM hesitates a moment, then rushes after PLATO. The officers fire again. Moving shot. JIM as he runs after PLATO. Med. shot. OFFICERS as they rise to their feet.</context>
      <utterance>Jim! Watch out!</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Full shot. Front of mansion. JUDY flies down the stairs and rushes past camera.</context>
      <utterance>Take the house! I'll head him off.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Prowl car. Another part of town (Process). RAY is driving. JIM's father is beside him. The mother is in the back seat.</context>
      <utterance>Halt! Halt!</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--located at Summit Drive--the Planetarium.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The planetarium? One kid inside-- five housebreaking in area. Will proceed.  There are some kids in trouble-- you'll have to go with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edge of woods as JIM hurtles in from the open ground beyond. He stumbles against a tree and sinks down.</context>
      <utterance>Perfectly all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Traveling shot in the woods as PLATO rushes through the moonlit trees, sobbing.</context>
      <utterance>Plato!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Med. shot. JIM at the base of a tree. He is whimpering, shaking his head. JUDY crashes through the brush and drops beside him.</context>
      <utterance>Plato!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is on the verge of hysteria.</context>
      <utterance>Did he hit you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to go back!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to rise.</context>
      <utterance>No! I got to find him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After he tried to shoot you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He didn't mean it--we shouldn't have left him. He needed us.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a sound of distant gunfire. Both kids freeze.</context>
      <utterance>He needed you, maybe. So do I.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JUDY, breaking into a run, follows after him through the brush.</context>
      <utterance>He needs you too. Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should have heard him talk about you tonight. Like you were the hero in the China Seas.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. He was trying to make us his family.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM runs ahead blindly and disappears in the trees. JUDY rushes after him a few steps, then stops. JUDY and JIM running. PLATO running. The planetarium. Moonlight. Shooting from the bridle path and panning to the building. PLATO reels in and goes to the front door. Med. shot. Door to planetarium. PLATO clutches the handle. The door is locked. He whimpers once in frustration. Med. shot. Policeman running up same path PLATO has followed. PLATO at door to planetarium. He smashes the glass with his gun and dives through. Inside planetarium as PLATO lands. He is cut and bleeding.</context>
      <utterance>They're killing him!</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>PLATO wheels and skitters backward across the floor of the observatory on his hands and knees until he comes to the door of the planetarium theater. Reverse shot. Main entrance. Seen from inside. The OFFICER in b.g., PLATO in f.g. The OFFICER appears in the entrance, then moves quickly to one side to be less of a target. He reaches in to unlatch the door.</context>
      <utterance>Come out of there.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PLATO fires at him, then opens the door of the planetarium theater and runs inside. The door swings shut behind him. Outside planetarium. The OFFICER is hugging the outside wall. Another siren wails and a spotlight catches the OFFICER who runs out into the light.</context>
      <utterance>You're making it tough on yourself, kid. Come out quietly now. You didn't kill anybody yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Full shot. Parking lot as the CHIEF's car wheels to a stop. It is followed by a civilian car and a cab. CHIEF's car.</context>
      <utterance>Need a little help here!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You alone?</context>
      <utterance>We heard firing. He get anybody?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got a cookaboo inside. He wounded some kid earlier.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd he get in?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smashed the front door.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any other entrance?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Med. shot. Bushes bordering planetarium as JIM climbs through them and stops short, staring in amazement. JUDY is in b.g. Full shot. Parking lot. JIM seen in f.g. hiding in the screen of leaves. Beyond we see the full activity--the crowd, the cars, searchlights playing on the planetarium entrance, police moving in under direction of the CHIEF.</context>
      <utterance>Down in back.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEGRO WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, lady. Some kid's in trouble. Stand back, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEGRO WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Med. shot. CHIEF's car as RAY hurries in.</context>
      <utterance>I got to know. My boy run off tonight. He had a gun with him, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Ray--Know anything about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As much as you do--Loan me your mike, will you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Help yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am addressing the boy in the planetarium. I am speaking to the boy inside. This is Ray Framek from the Juvenile Division-- Close-up JIM as he reacts to RAY's name. He rises and looks off.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are now surrounded. You are surrounded by many armed police. Whoever you are, drop your weapon and come outside. Med. shot. JIM'S FATHER standing by RAY's car, gazing off with interest. His wife comes out and stands beside him, looks at him questioningly.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The FATHER's gaze has traveled over the scene. Suddenly he sees his son followed by JUDY, run into the planetarium.</context>
      <utterance>Come outside. Clasp your hands over your head and come outside quietly--</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank!</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay here.  That was my son!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The FATHER moves behind the crowd, camera trucking with him, until he reaches the bushes at the edge of the parking lot and stops, gathering himself. Meanwhile RAY's voice continues over:</context>
      <utterance>I think I know my son.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The FATHER starts forward along the bushes as if stalking game. Each step is carefully placed and quiet, but his heart tugs him along like a kite dragging an anchor.</context>
      <utterance>Jim Stark! I'm addressing Jim Stark. Nobody will harm you or your friends if you follow these instructions. We are here to protect you. Drop your guns and come outside. Nobody will hurt you if you do as I say--</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inside planetarium as JIM comes dashing in, spins around, staring. JUDY follows. A siren is heard outside growing shrill.</context>
      <utterance>Officers! Another boy and girl just ran into the planetarium. We do not know if they are armed. Hold your positions until further instruction.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Floodlights strike the door and illuminate the lobby dimly.</context>
      <utterance>Ambulance. Ambulance is coming through. Clear a passage. Will you people make way there?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. JIM moves cautiously to the door of the planetarium theater. JUDY hangs back. Another siren is heard approaching. More floodlights strike the door.</context>
      <utterance>Plato?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inside theater. Darkness except for the splash of light from the door where JIM stands in silhouette. He lets the door close. Blackness.</context>
      <utterance>Plato? Plato, you in there?  Hey, I'm going to open the door now. You'll be able to see me and you can shoot me if you want, but just remember one thing, Plato--You're my friend. That means a lot to me. JIM opens the door slowly.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Plato?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, I'm blind as a bat! You got a match? I'm going to break my neck in here. Where are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got a gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PLATO obeys.</context>
      <utterance>I know. Light a match, will you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's swell. How are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another siren is heard outside. JIM has reached the lecturer's desk and, just as the match goes out, he throws a switch. The stars appear on the dome and the projector starts its slow revolution.</context>
      <utterance>I'm fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think the end of the world will come at nighttime, Jim?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. At dawn.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just have a feeling. Where are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM waits. Nothing happens.</context>
      <utterance>Well, stop hiding and stand up. I can't talk to you if I don't see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Plato rises from behind a row, then JIM continues:</context>
      <utterance>Hey, look at the stars, Plato. Stand up and look at the stars.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM approaches slowly.</context>
      <utterance>That's fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not going to hurt you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did you run out on me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We didn't run out. We were coming right back.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A siren is heard.</context>
      <utterance>Sure I'm sure. Judy's waiting. You ready to come out now?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM takes off his jacket and holds it out to PLATO.</context>
      <utterance>I promise nothing'll happen if you do.  You want my jacket? It's warm.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I keep it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM gives him the jacket--PLATO puts it on.</context>
      <utterance>What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to give me your gun now, Plato?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My gun?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In your pocket. Give it to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PLATO hands him the gun. JIM removes the cartridges and puts them in his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>You trust me, don't you? Just give it to me for a second.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You promised to give it back.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Friends never break promises, do they?  Okay. Here. Now listen. There are a lot of people outside and they all want you to be safe. You understand that? They said I could come in and bring you out.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They like you. Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM opens the door for PLATO, then follows him out. JUDY joins them.</context>
      <utterance>Come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Plato!</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Observatory as JIM, JUDY and PLATO come to the entrance. PLATO sees an OFFICER.</context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a guard.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I shot at one of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Outside observatory as PLATO and JIM come forward into the early dawn. PLATO stops and looks off, scared. Slow pan shot. The crowd. It has grown enormously. Silence. There are armed officers everywhere--all waiting, alert. Med. shot. NEGRO WOMAN. Her eyes are moist. Her lips move in silent prayer. Med. shot. JIM's parents. The FATHER looking on anxiously. The MOTHER is crying against the car. Med. shot. JIM and PLATO.</context>
      <utterance>But you didn't hurt anybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those aren't my friends. Make them go away.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly PLATO bolts. JIM wheels after him.</context>
      <utterance>Ray! Will you tell these guys to move back?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Full shot. Balcony. Shooting down the stairs as PLATO rushes up. JIM closes behind him. Camera pans with PLATO as he climbs the ladder to the ledge of the small dome. JIM stops at the foot of the ladder.</context>
      <utterance>It's Jim!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Plato!</utterance>
   <speaker>PLATO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He raises the gun as if to shoot JIM. An OFFICER drops to one knee and fires a shot at PLATO. Full shot. Small dome. PLATO drops like a stone to JIM's feet. Close-up. JIM.</context>
      <utterance>Keep away from me! I don't believe you anymore!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is nothing. He rises and faces the crowd, shaking his head in wonder and reproach.</context>
      <utterance>Plato?  Plato. Hey, Jerkpot!</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RAY, who has witnessed this, motions to the officers.</context>
      <utterance>Let him alone! He's mine! I'll take care of him!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The FATHER stares down at JIM for a moment. Then he kneels beside his son, puts his coat over JIM's shoulders. He speaks very gently.</context>
      <utterance>It's all right! It's all right!</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes JIM by the elbow and starts to bring him to his feet. The boy suddenly resists, and remains kneeling.</context>
      <utterance>For a minute...that jacket...I thought...  You couldn't help it, son.  You did everything a man could do.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A faint hope appears in the boy's face. He no longer resists as the FATHER helps him to rise. But he still keeps his back to him. The ambulance attendants start putting PLATO on a stretcher. JIM moves, as if to stop them, but the FATHER still holds his shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>Stand up, Jim. I'll stand up with you. Let me try to be as strong as you want me to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He depended on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM feels, for the first time, the love and security he has always wanted. He clutches at his FATHER, crying unashamedly. The FATHER's arms envelop him. PLATO, through his death, has helped these two find each other. Close shot. JUDY and RAY watching. Low angle. NEGRO WOMAN as she bends over PLATO's body.</context>
      <utterance>And you can depend on me, son. Trust me. Whatever comes we'll face it together, I swear.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JUDY moves to JIM and touches his arm lightly. He looks down at her. Med. shot. The group. JIM's arm is around JUDY as he leads her, firmly, towards his MOTHER and FATHER. His voice is warm, brimming with the new found pride he takes in his parents as he introduces JUDY to them.</context>
      <utterance>He was always cold.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The parents nods warmly and smile at her. She smiles shyly in response, happy at being accepted. There is a warmth emanating from the tight little group. Changes have happened to them. Old things have been shed and a new start has been made. Camera booms--pulls back high to: High general shot. Planetarium, JIM and JUDY, FATHER and MOTHER threading their way through the crowd as the camera continues to pull back.</context>
      <utterance>Mom--Dad--this is my friend. Her name is Judy.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
