<movie id="462" title="Ringu">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MASAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Masami points so suddenly and dramatically at her friend that Tomoko actually jumps in her seat. MASAMI (cont’d) “One week from now, you will die.” Short silence as Masami pauses, relishing the moment. MASAMI (cont’d) Of course the kid’s completely freaked, and he stops the video. Just then the phone rings, and when he picks it up a voice says-- Her voice drops voice almost to a whisper. MASAMI (cont’d) “You watched it, didn’t you?” That same time, exactly one week later... he’s dead! Masami laughs loudly, thoroughly enjoying her own performance. Tomoko, however, is completely silent. She begins looking more and more distressed, until finally Masami notices.</context>
      <utterance>They say that some elementary school kid spent the night with his parents at a bed and breakfast in Izu. The kid wanted to go out and play with everybody, right, but he didn’t want to miss the program he always used to watch back in Tokyo, so he records it on the VCR in their room. But of course the stations in Izu are different from the ones in Tokyo. In Izu, it was just an empty channel, so he should’ve recorded nothing but static. But when the kid gets back to his house and watches the tape, all of a sudden this woman comes on the screen and says--</utterance>
   <speaker>MASAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tomoko comes out of her chair and drops onto the floor next to her friend. Her words are quick, earnest.</context>
      <utterance>What is it, Tomoko?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMOKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who did you hear that story from?</utterance>
   <speaker>MASAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who? It’s just a rumor. Everybody knows it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMOKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Youko told you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MASAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tomoko looks away, worried. Masami slaps her on the knee, laughing.</context>
      <utterance>No, it wasn’t Youko...</utterance>
   <speaker>MASAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tomoko speaks slowly, still looking away.</context>
      <utterance>What’s up with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMOKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The other day, I... I watched this strange video.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>MASAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMOKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With Youko and them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So that’s what I’ve been hearing about you doing some double-date/ sleepover thing! So, you and that guy Iwata, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMOKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their eyes meet and Tomoko half-blushes, looks away again. Her expression becomes serious as she resumes her conversation.</context>
      <utterance>No, it’s not like that. Nothing happened!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMOKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Iwata... he found this weird video. Everyone was like, “What’s that?” so he put it on and we all watched it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And? What kind of video was it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMOKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. Masami curls up on herself, thoroughly spooked.</context>
      <utterance>Just... weird, I can’t really explain it. Anyway, right after we finished watching it, the phone rang. Whoever it was didn’t say anything, but still...</utterance>
   <speaker>MASAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMOKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a long, heavy silence as neither of them says anything.</context>
      <utterance>It's cuz, you know, we'd all heard the rumors. Tomoko looks seriously over at her friend. TOMOKO  That was one week ago today.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tomoko’s face suddenly breaks into a smile.</context>
      <utterance>Waaait a minute. Are you faking me out?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMOKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both crack up laughing.</context>
      <utterance>Busted, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MASAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Masami reaches out, slaps her friend on the knee. MASAMI (cont’d) You’re terrible!</context>
      <utterance>Oh, my... I can’t believe you!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMOKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gotcha!</utterance>
   <speaker>MASAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tomoko nods, uh-huh. Masami dives forward, pinching her friend’s cheeks and grinning wildly.</context>
      <utterance>But hang on... you really stayed the night with Youko and Iwata, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MASAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, how far did you and he get?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMOKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh... I can’t remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Masami laughs, then slaps Tomoko on the knee again as she remembers the trick her friend played on her.</context>
      <utterance>You can’t remember, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MASAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, you had me freaked me out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MASAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tomoko nods her head, still holding on tightly. Masami has to forcibly disengage herself in order to stand. The phone is downstairs, so Masami opens the bedroom DOOR and races down the STAIRS. Tomoko calls out to her from behind.</context>
      <utterance>Was it true?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMOKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Masami!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MASAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Still grinning, she hands the phone to Tomoko. Tomoko snatches it quickly.</context>
      <utterance>I’ll put her on.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMOKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is silent for a moment, then smiling widely.</context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMOKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is so relieved that all the strength seeps out of her and she sinks to the kitchen floor. Masami, equally relieved, slides down the wall and sits down next to her.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, man!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMOKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tomoko stands to place the phone back in its wall cradle, and then squats back down onto the kitchen floor.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I’ve got a friend over now. Yeah. Yeah, OK. Bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMOKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They burst out laughing with relief again, and are soon both clutching their stomachs.</context>
      <utterance>The game’s gone into overtime, so they’re gonna be a little late.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMOKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeeezus, my parents...</utterance>
   <speaker>MASAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tomoko shakes her head, -Don’t you dare-.</context>
      <utterance>Oh man, I’m tellin’ everybody about this tomorrow!</utterance>
   <speaker>MASAMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I’m gonna use your bathroom. Don’t go anywhere.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There seems to be a popular rumor going around about a ”cursed” videotape.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you heard what kind of video it might be?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girl looks directly at the camera, her mouth dropping into an “O” as she’s suddenly overcome by a kind of stage fright. She continues staring, silently, at the camera.</context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>YOUNG GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa glances over her shoulder, makes sure that Komiya is ready.</context>
      <utterance>Let’s do it again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you heard what kind of video it might be?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I heard was, all of a sudden this scaaarry lady comes on the screen and says, “In one week, you will die.”</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard that if you’re watching TV late at night it’ll come on, and then your phone’ll ring.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watching TV late at night... do you know what station?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmmm... I heard some local station, around Izu.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Izu?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmm-hmm.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girl flashes a look at her two friends.</context>
      <utterance>And, do you know if anyone’s really died from watching it?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Girl 2 nods her head. Girl 3 nods slowly, opens and closes her mouth as if deciding whether to say something or not. The reporter notices.</context>
      <utterance>Well, no one that we know, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard this from a friend of mine in high school. She said that there was this one girl who watched the video, and then died a week later. She was out on a drive with her boyfriend.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were in a wreck?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, their car was parked, but they were both dead inside. Her boyfriend died because he’d watched the video, too. That’s what my friend said. Girl 3 grows suddenly defensive. GIRL 3  It’s true! It was in the paper two or three days ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know the name of the high school this girl went to?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... I heard this from my friend, and it didn’t happen at her school. She heard it from a friend at a different school, she said.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>KOMIYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Asakawa?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hm?</utterance>
   <speaker>KOMIYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Komiya has a seat.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOMIYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This same kind of thing happened about ten years ago too, didn’t it? Some popular young singer committed suicide, and then suddenly there was all this talk about her ghost showing up on some music show.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I wonder what this rumor’s all about. Everyone you ask always mentions “Izu.”</utterance>
   <speaker>KOMIYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>> Literally “Ripped-Mouth Lady,” a kind of ghastly spectre from >Japanese folk stories who wears a veil to hide her mouth, which >has been ripped or cut open from ear to ear. She wanders the >countryside at night asking men “Do you think I’m beautiful?” then >lowering her veil to reveal her true features.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe that’s where it all started. Hey, where was that Kuchi-sake Onna story from again?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gifu, but there was some big accident out there, and that ended up being what started the rumor.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOMIYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A big accident?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmm-hmm. Something terrible like that is going to stay in people’s minds. Sometimes the story of what happened gets twisted around, and ends up coming back as a rumor like this one. That’s what they say, at least.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOMIYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>D’you think something like that happened out at Izu?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe. Well, anyway, I’m off. See you tomorrow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>GUY IN SUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OK, Okazaki, I’m counting on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>OKAZAKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guy in the suit pats Okazaki on the shoulder and walks off. Okazaki turns to walk away, spots Asakawa bent over the small table and peering intently at the newspaper article.</context>
      <utterance>Yessir.</utterance>
   <speaker>OKAZAKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa turns around and begins speaking excitedly.</context>
      <utterance>Miss Asakawa? I thought you were going home early today.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okazaki, can I ask you a favor?</utterance>
   <speaker>OKAZAKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa points to the newspaper.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could you check out this article for me? Get me some more info.?</utterance>
   <speaker>OKAZAKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess...</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. Call me as soon as you know more, OK?</utterance>
   <speaker>OKAZAKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa walks off. Okazaki, still carrying the videotapes, leans forward to take a look at the article.</context>
      <utterance>Ma’am.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Hearing his name, the boy puts down the BOOK he was reading and stands up, facing the door. He is wearing a white DRESS SHIRT with a brown sweater-type VEST over it. He sees Asakawa, his mother, run in the door. She is panting lightly.</context>
      <utterance>Yoichi!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry I’m late. Oh, you’ve already changed.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOICHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points over to his mother’s right. YOICHI (cont’d) I got your clothes out for you. Asakawa turns to see a DARK SUIT hanging from one of the living room shelves. She reaches out, takes it.</context>
      <utterance>Yup.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She runs into the next room to change.</context>
      <utterance>Aargh, we’ve gotta hurry!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did grandpa call?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOICHI</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Yoichi walks into the room and faces his mother.</context>
      <utterance>Nope.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOICHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>> ”-chan” is a suffix in Japanese that denotes closeness or affection. >It is most often used for young girls, though it can also be used for >boys.</context>
      <utterance>Why did Tomo-chan die?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes a seat on the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Well... it looks like she was really, really sick.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yoichi fastens the rear button of his mother’s dress and zips her up.</context>
      <utterance>Will you do me up?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOICHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can die even if you’re young?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa turns to face her son, puts an arm around him.</context>
      <utterance>If it’s something serious... well, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yoichi nods.</context>
      <utterance>As hard as it is for us, what your auntie and uncle are going through right now is even harder, so let’s not talk about this over there, OK?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yoichi says nothing.</context>
      <utterance>You and her used to play a lot together, didn’t you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kouichi turns to see her.</context>
      <utterance>Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOUICHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is sis holding up?</utterance>
   <speaker>KOUICHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa nods.</context>
      <utterance>She’s resting inside right now. She’s shaken up pretty badly, you know. It’s best she just take things easy for a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I’ll go check on auntie and them, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOUICHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs the young boy and seats him on a cushion next to the two guests. As the guests resume their conversation with Asakawa’s father, Yoichi’s eyes wander to the ALTAR at the front of the room set up to honor the deceased. It is made of wood, and surrounded by candles, flowers, and small paper lanterns. At the center is a PICTURE of the deceased, a teenage girl. A small wooden PLAQUE reads her name: Tomoko Ouishi. It is the same Tomoko from the first scene. Yoichi continues to stare at Tomoko’s picture. He makes a peculiar gesture as he does so, rubbing his index finger in small circles just between his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>OK. Ah, Yoichi. Why don’t you sit here for a little while?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>AUNT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you heard anything more about Tomo-chan’s death?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I...</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But the police have already finished their autopsy!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, they said there was no sign of foul play.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was no normal death. They haven’t once opened the casket to let us see the body. Don’t you think that’s strange?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Asakawa looks away, thinking.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ASAKWAWA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Yoichi turns to face her as she approaches, puts an arm around him.</context>
      <utterance>Yoichi?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without replying, Yoichi’s gaze slowly returns to the television set. Asakawa holds him by the shoulders, turning him to meet her.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing up here? You shouldn’t just walk into other people’s rooms.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You go on downstairs, OK?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>OKAZAKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa blinks at this, looks disturbed.</context>
      <utterance>Uh... this is Okazaki. I’ve got some more info on that article for you. The girl was a student of the uh, Seikei School for Women in Yokahama City.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hangs up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three girls turn their faces to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me. This is, um, kind of a strange question, but by any chance were you friends of that young girl that died in the car as well?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. If you know anything...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL RIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They all died the same day. Youko. Tomoko. Even Iwata, he was in a motorcycle accident.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL LEFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because they watched the video.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Video?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL LEFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That’s what Youko said. They all watched some weird video, and after that their phone rang.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Girl Left shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>Tomoko-chan watched it, too? Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL LEFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She just said they all stayed somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL RIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was a girl with Tomoko when she died. She’s had to be hospitalized for shock.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL MIDDLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They say she won’t go anywhere near a television.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>YOSHINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Onscreen, the policeman has finally picked the lock. The door opens, and a girl’s BODY half–falls out, head facing upwards. Yoshino flicks a BUTTON on the control panel, scans the footage frame by frame. He stops when he gets a good close-up of the victim. Her face is twisted into an insane rictus of fear, mouth open, eyes wide and glassy. Yoshino and Asakawa lean back in their seats.</context>
      <utterance>The bodies of those found were Tsuji Youko, age 17, a student of the Seikei School for Women, and Nomi Takehiko, age 19, preparatory school student. Both their doors were securely locked.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOSHINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the first time I’ve -ever- seen something like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cause of death?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOSHINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Couldn’t say, aside from sudden heart failure.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drugs?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOSHINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yoshino takes the video off pause. Onscreen, a policeman has caught the young girl’s body from completely falling out, and is pushing it back into the car. As the body moves into an upright position, we can see that the girl’s PANTIES are mid-way around her left thigh.</context>
      <utterance>The autopsy came up negative.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOSHINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These two, about to go at it, suddenly up and die for no apparent reason. He sighs. YOSHINO  Do -you- get it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RYOMI</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Asakawa steps back into the kitchen. She addresses her sister, who continues to stare out at nothing.</context>
      <utterance>They tell me that Yoichi came to the funeral, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmm-hmm.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I’m probably going to be late coming home tonight, so just stick your dinner in the microwave when you’re ready to eat, OK?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOICHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>‘K... Mom?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmm?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOICHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa leaves the food on the stove, runs over to Yoichi and grabs him by the shoulders. She shakes him roughly.</context>
      <utterance>Tomo-chan watched some cursed video!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you say? You are not to speak of this at school, do you hear me?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOICHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yoichi walks off. Asakawa goes back to the stove, but stops after only a few stirs, staring off and thinking. Caption-- “September 13th. Monday.”</context>
      <utterance>I won’t. I’m going to school now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Room for one?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She passes the clerk a picture of Tomoko and her three other friends. He stares at it for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Um, actually I’m here on business.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They would have stayed here on August 29th, all four of them. If there’s any information you might have...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The clerk turns his back to her, begins leafing through a guest log.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, hang on just a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>While she waits, Asakawa’s eyes start to wander around the room. Behind the desk is a sign reading “Rental Video,” and a large wooden BOOKSHELF filled with VIDEOTAPES. They are all in their original boxes, and she lets her eyes glance over the titles. Raiders of the Lost Ark, 48 Hours-- --and then, suddenly, she spies a VIDEOTAPE in a plain, unmarked sleeve, tucked away in the back of the very bottom shelf. She feels the hairs on the back of her neck rise.</context>
      <utterance>August 29th...</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The clerk looks up.</context>
      <utterance>That...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa stabs a finger excitedly towards the shelf.</context>
      <utterance>Hmm?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The clerk reaches out for it, grabs it.</context>
      <utterance>That! What tape is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The clerk pulls the tape out of its SLEEVE and checks for a label. It’s unmarked.</context>
      <utterance>This? Hmm...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe one of the guests left it behind</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yoichi’s in elementary school already, is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His first year. What about you, Ryuji? How have you been recently?</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes a seat next to him, serves the tea. On the coffee table before them is a VIDEOTAPE in a plain, unmarked case.</context>
      <utterance>Same as always.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And money is...?</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryuji picks up his cup of tea but stops, grimacing, before it is to his lips. He rubs his forehead as if experiencing a sudden headache. Ryuji shakes it off and quickly regains his composure.</context>
      <utterance>I’m teaching at university.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyway. You said that the phone rang?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That’s right.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So if I watch it too, that phone over there-- He gestures with his mug RYUJI  --should ring.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ryuji, four people have already died. On the same day!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryuji raises the camera to his eye.</context>
      <utterance>Take my picture.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turn this way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryuji pops the tape from the deck, hands it to Asakawa.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it looks like your phone’s not ringing.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make me a copy of this, will you? I’d like to do a little research of my own. There’s no reason to write us off as dead just yet. He dramatically takes a seat. RYUJI  If there’s a video, that means that somebody had to make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa pulls a NOTEPAD from her purse and begins busily scribbling away.</context>
      <utterance>There’s the guest list from the cottage to look into... and the possibility of someone hacking into the local station’s broadcast signals.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>OKAZAKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here’s that guest list you wanted.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>OKAZAKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you gonna do with this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh... sorry, I’m working on something personal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa notes in his face that something is wrong.</context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He enters the building, carrying his bicycle. Asakawa follows.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, what’d you come up with?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don’t think any of the guests on the list brought the tape with them. I couldn’t confirm it face-to-face of course, but even over the phone I got the feeling they were all being upfront with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>How about the other angle? Pirate signals or...</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches into her purse, pulls out a large white ENVELOPE.</context>
      <utterance>There’re no traces of any illegal television signals being broadcast around Izu.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryuji tears the package open. He squats down on the tatami in frontof his TV and slides the tape in. Asakawa sits on the tatami as well, but positions herself away from the TV and keeps her eyes averted. Ryuji glares over his shoulder at her.</context>
      <utterance>Here’s that copy of the videotape you wanted.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reluctantly scoots closer, looks up at the screen. Ryuji fast-forwards the tape a bit, stopping at the scene where the woman is brushing her long hair before an oval mirror. He puts the video on frame-by-frame.</context>
      <utterance>Asakawa.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa regards the screen intently.</context>
      <utterance>Have you ever seen this woman?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The tape advances to the scene where the mirror suddenly changes positions. When it does, we can again see the small figure in the white gown, a figure with long black hair. When Ryuji sees this his body stiffens, becomes tense. Asakawa notices but says nothing. She also notices something else.</context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes the remote from Ryuji, rewinds it a ways. Onscreen, the woman begins coming her long hair again.</context>
      <utterance>There’s something strange about this shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From this angle, the mirror should be reflecting whoever’s filming.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa lets out a short sigh.</context>
      <utterance>So, what does that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The screen changes, showing the mass of squiggling kanji characters again.</context>
      <utterance>Well, if the person who made this is a pro, there’d be a way around that, I guess, but still...</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are both still staring at the screen when from behind them comes the SOUND of someone opening the front door. Ryuji turns off the TV, ejects the tape from the deck.</context>
      <utterance>This is gonna be impossible to figure out on just a regular TV screen, don’t you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa flashes a look at Ryuji and then turns her head back towards the front door to see who has entered. A cute, nervous-looking young GIRL with short hair approaches slowly. She is carrying a PLASTIC BAG filled with groceries.</context>
      <utterance>Come on in.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryuji gets up and walks conveniently away.</context>
      <utterance>Asakawa, meet my student, Takano Mai. He turns, addresses Mai. RYUJI  This is Asakawa, my ex-wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice to meet you. I’m Takano.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>> As you may already be aware, Japanese name order is the >opposite of English’s, and even close friends may continue to >address one another by their last names. Incidentally, Asakawa’s >first name is “Reiko.” In this scene, Mai deferentially refers >to Ryuji as sensei, meaning “teacher.” Mai sets the bag of groceries down and chases after Ryuji. He is putting on his jacket and getting ready to leave.</context>
      <utterance>Asakawa.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sensei, the people from the publishing company called about the deadline on your thesis again.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What’re they talkin’ to you about it for?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryuji picks up his keys, video firmly in hand.</context>
      <utterance>Because they can never get a hold of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ask them to wait another week.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryuji is already headed for the door. His back is to her as he responds.</context>
      <utterance>Sensei, ask them yourself, please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryuji fast forwards, stopping at the scene with the kanji reflected inside an alien-looking EYE. He reads the kanji aloud.</context>
      <utterance>This is impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryuji moves to make a note of this, notices the time.</context>
      <utterance>Sada...</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is Yoichi gonna be all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Short silence. Ryuji breaks it by gesturing towards the screen.</context>
      <utterance>He’s used to it...</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa turns a DIAL to bring up the volume, which up until now has been on mute. The room is filled with an eerie, metallic GRATING, and Asakawa spins the dial again, shutting it off. Just as she does, Ryuji’s eyes widen.</context>
      <utterance>Whoever made this had to have left some kind of clue behind. They’re probably waiting for us to find it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns the dial again, punches a few buttons as if searching for something. He listens carefully, and when he hears that strange something again he stops, looks at the screen. It is paused at the scene with the figure, pointing, a CLOTH draped over its head. The figure now looks oddly like a messenger. Ryuji and Asakawa exchange glances. This could be it. Ryuji flips some more switches, setting the sound for super-slow mo. What follows is a strange, labored sort of speech-— a hidden message-- framed in the skittering distortion of the tape in slow motion.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shoooomonnn bakkkkkarrri toou... boooouuuukonn ga kuuru zouuu...</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa nods. Ryuji is already writing it down excitedly.</context>
      <utterance>Shoumon bakkari, boukon ga kuru zo. Did you hear that, too?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryuji tears the sheet of paper off the notepad, folds it, and tucks it into his shirt pocket.</context>
      <utterance>What does that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I’m gonna check it out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>> Translated from standard Japanese, the phrase from the videotape >would initially have sounded like, "If only SHOUMON then the >BOUKON will come." These two capitalized words, later identified to >be dialectical, were at the time completely incomprehensible to Ryuji >and Asakawa. Dialect can vary dramatically from region to region in >Japan, to the point of speakers of different dialect being unable to >understand one another. >The phrase on the tape can now be rendered, "If you keep playing in >the water, the monster will come for you."</context>
      <utterance>I’ve got it. It’s a dialect, just like I thought. SHOUMON means “playing in the water” and BOUKON means “monster.”</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, dialect from where?</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oshima. And the site of our “eruption” is Mt. Mihara.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yoichi? I’m gonna be a little late tonight, honey. Ryuji looks over his shoulder at her, scowls.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hangs up, returns to her seat at the cubicle. She resumes her scanning of the newspaper articles, and Ryuji shoots her another scowl. Asakawa turns a page and then stops, frowning. She has spied an article that looks like... Nervously, Asakawa puts the thumb and forefinger of each hand together, forming the shape of a rectangle. Or a screen. She places the rectangle over the article she has just discovered, its headlines reading: Mount Mihara Erupts Local Residents Urged to Take Precautions Ryuji notices her, leans forward excitedly.</context>
      <utterance>You can do it yourself, right? OK. Sorry. Bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two scan the remainder of the page, and find a smaller, related article. Did Local Girl Predict Eruption? A young lady from Sashikiji prefecture... The two read over both articles, absorbing the details. Ryuji stands suddenly, gathering his things.</context>
      <utterance>I’ve got it! This old article...</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Has your newspaper got someone out there at Oshima?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think so. There should be a correspondent out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He begins walking briskly away. Asakawa chases after him.</context>
      <utterance>I need you to find out, and let me know how to get hold of him. Tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think you’re--?</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryuji strides off. Asakawa stands motionless.</context>
      <utterance>You’ve only got four days left, Asakawa! Your newspaper contact and I can handle this from here on out. You just stay with Yoichi.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>YOICHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grandpa!</utterance>
   <speaker>KOUICHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Caption-- “September 17th. Friday.”</context>
      <utterance>Whoa, there! So, you made it, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yoichi says he’s looking forward to doing some fishing with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOUICHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yoichi begins tugging excitedly at his grandfather’s arm.</context>
      <utterance>Is that so?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOICHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C’mon grandpa, let’s go!</utterance>
   <speaker>KOUICHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OK, OK. We’ll get our things together and then we can go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KOUICHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yoichi tries to scoop up the fish his grandfather is pointing out.</context>
      <utterance>There he is! C’mon, there he is, don’t let him go!</utterance>
   <speaker>KOUICHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, oh! Ah... guess he got away, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOICHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa’s father laughs.</context>
      <utterance>That was your fault, grandpa.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOUICHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He begins sloshing noisily out to the center of the stream, Yoichi in tow.</context>
      <utterance>Well, whaddya say we try again?</utterance>
   <speaker>KOUICHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa looks away, pensive.</context>
      <utterance>We’ll get ‘im this time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Your Oshima contact came through. It looks like the woman who predicted the Mihara eruption is the same woman from the video.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you got anything else?</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I’m gonna have to check it for myself. I’ll be leaving for Oshima tomorrow morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oshima? I’ve only got three days left!</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Short silence.</context>
      <utterance>I know. And I’ve got four.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Ryuji hangs up. Asakawa, deep in thought, slowly places the phone back in its CRADLE. She turns around to walk back down the hallway only to find her father standing there, face full of concern.</context>
      <utterance>I’ll be in touch.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>What’s happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks past her father, who glances worriedly after her over his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing. I just had some things left over from work.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TOMOKO</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Asakawa looks around the room, gets her bearings. Her eyes fall on the futon next to hers.</context>
      <utterance>Auntie?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a BODY in that futon, but it is full-grown, dressed all in black. It is curled into a fetal position and has its head turned away. Suddenly, the IMAGE from the video of the figure with its face shrouded springs to Asakawa’s mind. Just an instant, its pointing visage materializes, and then disappears. It reappears a moment later, pointing more insistently now, and disappears again. Asakawa blinks her eyes and realizes that the futon next to hers is empty. Yoichi is nowhere to be seen. Just then, she hears that high-pitched, metallic SQUEAKING from the video. Eyes wide with horror, she flings the sliding doors apart-- --and there, seated before the television, is Yoichi. He is watching the video. It is already at the very last scene, the shot of the outdoor well. CLOSEUP on the screen now, and for just an instant we can see that something is trying to claw its way out of the well. The video cuts off, and the screen fills with static. Shrieking, Asakawa races over to Yoichi, covers his eyes though it is already too late. She scoots over to the VCR, ejects the tape and stares at it uncomprehendingly. She is then at Yoichi’s side again, shaking him roughly.</context>
      <utterance>Yoichi?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yoichi! You brought this with you, didn’t you? Why?!?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOICHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa freezes, her eyes wide.</context>
      <utterance>Tomo-chan...</utterance>
   <speaker>YOICHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tomo-chan told me to watch it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should’ve been more careful. When I was at your place that day, I could feel something there. I thought it was just because of the video...</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean that Tomoko—</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That’s not Tomoko. Not anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryuji nods his head, lowers it sadly.</context>
      <utterance>Yoichi... he can see them too, can’t he?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It’s all my fault. First Tomoko died, then those three others. It should have stopped there, but it didn’t. Because of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa turns to Ryuji suddenly.</context>
      <utterance>I wonder...</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did the rumors about the video even start in the first place?</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This kind of thing... it doesn’t start by one person telling a story. It’s more like everyone’s fear just takes on a life of its own.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fear...</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or maybe it’s not fear at all. Maybe it’s what we were secretly hoping for all along.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Hayatsu?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYATSU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Hayatsu leads Asakawa and Ryuji to an awaiting minivan. Caption-- “September 18th. Saturday.”</context>
      <utterance>Aah, welcome! You must be tired after your long trip. Please, this way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HAYATSU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa gives the briefest of nods in reply, after which the minivan lapses into silence. Asakawa looks dreamily out at the mountain-studded landscape, then suddenly snaps to.</context>
      <utterance>Back in the old days, the Yamamuras used to head fishing boats out in Sashikiji, though they don’t much anymore. You know, one of Shizuko’s cousins is still alive. He’s just an old man now. His son and his daughter-in-law run an old-fashioned inn. I went ahead and booked reservations for y’all, hope that’s alright...</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did Yamamura Shizuko commit suicide?</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CUT to a scene of the minivan speeding along a country road.</context>
      <utterance>She was taking a real beating in the press, being called a fraud and all sorts of names. After a while she just lost it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shizuko was getting a lot of attention around the island after predicting the eruption of Mt. Mihara. Seems that for some time she’d had a rather unique ability: precognition. It was around then that she attracted the attention of a certain scholar whom you may have heard of; Ikuma Heihachiro.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryuji nods.</context>
      <utterance>He was driven out of the university, wasn’t he?</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa continues, ignoring Ryuji’s barb.</context>
      <utterance>This Professor Ikuma convinces Shizuko to go to Tokyo with him, where he uses her in a series of demonstrations meant to prove the existence of ESP. At first she’s the darling of the press, but the next thing you know they’re knocking her down, calling her a fraud. Hmph. Forty years later, the media still hasn’t changed that much.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A strange look crosses Ryuji’s face. He looks away, ignores her for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>I’ve heard this story. But... I’m sure I remember hearing that somebody died at one of those demonstrations.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After getting kicked out of university, Ikuma just vanished, and no one’s been able to get hold of him since. He’s probably not even alive anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, why even try looking for him?</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa freezes. In her mind, she sees a small FIGURE dressed in white, its face hidden by long, black HAIR. It is the figure from the video.</context>
      <utterance>Because he’s supposed to have had a child with Shizuko. A daughter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HAYATSU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The INKEEPER, a middle-aged lady named KAZUE wearing a traditional KIMONO, comes shuffling up. She addresses Mr. Hayatsu.</context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAZUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. She turns to Asakawa and Ryuji. KAZUE  Welcome.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYATSU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives a little bow and is off. Kazue, meanwhile, has produced two pairs of SLIPPERS, which she offers to Ryuji and Asakawa.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I’ll be off then.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAZUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. Ryuji and Asakawa begin removing their shoes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>KAZUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And for your rooms, how shall we...?</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Separate, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAZUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>‘Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAZUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kazue turns to the right. Almost immediately after reaching the top of the steps, however, a strange look crosses Ryuji’s face. He heads down the opposite end of the corridor, Asakawa close behind.</context>
      <utterance>This way.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAZUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryuji flings open the SLIDING DOOR to one of the older rooms. There, hanging from one of the walls, is the oval-shaped MIRROR from the video, the one used by the mysterious lady to brush her long hair. Ryuji stares at the mirror, almost wincing. He turns around as if to look at Asakawa,but continues turning, looks past her. Asakawa follows his gaze, as does Kazue. Standing at the end of the corridor is an old man, MR. YAMAMURA. Yamamura regards them silently, balefully. Breaking the silence, Kazue gestures for Asakawa and Ryuji to follow.</context>
      <utterance>Sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>KAZUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa races past the innkeeper towards the old man. He keeps his back turned towards her.</context>
      <utterance>Please, this way.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please! If you could just answer a few questions, about Shizuko...</utterance>
   <speaker>YAMAMURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got nuthin’ to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The old man says nothing.</context>
      <utterance>It’s about Shizuko’s daughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yamamura regards her for a moment, then turns to walk away.</context>
      <utterance>She did have a daughter, didn’t she?</utterance>
   <speaker>YAMAMURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You’re wasting your time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="32">
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren’t you gonna eat?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Umm...</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hm?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You’ll stay with me won’t you? When it’s time for me to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa scoots across the tatami mats towards the table, grabs Ryuji fiercely by the arm.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, stop it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You’ll stay, won’t you? If you stayed, maybe you’d learn something that could help Yoichi--</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said stop it! Have you forgotten There was a girl with Tomoko when she died? That girl’s now in a mental institution. Who knows what could happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you could stay with me, Ryuji. You’d be OK.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa releases her hold on Ryuji’s arm, lowers her head. Ryuji slams his chopsticks down angrily.</context>
      <utterance>Why, because I’m already not right in the head?</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If that’s the case, why not just let things run its course, get rid of father -and- son? Yoichi was a mistake, anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Short silence. When Ryuji speaks up again, his voice is soft, reassuring.</context>
      <utterance>Stop it!</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then the VOICE of the innkeeper calls tentatively out from the other side of the sliding door.</context>
      <utterance>We still have two days left...</utterance>
   <speaker>KAZUE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kazue slides the door open. She stands hesitantly in the doorway, something tucked under one arm.</context>
      <utterance>Come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAZUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryuji shoots a glance at Asakawa and stands up from the table, walks towards the innkeeper.</context>
      <utterance>It’s about Miss Shizuko.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAZUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kazue produces an old black and white PHOTOGRAPH. The photo shows a WOMAN, seated, dressed in a KIMONO. A MAN in a Western-style SUIT stands beside her.</context>
      <utterance>This is all that there is...</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hearing this Asakawa leaps up, walks over to examine the picture for herself.</context>
      <utterance>Is this Professor Ikuma?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAZUE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The innkeeper scuttles off, leaving Asakawa and Ryuji alone with the photograph. Unbidden, the VOICE from the video enters their thoughts.</context>
      <utterance>...yes. This picture is from before I’d entered the household. She pauses a moment. KAZUE  I should go now.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shoumon bakkari... boukon ga kuru zo...</utterance>
   <speaker>YAMAMURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y’all’d do best to be off soon. Sea’s probably gonna be rough tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of a child was Shizuko?</utterance>
   <speaker>YAMAMURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shizuko was... different. She’d come out here by herself ever’day an’ just stare out at the ocean. The fishermen all took a dislikin’ to her. Ocean’s an unlucky place for us, y’see: every year it swallows up more of our own. You keep starin’ out at somethin’ ike that...</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shoumon bakkari shite’ru to, boukon ga kuru zo. “If you keep playing in the water, the monster will come for you.” Yamamura looks at Ryuji, surprised.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yamamura rises unsteadily to his feet, features twisted angrily.</context>
      <utterance>Shizuko could see “inside” people, couldn’t she? Down to the places they’d most like to keep hidden. It must have been difficult for her...</utterance>
   <speaker>YAMAMURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryuji stands, takes hold of Yamamura’s arm.</context>
      <utterance>Please leave! Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I’ve got a little of that ability myself. It was you who spread the word about Shizuko, wasn’t it? And you who first contacted Professor Ikuma?</utterance>
   <speaker>YAMAMURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What’re you--?</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You thought you’d be able to make some money off her. You even got some, from one of the newspapers.</utterance>
   <speaker>YAMAMURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Yamamura strides angrily off. Both Ryuji and Asakawa take pursuit, Ryuji calling out from behind Yamamura’s back.</context>
      <utterance>Leave me the hell alone!</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell us about Shizuko’s daughter. Who was she?</utterance>
   <speaker>YAMAMURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don’t know!</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yamamura’s pace, which has become increasingly erratic, finally causes him to stumble and fall. Ryuji comes up behind him, grasping him firmly. At their touch Ryuji’s power awakens, and as he peers into the old man’s mind there is a sudden blinding</context>
      <utterance>She was there, with Shizuko. She had to be.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JUDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cameras begin FLASHING excitedly. Shizuko’s features melt into a soft smile. The experiment is performed again, and again the phrase written by Shizuko corresponds to the sealed sheet of paper.</context>
      <utterance>Match.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again and again, Shizuko unerringly demonstrates her power to “see” the unseen. Finally, a bearded REPORTER explodes from his chair, begins striding angrily towards the stage.</context>
      <utterance>Match.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The reporter stops at the foot of the stage, points his finger accusingly at Shizuko.</context>
      <utterance>Faker! This is nothing but trickery, and the lowest form of trickery at that.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A SECOND REPORTER sitting in the front row also rises to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>What are you trying to pull, woman?</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>By now most of the press has risen from their chairs, pointing and shouting angrily. Onstage, Shizuko backs away, eyes wide and frightened. She covers both ears, trying to block out the increasing din. Professor Ikuma holds her protectively by the shoulders. The first reporter is still shouting angrily, his voice rising above the others. Suddenly, a pained look crosses his face and he collapses to the floor. The crowd, and Asakawa as well, see that the reporter’s face is contorted into a grotesque mask of fear.</context>
      <utterance>That’s right! Professor Ikuma, you’re being fooled!</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What’s happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He’s dead!</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER #5</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Professor Ikuma begins leading Shizuko offstage. They stop as someone unseen steps up, blocking their passage. Shizuko’s eyes widen, her head shaking in disbelief.</context>
      <utterance>Witch!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHIZUKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CUT to Ryuji on the beach. He looks up excitedly.</context>
      <utterance>Sadako? Was it you?</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He recalls the image from the video, the alien eye with the single character SADA reflected in reverse. > The majority of girls' names in Japanese end in either -mi ("beauty") >or -ko ("child"). Thus, Sadako means "Chaste child." Sadako is, of >course, the mysterious daughter of Shizuko and Professor Ikuma.</context>
      <utterance>Sadako?!</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sadako killed him? She can kill just with a thought?</utterance>
   <speaker>YAMAMURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CUT back to the demonstration hall. Sadako, her face completely hidden by her long hair, runs offstage... and heads directly for Asakawa. Asakawa instinctively raises her arm, and Sadako grasps it fiercely. All the nails on Sadako’ hand are stripped away; her fingers are raw, bloody stumps. CUT back to the beach. Asakawa, still caught in the throes of the vision, has begun to swoon. Finally her legs give out and she crumples to the beach. Ryuji grabs hold of her supportively. He glances down at her wrist, sees an ugly, purple BRUISE already beginning to form. The bruise is in the shape of five long, spindly fingers. Mr. Yamamura slowly rises to a sitting position, and together the three watch the approach of ominous, dark STORM CLOUDS.</context>
      <utterance>She’s... a devil spawn.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa slams the phone down. PAN to show Ryuji slumped in one corner of the room, his back to the wall.</context>
      <utterance>That’s right. After Yamamura Shizuko committed suicide, Professor Ikuma took the daughter and ran. No, no one knows where they went. That’s why I need -you- to find out where they are. Even if the professor’s dead, Sadako should still be in her forties. I’ll explain it all later, but right now just hurry!</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sadako’s probably already dead. She could kill people with just a thought, remember? Her mother wasn’t even close to that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what about that video? If Sadako’s dead then who made it?</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryuji turns to regard Asakawa, his eyes blank.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody made it. It wasn’t made at all. That video... is the pure, physical manifestation of Sadako’s hatred.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a moment of silence before Mr. Hayatsu slides the door open, almost falling into the room. He is out of breath, and speaks rapidly.</context>
      <utterance>We’ve been cursed.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYATSU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It’s no good. With the typhoon coming in, all ships are temporarily staying docked.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the fishing boats? Tell their captains I’ll pay.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYATSU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryuji interrupts him, slamming both palms on the table. Glasses rattle wildly.</context>
      <utterance>Fishing boats? Sir, without knowing whether this typhoon is going to hit us or not, I think it’d be better to wait and see how things turn--</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryuji stands and races past Mr. Hayatsu out into the rain. Hayatsu takes pursuit, calling after him.</context>
      <utterance>Fine! I’ll try searching myself!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYATSU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa, left alone, stares down at the tatami mats.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Takayama!? Mr. Takayama...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>OKAZAKI</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>A look of abject fear crosses Asakawa’s face. She begins retreating into herself.</context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Asakawa? I’m sorry. I tried, but I couldn’t come up with any leads at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>OKAZAKI</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa slowly places the phone back in its cradle. Almost immediately, her face begins to crumple. She falls to her knees, sobbing into the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you...</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She cries a while longer but suddenly stops. Her face, eyes streaked with tears, shoots suddenly up, stares directly at the telephone.</context>
      <utterance>Yoichi...</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Izu...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa runs down onto the wharf, heading towards Ryuji. He is in mid-conversation with Mr. Hayatsu.</context>
      <utterance>Ryuji!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ryuji! The phone in my apartment never rang! It only ever rang at the rental cottage! Professor Ikuma must’ve...</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And we’ve got no way of going back.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYATSU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three fall into silence as they realize the powerlessness of their situation. Suddenly, a deep VOICE booms from behind them.</context>
      <utterance>It’s too dangerous! The thought of anybody going out in this weather...</utterance>
   <speaker>YAMAMURA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The three spin around to see Mr. Yamamura, his ROBES flapping in the gusty night air. He begins walking towards them.</context>
      <utterance>I’ll take you out.</utterance>
   <speaker>YAMAMURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Short silence. Ryuji shoots a short questioning glance at Asakawa, turns back to face Mr. Yamamura.</context>
      <utterance>Sadako is callin’ y’all, reckon. Mayhap to drag you down under the water.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. Take us out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryuji leans over, rubs her hand comfortingly. Suddenly he switches back into analytical mode.</context>
      <utterance>It’s funny. I’m not afraid at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sadako probably died back out there at Izu, before the rental cottages were ever built.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, Sadako was Professor Ikuma’s daughter?</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ikuma smuggled her out in secret. His relationship with Shizuko was already a scandal, and one of the reasons he got drummed out of the university... We’ve gotta find Sadako’s body.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that going to break the curse? Will Yoichi be all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It’s all we’ve got left to try.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryuji puts his arm around Asakawa.</context>
      <utterance>Just one more day...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Long pause as Mr. Yamamura says nothing.</context>
      <utterance>We made it. Maybe Sadako doesn’t have it out for us after all.</utterance>
   <speaker>YAMAMURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shizuko... she used to -speak- to the ocean, just ramble away. One time I hid, listenin’ to one of her conversations. Mr. Yamamura pauses again. YAMAMURA  And it weren’t in no human language.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>YOICHI</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yoichi? It’s mommy. I just called to say I’ll be coming home tomorrow. Ryuji shoots a look at her over his shoulder.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOICHI</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I’m tired of it here, mom! I wanna go back to school.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yoichi, it’s rude to your grandpa to talk like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOICHI</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He’s laughing. You wanna talk to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa pauses, her voice hitching. She seems about to lose her composure.</context>
      <utterance>No, that’s...</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I’m sorry, Yoichi. I’ll... I’ll see you tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOICHI</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Asakawa’s face scrunches up in an effort to hold back tears.</context>
      <utterance>What’s wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryuji stands by the car, scowling over at Asakawa. He shuts the DOOR just short of a slam. CUT to Asakawa hanging up the phone. She half- runs towards the rental car and enters the passenger side, staring blankly into space. Ryuji slides into the driver’s seat, buckles his</context>
      <utterance>Mommy’s got something she has to do. Say hello to grandpa for me, OK?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa glances at her watch.</context>
      <utterance>What time was it when you first watched the video?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seven or eight minutes past seven. PM. No more than ten minutes past.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He squats down beside the well, setting the flashlight on the lid. Asakawa sinks slowly down beside him.</context>
      <utterance>I knew it! The well.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryuji reaches out and takes Asakawa’s hand. He sets their enclasped hands onto the lid, and together they begin lightly tracing the surface of the lid with their free hands. Asakawa closes her eyes in concentration... and suddenly, as with the incident on the beach, Asakawa finds herself drawn into Ryuji’s psychometric VISION.</context>
      <utterance>The well...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The energy seems to drain out of Asakawa in a rush, and her body crumbles. Ryuji catches hold of her.</context>
      <utterance>Her own father!</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryuji stands quickly, takes hold of the crowbar. He inserts it under the lid and begins trying to pry it off, face scrunched with effort. Asakawa digs her fingers in and lends her own strength as well. Slowly, the lid begins to move. Ryuji tosses the crowbar aside and the two lean the combined weight of their bodies into it. The lid slides off, dropping to the earth with a dull THUD. Ryuji sits to one side, winded with effort, as Asakawa takes hold of the flashlight. She shines it down into the well, but it only seems to intensify the gloom. What WATER she can see looks fetid and brackish. Ryuji sees her expression and begins removing his JACKET.</context>
      <utterance>It was Ikuma who put this lid on. And Sadako’s still inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks off, leaving Asakawa alone. CUT to an overhead shot of the well. A ROPE is fastened to one side, and Ryuji has already begun lowering himself down. His eyes wander overthe grime-smeared WALLS, and with a shudder he begins to pick out human FINGERNAILS. Torn loose and spattered with blood, countless fingernails line the sides of the well.</context>
      <utterance>I’ll go.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryuji’s face twists into a grimace as if momentarily experiencing Sadako’sterrible agony. He waits a moment longer before edging his way down the rope again, finally SPLASHING to rest at the bottom of the well. He holds his flashlight above the brackish water, calls up to Asakawa.</context>
      <utterance>Sadako was alive! She’d tried to climb her way out.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa nods and lowers two plastic BUCKETS fastened to a rope. Ryuji grabs one and scoops up a bucketful of water, tugging on the rope when finished.</context>
      <utterance>Lower the buckets!</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa hoists the bucket up to the rim of the well. She walks a small distance and tosses the contents out onto the ground. She happens to glance through the wooden lattice to the outside, and with a start realizes that the sun has already started to set. A nervous glance at her WATCH later and she is back at the well, lowering the empty bucket to find another full one already awaiting her.</context>
      <utterance>Take it up!</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the well, Ryuji glances at his watch. He looks at it for a long moment, the expression on his face saying We’re not going to make it. Time passes as Asakawa pulls up bucketload after bucketload, her strength beginning to fade. She half-stumbles, glances up... and is shocked to realize that NIGHT has fallen. CUT to Asakawa slowly pulling up yet another bucket, her strength almost gone. She looks at her watch and sees that it is now past 6:00. She calls frantically down to Ryuji.</context>
      <utterance>Take it up!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It’s already six!</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nothing happens.</context>
      <utterance>Take it up!</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The bucket begins moving, even slower than before. CUT to Asakawa, her body trembling with effort. By now it’s all she can do to simply keep her body moving. She glances behind her, sees through the wooden lattice that it is now pitch black. A look of resignation crosses her face and she releases her hold on the bucket, her body crumpling and falling in on itself.</context>
      <utterance>Asakawa!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CUT back to Asakawa, her face dead. Ryuji calls out from the well.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you doing? Trying to get me killed?</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Asakawa falls backward onto the ground, arms splayed. CUT to the rim of the well. Ryuji pulls himself up over the rim, catches sight of Asakawa.</context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lifts her head up but says nothing as Ryuji walks over to her.</context>
      <utterance>Asakawa!</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa suddenly springs into life. Her voice is frantic, fearful.</context>
      <utterance>We’ll change. You’re in no condition to keep this up.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who do you expect to pull up these buckets, then?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryuji strides forward and slaps Asakawa painfully across the cheek. He begins shaking her roughly for good measure.</context>
      <utterance>But, we don’t even know if it’s doing any good...</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He releases his hold on her. The two stare at each other a long time, saying nothing.</context>
      <utterance>And what about Yoichi, huh? Is his mother not coming to pick him up after all?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She returns her gaze, cranes her neck upward. CUT to Ryuji leaning over the rim of the well, peering down at her. For an instant, everything becomes monochrome. It’s not Ryuji looking down at her at all; it’s Professor Ikuma, checking to see if she’s still alive or if the blow to the back of her head has finished her off. CUT to Asakawa, her eyes wide with fright. Asakawa comes to rest at the bottom of the well. A FLASHLIGHT hangs from another rope, but its beam has almost no effect on the darkness. Asakawa crouches forward, hands moving searchingly through the water. She calls out pleadingly.</context>
      <utterance>Don’t look down!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa straightens, unties herself from the rope. A full bucket already awaits. She tugs on the rope and Ryuji pulls it up. She scoops up a second bucket, but something stops her from sending it up. Instead, she begins running her arms through the water again, her voice close to tears.</context>
      <utterance>Where are you? Please, come out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa continues her blind fumbling, which sends up little splashes of stagnant water. With a start, she realizes that her fingers have caught something. Seaweed? Asakawa draws her hands close for a better look... and sees that is HAIR. A thick clump of long, black hair. Suddenly a pale, thin ARM shoots out from beneath the water, catching Asakawa just below the wrist. Asakawa’s ears are filled with a SOUND like moaning as something slowly rises from its watery slumber. It is a GIRL, her face completely hidden by long, black hair. CUT to a shot of Asakawa’s face. Far from being frightened, her features are oddly placid. She regards the fearsome thing before her with an almost tender look. Asakawa reaches out, lightly strokes that long hair.</context>
      <utterance>Please. Where are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She strokes the hair again, and abruptly it peels right off the head with a loud SQUELCH. Revealed is not a face at all but a SKULL. Its sockets are at first menacingly empty, but then begin to ooze the green SLUDGE it has pulled up from the bottom of the well. Like a mother comforting a frightened child, Asakawa pulls the skeletal remains to her breast, strokes the bony head comfortingly. Her eyes begin to glaze. CUT to Ryuji racing up to the rim of the well, leaning down intently.</context>
      <utterance>It’s you...</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Down in the well, Asakawa continues staring blankly ahead. Her body suddenly falls forward, limp.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Asakawa! It’s already 10 minutes past seven! We did it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would Ikuma have killed her? His own daughter...</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe she wasn’t his daughter at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two exchange glances. Ryuji’s gaze falls to Asakawa’s WRIST, which he suddenly takes and holds close to his face. The ugly bruise where Sadako had grabbed her has disappeared.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe her father... wasn’t even human.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shakes his head, clearing his analytical mind of their ordeal.</context>
      <utterance>It’s gone...</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryuji stands, pulls Asakawa to her feet.</context>
      <utterance>Enough, already. It’s over. C’mon. I’ll take you home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He flashes her the slightest of grins. RYUJI (cont’d) I still have a thesis to finish. CUT to a shot of Ryuji and Asakawa, the car creating an almost metaphoric distance between them.</context>
      <utterance>Get some rest.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryuji nods silently by way of reply. He gets into his car and drives off. Asakawa watches him go, and then walks towards the entrance of her apartment.</context>
      <utterance>...thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The TELEPHONE rings, and Ryuji spins round towards it, breath catching in his throat. He looks at the phone, over his shoulder at the television, back to the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Why?!</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryuji scrambles wildly towards the phone. He takes the receiver but is unable to do more than clutch it fearfully as his gaze is drawn inexorably back to the television. Sadako’s shrouded face has filled the entire screen... and then, television popping and crackling, she jerks forward and emerges from the television onto the floor of Ryuji’s apartment. Ryuji backs away, screaming in terror.</context>
      <utterance>That’s it! Asakawa...</utterance>
   <speaker>RYUJI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sadako lies prone, collapsed, hair splayed out like a drowned corpse. Only her FINGERS are active, crawling, feeling. The TIPS of her fingers are little more than bloodied stumps, not a single fingernail on them. She uses the strength in those fingers to pull herself forward, coming jerkily to her feet. The joints of her body twist unnaturally, more insect-like than human. Ryuji flings the phone aside and begins scrambling about the apartment as if looking for cover. The strength has already begun to fade from his body, however, and his movements are clumsy, exaggerated. He falls to the floor, panting heavily. Sadako turns to regard him, and for just an instant we can see beneath her impenetrable shroud of hair; a single EYE burns with manic, unbridled hatred. Its gaze meets Ryuji’s, and his face twists into a grimace as he SCREAMS loudly.</context>
      <utterance>Aaargh!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you a resident here, ma’am?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guard drops his hand, and Asakawa makes for the entrance.</context>
      <utterance>I’m Takayama Ryuji’s wife!</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa’s spins around, eyes wide. Body?</context>
      <utterance>I’m sorry ma’am, but they’ve already taken the body away.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mai shakes her head dreamily.</context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I got here he was just lying there...</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mai shakes her head again, shakes it harder until the breath catches in her throat.</context>
      <utterance>Did he say anything to you? About a videotape?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mai falls into silence, curls up on herself. Asakawa leaves her and crosses toward the door to Ryuji’s apartment.</context>
      <utterance>His face...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asakawa gives up, lowers her face into her hands. When she looks up again, she happens to glance at the television screen-- and its GLARE reveals that there is someone ELSE in the room with her. It is the figure from the videotape, the silent accuser with the cloth draped over its face. With a start, Asakawa realizes that the figure is wearing Ryuji’s clothes.</context>
      <utterance>I was the only one to break Sadako’s curse. Ryuji... why...? Something I did that you didn’t... Something I did that you didn’t...</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She spins around, but the room is empty. Asakawa’s mind races. The figure had been pointing towards her BAG. She stands, rummages in her bag to produce her copy of the cursed videotape. She takes Ryuji’s COPY in her other hand, her eyes darting between the two tapes.</context>
      <utterance>Ryuji?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It suddenly clicks home as Asakawa looks full-on at Ryuji’s version of the tape, plainly marked COPY.</context>
      <utterance>Something I did that you didn’t...</utterance>
   <speaker>ASAKAWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CUT to Asakawa slowly pulling her VCR from the television stand. A look of almost frightening resolve etches her face.</context>
      <utterance>What broke the curse was that I copied the tape and showed it to someone else!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GIRL A</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They say there’s a way you can stay alive after you watch the video. You’ve gotta make a copy of it, and show it to somebody else inside a week.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL B</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what about the person you show it to?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL A</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, then they make a copy and show it to somebody else. Again, inside a week.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL C</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then there’s no end to it.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
